<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-29T00:31:35.290Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-29T00:31:35.290Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coastguard seizes half a tonne of cocaine floating off Algeria coast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/29/coastguard-seizes-half-a-tonne-of-cocaine-floating-off-algeria-coast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/29/coastguard-seizes-half-a-tonne-of-cocaine-floating-off-algeria-coast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T00:03:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fishermen alerted authorities to ‘suspicious’ items floating in the sea
The Algerian coastguard has seized almost half a tonne of cocaine after fishers alerted authorities to “suspicious” items floating off the north-west coast.
The coastguard fished out 490kg (1,080 pounds) of cocaine split up into 442 packages from the water six nautical miles (11 kilometres) off Oran’s Cap Carbon on Saturday evening, a defence ministry statement said on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccines minister condemns video of Chris Whitty being harassed by ‘thugs’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/29/vaccines-minister-condemns-video-of-chris-whitty-being-harassed-by-thugs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/29/vaccines-minister-condemns-video-of-chris-whitty-being-harassed-by-thugs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:57:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[​Nadhim Zahawi calls for two men filmed harassing the chief medical officer in the street to be charged
Footage has emerged online apparently showing Prof Chris Whitty being accosted in public, with the vaccine minister calling for the “thugs” to face charges.
The video, which has been shared on social media, seems to show the chief medical officer struggling to get away as the people filming in selfie mode appear to manhandle him. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Victory for Facebook as court dismisses lawsuits seeking to split company]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/28/facebook-antitrust-lawsuits-dismissed-ftc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/28/facebook-antitrust-lawsuits-dismissed-ftc"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Federal judge ruled suits by FTC and state attorneys general didn’t provide enough evidence to prove Facebook was a monopoly
In a significant blow to US regulators’ attempt to rein in big tech, a federal judge has dismissed lawsuits brought against Facebook by the Federal Trade Commission and a broad coalition of state attorneys general.
The US government and 48 states and districts sued Facebook in December 2020, accusing the tech company of abusing its market power in social networking to crush smaller competitors and seeking remedies that could include a forced spin-off of the social network’s Instagram and WhatsApp messaging services.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Love Island review – I hate myself but I can’t stop. Please, somebody, help!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/29/love-island-seven-review-i-hate-myself-but-i-cant-stop-please-somebody-help</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/29/love-island-seven-review-i-hate-myself-but-i-cant-stop-please-somebody-help"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest lineup of buff beauties are in the villa, with added mental health measures and more reasons to question yourself for viewing. But try not to dwell – let the nonsense commence!
I don’t know. I don’t know. If I had to bring in stringent checks on people’s mental health and resilience, if I had to ensure that a ‘welfare team’ was on set at all times during filming, provide ongoing psychological support plus social media training for those leaving, and ensure the screen was plastered with infographics begging viewers to “Think before they post” to try to mitigate the onslaught of online abuse that previous series of this and similar shows are proven to elicit, I might … pause for thought.
All these measures and more have been brought in by the makers of the phenomenal hit Love Island, as it returns for its seventh series, because of its bleak history. That includes contestants becoming the victims of revenge porn and death threats after their appearances, criticism from the charity Women’s Aid for the treatment of female contestants by “controlling” and “abusive” male participants and, most notably, the deaths by suicide of two contestants and its host for five series, Caroline Flack. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rev Richard Coles calls for end to glamourising of alcoholism on TV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/29/rev-richard-coles-calls-end-glamourising-alcoholism-tv</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/29/rev-richard-coles-calls-end-glamourising-alcoholism-tv"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vicar, whose partner died of alcoholic liver disease, hits out at inaccurate depictions of excess
The Rev Richard Coles has called for more realistic and less glamourised depictions of alcoholism on TV as he recalled his late husband’s battle with excessive drinking that led to his death.
Coles, a vicar in Northamptonshire, said there was a need to restore “realism to a distorted picture” of “how we poison ourselves” for fear of romanticising a debilitating disease.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once Upon a Time in Hollywood review – Tarantino’s debut novel shines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/29/once-upon-a-time-in-hollywood-review-tarantinos-debut-novel-shines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/29/once-upon-a-time-in-hollywood-review-tarantinos-debut-novel-shines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The director’s pulpy novelisation of his most recent film is entirely outrageous and addictively readable
Quentin Tarantino made a career alchemising movie trash into gold: with a connoisseur’s ecstasy, he worked with B-movie language and grindhouse rhetoric. Now he’s done the same with a genre the literary world wrinkles its nose at, the pulpiest of pulp fiction – the novelisation. This is normally the lowliest kind of movie brand promotion, which had its heyday before the VHS age, targeted at film fans who wanted a way to relive the experience.
Tarantino has turned his most recent film, Once Upon a Time in Hollywood, into a novel: messing with the timeline, cranking up the backstories, mulching up reality and alt.reality pastiche, ladling in new episodes. The result comes packaged in something like those New English Library paperbacks that used to be on carousel displays in supermarkets and drugstores. In the endpapers he cheekily includes ads for old commercial paperbacks real and imagined, such as Erich Segal’s Oliver’s Story, sequel to Love Story (“Soon to be a major motion picture”).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children of immigrants ‘held back by employer discrimination’ in UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/29/children-of-immigrants-held-back-by-employer-discrimination-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/29/children-of-immigrants-held-back-by-employer-discrimination-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Second-generation African, Caribbean and Asian people more likely to have a degree but also to be unemployed, report finds
Employer discrimination is holding back second-generation African, Caribbean and Asian people in the jobs market even though they tend to be more highly educated, according to a report by the Institute for Fiscal Studies.
People of that background whose parents emigrated to Britain were far more likely to get a university degree than their white British peers, but they faced much higher unemployment rates overall. However, the report also showed that once in employment, they tended to be more upwardly mobile and were more likely to be in professional or managerial jobs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Education secretary wants ban on mobile phones in English schools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/29/education-secretary-wants-ban-on-mobile-phones-in-english-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/29/education-secretary-wants-ban-on-mobile-phones-in-english-schools"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gavin Williamson launches consultation on behaviour, but unions say it is an attempt to distract from government’s Covid failures
Mobile phones could be banned in schools as part of a government clampdown on poor discipline in classrooms in England.
The education secretary, Gavin Williamson, said he wants a ban on mobile phones as he launched a consultation on pupil behaviour and discipline in schools. He said he wanted to make the school day “mobile-free” to help ensure that classrooms remain calm and pupils can overcome the impact of the pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equinor to triple UK hydrogen output with new plant near Hull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/29/equinor-to-triple-uk-hydrogen-output-with-new-plant-near-hull</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/29/equinor-to-triple-uk-hydrogen-output-with-new-plant-near-hull"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Norwegian oil company’s facility will be biggest in world with carbon capture and storage technology 
Norway’s state oil company Equinor will triple its UK hydrogen output, after setting out plans to build the world’s biggest hydrogen production plant with carbon capture and storage technology near Hull.
Equinor plans to produce clean-burning “blue hydrogen” to supply the Keadby gas power plant in Lincolnshire, owned by energy company SSE, making it the world’s first full-scale power plant to burn pure hydrogen to generate electricity.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘He is very affected by it’: Deschamps defends Mbappé as France crash out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/nobody-can-be-annoyed-with-him-deschamps-defends-mbappe-as-france-crash-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/nobody-can-be-annoyed-with-him-deschamps-defends-mbappe-as-france-crash-out"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:56:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PSG striker misses crucial penalty in Euros loss to Switzerland
Deschamps: ‘Kylian feels guilty, but he shouldn’t’

Didier Deschamps refused to blame Kylian Mbappé for the missed penalty that sent France to a stunning defeat against Switzerland on a dramatic night in Bucharest. Switzerland scored two late goals within the 90 minutes to send the game into extra-time, after which the PSG striker was the only man to miss in the shootout.
 Related: Switzerland’s Sommer saves Mbappé’s penalty to send France crashing out 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames at the National Arena Bucharest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mexico supreme court strikes down laws that ban use of recreational marijuana]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/mexicos-high-court-strikes-down-laws-that-ban-use-of-recreational-marijuana</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/mexicos-high-court-strikes-down-laws-that-ban-use-of-recreational-marijuana"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:22:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adults will be able to apply for permits to grow and consume cannabis after decision that moves country toward legalisation
Mexico’s supreme court has struck down laws prohibiting the use of recreational marijuana, moving the country toward cannabis legalisation even as the country’s congress drags its feet on a legalisation bill.
In an 8-3 decision on Monday, the court ruled that sections of the country’s general health law prohibiting personal consumption and home cultivation of marijuana were unconstitutional.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Agren in Mexico City</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[System *Things]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343040</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/system-things/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:14:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think we’re all largely aware of named colors in CSS:
color: OldLace;
background: rebeccapurple;
I guess you’d just call those “named colors” in CSS. 
Those aren’t the only kind of named colors there are though. Some of them …
The post System *Things appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obama: Trump broke ‘core tenet’ of democracy with ‘bunch of hooey’ over election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/barack-obama-donald-trump-democracy-election-hooey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/barack-obama-donald-trump-democracy-election-hooey"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:06:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-president calls for action to stop ‘delegitimizing of democracy’ during redistricting fundraiser
Barack Obama said on Monday that his successor in office, Donald Trump, violated a “core tenet” of democracy when he made up a “bunch of hooey” about last year’s election and refused to concede he lost.
Speaking at his first virtual fundraiser since the 2020 election, the former Democratic president said former Republican president’s claims undermined the legitimacy of US elections and helped lead to other anti-democratic measures such as efforts to suppress the vote.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami condo collapse: death toll rises to 11 as rescue teams continue search]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/miami-condo-collapse-rescue-surfside-search</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/miami-condo-collapse-rescue-surfside-search"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 150 unaccounted for as officials urge people to hope
White House says Biden wants federal inquiry into collapse

The death toll from a building collapse in the Miami suburb of Surfside rose to 11 on Monday, as rescue operations continued into a fifth day.
Officials urged people to maintain hope survivors might be found in the wreckage of the collapsed condo building. A further 150 people who may have been in the building remained unaccounted for, the mayor of Miami-Dade, Daniella Levine Cava, said on Monday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda Holpuch and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switzerland’s Sommer saves Mbappé’s penalty to send France crashing out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/france-switzerland-euro-2020-last-16-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/france-switzerland-euro-2020-last-16-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:03:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kylian Mbappé was France’s sure thing. That is why he was fifth in their list of penalty takers and is why, when he stepped up to keep them in Euro 2020, the thought he might miss felt like too heady a twist in the narrative. Things like that have simply not happened to Mbappé during a young career of rare accomplishment, but here came the kind of horror that exposes even the preternaturally gifted as flesh-and-blood mortals: Yann Sommer, Switzerland’s exceptional goalkeeper, smelled weakness and read his intentions correctly, diving right and clawing the spot-kick away. France were out; their delirious opponents had made their own slice of history and a tournament of unstinting drama took its least plausible turn yet.
 Related: ‘He is very affected by it’: Deschamps defends Mbappé as France crash out 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames at the National Arena Bucharest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wimbledon reopens as Andy Murray and vaccine scientists get huge cheers | Sean Ingle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/wimbledon-reopens-but-andy-murray-has-fans-on-edge-with-dramatic-victory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/wimbledon-reopens-but-andy-murray-has-fans-on-edge-with-dramatic-victory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the opening day, Andy Murray thrilled a 8,000-strong crowd on Centre Court, which also saw a new British star emerge
On a night of the highest sporting drama, Andy Murray rolled back the years with a stunning, seesawing win in his first appearance at Wimbledon since 2017. But it came only after an epic wobble against the 24th seed, Nikoloz Basilashvili, when victory had appeared a foregone conclusion.
 Related: Andy Murray overcomes Wimbledon wobble to defeat Nikoloz Basilashvili 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Germany’s Gündogan, Rüdiger and Gosens doubts for England game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/germanys-ilkay-gundogan-antonio-rudiger-and-robin-gosens-doubtful-for-euro-2020-england-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/germanys-ilkay-gundogan-antonio-rudiger-and-robin-gosens-doubtful-for-euro-2020-england-game"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:37:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Key trio all have fitness concerns before Euro 2020 clash
Manuel Neuer says team will take knee to ‘show solidarity’

Joachim Löw will be forced into late fitness calls on Ilkay Gündogan, Antonio Rüdiger and Robin Gosens before Germany’s last-16 meeting with England at Wembley on Tuesday. The trio, ordinarily starters, were among the party that arrived in London on Monday but doubts remain over their availability.
Löw explained Rüdiger and Gosens are suffering from “small infections” and “tiredness” which the coach likened to a cold, with Gündogan seeking to shake off a head injury. “We decide with the doctors on match day,” said Löw. “Maybe they [Rüdiger and Gosens] will get up and feel well but maybe it will get worse overnight so we need to wait. I don’t know if these three will be at our disposal, I cannot say that. But [if not] we will have other solutions.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sajid Javid, the TSB of health secretaries, arrives and says ‘yes’ to everything]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/sajid-javid-the-tsb-of-health-secretaries-arrives-and-says-yes-to-everything</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/sajid-javid-the-tsb-of-health-secretaries-arrives-and-says-yes-to-everything"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:35:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs pile in to celebrate his appointment, and you can see their point, he’s definitely preferable to Hancock
The rumour was that Matt Hancock’s departure became inevitable when the rest of the frontbench refused to go out and support him. Even so, it felt a bit iffy that, of a few words mangled by Sajid Javid, in his first performance as the new health secretary, the first was the prefix “honourable” to the MP for West Suffolk. Dude, nobody’s asking you to go out and bat for the man. You just have to get the letters in the right order.
It was a performance with a difference from Javid, the difference being that he basically said “yes” to everything. Where it wasn’t a yes, it was a hard confirm. He was the TSB of health secretaries, the man who says yes not because you’re his brother-in-law but because he likes to. It will unfold over time what this pile-up of yessing actually means – will he give NHS staff a pay rise? Yes, it will certainly be a “fair” settlement – but before he greeted thirty brisk questions in the affirmative (a pass for Richard Burgon’s, but we’ll come to that), there was the business of his speech.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combat staff shortages by relaxing Brexit immigration rules, says CBI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/combat-staff-shortages-by-relaxing-brexit-immigration-rules-says-cbi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/combat-staff-shortages-by-relaxing-brexit-immigration-rules-says-cbi"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:30:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business lobby group warns failure to act will put UK’s economic recovery from Covid crisis at risk

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The UK’s biggest business lobby group has called on the government to relax post-Brexit immigration rules to help companies struggling with staff shortages to hire more workers from overseas.
The Confederation of British Industry (CBI) said the government needed to immediately update its “shortage occupations list” to include several areas where employers are finding it difficult to recruit staff, including butchers, bricklayers and welders.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agents ‘will make hundreds of millions’ from post-Grenfell safety work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/agents-will-make-hundreds-of-millions-from-post-grenfell-safety-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/agents-will-make-hundreds-of-millions-from-post-grenfell-safety-work"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:30:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour calls for nationalisation of process of fixing high-rise flats to eliminate administration fees
Property agents stand to earn hundreds of millions of pounds by charging administration fees on works to make buildings safe after the Grenfell Tower fire, Labour has said, as it urged the government to nationalise the process of making high-rise flats safe.
Managing agents of tower blocks caught up in the building safety crisis are charging fees of around 4% on multimillion-pound works to fix cladding and combustible walls on thousands of homes. With the government having pledged £5.1bn for the works so far, the opposition has estimated that the fees on publicly funded repairs could reach £200m, with more charged on additional safety bills to be met from leaseholders’ own pockets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working around the viewport-based fluid typography bug in Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343139</id>
        <link href="https://www.sarasoueidan.com/blog/safari-fluid-typography-bug-fix/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sara digs into a bug I happened to have mentioned back in 2012 where fluid type didn’t resize when the browser window resized. Back then, it affected Chrome 20 and Safari 6, but the bug still persists today in Safari …
The post Working around the viewport-based fluid typography bug in Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Securely Access Secret API keys using Netlify Functions in a React App]]></title>
        <id>60d61acc6e1a1407b6b0bd46</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-access-secret-api-keys-using-netlify-functions-in-a-react-app/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:17:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you will learn how to securely access secret API keys using Netlify functions in a React app.  Netlify provides rich features that help you easily deploy Single Page Applications built using frameworks like React, Vue and Angular among others. This takes away the burden of coding and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Murray overcomes Wimbledon wobble to defeat Nikoloz Basilashvili]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/andy-murray-beats-nikoloz-basilashvili-wimbledon-tennis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/andy-murray-beats-nikoloz-basilashvili-wimbledon-tennis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:16:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Murray loses seven straight games from 5-0 up in third set
Scot eventually beats the 24th seed, 6-4, 6-3, 5-7, 6-3 

In the four years since Andy Murray last won a singles match at Wimbledon, the two-times champion has been to sporting hell and back, battered by constant doubt and injury setbacks in a career that seemed to have reached its end so many times. But at no point during his toils did he ever lose his will to succeed and he continues to do all he can in service of that goal.
Back in the Wimbledon singles draw once more, Murray took an invaluable step forward as he defeated Nikoloz Basilashvili, the 24th seed, 6-4, 6-3, 5-7, 6-3 to reach the second round.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol at Wimbledon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welsh leader attacks ‘aggressively unilateral’ UK government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/welsh-leader-mark-drakeford-attacks-aggressively-unilateral-uk-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/welsh-leader-mark-drakeford-attacks-aggressively-unilateral-uk-government"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Drakeford calls for urgent reset to protect ‘fragile’ union, and for Wales to get control of its own policing
The Welsh first minister has launched a fierce attack on the UK government’s attitude to the devolved nations, accusing it of favouring “flag flying” over constructive thinking and acting in an “aggressively unilateral way”.
Mark Drakeford argued that it was time for relations between Westminster and the devolved governments to be reset to protect the “fragile” union, and called for Wales to be allowed to take control of its own legal system and policing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy an NLP Model with FastAPI]]></title>
        <id>60d9766b6e1a1407b6b0cb4f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-an-nlp-model-with-fastapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T20:35:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're working with Natural Language Processing, knowing how to deploy a model is one of the most important skills you'll need to have. Model deployment is the process of integrating your model into an existing production environment. The model will receive input and predict an output for decision-making for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is an IDE in Programming? An IDE Definition for Developers]]></title>
        <id>60d07b4578f45307fee80aef</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-an-ide-in-programming-an-ide-definition-for-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T20:04:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every developer needs a good development enviroment, whether you're into mobile development or web apps or even if you're just learning your first programming language.  Just like any beginning developer, when I began to learn coding I needed some guidance on how to get started. And one of the most]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greek police recover two stolen paintings by Picasso and Mondrian]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/greek-police-recover-two-stolen-paintings-by-picasso-and-mondrian</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/greek-police-recover-two-stolen-paintings-by-picasso-and-mondrian"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:58:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Works by the 20th-century masters recovered nearly a decade after their theft from the country’s biggest state art gallery in Athens
Greek police have recovered two paintings by 20th-century masters Pablo Picasso and Piet Mondrian, nearly a decade after their theft from the country’s biggest state art gallery in Athens.
A statement late on Monday said the two works were in the hands of the police, but provided no detail on their condition and on whether any arrests had been made.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AP in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England sense their moment to shake off weight of history against Germany | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/28/understated-england-have-the-tools-to-pull-off-historic-victory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/28/understated-england-have-the-tools-to-pull-off-historic-victory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:45:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This understated England team are not universally popular but have the tools to win at Wembley and change their narrative
“Gareth Southgate, the whole of England is with you!” Is it, though? As Southgate prepares to send his injury-free, defensively unbreached, quietly purposeful England team into the last-16 tie against Germany on Tuesday night, two things stand out.
First, it is hard to recall such a talented, well-set England team approaching a tournament knockout tie so grudgingly praised in their own country. Welcome to England 2021, a place where even the football feels a little seasick right now. And second, like it or not, rail against the simplicity, draw attention instead to the process if you must – but this is a moment that will define the progress of Southgate’s England.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Shaking and bleeding’: plea for protection after violence on Batley and Spen campaign trail]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/i-was-terrified-campaigners-attacked-on-batley-and-spen-byelection-trail</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/i-was-terrified-campaigners-attacked-on-batley-and-spen-byelection-trail"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:45:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Candidates and canvassers have been heckled and manhandled in byelection described as the ‘worst ever’
“This is the worst election I have ever seen in my life,” says Dr Abdulrehman Rajpura. The 77-year-old retired GP and former chairman of the local mosque had just hung up the phone to an officer from West Yorkshire police, pleading for protection for himself and his home.
On Sunday afternoon Rajpura was with a group of Labour activists in Batley when they were physically attacked and pelted with eggs, he told the Guardian.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson and Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers set to end automatic isolation for pupils in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/28/ministers-set-to-end-automatic-isolation-for-pupils-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/28/ministers-set-to-end-automatic-isolation-for-pupils-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:25:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move means hundreds of thousands of schoolchildren will no longer have to stay at home after contact with Covid case

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Hundreds of thousands of pupils will no longer have to automatically isolate after contact with a positive Covid case when schools return in September in England, ministers are expected to announce.
A quarter of a million children missed school in a single week because of coronavirus infections, self-isolation or school closures this month – the most disrupted week since schools fully reopened across the country in March.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti, Jessica Elgot and Natalie Grover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scott Parker joins Bournemouth as manager after leaving Fulham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/scott-parker-fulham-bournemouth</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/scott-parker-fulham-bournemouth"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:24:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager one of a clutch of figures to leave Craven Cottage
Parker to replace Jonathan Woodgate at Bournemouth

Scott Parker has been confirmed as Bournemouth’s new manager after leaving Fulham by mutual consent.
The 40-year-old’s departure from Craven Cottage was swiftly followed by confirmation that he will succeed Jonathan Woodgate at the south coast club on a three-year deal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson: a new face at department of health – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/28/martin-rowson-boris-johnson-matt-hancock-departure-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/28/martin-rowson-boris-johnson-matt-hancock-departure-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buy a copy of this cartoon from our print shop
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interim government of Tigray flees as rebels seize capital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/interim-government-of-tigray-flees-as-rebels-advance-on-mekelle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/interim-government-of-tigray-flees-as-rebels-advance-on-mekelle"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T19:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spokesperson for Tigray People’s Liberation Front says Mekelle is ‘under our control’
The interim government of Ethiopia’s war-hit Tigray region has fled as rebel fighters advanced into the region’s capital and the national government announced a “unilateral ceasefire”.
Witnesses said federal soldiers and police were also abandoning Mekelle late on Monday, and fireworks and celebratory gunfire could be heard as Tigrayan fighters took the city’s airport and other key positions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emmanuel Akinwotu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain’s Álvaro Morata finds something extra to beat Croatia in thriller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/croatia-spain-euro-2020-last-16-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/28/croatia-spain-euro-2020-last-16-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:51:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a scoreline from another age and a match for the ages, a wild, thunderous and implausible afternoon that went from the ridiculous to the sublime and back again. It left the people up here as exhausted as the players were down there, struggling to remember everything that had happened but certain that they would never forget the way it made them feel. The kind of match that left many questions, including: how do you explain it? Where do you even start with this?
With the score: 5-3? With the 35 shots? With the fact that Spain won, securing a place in the quarter-final? Or the fact that they had to win twice? With Croatia’s implausible revival? With the noise, the occasion, the nerves? With the quality, and there was plenty of that? With the heart, of which there was even more? With the silliness, because there was some of that too? How about with the goal that ultimately brought this to an end perhaps, finally carrying Spain through a storm?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe at Parken Stadium, Copenhagen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Closure Tutorial – How Closures and Lexical Scope Work in JS]]></title>
        <id>60d675ac6e1a1407b6b0bea1</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-closure-lexical-scope/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:45:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In JavaScript, people often confuse closures with lexical scope. Lexical scope is an important part of closures, but it is not a closure by itself. Closures are an advanced concept that is also a frequent topic of technical interviews. You should have a foundational understanding of functions before attempting to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marco Gobbetti’s early exit leaves Burberry blindsided | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/28/marco-gobbettis-early-exit-leaves-burberry-blindsided</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/28/marco-gobbettis-early-exit-leaves-burberry-blindsided"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:44:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chief executive was hired to solve one boardroom crisis but his departure has caused another

Burberry boss Marco Gobbetti to step down after five years
Partnership ends that kept Burberry at leading cultural edge

Marco Gobbetti was hired by Burberry to solve one boardroom crisis – the uncomfortable reign as chief executive of Christopher Bailey, who was clearly better suited to being the creative boss. By skipping off early, though, he’s caused another. Burberry doesn’t have a succession plan, as far as one can tell, which is not ideal when the UK’s leading fashion house is persistently talked about as a takeover candidate.
You could see Burberry’s discomfort in its effort to describe Gobbetti’s time as “nearly” five years with the company. It depends on how you count it. He became chief executive almost exactly four years ago after a six-month warm-up tour of Asia. More relevantly, he launched his five-year plan in November 2017, so, even if he stays until the end of this year, he will have overseen only four years of a five-year overhaul, which is not quite a full lap of the catwalk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Batley byelection hit by claims of dirty tricks and ‘dog-whistle racism’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/tuc-condemns-batley-byelection-dirty-tricks-after-fake-labour-leaflet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/tuc-condemns-batley-byelection-dirty-tricks-after-fake-labour-leaflet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:39:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TUC takes legal advice over fake leaflets as Labour MP criticises some of own party’s literature
The Batley and Spen byelection has descended into allegations of dirty tricks as Labour’s campaign was targeted by fake leaflets and the party was accused by one of its own MPs of using “dog-whistle racism” to win votes.
Labour was criticised for distributing a flyer to Muslim voters showing Boris Johnson with India’s nationalist prime minister, Narendra Modi, in 2019, along with the message: “Don’t risk a Tory MP who is not on your side.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Halliday and Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lions arrive in South Africa but rising Covid rates threaten tour plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/lions-arrive-in-south-africa-but-rising-covid-rates-threaten-tour-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/lions-arrive-in-south-africa-but-rising-covid-rates-threaten-tour-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:19:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rise in infections in the province of Gauteng may move matches
All three Tests and other major matches could be in Cape Town

The British & Irish Lions have arrived safely in South Africa but uncertainty still hangs over their tour itinerary, with rising Covid-19 infection rates in the province of Gauteng prompting increasing concern. The possibility of staging the majority of the tour games, and potentially all three Tests, in Cape Town is under discussion, although South African officials remain keen to stick to the existing schedule.
Every precaution is being taken to ensure the tour can proceed safely, with the Lions’ hand luggage being carefully sprayed with disinfectant at Johannesburg airport, but the Lions are not yet absolutely sure if they will be staying put in Gauteng for their opening three tour fixtures next month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lorry driver shortage: UK government and retailers in emergency talks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/lorry-driver-shortage-uk-government-and-retailers-in-emergency-talks-covid-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/lorry-driver-shortage-uk-government-and-retailers-in-emergency-talks-covid-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:19:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Defra looks for solutions as Covid and Brexit problems threaten to leave gaps on supermarket shelves
The UK government has held emergency talks with retailers, logistics groups and wholesalers as a shortage of lorry drivers threatens to leave gaps on supermarket shelves.
Officials from the Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs (Defra) are understood to have discussed potential solutions, including relaxing restrictions on drivers’ working hours and increasing capacity for HGV driving tests and training to help bring in new local drivers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jack Draper gives Novak Djokovic brief Wimbledon scare before pressure tells]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/jack-draper-gives-novak-djokovic-brief-wimbledon-scare-before-pressure-tells</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/jack-draper-gives-novak-djokovic-brief-wimbledon-scare-before-pressure-tells"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:12:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World No 1 Djokovic wins 4-6, 6-1, 6-2, 6-2 in first round
British 19-year-old shows glimpse of his future potential

Jack Draper was milling around Wimbledon’s practice courts at Aorangi Park on Friday morning, unaware that the draw was taking place, when the 19-year-old caught a glimpse of his name in the top section and realised his first ever grand slam match would be against Novak Djokovic, the best player in the world, on the most famous court in the country.
Any kind of tension or trepidation would be completely understandable for an unproven teenager who has barely even had the chance to compete against top 100 players, yet he fearlessly embraced the moment and clearly demonstrated his talent. Eventually, Djokovic reeled in the world number 253 and moved on in four comfortable sets 4-6, 6-1, 6-2, 6-2.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol at Wimbledon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winner of BrewDog’s ‘solid gold’ beer can finds prize is made largely of brass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/winner-of-brewdogs-solid-gold-beer-can-finds-prize-is-made-mostly-of-brass</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/winner-of-brewdogs-solid-gold-beer-can-finds-prize-is-made-mostly-of-brass"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:12:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish brewery claims cans are worth £15,000 each but certificate says they are gold plated

A man who won a “solid gold” can of BrewDog beer has been left disappointed after the prize, which the Scottish brewery claims is worth £15,000, turned out to be largely made of brass.
BrewDog and its chief executive, James Watt, advertised the chance to win the can across multiple media platforms between November 2020 and March 2021, as part of a promotional competition.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on political trust: voters put store by it, the PM does not | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/the-guardian-view-on-political-trust-voters-put-store-by-it-the-pm-does-not</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/the-guardian-view-on-political-trust-voters-put-store-by-it-the-pm-does-not"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:09:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister wants no one in his cabinet to pay for their mistakes, a strategy that has failed

The departure of Matt Hancock from the cabinet is not the end of the matter. It may only be the beginning. Boris Johnson swiftly appointed former chancellor Sajid Javid to replace Mr Hancock, who resigned a day after pictures showing him kissing his aide Gina Coladangelo at work in breach of the government’s social distancing regulations. Yet the whole business raises questions about how government works, who it is in office to serve and risks eroding confidence in public health measures.
In breaking his own pandemic rules Mr Hancock diminished the public’s willingness to adhere to lockdown guidelines. He thought he could apologise and move on. But clearly nothing less than his resignation would restore trust in the government’s ability to manage the pandemic, which is vital as it underpins public attitudes and behaviours. There is such a thing as trust and respect in politics. They make a difference, despite Mr Johnson setting no store by them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nissan expected to announce plans to build battery ‘gigafactory’ in Sunderland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/nissan-expected-to-announce-plans-to-build-battery-gigafactory-in-sunderland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/nissan-expected-to-announce-plans-to-build-battery-gigafactory-in-sunderland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:09:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese carmaker understood to be preparing to build 200,000 batteries for electric vehicles every year in the UK
Japanese carmaker Nissan is set to confirm plans to build a battery “gigafactory” in Sunderland this week, handing a significant post-Brexit jobs and investment boost to the UK’s under-pressure automotive sector.
Nissan is expected to promise to build as many as 200,000 batteries for electric vehicles every year in the UK, in partnership with Chinese specialist Envision AESC.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on France’s regional polls: democracy a big loser | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/the-guardian-view-on-frances-regional-polls-democracy-a-big-loser</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/the-guardian-view-on-frances-regional-polls-democracy-a-big-loser"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:08:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A record-low turnout was bad news for Marine Le Pen, but should also be a cause for wider concern
The morning after the final round of France’s regional elections, the two most likely contenders for the Élysée in next year’s presidential elections were left licking their wounds. Marine Le Pen’s far-right Rassemblement National (RN) had the worst night, failing to win any of five regions it had targeted – some of them with high hopes of victory. President Emmanuel Macron’s party, La République En Marche, also failed to win anywhere and remains a phantasmagorical presence in the country at large. For a grassroots movement set up five years ago to renew politics, polling at around 7% is not a good look. The big winner of the night was the centre-right Republican, Xavier Bertrand, whose presidential ambitions have been considerably boosted by an impressive victory in the northern region of Hauts-de-France. A Macron-Le Pen run off next spring is not the foregone conclusion it once seemed.
Perhaps the most eye-catching statistic of all, however, was the turnout figure. The overwhelming, runaway winner of these polls was the unofficial stay-at-home party. Less than 35% of those eligible to vote opted to do so – a record low and only a fraction above last week’s first-round vote (also a record). Among 18- to 24-year-olds, close to 90% may have ignored the elections, while a huge majority of under-35s also found something better to do.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Organisers blame government as Womad festival cancelled again]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/womad-cancelled-as-organisers-blame-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/womad-cancelled-as-organisers-blame-government"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T18:06:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Co-founder Peter Gabriel points to lack of insurance support as festival is called off for second year
Womad festival has been cancelled for the second year in a row, with the co-founder Peter Gabriel blaming the government’s refusal to provide insurance support for festivals and a lack of clarity on how large-scale events should proceed after the proposed lockdown easing on 19 July.
“We feel that our audience, artists, staff and contractors, who have been amazingly supportive throughout all this, will understand the need for us to act to guarantee our survival,” Gabriel said in a statement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Snapes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health minister Helen Whately used private email for government work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/health-minister-helen-whately-used-private-email-for-government-work-matt-hancock</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/health-minister-helen-whately-used-private-email-for-government-work-matt-hancock"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:57:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: social care minister’s use of Gmail will raise further questions after reports about Matt Hancock
A third health minister, Helen Whately, used a private email account for government business, the Guardian can reveal, as the UK’s information watchdog said it was considering launching an investigation into the use of Gmail by Matt Hancock and James Bethell.
The Guardian can also reveal a number of emails were copied into Lord Bethell’s private email account. His address was copied into at least four official exchanges relating to a businessman who was attempting to get government contracts during the pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot and Rob Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have plenty’: community spaces study is disputed in Yarmouth North]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/we-have-plenty-community-spaces-study-disputed-yarmouth-north</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/we-have-plenty-community-spaces-study-disputed-yarmouth-north"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:41:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not all those in one of England’s worst-off wards agree with study on left behind neighbourhoods

England’s poorest areas left far behind with lack of social infrastructure

With its sand dunes and sprawling beach, the ward of Yarmouth North in Great Yarmouth does not at first glance appear to be somewhere that fits the tag of “left-behind neighbourhood” that it has been given in a study of England’s poorest areas.
The analysis, conducted by Oxford Consultants for Social Inclusion of public assets in the worst-off council wards, found that left-behind neighbourhoods on average have a disproportionate lack of social infrastructure in comparison with the national average.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s poorest areas left far behind with lack of social infrastructure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/england-poorest-areas-left-far-behind-lack-social-infrastructure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/england-poorest-areas-left-far-behind-lack-social-infrastructure"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:41:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds 10% worst-off wards are also least likely to get government funds to renew their communities

‘We have plenty’: community spaces study is disputed in Yarmouth North

England’s poorest neighbourhoods have by far the biggest shortages of basic social infrastructure such as parks, playgrounds, pubs, shops and sports facilities – and are least likely to get government funding to renew their community, a study has found.
An audit of public assets in the 10% worst-off council wards – known as “left behind neighbourhoods” – found they had disproportionately fewer public spaces and buildings, and were less than half as likely to have charities and community groups in their local area.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Butler Social policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We can actually make a big difference’: Peter Singer and philanthropic experts on giving well]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/29/we-can-actually-make-a-big-difference-peter-singer-and-philanthropic-experts-on-giving-well</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/29/we-can-actually-make-a-big-difference-peter-singer-and-philanthropic-experts-on-giving-well"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the end of the financial year looms, many Australians turn their eyes to charitable giving. Here,  professionals in the field suggest how to make donations that count
Just over a decade ago, Peter Singer issued a fundamental challenge to the relatively wealthy world. In The Life You Can Save, the Australian philosopher argued that most of us have more than we need to live a comfortable life. The money spent on that excess could instead be used to save someone’s life, and should be.
As Australians near the end of the financial year, eyes wander to sales and minds flicker to the subject of tax deductions. June is traditionally a time when many make charitable donations. But how has the way we give – and think about giving – changed, and how can we do it better?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Celina Ribeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds evacuated from Elephant and Castle fire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/28/fire-in-elephant-and-castle-south-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/28/fire-in-elephant-and-castle-south-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One person taken to hospital after 100 firefighters tackle large blaze near south London tube station
Hundreds of residents were evacuated and one person was taken to hospital after a large blaze in south London, which sent a fireball and black smoke billowing into the air.
Fifteen fire engines and about 100 firefighters were called to the incident, which began at a car repair garage below Elephant and Castle station shortly before 1.45pm on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique and Matthew Weaver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google search feature gives wrong guidance on UK self-isolation rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/28/google-search-feature-gives-wrong-guidance-on-uk-self-isolation-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/28/google-search-feature-gives-wrong-guidance-on-uk-self-isolation-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T17:25:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information was parsed from gov.uk website incorrectly, leading to possible confusion over Covid requirements

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Google has been sharing incorrect instructions on contact tracing through its Covid-19 “common questions” feature, advising some users that they can stop self-isolating when NHS rules say the opposite.
The flaw is the latest example of Google incorrectly parsing information from websites and trying to present a simple answer to keep users from clicking away from the search engine. The company has pledged that it will now fix the advice after a government request to do so.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern Technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK and Brussels near deal on Covid passports to boost holiday hopes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/uk-and-brussels-near-deal-on-covid-passports-to-boost-holiday-hopes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/uk-and-brussels-near-deal-on-covid-passports-to-boost-holiday-hopes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:58:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talks progressing on recognition of status certificates, while German calls for caution failing to win support

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Hopes have been raised of summer holidays in Europe for fully vaccinated Britons as a deal with Brussels on Covid passports neared completion and Germany failed to convince popular destinations to pull an “emergency brake” on UK visitors.
Restrictions on travel are tightening across the continent for tourists coming from the UK who have not had two jabs, owing to concerns over the highly transmissible Delta variant now dominant in Britain.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels and Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starmer appoints new political director amid Labour backroom shake-up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/starmer-appoints-new-political-director-amid-labour-backroom-shake-up-luke-sullivan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/starmer-appoints-new-political-director-amid-labour-backroom-shake-up-luke-sullivan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:53:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choice of Luke Sullivan, a longtime whips’ aide, will be seen as way to soothe rank-and-file MPs
Keir Starmer has replaced his controversial political director Jenny Chapman with longtime Labour whips’ aide Luke Sullivan, who ran the parliamentary operation during the Jeremy Corbyn years.
Sullivan was adviser to the former chief whip Nick Brown whom Starmer sacked in May. Chapman moves into the shadow cabinet to become the party’s Brexit spokesperson, shadowing Lord Frost.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Y-fronts at the ready! Why the Crown casting Jonny Lee Miller as John Major is discomfiting fans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/28/y-fronts-at-the-ready-why-the-crown-casting-johnny-lee-miller-as-john-major-is-discomfiting-fans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/28/y-fronts-at-the-ready-why-the-crown-casting-johnny-lee-miller-as-john-major-is-discomfiting-fans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:50:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Gillian Anderson as Margaret Thatcher, the series has cast the Trainspotting star as the former PM known as the grey man of politics
Name: Jonny Lee Miller.
Age: 48.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Pregnancy is another selling point’: the rise of the celebrity baby bump reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/28/pregnancy-is-another-selling-point-the-rise-of-the-celebrity-baby-bump-reveal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/28/pregnancy-is-another-selling-point-the-rise-of-the-celebrity-baby-bump-reveal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:37:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Beyoncé to Cardi B, pop culture pregnancy announcements are both destigmatising moments and marketing opportunities
On Sunday night, Cardi B announced her pregnancy in typically show-stopping fashion: on stage. At the BET awards in Los Angeles, during a performance with her husband, Offset’s band, Migos, the rapper appeared in a rhinestone-encrusted bodysuit with a bulging baby bump. On Instagram, she posted a profile photo of herself cradling the bump, with only a white plaster cast on her body, captioned with the simple hashtag #2.
No on stage pregnancy reveal will ever top Beyoncé announcing her pregnancy @ the 2011 VMAs to love on top! She served flawless vocals and looked stunning pic.twitter.com/e98LRfVx4m
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hancock, hypocrisy and the need for CCTV | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/hancock-hypocrisy-and-the-need-for-cctv</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/hancock-hypocrisy-and-the-need-for-cctv"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:24:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers react to video that exposed the former health secretary’s affair with an aide and the government’s response
In May, Boris Johnson told the Commons that the inquiry into how his government dealt with the coronavirus pandemic wouldn’t start before spring 2022. Johnson said: “We must not inadvertently divert or distract the people on whom we depend in the heat of our struggle against this disease” (Report, 12 May).
What a contrast with the announcement that the Department of Health and Social Care is to launch an investigation (Report, 27 June) into who leaked footage showing Matt Hancock in a clinch with his aide Gina Coladangelo. Announcing the investigation, the Northern Ireland secretary, Brandon Lewis, said that the department would try “to understand how this happened and to ensure this kind of situation can’t happen again”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three principles for public engagement | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/three-principles-for-public-engagement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/28/three-principles-for-public-engagement"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:24:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barry Jones responds to an article on the perils of groupthink and says that institutions must acknowledge creativity, tenacity and generosity
Martin Kettle promotes three Ts for public engagement – truth, transparency and trust – in his incisive article on how new ideas challenge institutional rigidities (What’s happened at the BBC and the Met police shows the perils of groupthink, 24 June).
A three-legged stool provides stability and the Christian trinity is core to faith. Let me add my favourite threesome gained from long experience as an engineering teacher and researcher in several British universities: creativity, tenacity and generosity (CTG).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New climate science could cause wave of litigation against businesses – study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/new-climate-science-could-cause-wave-of-litigation-against-businesses-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/new-climate-science-could-cause-wave-of-litigation-against-businesses-study"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:23:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts say scientific advances are making it easier to attribute the damages of climate breakdown to companies’ activities
Businesses could soon be facing a fresh wave of legal action holding them to account for their greenhouse gas emissions, owing to advances in climate science, experts have warned.
More than 1,500 legal actions have already been brought against fossil fuel companies whose emissions over decades have played a major role in building up carbon in the atmosphere.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palestinians protest for fifth day in West Bank after death of activist]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/palestinians-protest-for-fifth-day-in-west-bank-after-death-of-activist</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/palestinians-protest-for-fifth-day-in-west-bank-after-death-of-activist"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:18:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrations continue over treatment of Nizar Banat, a vocal critic of President Mahmoud Abbas
Demonstrations against the Palestinian Authority (PA) have continued across the West Bank after the death in custody of one of President Mahmoud Abbas’s biggest critics.
Several hundred people took to the streets of Ramallah, Hebron and Bethlehem for the fifth consecutive day on Monday to protest against the treatment of Nizar Banat, a social and political activist, who died during an arrest by the authority’s forces in Hebron on 24 June.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did you solve it? Carl Friedrich Gauss, money saving expert]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/28/did-you-solve-it-carl-friedrich-gauss-money-saving-expert</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/28/did-you-solve-it-carl-friedrich-gauss-money-saving-expert"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T16:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The answers to today’s puzzles
Earlier today I set you the following two puzzles, inspired by a money-saving trick devised by Carl Friedrich Gauss. (Click to the original for the explanation of the trick, and what it has got to do with Gauss).
1. The double bill.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Bellos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Where you live determines everything’: why segregation is growing in the US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/us-racial-segregation-study-university-of-california-berkeley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/28/us-racial-segregation-study-university-of-california-berkeley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:56:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the US has become more diverse, it has also become more racially segregated, a new study finds. Its lead author, Stephen Menendian, speaks about America’s failure to integrate
As the United States has become more diverse, it has also become more racially segregated, according to a new nationwide analysis from researchers at the University of California, Berkeley.
 Related: ‘It’s time to fix it’: can Chicago tackle its worsening racial life expectancy gap? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lois Beckett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tour de France: Roglic and Thomas tumble in ‘deplorable’ stage three chaos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/tour-de-france-crash-chaos-mars-stage-three-as-tim-merlier-wins-geraint-thomas-primoz-roglic-caleb-ewan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/tour-de-france-crash-chaos-mars-stage-three-as-tim-merlier-wins-geraint-thomas-primoz-roglic-caleb-ewan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:49:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Geraint Thomas dislocates shoulder on dramatic day
Tim Merlier wins, Caleb Ewan abandons after late crash

All hell broke loose in the Tour de France as overall favourites and sprint contenders both hit the tarmac in a chaotic climax to the third stage, won in Pontivy by Tim Merlier, a fast-rising Belgian sprinter.
The defending champion, Tadej Pogacar, the 2018 winner, Geraint Thomas, the 2020 runner-up, Primoz Roglic, the Australian star Jack Haig and the sprinters Caleb Ewan, Peter Sagan and Arnaud Démare were among the many high-profile casualties on a day when the peloton tackled narrow winding roads on the fast approach to the finish.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Whittle in Pontivy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New weight-loss tool prevents mouth from opening more than 2mm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/28/new-weight-loss-tool-dentalslim-diet-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/28/new-weight-loss-tool-dentalslim-diet-control"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:36:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DentalSlim Diet Control, which uses magnets, has been likened to ‘medieval torture device’
A weight-loss tool that uses magnets to stop people from opening their mouths wide enough to eat solid food has been developed by scientists in order to tackle obesity.
The device, developed by medical professionals from the University of Otago in New Zealand and scientists from Leeds in the UK, can be fitted by dentists and uses magnetic components with locking bolts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sonia Boyce review – kaleidoscopic collage that gets under your skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/sonia-boyce-review-middlesborough-institute-of-modern-art-mima</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/sonia-boyce-review-middlesborough-institute-of-modern-art-mima"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:32:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIMA, Middlesbrough
Eye-popping wallpaper trails across sculpture and space like Boyce’s touch in a layered exhibition whose warm embrace of other artists doesn’t always leave enough room for its headliner
Our skin holds us in, is protective but porous, commonplace yet entirely unique. The largest organ, it carries us through the world defining how we feel physically and how we are perceived socially. To exist day-to-day without thinking of it is a privilege afforded to those with the gender, skin colour, health and physique of the accepted hierarchies. Sonia Boyce’s exhibition at Middlesbrough Institute of Modern Art is acutely aware of this. Named after the autobiographical novel of colonial revolt by George Lamming, In the Castle of My Skin, the show explores skin through “castle” as an empowering safe place and “castle” as an inescapable prison.
Unsurprisingly, there is a lot of skin in this exhibition – not the peep show kind, but a vibrant film that covers all the plinths and climbs up the walls and on to sculpture. Making use of wallpapers she has been developing since the 1990s, Boyce plasters a kaleidoscopic collage of dancing figures, song lyrics, photographs and natural scenery across the white cube and over jagged sculptures that mimic the shape of fool’s gold and act as a display cabinet for the other, smaller artworks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Clugston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridget Christie: Ritual Britain made me proud to be British]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/bridget-christie-ritual-britain-crypt-gallery-ben-edge-museum-of-folklore</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/bridget-christie-ritual-britain-crypt-gallery-ben-edge-museum-of-folklore"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:31:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Morris dancers, druids, the Burryman – they’re all in Ben Edge’s spellbinding collaboration with the Museum of British Folklore, showcasing customs that stretch back into the mists of time
I’m Bridget Christie, a comedian, but I don’t just see comedy. Last weekend I went to a spellbinding exhibition of British folk art called Ritual Britain, set perfectly in London’s atmospheric Crypt Gallery in the bowels of St Pancras New Church in London.
Exploring and celebrating Britain’s calendar customs, it’s a collaboration between the artist Ben Edge and Simon Costin from the Museum of British Folklore. It features 20 striking and evocative oil on canvas paintings from Ben’s Frontline Folklore series, alongside objects from Simon’s collection. These included dolls of Morris dancers, a burnt hessian glove from the Ottery St Mary tar barrel burning festival, a selection of folklore archivist Doc Rowe’s photographs and a tall, attractive, well-dressed man made of straw – who has apparently been lined up as Andrew Neil’s next guest on GB news as soon as the exhibition ends on 4 July. Also included in the exhibition is Edge’s illuminating and thought-provoking film Frontline Folklore, documenting the same 20 customs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bridget Christie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A flaccid little attempt at spikiness’: Anne Robinson takes over Countdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/28/a-flaccid-little-attempt-at-spikiness-anne-robinson-takes-over-countdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/28/a-flaccid-little-attempt-at-spikiness-anne-robinson-takes-over-countdown"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:31:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It takes a specific type of person to sparkle in this presenting gig, and judging by her first episode, Robinson could prove to be Countdown’s weakest link
When Anne Robinson was announced as the newest Countdown host, it felt a little as if Channel 4 had hired Lewis Hamilton to sit at the wheel of a self-driving car. Robinson is, to paraphrase Liam Neeson, a woman with a particular set of skills; which is to say very sharp-witted and not altogether pleasant.
Countdown, meanwhile, is a peculiarly airless format that has a habit of sucking its presenters dry. The job of a Countdown host is to sit in front of a studio audience who sound so anaesthetised it’s easy to imagine them being cattle-prodded whenever it’s time to applaud, and mumble one-liners that never get more scintillating than “Numbers next”, or “Can you top that, Susie?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercedes insist they will not bow to Hamilton’s demands for car upgrades]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/formula-one-mercedes-red-bull-lewis-hamilton-toto-wolff-styrian-grand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/formula-one-mercedes-red-bull-lewis-hamilton-toto-wolff-styrian-grand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:23:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Briton was defeated by Max Verstappen at Styrian GP
Mercedes principal Toto Wolff says 2022 car is priority

Lewis Hamilton’s Mercedes team will not cede to their driver’s demands for swift action after the world champion was soundly defeated by Red Bull’s Max Verstappen at the Styrian Grand Prix. Hamilton warned that unless his team delivered upgrades to his car more defeats would inevitably follow, ending his hopes of securing an eighth world championship this season.
The Mercedes team principal Toto Wolff insisted, however, that the team will stick to their strategy of not putting resources into this year’s car but was optimistic the fight was far from over. Red Bull’s team principal Christian Horner said he felt that now was the time to “turn the screw” on Mercedes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A shift on aid hints British voters are finally tiring of the politics of spite | Zoe Williams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/aid-british-voters-politics-opinion-polls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/aid-british-voters-politics-opinion-polls"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:10:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Opinion polls show support for maintaining overseas aid is growing – and the government can no longer afford to ignore it
In all the political shocks of the past five years, large claims have been made about their architects: they’re playing multidimensional chess; they have seen straight through Westminster groupthink, into the very heart of the electorate; they have insights into digital campaigning that leave the other team in the dust.
In fact, the calculations that brought us Brexit, Boris Johnson’s victory, a pandemic marked by chaos and cronyism, and all the polling in between, have been repetitive and very simple. There is no limit to the passionate gullibility of a voter whose reptile brain has been activated. So long as your agenda plays to suspicion and hostility, focuses on the external threat of rapacious out-groups, emphasises the scarcity of all resources, which makes fighting for your own interests a necessity, you have your head of steam.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists develop wireless pacemaker that dissolves in body]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/28/wireless-pacemaker-dissolves-body</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/28/wireless-pacemaker-dissolves-body"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technology could be used for patients who need only temporary help to regulate their heartbeat
A wireless pacemaker that can dissolve in the body has been created for patients who need only temporary help to regulate their heartbeat.
Since the first pacemaker was implanted in 1958, millions of people have benefited from the devices. According to the national audit for cardiac rhythm management, 32,902 pacemakers were implanted for the first time in the UK in the year 2018-19 alone.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My dear old dog won’t be around for ever – so I will cherish every last walk | Emma Beddington]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/my-dear-old-dog-wont-be-around-for-ever-so-i-will-cherish-every-last-walk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/my-dear-old-dog-wont-be-around-for-ever-so-i-will-cherish-every-last-walk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have loved Oscar since he was a puppy. Twelve years on, the morning stroll is a challenge for both of us


Morning walks are not what they used to be. For years, my whippet, Oscar, and I would take a brisk hour’s trot at eight, taking care of business, physical (him) and mental (me). His bladder and bowels got a workout; the rhythm of our steps and the changing-unchanging view provided a gulp of oxygen and thinking time for my groggy brain.
Now, Oscar arrives outside my bedroom door at about 5.45am, making a polite but insistent noise like a slowly deflating balloon. When I get up, he shadows me, still making this noise, his eyes pools of anxiety, until I give up and grab his lead. Despite every appearance of tearing impatience to get out, the minute we leave the house he grinds to a halt by the front step and licks it insistently. If I don’t move him on, he will spend five minutes doing this, before peeing slowly on the spot, eyes fixed on me in a way that would be deeply creepy if I didn’t know him so well.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Beddington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Positioning Overlay Content with CSS Grid]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342971</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/positioning-overlay-content-with-css-grid/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T14:25:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not news to any web developer in 2021: CSS Grid is an incredibly powerful tool for creating complex, distinct two-dimensional modern web layouts.
Recently, I have been experimenting with CSS Grid and alignment properties to create component layouts that …
The post Positioning Overlay Content with CSS Grid appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Mulligan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turks and Caicos: 20 people found dead, including two children, on boat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/turks-and-caicos-20-people-found-dead-boat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/turks-and-caicos-20-people-found-dead-boat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T14:19:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Officials say investigators ruled out foul play but were still trying to determine what happened
Authorities in Turks and Caicos are investigating after a boat was found drifting about a mile off Grand Turk island with 20 dead people on board, including two children.
Officials said investigators had ruled out foul play but were still trying to determine what happened. The identities and origin of the dead were also under investigation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in Providenciales</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hancock has left the NHS in crisis. Don't assume Javid will save it | Andy Cowper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/matt-hancock-nhs-crisis-javid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/matt-hancock-nhs-crisis-javid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T14:18:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve had the PPE and care home scandals, and a waiting list of 5 million. But the new health secretary backed the cuts that crippled the NHS
Credit to Matt Hancock where it’s due. Overtaking Andrew Lansley to become the 21st century’s worst UK health secretary was no mean feat, but he managed it. Hancock’s record and ignominious exit from an ignominious tenure put him in pole position in the Academy of Useless Ministers.
Everyone has private lives, but Hancock’s affair with Gina Coladangelo became a public interest issue because he appointed her to the health department’s board, on a reported £15,000 salary for a few days’ work a year. This breaches pretty much all of the Nolan standards of public life, and drives a horse and cart through the ministerial code.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Cowper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five key takeaways from France’s regional elections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/five-key-takeaways-from-frances-regional-elections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/28/five-key-takeaways-from-frances-regional-elections"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T14:13:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: record low turnout makes it difficult to draw clear lessons but both Macron and Le Pen did badly
France’s regional elections produced a humiliating defeat for Marine Le Pen’s far-right Rassemblement National (RN), stinging failure for Emmanuel Macron and thumping wins for incumbents from the country’s traditional centre-right and centre-left parties.
A record low turnout of less than 35% makes it hard, however, to draw clear lessons for next year’s presidential elections, in which Macron and Le Pen remain clear frontrunners – although the race has certainly got a lot more interesting.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kid Creole and the Coconuts: how we made I’m a Wonderful Thing, Baby]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/kid-creole-and-the-coconuts-how-we-made-im-a-wonderful-thing-baby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/28/kid-creole-and-the-coconuts-how-we-made-im-a-wonderful-thing-baby"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:54:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I got away with it because of the clothes – zoot suits, baggy trousers and a fedora – and a knowingly raised eyebrow’
Had it not been for my brother, Stony, I would have remained a school teacher. He made fun of my job to such an extent that eventually I decided to join his group, Dr Buzzard’s Original Savannah Band, as the bass player.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Dave Simpson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Create a Design System in Figma]]></title>
        <id>60d4d3d86e1a1407b6b0bb25</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-how-to-create-a-design-system-in-figma/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:50:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A design system is a set of standards, reusable components, and patterns used to create visual consistency throughout different projects and pages. Figma is a vector graphics editor and prototyping tool. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org channel that will teach you how to build a design]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Learn Data Analytics]]></title>
        <id>60d4ea756e1a1407b6b0bb71</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/why-you-should-learn-data-analytics/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:44:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ok. I'm not suggesting that everyone needs to become a fully-credentialed data scientist. But these days, learning core data skills may provide as much value as basic financial literacy or knowledge of a simple coding language. This isn't just about your career: data has grown far beyond the world of]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Organizations Should Consider Building a Website Backed by a CRM Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343072</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/scaling-organizations-should-consider-building-a-website-backed-by-a-crm-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To make some terminology clear here:
CMS = Content Management System
CRM = Customer Relationship Management
Both are essentially database-backed systems for managing data. HubSpot is both, and much more. Where a CMS might be very focused on content and …
The post Scaling Organizations Should Consider Building a Website Backed by a CRM Platform appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parts of Australia under new Covid lockdown after cases of Delta variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/28/parts-of-australia-under-new-lockdown-after-cases-of-delta-variant-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/28/parts-of-australia-under-new-lockdown-after-cases-of-delta-variant-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coronavirus outbreaks renew questions about stuttering vaccine rollout and limited quarantine facilities

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Australia is grappling with several outbreaks of the highly contagious Delta variant of coronavirus, with a wave of restrictions rolling across the country and plunging some cities into lockdown for the first time since the pandemic began.
Residents of every state and territory in the country – except the island state of Tasmania – are again living under restrictions ranging from full-blown lockdowns in Sydney, Darwin and Perth, to mask mandates in some indoor settings in Adelaide and Canberra.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nino Bucci and Elias Visontay in Sydney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LGBTQ Pride parade weekend around the world – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/28/lgbtq-pride-parade-weekend-around-the-world-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/28/lgbtq-pride-parade-weekend-around-the-world-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T12:35:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and queer Pride month is celebrated in June to commemorate the 1969 Stonewall uprising in Manhattan. Although the coronavirus pandemic curtailed festivities, many revellers adapted to the new circumstances
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arnel Hecimovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dalian Atkinson killing: officer was kept on despite gross misconduct]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/28/dalian-atkinson-killing-officer-was-kept-on-despite-gross-misconduct</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/28/dalian-atkinson-killing-officer-was-kept-on-despite-gross-misconduct"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T12:11:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benjamin Monk previously found to have committed gross misconduct, but kept job and was given stun gun
The police officer convicted of the manslaughter of Dalian Atkinson had been previously found by a police disciplinary hearing to have committed gross misconduct but was allowed to remain an officer and given a stun gun, it has been revealed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tango festival and an illegal pet lion: Monday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/28/tango-festival-illegal-pet-lion-monday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/28/tango-festival-illegal-pet-lion-monday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T12:08:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experiences of Wimbledon 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/share-your-experiences-of-wimbledon-2021-tennis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/28/share-your-experiences-of-wimbledon-2021-tennis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T11:22:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your experiences of attending or working at Wimbledon tennis tournament this year
Wimbledon this year has started off with a damp morning on day one but with the roof on Centre Court, viewers in south-west London and at home will be able to watch some play.
We would like to hear from spectators and those working at the tennis tournament on their experiences this year. How has the All England Club adapted to the pandemic? What are you looking forward to the most?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olivia Rodrigo accused of plagiarism by Courtney Love and others]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/28/olivia-rodrigo-accused-of-plagiarism-by-courtney-love-and-others</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/28/olivia-rodrigo-accused-of-plagiarism-by-courtney-love-and-others"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T11:10:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artwork for Sour Prom, which has similarities to Hole album Live Through This, criticised as ‘rude’ and ‘bad form’ by Love
Olivia Rodrigo has been accused by Courtney Love and others of plagiarism in her artwork and a music video.
Love highlighted similarities between the album cover to Live Through This by her band Hole, photographed by Ellen von Unwerth, and the image used to promote Sour Prom, an Olivia Rodrigo concert film airing on 29 June. Each image features a prom queen in a tiara holding flowers, wearing smeared mascara. Love posted the Sour Prom artwork to Instagram with the caption “Spot the Difference! #twinning”, and later wrote on Facebook: “Stealing an original idea and not asking permission is rude. There’s no way to be elegant about it. I’m not angry. It happens all the time to me. But this was bad form.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How d’you like them apples? Great recipes for the summer using cider]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/28/how-dyou-like-them-apples-great-recipes-for-the-summer-using-cider</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/28/how-dyou-like-them-apples-great-recipes-for-the-summer-using-cider"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T10:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cider can give a kick to french onion soup, sweeten up a cake – and even take baked apples to a new level. Here are some ideas to add some sparkle to your summer
Before we begin, a quick clarification for our non-British readers. Your cider is not our cider. Your cider is merely jumped-up apple juice; ours is furiously alcoholic: lovely, delicious booze that’s just as good served over ice in the summer as it is heated and spiced in the winter. But let’s say you want to cook with cider – what are your options there? I’m glad you asked.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Custom Emmet Snippets In VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/custom-emmet-snippets-vscode/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/custom-emmet-snippets-vscode/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Manuel explains why Emmet is one of his favorite productivity tools for writing HTML and CSS, and how you can create custom Emmet snippets in Visual Studio Code to help you improve your front-end workflows even more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Manuel Matuzović)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Roddy’s recipe for chocolate chip and yoghurt ring cake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/28/rachel-roddy-recipe-chocolate-chip-yoghurt-ring-cake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/28/rachel-roddy-recipe-chocolate-chip-yoghurt-ring-cake"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T10:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nigella’s cake, gâteau au yaourt, Italian or Ukrainian yoghurt cake, seven-pot cake … so many names, and all of them delicious
I am at the supermarket, standing in front of the milk, cream and yoghurt fridge. To my left, an elderly man lifts his glasses so he can read the small print on the side of a tub of Greek yoghurt. He asks me if it is magro (low-fat), and I tell him it is. To my right, a woman a bit older than me is checking the dates on the milk, reaching deeper and deeper between the bottles, which are swaying like skittles, until she comes to one she is happy with. Only she doesn’t leave; instead, she gestures to the space she has created, an invitation for me to take a bottle with a long date, too. I don’t need milk, but I am always keen to join in, so take a litre anyway, as well as a twin pack of yoghurt. “Magro?” asks the man, still holding his pot. No, I tell him; the one I am holding is intero (whole).
As if there isn’t enough going on in front of the fridge, a man in a spotty face mask and wearing technical leggings crashes his trolley into the metal base of the fridge. It isn’t intentional, just careless. It makes all of us jump, especially the yoghurt man, who drops his pot, which hits the floor hard, splitting the foil and sending a fat blob of yoghurt streaking across the floor like one of those capsules from a paint gun.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Roddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘She broke a toe and snapped a tendon. I had to carry her around’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/28/how-we-met-she-broke-a-toe-and-snapped-a-tendon-i-had-to-carry-her-around</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/28/how-we-met-she-broke-a-toe-and-snapped-a-tendon-i-had-to-carry-her-around"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T10:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bobbie, 31, and Abelina, 29, found love in Guangzhou, China, in 2018 after meeting through a dating app. Bobbie came out as trans last year
At the start of 2018 Bobbie was recovering from a break-up. Seeking a fresh start, she left her job in Essex and travelled to China. “I’d always wanted to go there,” she says. “I wasn’t in a good place when I arrived. I was living on vodka and M&Ms and didn’t have a clear plan.” She found somewhere to stay in Zhongshan, 50 miles from Guangzhou.
In February, she connected with Abelina on a dating app. “I’m from Germany but I was working in Guangzhou for a government organisation. She sent me a message first but I was the one to ask her out,” says Abelina. “I was attracted to her eyes and the beard she had at the time.” Although Bobbie has always known she was a woman, she was presenting as a cisgender man. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine inequality: how rich countries cut Covid deaths as poorer fall behind]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/jun/28/vaccine-inequality-how-rich-countries-cut-covid-deaths-as-poorer-fall-behind</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/jun/28/vaccine-inequality-how-rich-countries-cut-covid-deaths-as-poorer-fall-behind"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T09:08:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developed countries are seeing the benefits of quickly vaccinating their populations, but concerns remain about the unequal share of global vaccine supplies

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

New analysis by the Guardian has confirmed that a speedy Covid vaccination campaign pays off when it comes to escaping the worst of the pandemic. 
As the chart below shows, countries such as Israel, the UK and the US have all seen deaths decline as vaccination coverage extended to the most vulnerable in their societies. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Gutiérrez and Ashley Kirk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why do writers need agents? To keep track of the rejections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/28/why-do-writers-need-agents-to-keep-track-of-the-rejections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/28/why-do-writers-need-agents-to-keep-track-of-the-rejections"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T09:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That 10% fee buys a novelist like me more than the chance of a big book deal – from a hand with the DIY to a shoulder to cry on after yet another knockback
A few weeks after the sudden death of my agent, Deborah Rogers, in 2014 the colleague deputed to take me on phoned. “I’ve found something in Deborah’s desk.”
“Yes?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Paling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Draught wines: French vineyards rediscover the power of horses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/draught-wines-french-vineyards-rediscover-the-power-of-horses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/draught-wines-french-vineyards-rediscover-the-power-of-horses"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T06:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working horses not only outperform tractors on tricky terrain but provide a natural way to improve health of soil and crops
It’s early morning and the air vibrates with the sound of birds and frogs at the L’Affût wine estate in Sologne, north-central France. Draught horses Urbanie and Bambi are slowly working their way between rows of vines. Carefully guided by their owner, Jean-Pierre Dupont, and his son, they each pull a cultivator that drags up grass growing between the grapevines.
Several times a year, Urbanie and Bambi can be seen working at L’Affût, often to the surprise of passersby: working horses can be deemed obsolete, relics of a time before the mid-20th century’s mechanisation of farming.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ginger Clark</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My English will never be ‘perfect’ – and that’s what keeps a language alive | Nesrine Malik]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/english-perfect-language-arabic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/28/english-perfect-language-arabic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T06:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a child, I mixed English with Arabic. Now I know there’s no such thing as a fixed language that belongs to one special group
My first day in an English-speaking school was miserable. It was full of little humiliations: the kind that with the hindsight of adulthood seem trivial but in childhood plant the seed of a feeling of inadequacy that one can never expel.
My family had just moved to Kenya, where English was the official language. I was seven and could not speak a word of it, having grown up until that point in an Arabic-speaking country, and been educated at an Arabic school.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nesrine Malik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damaging ‘fly-shooting’ fishing in Channel sparks concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/damaging-fly-shooting-fishing-in-channel-sparks-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/28/damaging-fly-shooting-fishing-in-channel-sparks-concerns"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T06:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Small-scale fishers say mostly EU fleet is devastating catches with method that nets entire shoals of fish
The UK has been accused of allowing a fleet of mainly EU “fly-shooting” fishing boats “unfettered access” to the Channel, without a proper assessment of the impact on fish populations, the seabed or the livelihoods of small-scale fishers.
Organisations representing small-scale fishers on both sides of the Channel have warned that the fleet is having a “devastating” effect on their catches. They are calling for a review of the vessels’ UK licences until an impact assessment has been carried out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karen McVeigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Women Photographers on the theme of ‘home’ – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/black-women-photographers-on-the-theme-of-home-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/28/black-women-photographers-on-the-theme-of-home-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From a database to a website, Black Women Photographers is a community of visual creators that provides a resource for the industry’s commissioning editors to facilitate more diversity in editorial photography. We showcase a selection of work by members of the community on the theme of ‘home’
Black Women Photographers was launched in July 2020 by Polly Irungu, coming out of a Covid-19 relief fund – (#BWPReliefFund) – which raised more than £10,000 to provide financial support to Black women and non-binary photographers during the pandemic.
Established to develop, encourage and promote inclusive hiring practices in the industry, the database – and website – highlights all Black women who elect to be submitted. Working through social conversations and workshops, the platform is empowering Black women to make the industry more diverse.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is chronic pain and how does it work? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/28/what-is-chronic-pain-and-how-does-it-work-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/28/what-is-chronic-pain-and-how-does-it-work-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T05:08:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years people with conditions such as fibromyalgia or bad back pain – to name just two – have been told the pain is all in their head. With no obvious physical symptoms, nociplastic pain can be difficult to diagnose but its effects are very, very real. Research suggests that the immune system plays a role in nociplastic pain, giving people 'feel bad' symptoms including fatigue, anxiety and nausea

Sufferers of chronic pain have long been told it’s all in their head. We now know that’s wrong
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Fanner, Laura Murphy-Oates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remote working v the office: four company bosses have their say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/remote-working-v-the-office-four-company-bosses-have-their-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/28/remote-working-v-the-office-four-company-bosses-have-their-say"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T05:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working longer hours or getting more done? Managers debate the upside and downside of how we work
The global pandemic and lockdown restrictions forced many UK businesses to move employees to remote working, practically overnight.
Four company bosses speak about the upsides and downsides of working from home versus the traditional office-based model as they consider what the future might look like for their businesses and staff.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jedidajah Otte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Health systems should be prepared’: doctors brace for tsunami of long Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/28/health-systems-should-be-prepared-doctors-brace-for-tsunami-of-long-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/28/health-systems-should-be-prepared-doctors-brace-for-tsunami-of-long-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the debilitating post-viral condition affects millions around the world, medical experts are scrambling to nail down what causes it – and how to treat it

Sufferers of chronic pain have long been told it’s all in their head. We now know that’s wrong

When his throat first started hurting, John Brown didn’t think much of it.
It was March 2020 and the 48-year-old was onboard the Voyager of the Seas, a cruise travelling through the Pacific Islands.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The anxiety is palpable’: EU citizens face looming settled status deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/the-anxiety-is-palpable-eu-citizens-face-looming-settled-status-deadline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/28/the-anxiety-is-palpable-eu-citizens-face-looming-settled-status-deadline"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those submitting last-minute applications for right to stay in UK describe  stress of dealing with an overwhelmed system
With just three days to go before the deadline for EU citizens who wish to remain living in the UK to apply for EU settled status (EUSS), applicants have described the stress they are experiencing as they submit last-minute applications or wait to hear from the Home Office about whether their applications have been accepted.
They describe the frustration of trying to get through to a Home Office helpline that is often unable to accept calls because of excessive numbers of people seeking advice; many are worried that they may find themselves in a legal limbo, despite government reassurances to the contrary.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll and Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young, hot and bothered: going through menopause in my 30s | podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/28/young-hot-and-bothered-going-through-menopause-in-my-30s</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/28/young-hot-and-bothered-going-through-menopause-in-my-30s"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T02:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harriet Gibsone tells the scary, sad, and surprisingly funny story of going through early menopause – and hoping for a baby

In 2017, Harriet Gibsone was a music journalist for the Guardian – working hard, going out lots, and just married. She was ready for her 30s, but not quite ready for a family.
Then, at 31, she started to experience symptoms she couldn’t make sense of: forgetfulness, mysterious mood swings and bouts of weeping, and being woken in the night by sudden hot flushes. The sudden bursts of aggression made her feel like Piers Morgan. Her world was crumbling – but nobody could tell her exactly what was wrong.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Harriet Gibsone; produced by Hannah Moore and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sailplanes, Pride marches and a liberated lion: the weekend’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/27/sailplanes-pride-marches-and-a-liberated-lion-the-weekends-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/27/sailplanes-pride-marches-and-a-liberated-lion-the-weekends-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-27T13:48:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: Mennonite women in Belize]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/27/the-big-picture-mennonite-women-in-belize-c1950-jake-michaels</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/27/the-big-picture-mennonite-women-in-belize-c1950-jake-michaels"/>
        <updated>2021-06-27T06:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Jake Michaels captures the tension between tradition and technology in the Christian community
In 2018, the Los Angeles-based photographer Jake Michaels escaped from Instagram and 24-hour news for a while, to go in search of a community with a different sense of time. A colleague had suggested that he visit the Mennonite settlements in Belize, which were established in the middle of the last century and have hardly changed since. Michaels arrived among homesteads set in lush green hills in the twilight and the village pastor gave him permission to photograph the community’s families. He was struck by the silence, only interrupted by the sound of horses’ hooves and the wooden wheels of the buggies they pulled. He stayed for a long week.
The result of that trip is a book titled c1950 that captures the ways in which the Mennonites, an Anabaptist Christian sect, believe that they should be “in the world but not of it”. Their lives are based on principles of agrarian cooperation and mutual aid: older children take care of younger ones; neighbours are always on hand to fix farm equipment or help out with a harvest. The Belize government allows the group to live mostly independently on their own land; young men are not called up for national service and children are educated in line with the community faith.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stories to save the world: the new wave of climate fiction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/stories-to-save-the-world-the-new-wave-of-climate-fiction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/stories-to-save-the-world-the-new-wave-of-climate-fiction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T08:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now more than ever, novelists are facing up to the unthinkable: the climate crisis. Claire Armitstead talks to Margaret Atwood, Amitav Ghosh and more about the new cli-fi
In September 2017, David Simon, creator of The Wire, tweeted a photograph of golfers calmly lining up their putts on an Oregon course as wildfires raged in the background. “In the pantheon of visual metaphors for America today, this is the money shot,” he wrote of the picture, which was taken by an amateur photographer who spotted the photo-op as she was about to skydive out of a plane. Everything about this story – the image, the circumstances – seems stranger than fiction.
A year before Simon’s tweet, in a landmark polemic, The Great Derangement: Climate Change and the Unthinkable, Indian novelist Amitav Ghosh had questioned why so few writers – himself included – were tackling the world’s most pressing issue in their fiction. But now, as extreme weather swirls around the globe, melting glaciers, burning forests, flooding districts and annihilating species, the climate emergency has brought the unimaginable into our daily lives and literature. A survivor in Jessie Greengrass’s haunting new novel The High House sums it up: “The whole complicated system of modernity which had held us up, away from the earth, was crumbling … and we were becoming again what we had used to be: cold, and frightened of the weather, and frightened of the dark. Somehow while we had all been busy, while we had been doing those small things which added up to living, the future had slipped into the present.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Armitstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/twenty-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/twenty-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:55:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protests in the West Bank, summer solstice at Stonehenge, Juneteenth in Galveston and the election in Ethiopia: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Property Brain Twisters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342718</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-property-brain-twisters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:39:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am part of that 82% that got the answer to Lea Verou's quiz wrong. Stephen Shaw posted a similar quiz as well and it's a fun exercise sharpen your CSS chops.
The post Custom Property Brain Twisters appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anywhere but Westminster: 10 years in 10 minutes – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a decade of reports from all over the UK, the Guardian's flagship video series has won this year's Orwell prize for political journalism. Here, John Harris and John Domokos collect the highlights of their journey and ask viewers a simple question: where should they go next?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris and Noah Payne-Frank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cancel Pending API Requests to Show Correct Data]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342911</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-cancel-pending-api-requests-to-show-correct-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently had to create a widget in React that fetches data from multiple API endpoints. As the user clicks around, new data is fetched and marshalled into the UI. But it caused some problems.
One problem quickly became evident: …
The post How to Cancel Pending API Requests to Show Correct Data appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Georgi Nikoloff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating A Multi-Author Blog With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains how we can connect different types of content in a Next.js application. With this technique, we can add any kind of one-to-one, one-to-many, or even many-to-many relationship to our projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Dom Habersack)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your area’s exciting green projects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/tell-us-about-your-areas-exciting-green-projects</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/tell-us-about-your-areas-exciting-green-projects"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear about interesting green initiatives of all shapes and sizes around the country
Does your city, town or village have exciting environmental plans that are aimed at creating jobs and improving lives? Perhaps you already have flourishing green initiatives? Should we be jumping on a train/bicycle to come and see them? 
There has been lots of talk about a green recovery – but what does it actually look like? What are communities already doing to boost their own local green economy, and to create sustainable jobs? We would like to find out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Run A UX Audit For A Major EdTech Platform (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article is a case study of how a UX audit affects a UI. It explains how a famous educational platform can be analyzed edX against Jakob Nielsen’s usability guidelines. To get started, Mark Lankmiller shares all of the criteria and metrics he used for his UX audit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mark Lankmilier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yellowstone: report reveals extent of climate threat to oldest US national park]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T08:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say temperatures, already the highest in the past 20,000 years, could increase by up to 10F by 2100
Yellowstone, established in 1872, is famous around the globe for good reason: it’s the oldest national park in the United States and one of the most popular.
But a new report issued this week shows how Yellowstone’s near pristine environment, with attractions like the Old Faithful geyser and herds of bison, is under threat from global heating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Gammon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how are you affected by the recent changes to the UK travel list?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/tell-us-how-are-you-affected-by-the-recent-changes-to-the-uk-travel-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/tell-us-how-are-you-affected-by-the-recent-changes-to-the-uk-travel-list"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T08:02:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those living in Malta, Madeira and the Balearic islands, as well as travellers about the changes
The government has announced that Malta, Madeira and the Balearic islands have been added to the UK green travel list meaning that travellers do not need to quarantine when returning from these countries.
At the moment, people who travel to amber list countries have to quarantine on return, however on Tuesday the health secretary said ministers are planning to allow quarantine-free travel to amber-list countries for people in England who have been fully vaccinated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How trans kids' rights are under attack in the US – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T07:39:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the first day of Pride month, the governor of Florida signed a law banning transgender girls from joining girls’ sports teams in schools and colleges. It was just one of 13 anti-trans bills conservative lawmakers in the US passed this year – and one of more than 110 proposed bills, many of which also target access to gender-affirming healthcare. This is by far the largest number filed in a single year in US history.
Guardian LA correspondent, Sam Levin, and Prof Jules Gill-Peterson, a historian and expert on trans kids, examine how this legislative attack has escalated and how the presence of trans kids in America is not a new phenomenon

Mapping the anti-trans laws sweeping America: ‘A war on 100 fronts’

In the US, the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255. In the UK and Ireland, Samaritans can be contacted on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org or jo@samaritans.ie. In Australia, the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new Brexit crisis for Northern Ireland’s unionists - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/25/the-new-brexit-crisis-for-northern-irelands-unionists-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/25/the-new-brexit-crisis-for-northern-irelands-unionists-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T02:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From a leadership fiasco to the ‘sausage wars’, the Democratic Unionist party’s stance on Brexit has forced it to contend with a new – perhaps even existential – set of problems. What will they mean for the region’s future?
When the Democratic Unionist party decided to support Brexit, many warned that the decision could have profound consequences for Northern Ireland’s position within the UK. Five years on, new customs arrangements and an Irish Sea border mean trade flows with the Republic of Ireland are growing – even as imports from Great Britain are slowing. And some on the unionist side fear that bit by bit, the argument for a united Ireland is gaining ground.
Now the region has found itself in the grip of a so-called ‘sausage war’ over chilled processed meats. At the same time, the DUP is about to install its third leader in a month, a crisis at the top that has exacerbated fears that the party could face electoral annihilation. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s Ireland correspondent, Rory Carroll, and the Brexit correspondent, Lisa O’Carroll, about a seismic moment for Northern Ireland – and what a political crisis for Stormont’s leading unionist party could mean for the region’s future.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rory Carroll and Lisa O'Carroll; produced by Courtney Yusufand Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears and her battle for freedom: what we know so far – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears has spoken out publicly for the first time against the controversial legal arrangement that has stripped her of independence for 13 years – and handed control of her estate, career and aspects of her personal life to her father, Jamie Spears, who also at times had authority over her medical and mental health treatment. 

The 39-year-old delivered an emotional speech to a Los Angeles court on Wednesday 23 June, saying she has been forced to work against her will, and that the conservatorship has blocked her from getting married and from having her IUD birth control removed so she could try to have another child. She added: 'I just want my life back.'
Her allegations were detailed and disturbing, and will fuel the growing #FreeBritney movement, as Guardian US correspondent Sam Levin explains.

‘Denied a baby’: key claims from Britney Spears testimony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Common React Mistakes You Might Be Making – And How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>60d3ee396e1a1407b6b0b6ef</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/common-react-mistakes-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go over the most common mistakes you might be making in your React code right now, plus how to fix them. If you want to create amazing React applications, it's essential to avoid many common errors along the way. In this article, we'll not only cover how to fix]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenTelemetry to Understand Software Performance]]></title>
        <id>60d4b5e96e1a1407b6b0bac4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opentelemetry/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want good performance in your application, you need to collect data to figure out where to make improvements. That's where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemetry offers a single set of APIs and libraries that standardize how you collect and transfer telemetry data. OpenTelemetry provides a specification for instrumentation so]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 9: Community]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342818</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/chapter-9-community/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April of 2009, Yahoo! shut down GeoCities. Practically overnight, the once beloved service had its signup page replaced with a vague message announcing its closure.
We have decided to discontinue the process of allowing new customers to sign up 
…
The post Chapter 9: Community appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Hoffmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rise Of Design Thinking As A Problem Solving Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the dynamic and unpredictable environments in which we work, even the most carefully crafted solutions can have a short shelf life. When we accept that our work is impermanent and our problem-solving abilities are limited, our goal can shift from delivering full solutions to developing tools that empower our users to adaptively design for themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Josh Singer)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How meme stars of the early internet are striking it rich with NFTs - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of non-fungible tokens has given rise to massive windfalls for those behind early virals. Sirin Kale and Alex Hern explain all
On 28 May 2016 the photographer Jeff McCurry was taking pictures of a 17-year-old western lowland gorilla called Harambe in Cincinnati zoo when a child entered the enclosure. The zookeepers reacted by shooting the gorilla dead. The child was unhurt. What was a local story suddenly became a global phenomenon due to the combination of social media and McCurry’s picture. Harambe’s image was everywhere. But, despite his photo being shared billions of times, McCurry did not see much of a financial benefit. Now advances in technology have given the world non-fungible tokens (NFTs) – and McCurry has a way of finally cashing in on his famous image.
The Guardian’s technology editor, Alex Hern, tells Rachel Humphreys that this year’s craze for NFTs follows in the wake of speculation on cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin. Now similar technology means unique images, film clips, animations and even poems are being bought and sold online for increasingly large sums.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Alex Hern; produced by Alex Atack, Ned Carter Miles and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Data Analysis? How to Visualize Data with Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib &amp; Seaborn Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>605abca5687d62084bf6b7cd</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/exploratory-data-analysis-with-numpy-pandas-matplotlib-seaborn/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T00:11:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Analysis is the process of exploring, investigating, and gathering insights from data using statistical measures and visualizations.  The objective of data analysis is to develop an understanding of data by uncovering trends, relationships, and patterns. Data analysis is both a science and an art. On the one hand it]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microservices Architecture – Explained in Plain English]]></title>
        <id>6072ffd4d5756f080ba98b27</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/microservices-architecture-for-humans/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few years, microservices have gone from an overhyped buzzword to something you should understand as a software engineer.  According to an O'Reilly developer survey in 2020:  61% of companies have been using microservices in the last year29% say at least half of their company systems are built]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343076</id>
        <link href="https://www.bram.us/2021/06/21/tablesng-improvements-to-table-rendering-in-chromium/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:37:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I blogged “Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier” recently, I mentioned that the “stickiness” improvement was just one of the features that got better for <table>s in Chrome as part of the TablesNG upgrade…
The post TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342750</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-performant-next-gen-images-in-css-with-image-set/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T19:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS image-set() function has been supported in Chromium-based browsers since 2012 and in Safari since version 6. Support recently landed in Firefox 88. Let’s dive in and see what we can and can’t do today with image-set().…
The post Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Weak declaration”]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342669</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/weak-declaration/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK looks at aspect-ratio, a CSS property for layout that, for the most part, does exactly what you would think it does. It’s getting more interesting as it’s behind a flag in Firefox and Safari now, so we’ll have …
The post “Weak declaration” appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experience of having periods during menopause]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re interested to hear how women going through menopause experience their menstrual cycles and periods
An estimated 13 million women in the UK are living with menopause, with 4.5 million of them making up the fastest-growing demographic in the workplace.
We’d like to hear how women experience their periods leading up to and during this time of hormonal change, and how this might be affecting their lives. How are you coping with period changes at work? How are your home and social lives affected?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Online Workshops (July-October 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frontend and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run [online workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automating Screen Reader Testing On macOS Using Auto VO]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated testing is an important part of any software project, including testing for accessibility. There are already tools for linting and integration testing accessibility, but what about end-to-end testing with real assistive technology? Since I hadn’t seen this before, I set out to build Auto VO, a driver for the VoiceOver screen reader.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cameron Cundiff)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[inherit, initial, unset, revert]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342930</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inherit-initial-unset-revert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:20:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are four keywords that are valid values for any CSS property (see the title). Of those, day to day, I’d say I see the inherit used the most. Perhaps because it’s been around the longest (I think?) but also …
The post inherit, initial, unset, revert appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Custom Elements in Svelte]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342634</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-custom-elements-in-svelte/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:37:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte fully supports custom elements (e.g. <my-component>) without any custom configuration or wrapper components and has a perfect score on Custom Elements Everywhere. However, there are still a few quirks you need to watch out for, especially around …
The post Using Custom Elements in Svelte appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Rich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342925</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/if-were-gonna-criticize-utility-class-frameworks-lets-be-fair-about-it/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not here to raise a shield protecting CSS utility frameworks. I don’t even particularly like the approach, myself, and nothing is above fair criticism. But fair is a key word there. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve …
The post If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing With Code: A Modern Approach To Design (Development Challenges)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of innovation in both tools and processes, the struggle between design and development is still real. This article focuses on the best practices for improving the design to development processes and how cutting-edge solutions, such as UXPin powered by Merge technology, can help in facilitating the change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342887</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/new-responsive/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una is calling it the new responsive. A nod to the era we were most certainly in, the era of responsive design. Where responsive design was fluid grids, flexible media, and media queries, the new responsive is those things …
The post Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342448</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-css-charts-with-interesting-shapes-glyphs-and-emoji/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:32:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s forego the usual circles and bars we typically see used in charts for more eccentric shapes. With online presentations more and more common today, a quick way to spruce up your web slides and make them stand out is …
The post How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image To Text Conversion With React And Tesseract.js (OCR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have to process data manually because it is served through images or scanned documents? An image-to-text conversion makes it possible to extract text from images to automate the processing of texts on images, videos, and scanned documents. In this article, we look at how to convert an image to text with React and Tesseract.js(OCR), preprocess images, and deal with the limitations of Tesseract (OCR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ayobami Ogundiran)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>