<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-09T00:29:57.275Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-09T00:29:57.275Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.5.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elections 2021: Sadiq Khan wins second term as London mayor – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2021/may/08/elections-2021-scotland-england-wales-london-mayoral-devolved-local-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2021/may/08/elections-2021-scotland-england-wales-london-mayoral-devolved-local-live"/>
        <updated>2021-05-09T00:10:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All the latest news and results as counts continue in England and Scotland after Thursday’s elections 

London reelects Sadiq Khan for mayor
Labour’s Marvin Rees re-elected as mayor of Bristol
SNP is Holyrood’s largest party with 64 seats

Angela Rayner sacked as Labour chair

Labour gains mayoralties in Cambridgeshire &amp; Peterborough and West of England

Conservatives hold West Midlands
First minister Mark Drakeford promises radical plans for Wales

2021 elections: results for the English local, Scottis…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Sullivan (now); Clea Skopeliti ,Andrew Sparrow and Molly Blackall (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tui’s feeling beach-ready, thanks partly to a big bailout from Berlin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/09/tuis-feeling-beach-ready-thanks-partly-to-a-big-bailout-from-berlin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/09/tuis-feeling-beach-ready-thanks-partly-to-a-big-bailout-from-berlin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T23:05:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s biggest holiday firm is setting sail for a brighter summer as Brits grab their chance to seek some (Algarve) sun
Tristan da Cunha, here we come. Travel firm Tui will have given one tiny cheer at the end of last week, when the UK government finally confirmed the resumption of international leisure travel with a threadbare “green list” of far-flung countries, where desperate holidaymakers can safely venture without a 10-day quarantine on return.
For those who want to stay in the northern hemispher…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe and Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sadiq Khan reelected as London mayor after rival runs him close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/sadiq-khan-london-mayor-second-term-labour-shaun-bailey-conservatives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/sadiq-khan-london-mayor-second-term-labour-shaun-bailey-conservatives"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T22:57:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Victory was less emphatic than predicted after late increase in support for Tory Shaun Bailey
Sadiq Khan has been elected as mayor of London for a second term, following a victory that was less emphatic than predicted after a late increase in support for his Conservative opponent.
As recently as March, polls had given Khan a 25-point lead over his Tory rival, Shaun Bailey, handing him 53% of the vote. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We love: fashion fixes for the week ahead – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/08/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/08/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T22:50:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From House of Goya’s vibrant tracksuits to The Ten: the book that tells the story of 10 of the key wardrobe classics – and this summer’s hottest shoe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharpen up: 10 of the best oversized blazers – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/08/sharpen-up-10-of-the-best-oversized-blazers-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/08/sharpen-up-10-of-the-best-oversized-blazers-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T22:45:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shrugged over a summer dress for the evening or paired with a T-shirt and jeans, a blazer offers endless styling possibilities to elevate every outfit
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland’s unionist movement in turmoil as UUP leader steps down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/ulster-unionist-party-leader-announces-resignation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/ulster-unionist-party-leader-announces-resignation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T22:02:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Aiken’s move throws unionism in Northern Ireland into further flux after Arlene Foster was forced to quit
Political unionism in Northern Ireland has been thrown into further flux after the leader of the Ulster Unionist party announced his resignation.
Steve Aiken’s move comes 10 days after the Democratic Unionist party leader Arlene Foster was forced to quit after an internal heave against her.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arsenal’s squad needs changing, admits struggling Mikel Arteta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/arsenals-squad-needs-changing-admits-struggling-mikel-arteta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/arsenals-squad-needs-changing-admits-struggling-mikel-arteta"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager believes he will get time and funds 

Arsenal face West Brom with Europe hopes almost gone

Mikel Arteta expects to be backed heavily by the Kroenke family in his efforts to reverse Arsenal’s slide and accepts significant changes to a floundering squad will be required over the summer.
Arsenal host West Brom on Sunday in what is virtually a dead rubber, with the sides having purely mathematical chances of qualifying for Europe and escaping relegation respectively. Thursday’s Europa League semi-final…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mané and Thiago sink Southampton to keep Liverpool’s top-four hopes alive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/liverpool-southampton-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/liverpool-southampton-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T21:11:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jürgen Klopp has described Champions League qualification as unlikely for Liverpool. He has unwittingly spoken of it in the past tense on occasion too. It remains, however, a possibility in the present after Sadio Mané’s first-half header and Thiago Alcântara’s first goal for the club downed Southampton while heightening the anxiety that stalks Leicester once again.
The Premier League champions, for a little while longer at least, can sniff blood in the form of Brendan Rodgers’ faltering side, who they now …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter at Anfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age before beauty is backbone of Warren Gatland’s beefed up Lions | Michael Aylwin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/age-before-beauty-is-backbone-of-warren-gatlands-beefed-up-lions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/age-before-beauty-is-backbone-of-warren-gatlands-beefed-up-lions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pragmatic intent in taking on South Africa is clear in the coach’s selection of an experienced batch of players
Warren Gatland has insisted the squad he picked for the British &amp; Irish Lions tour to South Africa would have looked different had the destination been New Zealand, and different again were it to be heading for Australia. It is always difficult to discern whether such claims are genuine or just easy soundbites to make a coach’s job sound more nuanced, but a quick glance at the age profile of t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Aylwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emma Hayes leans into lessons from geese to find Chelsea a V for victory | Louise Taylor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/emma-hayes-chelsea-womens-super-league-reading-final-day</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/emma-hayes-chelsea-womens-super-league-reading-final-day"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chelsea manager wants her side to ‘honk hard’ and seal the WSL title with victory over Reading on Sunday
Emma Hayes has been showing her Chelsea team films of geese flying in V formation and, by way of proving the point, does a decent impression of the birds honking encouragement to each other. Quite apart from enlivening a Zoom-enabled media address, the manager can think of no better way to limber up for Sunday’s Women’s Super League title denouement than reminding her formidable squad about the impor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louise Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United lose £200m training kit deal over fans’ anti-Glazers campaign]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/manchester-united-lose-200m-training-kit-deal-over-fans-anti-glazers-campaign</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/manchester-united-lose-200m-training-kit-deal-over-fans-anti-glazers-campaign"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:48:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Hut Group pulls out of contract starting in July, sources say 
Fans are campaigning for boycott of club’s commercial partners

Manchester United have missed out on a proposed new training kit deal worth £200m over 10 years after the Manchester-based company The Hut Group had concerns about the supporters’ campaign to boycott the club’s commercial partners in protest at the Glazers’ ownership, the Observer understands.
Richard Arnold, United’s group managing director, was told on Friday that THG had pull…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Exclusive by Jamie Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sergio Agüero’s rush of blood gives Thomas Tuchel a day to savour | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/sergio-agueros-rush-of-blood-gives-thomas-tuchel-a-day-to-savour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/08/sergio-agueros-rush-of-blood-gives-thomas-tuchel-a-day-to-savour"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City will still win the title but this was a win of genuine significance for Chelsea’s German coach
Oh, Sergio. A reminder from Mr Guardiola to all boys – particularly those who are leaving the Etihad Campus at the end of the year. Term is not over. The final exam is not yet passed. And this really isn’t the moment to start having fun.
This was an odd, increasingly gripping game. A 2-1 Chelsea win only delayed the inevitable title celebrations for Manchester City. But it carried a genuine signifi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scarlett Johansson joins criticism of Golden Globes body amid accusations of racism and sexism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/scarlett-johansson-hollywood-foreign-press-association-golden-globes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/scarlett-johansson-hollywood-foreign-press-association-golden-globes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:05:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor said the film industry should step back from the Hollywood Foreign Press Association
The actor Scarlett Johansson urged the film industry on Saturday to “step back” from the Hollywood Foreign Press Association as criticism of the opaque film industry group, which controls the influential Golden Globe awards, continues to mount for sexism and racism.
In a carefully-worded statement, the Avengers star said the “HFPA is an organization that was legitimized by the likes of Harvey Weinstein to amass mo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we stay together: ‘You’ve got to either take space or give space’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/09/how-we-stay-together-youve-got-to-either-take-space-or-give-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/09/how-we-stay-together-youve-got-to-either-take-space-or-give-space"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Metaphorically and literally, Clive and Mary have spent their almost four decades together learning to speak each other’s language
Names: Clive Smallman and Mary Haropoulou
Years together: 38
Occupations: academics
Clive Smallman and Mary Harapoulou were polar opposites when they first got together, they say. He was an agnostic Englishman while she was religious and Greek. Now, after almost 40 years together, while many differences remain, some things have shifted. Mary recalls the Greek proverb about addin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Spring</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Houchenism – the brand of can-do Tory threatening the left and right old guard | Will Hutton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/houchenism-the-brand-of-can-do-tory-threatening-the-left-and-right-old-guard</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/houchenism-the-brand-of-can-do-tory-threatening-the-left-and-right-old-guard"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a 73% majority and a string of interventionist initiatives, Tees Valley mayor, Ben Houchen, is reinventing Conservatism
After Thatcherism and Corbynism, welcome to Houchenism, the doctrine of Tees Valley mayor, Ben Houchen, and endorsed by a whopping 73% of Teesside voters. This 34-year-old northern loyalist is the Tory party’s contemporary version of Michael Heseltine, the lone standard bearer at Thatcher’s zenith of a willingness to intervene “at breakfast, lunch and supper”. Houchen is today’s Tory …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Hutton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramadan night markets: Sydneysiders celebrate at Lakemba after sunset – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/09/ramadan-night-markets-sydneysiders-celebrate-at-lakemba-after-sunset-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/09/ramadan-night-markets-sydneysiders-celebrate-at-lakemba-after-sunset-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T20:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From chips on a stick to camel burgers and kanafeh, crowds come to Lakemba’s annual street bazaar for the food and the energy
When the Canterbury Bankstown council announced it had cancelled the annual and extremely popular Ramadan night markets in Lakemba, there was disappointment all round.
The markets have grown to become a staple during Ramadan, the ninth month of the Islamic calendar when Muslims fast from sunrise to sunset.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mostafa Rachwani and Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicola Sturgeon pledges second referendum as SNP lands election win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/nicola-sturgeon-second-independence-referendum-snp-scottish-elections-holyrood</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/nicola-sturgeon-second-independence-referendum-snp-scottish-elections-holyrood"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T19:51:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First minister says there is ‘no democratic justification’ for No 10 denying second vote

Elections 2021: results and reaction - live

Nicola Sturgeon has pledged to press ahead with plans for a second independence referendum after the Scottish National party won its fourth consecutive Holyrood election, triggering a constitutional battle with Boris Johnson.
After counting ended late on Saturday evening, the SNP won 64 seats, missing out on an overall majority by just one seat, after winning a record number…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell and Libby Brooks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Rayner fired as Labour gripped by post-poll rancour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/angela-rayner-fired-labour-keir-starmer-local-elections-polls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/angela-rayner-fired-labour-keir-starmer-local-elections-polls"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T19:22:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Questions grow on Keir Starmer’s leadership with accusations of ‘cowardly avoidance of responsibility’

Elections 2021: results and reaction - live

Labour chair Angela Rayner has been dramatically fired by Keir Starmer as a bitter row erupted over the party’s disastrous performance in Thursday’s bumper set of elections.
She was blamed for her role in running the council and mayoral polls and the byelection in Hartlepool, but her allies said she was never given control over campaigns that were “run out of S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[States turning down Covid-19 vaccine doses as US demand declines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/us-coronavirus-vaccine-demand-states-turning-down-doses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/us-coronavirus-vaccine-demand-states-turning-down-doses"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T19:03:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reduced demand comes as Joe Biden has announced a plan to vaccinate 70% of US adults by the Fourth of July
Declining demand for Covid-19 vaccines in the US is causing states across the country to refuse their full allocations of doses from the federal government, despite concerted efforts to raise national take-up rates.
Reduced demand, which is contributing to a growing stockpile of doses, comes as nearly 46% of the US population has received at least one dose of a two-shot vaccine and about 34% are fully …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dan Carter: ‘Rugby needs fun, it needs characters, or it gets stale’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/dan-carter-rugby-world-cup-all-blacks-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/dan-carter-rugby-world-cup-all-blacks-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The former All Blacks fly-half recalls his torturous relationship with the World Cup and reflects on a family-filled retirement
Dan Carter is as bemused as any father of an eight-year-old. “He wishes he was born in Argentina,” he says of his eldest son. “He wants to play for Barcelona and never play for the All Blacks ever. Because he thinks he’s Argentinian.”
Lionel Messi has a lot to answer for. “I wonder how we can commercialise rugby as well as football,” Carter asks, fascinated by the preoccupations of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Aylwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There are no easy answers to how football tackles its billionaire owners | Jonathan Wilson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/08/no-easy-answers-how-football-tackles-unloved-billionaire-owners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/08/no-easy-answers-how-football-tackles-unloved-billionaire-owners"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans are right to protest but unless the game’s riches are better redistributed the super-rich benefactors are here to stay 
Whether you see in the demonstrations at Old Trafford last week an outrageous affront to law and decency or a legitimate mode of dissent, a public expression at last of long-held grievances, it is clear, perhaps for the first time in English football, that there is a real sense of militancy among fans. With the super-clubs in retreat, the possibility of change appears real – or at lea…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ethiopian patriarch pleads for international help to stop rape and genocide by government troops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/ethiopian-patriarch-pleads-for-international-help-to-stop-and-genocide-by-government-troops</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/ethiopian-patriarch-pleads-for-international-help-to-stop-and-genocide-by-government-troops"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T18:22:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Orthodox priest releases video statement on suppression of Tigray district
Ethiopian government forces and their allies are committing genocide in the country’s war-torn northern province of Tigray, the head of Ethiopia’s Orthodox Church has claimed in a videoed statement demanding urgent international intervention.
The appeal by Abuna [Patriarch] Mathias follows fresh allegations of ethnic cleansing, gang rapes, extrajudicial killings and other atrocities by soldiers loyal to Ethiopia’s prime minister, Abi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Observer staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s Dan Norris wins West of England mayor election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/labour-dan-norris-wins-west-of-england-mayor-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/labour-dan-norris-wins-west-of-england-mayor-election"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:38:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-government minister replaces Tory Tim Bowles and praises Keir Starmer for ‘unlocking’ the area

There was a glimmer of optimism for Labour in the south-west of England where the former Labour government minister Dan Norris got the better of the Tories in the contest for West of England mayor.
In his acceptance speech, Norris said Keir Starmer had “unlocked” the area, which includes Bristol, Bath and North East Somerset, and South Gloucestershire.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyber-attack forces shutdown of one of the US’s largest pipelines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/08/colonial-pipeline-cyber-attack-shutdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/08/colonial-pipeline-cyber-attack-shutdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:06:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colonial Pipeline said it shut down 5,500 miles of pipeline, which carries 45% of the east coast’s fuel supplies
One of the largest pipelines in the US has been shut down after an apparent cyber-attack, its operator has said.
Colonial Pipeline said it had shut down its 5,500 miles of pipeline, which carries 45% of the east coast’s fuel supplies and travels through 14 southern and eastern US states, after the breach of its computer networks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erum Salam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italy’s birthrate is falling. Can the storks help?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/italys-birthrate-is-falling-can-the-storks-help</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/italys-birthrate-is-falling-can-the-storks-help"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, the population of Europe’s fourth biggest economy dropped by the equivalent of a city the size of Florence. Yet the northern hamlets of Val d’Ultimo have found ways to buck the trend
Read more: As the global family shrinks, migrants and the planet benefit
As if having a baby wasn’t expensive enough, fathers of newborns in the mountain hamlets that make up Italy’s Val d’Ultimo have an additional cost.
In a revival of an ancient myth that white storks deliver babies, carved wooden storks carrying a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida in Bolzano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curtis Sittenfeld: ‘People misunderstood the sex scenes in Rodham’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/curtis-sittenfeld-people-misunderstood-the-sex-scenes-in-rodham</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/curtis-sittenfeld-people-misunderstood-the-sex-scenes-in-rodham"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The bestselling author on reimagining Hillary Clinton’s life, what novelists have learned from Covid and the mood in her home town, Minneapolis, since the murder of George Floyd
Curtis Sittenfeld, 45, is the author of two short story collections and six novels, including Prep, her 2005 debut about a teenage girl at boarding school, and American Wife, narrated by a White House first lady, based on Laura Bush. Both books were bestsellers longlisted for the Orange prize (now the Women’s prize for fiction). Her…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anthony Cummins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer’s red wall – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/08/keir-starmers-red-wall-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/08/keir-starmers-red-wall-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour leader’s rebuilding job just got that much harder
•You can buy your own print of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are our courts a playground for bullies? Just ask Catherine Belton | Nick Cohen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/are-our-courts-a-playground-for-bullies-just-ask-catherine-belton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/are-our-courts-a-playground-for-bullies-just-ask-catherine-belton"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T17:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Her acclaimed book is under attack from Russian billionaires. Are they out to silence her?
Welcome to London, the censorship capital of the democratic world, where you must watch your step and bite your tongue if you know what’s good for you.
Everyone here who writes or broadcasts about plutocratic power should be honest with you before getting down to business. We’re pretty much free to say what we want about Boris Johnson, for example, or Dominic Raab. They’re only our prime minister and foreign secretary…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blasts target school in west Kabul killing at least 40 people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/explosion-near-school-kabul-afghanistan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/explosion-near-school-kabul-afghanistan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:50:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attack in Afghan capital injures mainly female students coming out of school in Shia Muslim area

At least 40 people have been killed and dozens more injured in a bomb attack on girls leaving their school in a largely Shia Muslim neighbourhood in Kabul.
Residents said they heard multiple blasts just as girls were leaving classes at the Sayed ul-Shuhada school in the Afghan capital to return home and break their Ramadan fast. Most of the victims appear to have been students.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Graham-Harrison and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arlo Parks: Gen Z star entrances all who hear her]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/08/arlo-parks-gen-z-star-entrances-all-who-hear-her</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/08/arlo-parks-gen-z-star-entrances-all-who-hear-her"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 20-year-old’s debut album is up for three Brits this week – and has captivated fans from Billie Eilish to Michelle Obama
There were fewer than a dozen people out in east London on a Saturday night in Paper Dress Vintage when Arlo Parks arrived on stage. The clothes shop by day turned live music venue by night had the then 17-year-old second on the bill, where she performed with a band made up of schoolfriends. Most of the audience were mates from sixth form. But there was also a scout from Transgressive…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nosheen Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: British Scandal; Victoria Derbyshire sitting in for Jeremy Vine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/08/british-scandal-podcast-litvinenko-review-victoria-derbyshire-jeremy-vine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/08/british-scandal-podcast-litvinenko-review-victoria-derbyshire-jeremy-vine"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A strange new podcast attempts to mix humour with the murder of Alexander Litvinenko. Never a wrong note, though, from Victoria Derbyshire
British Scandal (Wondery) | wondery.com
Victoria Derbyshire sits in for Jeremy Vine (BBC Radio 2) | BBC Sounds
British Scandal, a new podcast from Wondery hosted by Alice Levine and Matt Forde, is a strange affair. Before I get to the show, let’s look at its elements. Wondery is a successful US podcast producer that began by specialising in true-crime shows such as Dirty…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How creative of the Tories to invent a culture war to disguise arts cuts | Barbara Ellen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/how-creative-of-the-tories-to-invent-a-culture-war-to-disguise-arts-cuts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/how-creative-of-the-tories-to-invent-a-culture-war-to-disguise-arts-cuts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone is the poorer when scientists are pitted against artists by the morally bankrupt
The arts are being screwed over. Again. If we keep allowing this to happen, there will be an atrophying of the national soul the like of which the UK has never seen. The added insult is that this latest round of cultural vandalism is being wreaked under the guise of a bogus battle between the arts on one side and science, medicine and technology on the other.
A consultation by the education secretary, Gavin Williamson,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barbara Ellen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic captured in patchwork art – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/08/the-pandemic-captured-in-patchwork-art-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/08/the-pandemic-captured-in-patchwork-art-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Pinochet-era Chile, a group of women known as the Arpilleristas denounced the violent regime by creating patchwork images out of scraps. That movement is the inspiration behind a new show, All in the Same Storm: Pandemic Patchwork Stories ( 19 May-30 August) , a collaboration between the De La Warr Pavilion in East Sussex and the local Refugee Buddy Project, founded by Rossana Leal. 
The patches, she says, express how people felt in lockdown: “fear, loneliness, gratitude to the NHS”. Created by refugees,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The non-binary underwear company that wants to ‘degender’ fashion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/08/urbody-gender-free-underwear-fashion-industry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/08/urbody-gender-free-underwear-fashion-industry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T15:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The founders of Urbody say the fashion industry is ‘grounded in a binary understanding of bodies’
The founders of a new underwear company say they want to “degender fashion” and believe that the future of the industry will be gender free clothes for everyone.
Urbody, a non-binary undergarments company that launched in March founded by friends Mere Abrams (who goes by they/them) and Anna Graham (she/her), believe that the fashion industry is not keeping up with societal conversations around gender.
 Continue…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Island paradise: an Anglesey house that became a stunning family home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/island-paradise-an-anglesey-house-that-became-a-stunning-family-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/island-paradise-an-anglesey-house-that-became-a-stunning-family-home"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T15:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How a large Victorian house provides a striking backdrop for a young family with stunning views across to the coast
Not many people buy a kitchen before they’ve found the house to put it in, but no one who knows designer Mairead Turner and her restaurateur husband Robin Hodgson is surprised to hear this is what they did. When they fall in love with a beautiful pre-loved bargain they snap it up and work out where it’s going to go later.
“I spotted these kitchen units years ago, while on one of my regular eBa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Tobin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homebuyers struggle: ‘Sellers just add the stamp duty saving to the price’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/homebuyers-struggle-sellers-just-add-the-stamp-duty-saving-to-the-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/homebuyers-struggle-sellers-just-add-the-stamp-duty-saving-to-the-price"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T15:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Young people in the UK are finding properties even further out of reach as tax breaks and easier credit drive up prices
The housing market has defied expectations over the past year, fuelled by people’s desire to move to properties with gardens and space to work from home, and boosted by stamp duty holidays across the UK. 
But the frenzy means many would-be buyers have been left behind. For them, despite the launch of a government guarantee scheme for 95% mortgages, owning a home is now further out of reach…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones and Hilary Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU posts bail to free jailed Georgia opposition leader]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/eu-posts-bail-to-free-jailed-georgia-opposition-leader-nika-melia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/eu-posts-bail-to-free-jailed-georgia-opposition-leader-nika-melia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:41:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move paves way for Nika Melia’s release and end to political crisis that has gripped the country
The European Union said on Saturday it had posted bail for Georgia’s jailed opposition leader, Nika Melia, paving the way for his release and ending a protracted political crisis in the Caucasus country.
Melia, the chair of Georgia’s main opposition force, the United National Movement (UNM), was arrested in February in a violent police raid on his party headquarters, sparking protests and condemnation from the w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Tbilisi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lewis Hamilton makes history by claiming 100th F1 pole at Spanish GP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/lewis-hamilton-claims-100th-f1-pole-at-spanish-gp-verstappen-starts-second</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/08/lewis-hamilton-claims-100th-f1-pole-at-spanish-gp-verstappen-starts-second"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:36:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World champion edges out Max Verstappen to reach century

Mercedes teammate Valtteri Bottas starts in third

Lewis Hamilton was unable to hide his delight as he celebrated his 100th pole position in Formula One with the same unbridled joy that marked his first. In claiming the top spot for Sunday’s Spanish Grand Prix this was a unique century for a unique driver, the first time any F1 driver has reached the century as yet another milestone fell to the world champion.
Hamilton has never chased records but it…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards at the Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s victories show importance of localism and positive vision]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/labours-victories-show-importance-of-localism-and-positive-vision</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/labours-victories-show-importance-of-localism-and-positive-vision"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:29:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: on a poor night for party, lesson from areas where it did well is that it cannot win on negativity alone

Elections 2021: results and reaction - live

A meme was doing the rounds on Saturday morning that offered a theory of why Labour had done so badly in the local elections.
It read: “Labour: a bunch of rich people convincing poor people to vote for rich people by telling poor people that ‘other’ rich people are the reason they are poor.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remains of nine Neanderthals found in cave south of Rome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/08/remains-of-nine-neanderthals-found-in-cave-south-of-rome</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/08/remains-of-nine-neanderthals-found-in-cave-south-of-rome"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:19:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Italian archaeologists believe most of Neanderthals were killed by hyenas then dragged back to den
Italian archaeologists have unearthed the bones of nine Neanderthals who were allegedly hunted and mauled by hyenas in their den about 100km south-east of Rome.
Scientists from the Archaeological Superintendency of Latina and the University of Tor Vergata in Rome said the remains belong to seven adult males and one female, while another are those of a young boy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Tondo in Palermo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On my radar: Fiona Shaw’s cultural highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/08/on-my-radar-fiona-shaws-cultural-highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/08/on-my-radar-fiona-shaws-cultural-highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The award-winning actor on the genius of Fritz Lang, the human cost of Homer’s Iliad and where to find the best live music in Ireland
Born in County Cork, Ireland, in 1958, Fiona Shaw studied philosophy at University College Cork before training at Rada. Her stage roles have ranged from Sophocles to Shakespeare, Beckett to Brecht; she has won two Olivier awards and directed theatre productions and operas including Britten’s The Rape of Lucretia. She has also appeared in numerous films, including My Left Foo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charlatan review – inside the mind of a prickly mystic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/charlatan-review-agnieszka-holland-jan-mikolasek</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/charlatan-review-agnieszka-holland-jan-mikolasek"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Agnieszka Holland’s austere drama about a famous Czech healer sets his internal conflict against the turbulence of eastern Europe
A local legend in the mid-20th century Czech Republic who scrutinised the urine of his clients and made diagnoses based on a blend of science and mysticism, Jan Mikolášek is a prickly subject for Agnieszka Holland’s latest biographical drama. Its title notwithstanding, the film expends little energy exploring whether or not Mikolášek’s healing gift was genuine. The recurring shot…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wendy Ide</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paddy McGuinness: watching people telling lies is oddly irresistible | Rebecca Nicholson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/paddy-mcguinness-watching-people-telling-lies-is-oddly-irresistible</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/paddy-mcguinness-watching-people-telling-lies-is-oddly-irresistible"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T14:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The host of I Can Hear Your Voice has turned no-way TV into a must-see-every-Saturday-night hit show
It seems, lately, that whenever a television show arrives promising a brave new format, my first thought is: “There’s no way I’m watching that.”
I had it with The Masked Singer. I had it with The Wall, the quiz show where Danny Dyer prowls along the bottom of a giant, upturned pinball machine and talks dirty to the big balls.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK government ‘failed to consider gender’ in its response to Covid pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/uk-government-failed-to-consider-gender-in-its-response-to-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/uk-government-failed-to-consider-gender-in-its-response-to-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:42:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sage overlooked the heavy toll suffered by women when developing policies to combat coronavirus, says study
The government has “consistently failed” to consider gender in its response to Covid-19 despite men and women being affected in distinct ways by the pandemic, claim researchers from the London School of Economics.
While more men have died from the virus, women have suffered more due to the impact of policies introduced to prevent disease transmission.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Summers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secret Service extension for Trump’s adult children cost $140,000 in a month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/08/trump-secret-service-detail-children-post-white-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/08/trump-secret-service-detail-children-post-white-house"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:32:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trump extended post-presidency protections by six months
Secret Service detailing four siblings and two of their spouses

Donald Trump’s adult children reportedly cost taxpayers $140,000 in Secret Service security in the month after the clan’s patriarch left the White House in January.
 Related: The sleazy, sordid Matt Gaetz scandal: are the walls now closing in on him? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK high-speed trains cancelled after cracks found in carriages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/uk-high-speed-trains-cancelled-after-cracks-found-in-carriages</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/uk-high-speed-trains-cancelled-after-cracks-found-in-carriages"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:23:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Passengers face ‘significant’ disruption as GWR and LNER suspend services in order to inspect trains

Have you been affected by the recent GWR and LNER train cancellations?

Rail services on Britain’s main intercity lines were halted and passengers told of potential prolonged disruption ahead, after cracks were found on high-speed trains.
All intercity trains on Great Western Railway and London North Eastern Railway were suspended on Saturday morning, as their entire fleets of Hitachi trains were taken out …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham and Jedidajah Otte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists launch search for genetic test to spot killer prostate cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/scientists-launch-search-for-genetic-test-to-spot-killer-prostate-cancer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/scientists-launch-search-for-genetic-test-to-spot-killer-prostate-cancer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:18:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gene-screening, as is used to detect some breast cancer risks, could save thousands of lives
Scientists have begun work to create a prostate cancer screening service for the UK. In a few years, middle-aged men could be tested to reveal their genetic susceptibility to the condition, with those deemed to be under significant threat of developing it being offered treatment or surgery.
The service would tackle a disease that has become the nation’s most commonly diagnosed cancer and would parallel Britain’s bre…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s just pants: ads for skimpy men’s underwear too racy for media giants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/08/its-just-pants-ads-for-skimpy-mens-underwear-too-racy-for-media-giants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/08/its-just-pants-ads-for-skimpy-mens-underwear-too-racy-for-media-giants"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:17:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retailer Moot fears for future of its business as TV and web companies remove its promotions
A male underwear company that had its adverts pulled from social media and an appearance on a morning television show dropped has accused the industry of double standards when it comes to images of semi-clothed male and female bodies.
Moot, an underwear retailer set up by Jules Parker – a metal worker turned undergarment designer – was to be featured on ITV’s This Morning. The show then pulled the planned segment, w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid restricted Keir Starmer from setting out vision for UK, says Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/covid-restricted-keir-starmer-from-setting-out-vision-for-uk-says-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/08/covid-restricted-keir-starmer-from-setting-out-vision-for-uk-says-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:06:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour supported government in pandemic and did not play party political games, says shadow home secretary
Labour has been unable to set out its vision for the country because of the pandemic, the party’s shadow home secretary has said, with the party braced for further knife-edge results over the weekend.
Important mayoral elections could provide further difficult results for the Labour leader but the party is hoping for narrow victories in the west of England mayoralty and the West Yorkshire mayoralty, ex…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alastair Campbell’s partner Fiona Millar: Coping with his depression taught me: don’t blame yourself]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/fiona-millar-coping-with-alastair-campbell-depression-taught-me-this-dont-blame-yourself</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/fiona-millar-coping-with-alastair-campbell-depression-taught-me-this-dont-blame-yourself"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T13:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades of living with a partner tormented by mental illness, Cherie Blair’s former aide appeals for more help for sufferers and their families
Over the years, I have grown used to various different “identities” – aide to Cherie Blair, partner of Alastair Campbell, latterly mother of comedian Grace Campbell. More recently, I have adopted a new persona; the partner of someone with mental health issues. I have lived this role in private for more than 40 years but only recently “gone public” since Alasta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Millar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rent arrears put thousands at risk as end of eviction ban in England looms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/08/rent-arrears-put-thousands-at-risk-as-end-of-eviction-ban-in-england-looms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/08/rent-arrears-put-thousands-at-risk-as-end-of-eviction-ban-in-england-looms"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T12:59:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs and charities fear a wave of homelessness when landlords can once again legally force out tenants in debt

See all our coronavirus coverage

Clare Austin* and family live in a privately rented house in Hertfordshire. She and her husband could afford the monthly rent of £1,700 when they were both working but when he lost his job a couple of years ago, they fell behind with their payments. He got another job and things were almost back on track when Covid hit and both were furloughed.
“We can’t claim anyt…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hilary Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Julia James: Kent police arrest man in his 20s]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/julia-james-kent-police-arrest-man-in-his-20s</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/08/julia-james-kent-police-arrest-man-in-his-20s"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T12:48:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Man held in connection with death of PCSO whose body was found in Kent woodland on 27 April 
A man in his 20s has been arrested in connection with the death of PCSO Julia James, Kent police have said.
James, 53, was found dead in Akholt wood near her home in Snowdown, Kent, on 27 April. A postmortem examination revealed she had suffered significant head injuries and died as a result of blunt force trauma.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Molly Blackall and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leonardo da Vinci bear drawing expected to fetch £12m at auction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/leonardo-da-vinci-bear-drawing-is-expected-to-fetch-12m-at-auction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/leonardo-da-vinci-bear-drawing-is-expected-to-fetch-12m-at-auction"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T12:38:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Head of a Bear is to be sold in London in July by Christie’s auction house
A drawing of a bear by Leonardo da Vinci is expected to fetch up to £12m at auction.
The picture, titled Head of a Bear, is being sold in London by Christie’s. It will go on display in New York and Hong Kong before being auctioned and is expected to fetch between £8m and £12m, according to the auction house.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emma Donoghue on writing Room: ‘I toned down some of the horror of the Fritzl case’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/emma-donoghue-on-writing-room-i-toned-down-some-of-the-horror-of-the-fritzl-case</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/emma-donoghue-on-writing-room-i-toned-down-some-of-the-horror-of-the-fritzl-case"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T12:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Donoghue’s bestseller drew on the case of Felix Fritzl, who was held captive in a dungeon by his father, and her observations of her own children
I got the notion to write Room in 2008 when I was driving to a book event and mulling over a news story from a few days before about a five-year-old called Felix Fritzl, rescued from the Austrian dungeon where his mother had raised him and his siblings. By the time I parked, and grabbed a napkin to scribble down my thoughts, I knew my novel had to be from the chil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Donoghue</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘This isn’t how my gap year was meant to be’: how Covid turned young people’s lives upside down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/08/this-isnt-how-my-gap-year-was-meant-to-be-how-covid-turned-young-peoples-lives-upside-down</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/08/this-isnt-how-my-gap-year-was-meant-to-be-how-covid-turned-young-peoples-lives-upside-down"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T11:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some have missed out on adventure, others on university places – but as well as turmoil, the pandemic has thrown up some surprising consolations
When Daisy Davis imagined her gap year, she pictured global adventure. Building schools as a volunteer in Tanzania or Ghana, perhaps, Interrailing through Europe, or travelling in Thailand. Finally 18 and with a year of blissful freedom before university, Daisy presumed that the world was there to be explored.
At school near her home in East Sussex, where she lives…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travel industry says England’s ‘green list’ too cautious]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/travel-industry-says-england-green-list-covid-too-cautious</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/travel-industry-says-england-green-list-covid-too-cautious"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T10:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sector leaders say Covid scheme is ‘reopening in name only’ and call for more destinations to be added

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Travel industry bosses have criticised the government’s plan for overseas summer holidays for being “overly cautious”, warning it will delay the recovery of the sector.
A traffic light system for international travel will come into force in England on 17 May, the first easing of tight restrictions on foreign travel in several months.
 Continue…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Molly Blackall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve spent so much of my life dreaming of homes I cannot afford | Deborah Levy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/deborah-levy-real-estate-ive-spent-so-much-of-my-life-dreaming-of-homes-i-cannot-afford</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/deborah-levy-real-estate-ive-spent-so-much-of-my-life-dreaming-of-homes-i-cannot-afford"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this extract from Real Estate, the final instalment of Deborah Levy’s ‘living autobiography’ series, she reflects on fantasy properties, empty nests and the relationship between property and freedom
I walked to Central Park. It had suddenly become warm and I was so jet lagged I thought I might faint. I found a place near the entrance to the park under a tree and collapsed on to the grass. Lying on my back, looking up at the big American sky between the leaves, I saw something hanging from the branches. I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deborah Levy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life on the rocks in Brazil’s campo rupestre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/08/life-on-the-rocks-brazils-campo-rupestre-species-under-threat-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/08/life-on-the-rocks-brazils-campo-rupestre-species-under-threat-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T10:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a little-known region that calls to mind Tolkien’s Middle-earth, photojournalist Augusto Gomes marvels at one of the oldest, harshest, most biodiverse – and most threatened – ecosystems on the planet
When I was a child, my family would drive three hours from our home in Belo Horizonte to visit my grandfather’s ranch near the town of Santana dos Montes. On the way, we would cross the Espinhaço mountain range, which runs north to south in the central-eastern portion of Brazil.
Espinhaço means “spine” in Po…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Augusto Gomes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I walked out of Avengers profoundly changed’: our writers’ favourite cinema moments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/our-writers-favourite-cinema-moments</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/08/our-writers-favourite-cinema-moments"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:30:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Big-screen highlights, from a magnificent montage in The Royal Tenenbaums to an all-time high in Harold &amp; Kumar Escape from Guantanamo Bay

Catherine Bray on cinema’s long-awaited return

It is so difficult to pin down a “happiest” moment in the cinema, as opposed to the clearer spikes of fear, amusement or euphoria, maybe because the happy feeling can bubble along more or less unobtrusively all the way through a good film. But for pure directionless, laid-back, sunlit happiness that I remember coursing…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw; Kathryn Bromwich; Ryan Gilbey; Joel Golby; Simran Hans; Steve Rose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Maldives president is off life support after bomb attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/mohamed-nasheed-former-maldives-president-is-off-life-support-after-bomb-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/mohamed-nasheed-former-maldives-president-is-off-life-support-after-bomb-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police make two arrests in connection with explosion at Mohamed Nasheed’s family home in Malé
The former Maldives president Mohamed Nasheed is conscious after life-saving surgery, his family said on Saturday, as police made two arrests in connection with an explosion they said was being treated as a terror attack.
Nasheed, the president of the ruling Maldivian Democratic party and the current parliament speaker, was critically injured after a bomb exploded as he left his family home in the capital Malé on T…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Malé</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1821-2021: the greatest Guardian front pages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/gallery/2021/may/08/guardian-200-best-guardian-front-pages</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/gallery/2021/may/08/guardian-200-best-guardian-front-pages"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 200 years, the Guardian has produced more than 54,000 front pages. Here are some of the most memorable
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conservatives’ win in Hartlepool is a triumph of political rebranding | Carl Shoben]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/conservatives-hartlepool-triumph-political-rebranding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/conservatives-hartlepool-triumph-political-rebranding"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tories are selling themselves as a party of change and investment, and voters are buying it
Amid all the inevitable soul-searching for Labour following Thursday’s defeat in the Hartlepool byelection, it is just as instructive to examine what went right for the Conservatives. They have done a far better analysis of the electorate, changing demographics, changing economies, and successfully moulded a coalition that is becoming embedded in the old parts of Labour country. A “red wall” is the wrong way to d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carl Shoben</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The sleazy, sordid Matt Gaetz scandal: are the walls now closing in on him?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/08/matt-gaetz-florida-sleazy-scandal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/08/matt-gaetz-florida-sleazy-scandal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigation into Florida congressman is reported to have grown beyond sex trafficking allegations
There could have been no more fitting venue for the bellicose US congressman Matt Gaetz to launch his nationwide “America first” speaking tour than The Villages. Where better to perpetuate the fantasy that all is going well for a politician seen as the “ultimate Maga bro” than Florida’s ultra-conservative “Disney World for retirees”?
 Related: Florida governor signs new restrictive bill in ‘blatant attack on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faith during the Covid pandemic – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/faith-during-covid-pandemic-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/faith-during-covid-pandemic-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Suki Dhanda documents how different religious beliefs have helped people come through the coronavirus crisis and lockdown restrictions in England
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suki Dhanda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post Office contacts hundreds who may have been wrongfully prosecuted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/post-office-contacts-hundreds-who-may-have-been-wrongfully-prosecuted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/post-office-contacts-hundreds-who-may-have-been-wrongfully-prosecuted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:52:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Extensive exercise’ under way after theft, fraud and false accounting convictions quashed
The Post Office is contacting hundreds of people who may have been wrongfully prosecuted after the post office operator miscarriage of justice scandal.
Dozens of post office operators were prosecuted for theft, fraud and false accounting because of the Post Office’s defective Horizon accounting system, which had “bugs, defects and errors” from the outset.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 205 Palestinians wounded in Jerusalem al-Aqsa clashes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/israel-more-than-205-palestinians-wounded-in-jerusalem-al-aqsa-clashes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/israel-more-than-205-palestinians-wounded-in-jerusalem-al-aqsa-clashes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:44:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Confrontations at holy site leave 17 Israeli police officers wounded, with international calls for calm
More than 205 Palestinians and 17 Israeli police officers were wounded during a night of intense clashes at a sacred Jerusalem site that holds the Dome of the Rock, medics and police said, a serious escalation in a weeks-long rise in violence.
Tensions in Jerusalem have soared recently, with Palestinians complaining of oppressive restrictions during the Muslim holy month of Ramadan. An upcoming Israeli co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bobby Gillespie: ‘I am a lead singer, I love myself’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/bobby-gillespie-i-am-lead-singer-i-love-myself</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/bobby-gillespie-i-am-lead-singer-i-love-myself"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The musician on his Raquel Welch wallpaper, crying when Maradona died and breaking his back in four places
Born in Glasgow, Bobby Gillespie, 58, founded Primal Scream in 1982. The band’s third album, Screamadelica, won the 1992 Mercury music prize. Utopian Ashes, Gillespie’s album with Jehnny Beth, is released on 2 July; their single, Remember We Were Lovers, is out now. He lives in London with his wife, fashion stylist Katy England, and two sons.
When were you happiest?
Standing on stage in between Robert …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rosanna Greenstreet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yotam Ottolenghi’s barbecue recipes for outdoors or in]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/08/yotam-ottolenghi-barbecue-recipes-grilled-peas-wasabi-dressing-furikake-baked-potatoes-onoin-harissa-sauce</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/08/yotam-ottolenghi-barbecue-recipes-grilled-peas-wasabi-dressing-furikake-baked-potatoes-onoin-harissa-sauce"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An alfresco duo that you can cook outdoors or in: baked potato with onion and harissa butter, and peas in the pod with wasabi dressing
One game I’m definitely playing in the next year or so is Spot the Park/Common/Outdoor Scene in every film or TV series I watch, because I’ve seen so many film crews at work outside over the past year. And, just as I predict a spate of outdoor film and TV action, I also predict that, this summer, there will be a whole lot of recipes for outdoor cooking and eating. So long as…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yotam Ottolenghi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK taskforce to tackle rising number of pet thefts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/uk-taskforce-to-tackle-rising-number-of-pet-thefts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/08/uk-taskforce-to-tackle-rising-number-of-pet-thefts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Body will look into what is contributing to surge in thefts and recommend solutions to tackle problem
A taskforce has been set up by the government to look into tackling the “deplorable” crime of pet theft, which has soared during the Covid-19 pandemic.
In March, DogLost, a UK charity that helps victims of dog theft, recorded a 170% increase in the crime, from 172 dogs reported stolen in 2019 to 465 in 2020.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows on the world: pandemic poems by Simon Armitage, Hollie McNish, Kae Tempest and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/windows-on-the-world-pandemic-poems-by-simon-armitage-hollie-mcnish-kae-tempest-and-more</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/08/windows-on-the-world-pandemic-poems-by-simon-armitage-hollie-mcnish-kae-tempest-and-more"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six of the UK’s best poets reveal exclusive new work and reflect on the last year, losing relatives, long-distance relationships and ‘artistic claustrophobia’
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Armitage, Hollie McNish,  Roger McGough, Kae Tempest, Jay Bernard and Raymond Antrobus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If Carrie Symonds wants to master the grand gesture, she should listen to Meat Loaf | Hadley Freeman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/carrie-symonds-grand-gesture-meat-loaf-hadley-freeman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/08/carrie-symonds-grand-gesture-meat-loaf-hadley-freeman"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T08:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spending money you don’t actually have is a classic sign of someone not being honest about who they are
This opinion feels about as unfashionable as matching your overly patterned wallpaper to your sofa, but I have some sympathy with Carrie Symonds. As I write, it looks increasingly like Boris Johnson’s reputation might actually be damaged by some rolls of wallpaper, which, on the one hand, is quite amusing when you think of all the terrible things that man has done in his life – and now he’s getting felled…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadley Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[200 years of newsroom style: what journalists wear to work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/08/guardian-200-what-do-journalists-wear-to-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/08/guardian-200-what-do-journalists-wear-to-work"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T07:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian journalists on the role of their outfits in their reporting, and the importance of pockets

What do you imagine journalists wear to work? Three-piece vanilla silk suits, like Tom Wolfe? Robert Redford’s Wasp-y needlecord in All the President’s Men? Or something uniquely earth-tone like Paddy Considine’s “Guardian” reporter in The Bourne Ultimatum?
The late journalist Betty Jerman, who joined the paper in 1951 and worked simultaneously as secretary and columnist, once said of her “rather shabby” mal…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Morwenna Ferrier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cost of building work on UK homes to rise as price of materials soars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/cost-of-building-work-on-uk-homes-to-rise-as-price-of-materials-soars</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/08/cost-of-building-work-on-uk-homes-to-rise-as-price-of-materials-soars"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T07:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Booming housing market as ‘incredible demand’ fuels shortage of essentials from concrete and timber to taps and roof tiles
UK homeowners face higher bills for renovation work as builders grapple with soaring material costs and shortages of essentials ranging from concrete and timber to taps and roof tiles in a booming housing market.
“It is a bit like going to Sainsbury’s and them not having any bread, milk or eggs in,” said Paul Bence, the managing director of builders merchants Bence, of the runaway deman…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French military pilot tied up on firing range during bombing as hazing prank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/french-military-pilot-tied-up-on-firing-range-during-bombing-as-prank</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/french-military-pilot-tied-up-on-firing-range-during-bombing-as-prank"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T06:24:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawyer gives details of airman’s complaint over Corsica incident where he was tied to target while bombs and bullets hailed around
A French pilot has filed a legal complaint after being subjected to a hazing ritual in which he was tied to a target and had fighter jets open fire around him, his lawyer has said.
The young man had just been posted to an airbase in the south of the island of Corsica in March 2019 when he was grabbed by colleagues and tied up with adhesive tape, his lawyer said, confirming detai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refugees and the Armenian genocide: human rights this fortnight in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/08/refugees-and-the-armenian-genocide-human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/08/refugees-and-the-armenian-genocide-human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T06:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A roundup of the coverage on struggles for human rights and freedoms, from Colombia to China
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Captions by Sarah Johnson, compiled by Eric Hilaire</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Branching out: why Britons are buying woodland in the Covid crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/08/branching-out-buying-woodland-covid-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/08/branching-out-buying-woodland-covid-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T06:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More people are seeking their own outside space to experience nature and spend time with family
Lockdown spurred some people to start yoga, crack on with DIY or watch more Netflix. For others, it prompted them to splash out on their very own green oasis.
Owen Gardner, 46, and his wife, Anya, 48, who live in Farnborough in Hampshire, decided to buy 2.2 hectares (5.5 acres) of woodland in Surrey last summer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suzanne Bearne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colorado’s ‘rebel’ farmers – ‘I’d like to see industrial farming go extinct’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/08/colorado-regenerative-farming-cedar-springs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/08/colorado-regenerative-farming-cedar-springs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T05:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jake Takiff is part of a trend towards ‘regenerative’ farming, a more environmentally and economically sustainable model of managing the land
Last September, Jake Takiff, a farmer in Hotchkiss, Colorado, posted a photo of himself on Instagram standing next to a dead sow tied up by its hind feet.
The post pays tribute to Fat Auntie’s prolific litters, how she “took good care of all the piglets and was a joy to be around”, how fond she was of belly rubs. It ends with Jake explaining why, after her long full l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Lampert in Colorado</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK aid cuts will put tens of thousands of children at risk of famine, says charity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/08/uk-aid-cuts-will-put-tens-of-thousands-of-children-at-risk-of-famine-says-charity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/08/uk-aid-cuts-will-put-tens-of-thousands-of-children-at-risk-of-famine-says-charity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T05:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Save the Children’s analysis finds Britain will spend 80% less on nutrition abroad this year, as hunger levels rise around the world
Britain is set to spend 80% less on helping feed children in poorer nations than before the pandemic, according to a charity’s analysis.
Save the Children said the British government will spend less than £26m this year on vital nutrition services in developing countries, a drop of more than three-quarters from 2019. The estimate of aid cuts to nutrition comes after UN agencies…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karen McVeigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China tries to scupper UN talk on plight of Uyghurs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/china-tries-to-scupper-un-talk-on-plight-of-uighurs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/china-tries-to-scupper-un-talk-on-plight-of-uighurs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T04:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beijing’s mission asks other members not to attend, with Human Rights Watch saying it continues pattern of ‘trying to bully governments into silence’
China is trying to convince UN member states to boycott an event planned next week by Germany, the US and Britain on the repression of Uyghur Muslims and other minorities in Xinjiang, according to a note seen by Reuters on Friday.
China charged that the organisers, who include several other European states along with Australia and Canada, use “human rights iss…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picture of two pandemics: Covid cases fall in rich west as poorer nations suffer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/picture-of-two-pandemics-covid-cases-fall-in-rich-west-as-poorer-nations-suffer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/picture-of-two-pandemics-covid-cases-fall-in-rich-west-as-poorer-nations-suffer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T04:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[India’s tragedy could be followed by Africa’s, campaigners warn, as wealthy nations fail to extend vaccines – and decide who will live or die

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The past seven days has been a picture of two pandemics. Among the world’s richest nations, lockdowns and well-resourced vaccine campaigns, which have monopolised the early global supply of doses, have brought down infections and deaths. Economies have slowly opened. Restrictions have been lifted. Life ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zulu queen’s will designates Prince Misuzulu as heir]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/zulu-queens-will-designates-prince-misuzulu-as-heir</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/08/zulu-queens-will-designates-prince-misuzulu-as-heir"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T02:12:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Succession battle in South Africa takes latest turn after king and queen both died within less than two months
Prince Misuzulu Zulu – the eldest son of South Africa’s late Zulu king Goodwill Zwelithini and his more recently deceased regent queen – has been designated heir to the monarchy amid a turbulent succession battle.
Misuzulu Zulu, 46, whose name means “strengthening the Zulus”, was named heir in the last will of his deceased mother and queen, Shiyiwe Mantfombi Dlamini Zulu. The will was read out on t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 1m homes in England with planning permission not built]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/over-1m-homes-in-england-with-planning-permission-not-built</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/08/over-1m-homes-in-england-with-planning-permission-not-built"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T23:01:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local Government Association says 2.78m homes approved since 2010-11, with only 1.6m built 
More than 1.1m homes that received planning permission in England over the last decade are yet to be built, according to the Local Government Association, which called for new powers to be given to councils to encourage developers to build housing more quickly.
The LGA, which represents 327 of the 333 councils in England, said that 2.78m homes have been granted planning permission by councils since 2010-11, but over …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Systems Book Recommendations – Learn How to Build and Understand ML Systems]]></title>
        <id>609558382cd0545b5e943c6f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-systems-book-recommendations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T21:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Good friends, good books, and a sleepy conscience: this is the ideal life.” ― Mark TwainI hope you’re reading this blog in your pjs looking forward to a rejuvenating and healthy weekend.  I have been working on multiple projects lately, from creating Machine Learing Engineering and Machine Learning Operations courses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inquest to be held into Covid death of rail worker allegedly spat at by customer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/07/inquest-to-be-held-into-covid-death-of-rail-worker-allegedly-spat-at-by-customer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/07/inquest-to-be-held-into-covid-death-of-rail-worker-allegedly-spat-at-by-customer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T18:41:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senior coroner says there needs to be an investigation into what may have been the ‘unnatural’ death of Belly Mujinga

An inquest will held into the death of Belly Mujinga, the railway worker who died with Covid-19 after an alleged incident where she was coughed on and spat at by a customer.
Mujinga, 47, died last April, two weeks after the alleged incident on the concourse at London’s Victoria station where she worked as a sales clerk for Govia Thameslink Railway (GTR).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Boris Johnson’s win: Brexit is remaking politics | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/07/the-guardian-view-on-boris-johnsons-win-brexit-is-remaking-politics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/07/the-guardian-view-on-boris-johnsons-win-brexit-is-remaking-politics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T17:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson has been forced to discover and explain what he stands for. Keir Starmer cannot, and voters are unimpressed

One can read too much into the Conservative party’s astounding victory at the byelection in Hartlepool, a deprived port town seat in north-east England. But it is rare that a government wins such contests, especially when it has been in power for 11 years and when the seat had been the opposition’s for decades. Now the town with the highest unemployment rate in the country has a Tory MP…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/07/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/07/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T17:28:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police target drug traffickers in Rio, migrants on the Rio Grande, protests against the government in Colombia and the enduring impact of Covid-19: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on secondhand clothes: the thrill of the old | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/07/the-guardian-view-on-second-hand-clothes-the-thrill-of-the-old</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/07/the-guardian-view-on-second-hand-clothes-the-thrill-of-the-old"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T17:25:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Big business is getting in on the act as sales of ‘preloved’ garments boom. But can the trend curb our love for fast fashion?

“Few articles change owners more frequently than clothes. They travel downwards from grade to grade in the social scale with remarkable regularity,” wrote the journalist Adolphe Smith in 1877 as he traced a garment’s journey: cleaned, repaired and resold repeatedly; eventually cut down into a smaller item; finally, when it was beyond all wearability, the fibres recycled into new fab…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recursion Might Seem Scary – But it Doesn&#x27;t Have to Be]]></title>
        <id>609551f02cd0545b5e943bc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recursion-doesnt-have-to-be-scary/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T16:59:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any concept that we don't fully understand can be scary at first. Recursion is a topic that programming students don't learn right away. But that doesn't mean it needs to be scary or cause anxiety. In fact, recursion is a concept that we can define rather simply. According to Wikipedia:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how has your life been affected by the Black Lives Matter movement?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/07/tell-us-how-has-your-life-been-affected-by-the-black-lives-matter-movement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/07/tell-us-how-has-your-life-been-affected-by-the-black-lives-matter-movement"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T16:12:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to speak to families about how their lives have been affected by the BLM movement
As part of our commemorations for the upcoming one-year anniversary of George Floyd’s death and the Black Lives Matter protests of last summer, we would like to speak to families about how their lives have been affected by the BLM movement.
We want to hear about how each of your lives has changed – or not changed – over the last year, for example in the workplace, in education, in personal relationships, to refle…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s 200-year fight for social justice won’t end now | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/the-guardians-200-year-fight-for-social-justice-wont-end-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/the-guardians-200-year-fight-for-social-justice-wont-end-now"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T15:43:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reflect on the Guardian’s anniversary and share what the publication has brought to their lives 
I went to school in Manchester in the 1950s. In the first week of term, we were told that there were two things that all Mancunians should be proud of: the Hallé Orchestra and the Manchester Guardian. The newspaper was available daily in the school library. I had never seen any newspaper at home other than the Daily Mirror. I started to read the Manchester Guardian then and continue to do so. Many congra…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t underestimate the value of arts degrees | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/07/dont-underestimate-the-value-of-arts-degrees</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/07/dont-underestimate-the-value-of-arts-degrees"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T15:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If funding for arts subjects is slashed, the country will not only be culturally poorer but will also lose skilled and highly motivated graduates, writes Martin Dove 
The fact that education comes down to strategic value indicates to me that the people who think about these things do not properly understand education (Plans for 50% funding cut to arts subjects at universities ‘catastrophic’, 6 May). It is obvious that, for some of the needs of society, we need strategic choices in education, because society…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is CSS a Programming Language?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339781</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-css-a-programming-language/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real distaste for this question. It might seem like a fun question to dig into on the surface, but the way it enters public discourse rarely seems to be in good faith. There are ulterior motives at &#8230;
The post Is CSS a Programming Language? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339574</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:54:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These are a few great links about typography that have been burning a hole in my saved bookmarks folder that I'm just now getting around to sharing. There's good stuff in there, from how to choose typefaces for app design to ideas for how to fix the concept of font sizing in CSS.
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day one: investigations, from WikiLeaks to Snowden

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you had a hair transplant during the pandemic?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/07/tell-us-have-you-had-a-hair-transplant-during-the-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/07/tell-us-have-you-had-a-hair-transplant-during-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T09:18:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from men about their hair transplant experiences and why they underwent the procedure
Hair transplants are booming in popularity and there are signs that demand has grown even faster during the pandemic, partly because people have been able to recover out of sight at home. We would like to hear from men about their hair transplant experiences.
What was the recovery like, physically and emotionally? How much did the procedure cost? Are you satisfied with the results? What would you say …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: guess the date of the Guardian article – week one]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-of-the-guardian-article</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-of-the-guardian-article"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T09:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pinpoint the date the story first appeared in the Guardian to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
Each of these six stories will be published on the Guardian website on successive Fridays, with t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noel Clarke accused of sexual harassment on Doctor Who set]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-accused-of-sexual-harassment-on-doctor-who-set</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-accused-of-sexual-harassment-on-doctor-who-set"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T09:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: BBC faces questions as further allegations made about Clarke – and co-star John Barrowman is accused of exposing himself 
The Noel Clarke sexual harassment controversy threatens to embroil the BBC after several sources came forward to allege they were sexually harassed or inappropriately touched by the actor on a flagship show, Doctor Who.
Another Doctor Who actor, John Barrowman, has also been accused of repeatedly exposing himself to co-workers on two BBC productions, prompting questions about …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale and Lucy Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The young people taking their countries to court over climate inaction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/07/the-young-people-taking-their-countries-to-court-over-climate-inaction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/07/the-young-people-taking-their-countries-to-court-over-climate-inaction"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T08:21:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Children and young adults around the world are demanding action from governments on global heating and the ecological crisis
Sofia Oliveira is one of six young Portuguese people who have filed a lawsuit against 33 countries with the European court of human rights, demanding that governments do more to reduce emissions and safeguard their future physical and mental wellbeing. Last October the Strasbourg-based court granted the case priority status.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Taylor, Emily Holden, Dan Collyns, Michael Standaert and Ashifa Kassam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we got wrong: the Guardian’s worst errors of judgment over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-what-we-got-wrong-the-guardians-worst-errors-of-judgment-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-what-we-got-wrong-the-guardians-worst-errors-of-judgment-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T06:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fiercely critical of Abraham Lincoln and at times racist, this newspaper’s leader columns did not always get it right

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber

A daily newspaper cannot publish for 200 years without getting some things wrong. This one has made its share of mistakes.
There will always be errors of news judgment given the nature of the work. Tight deadlines meant the sinking of the Titanic was relegated to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Randeep Ramesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuba during the pandemic – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/07/cuba-during-the-pandemic-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/07/cuba-during-the-pandemic-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T06:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Leysis Quesada Vera describes life during the pandemic in Havana’s Los Sitios neighbourhood. Her work is supported and produced by the Magnum Foundation, with a grant from the Henry Luce Foundation. Magnum Foundation is a nonprofit organisation that expands creativity and diversity in documentary photography. Through grant making and mentorship, Magnum Foundation supports a global network of social justice and human rights-focused photographers and experiments with new models for storytelling

…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruaridh Nicoll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I Email…]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339822</id>
        <link href="https://www.caniemail.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:38:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m 85% certain you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Use&#8230;, I bet there is only a 13% chance that you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Email&#8230;. It&#8217;s the same vibe—detailed support information for web platform features—except instead &#8230;
The post Can I Email&#8230; appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noel Clarke and the allegations that have shaken the film and television industry – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalists Lucy Osborne and Sirin Kale discuss the allegations of verbal abuse, bullying and sexual harassment by 20 women against Clarke
On 10 April 2021, the actor, director and writer Noel Clarke was awarded one of the most prestigious accolades bestowed by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts, the prize for outstanding British contribution to cinema. But 13 days before presenting Clarke with his award, Bafta was informed about the existence of several allegations of verbal abuse, bullying an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Lucy Osborne, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is &quot;Lifting State Up&quot; in React?]]></title>
        <id>609409c201fc34080ef81f97</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-lifting-state-up-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T21:41:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a simple and practical example what it means to "lift state up" in React, and how it can help you build your applications. Lifting state up is a common pattern that is essential for React developers to know. It helps you avoid more complex (and often unnecessary) patterns]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340015</id>
        <link href="https://betterprogramming.pub/apparently-you-can-use-route53-as-a-blazingly-fast-database-dd416b56b005"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T20:03:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Route53 is DNS management service by AWS. DNS is absolutely not a database, and yet here&#8217;s Nicholas Martin writing up some very clever trickery originally done by Corey Quinn:
When you think about it, DNS configuration is actually a 
&#8230;
The post Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339936</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-googles-new-page-experience-update-means-for-images-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T19:57:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to forget that, as a search engine, Google doesn’t just compare keywords to generate search results. Google knows that if people don’t enjoy their experience on a web page, they won’t stay on the page long enough to &#8230;
The post What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Use the Chrome DevTools to Troubleshoot Websites]]></title>
        <id>609415eb2cd0545b5e943534</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-how-to-use-the-chrome-devtools-to-troubleshoot-websites/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome DevTools is a set of web developer tools built directly into the Google Chrome browser. They can be super helpful for web developers. We just published a crash course that will teach you how to use Chrome DevTools to improve your productivity as a web developer. You will learn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optional Types in Swift – How to Use and Unwrap Optionals]]></title>
        <id>60939bde01fc34080ef81a19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/optional-types-in-swift/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're coming from Java, C++, or other object-oriented languages, chances are that you've never come across optional types or "optionals". And you might be quite surprised to know that such a concept exists in Swift. Optionals are a fundamental topic that you need to thoroughly understand to code in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using hydrogen fuel risks locking in reliance on fossil fuels, researchers warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/06/hydrogen-fuel-risks-reliance-on-fossil-fuels</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/06/hydrogen-fuel-risks-reliance-on-fossil-fuels"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T15:14:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Electrification of cars and home boilers best choice to fight the climate crisis, say scientists
Using hydrogen-based fuels for cars and home heating risks locking in a dependency on fossil fuels and failing to tackle the climate crisis, according to a new analysis.
Fuels produced from hydrogen can be used as straight replacements for oil and gas and can be low-carbon, if renewable electricity is used to produce these “e-fuels”. However, the research found that using the electricity directly to power cars a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339586</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-state-pseudo-classes-in-chrome/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T14:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is an increasing number of “custom” features on the web platform. We have custom properties (--my-property), custom elements (&#60;my-element&#62;), and custom events (new CustomEvent('myEvent')). At one point, we might even get custom media &#8230;
The post Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Šime Vidas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[English seaside resorts coming out of lockdown – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/06/english-seaside-resorts-coming-out-of-lockdown-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/06/english-seaside-resorts-coming-out-of-lockdown-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T12:41:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Andy Hall visited Southend, Margate, Broadstairs, Bournemouth and Whitstable over Easter and May bank holidays to take a look at the ‘new normal’
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Germany to bring forward climate goals after constitutional court ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/06/germany-to-bring-forward-climate-goals-net-zero-after-constitutional-court-ruling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/06/germany-to-bring-forward-climate-goals-net-zero-after-constitutional-court-ruling"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:48:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government proposes net zero deadline of 2045 instead of 2050, but critics demand actions not numbers
Germany’s government is to revise its emission reduction targets after the country’s constitutional court declared the current climate protection measures insufficient, aiming to become greenhouse gas neutral by 2045 rather than 2050.
The finance minister, Olaf Scholz, and the environment minister, Svenja Schulze, laid out a legislative proposal on Wednesday to cut emissions by 65% from 1990 levels by 2030.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann and Fiona Harvey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how have you been affected by the fishing row in Jersey?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/06/tell-us-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-fishing-row-in-jersey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/06/tell-us-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-fishing-row-in-jersey"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T09:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Jersey about how they feel about the situation. Share your views and experiences
Around 80 French boats have been met by two British naval patrol boats off the coast of Jersey, as French fishers protest over post-Brexit fishing rights.
The French boats gathered at the port in St Helier and are protesting over new licences that restrict the number of days they can operate in shared waters for the first time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Jewish parents used Guardian ads to save their children’s lives - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/06/how-jewish-parents-used-guardian-ads-to-save-their-childrens-lives-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/06/how-jewish-parents-used-guardian-ads-to-save-their-childrens-lives-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T02:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This month is 200 years since the Guardian was first established in Manchester. For the Guardian’s world affairs editor, Julian Borger, a part of that history is deeply personal. In 1938, there was a surge of classified ads in the Guardian as parents – including his grandparents – scrambled to get their children out of the Reich. What became of the families?
On Wednesday 3 August 1938, a short advertisement appeared on the second page of the Manchester Guardian, under the title “Tuition”. 
“I seek a kind pe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Julian Borger, Ruthie Elkana and Danny Segal, produced by Courtney Yusuf, Elizabeth Cassin and  Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astro]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339563</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/astro/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:49:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t even look at code or documentation for Astro (publicly) yet — it&#8217;s an in-progress idea — but you can watch a video of Fred showing it off to Feross. 
I gotta admit: it looks awesome. I&#8217;m bullish &#8230;
The post Astro appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python and OpenCV Course –Create Computer Vision Apps in the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>609307e801fc34080ef8191e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-computer-vision-apps-in-the-cloud-with-opencv-and-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:11:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a library of programming functions mainly aimed at real-time computer vision.  We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to use OpenCV in the cloud with Python. Misbah Mohammed created this course. He has a lot of experience with machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339954</id>
        <link href="https://infrequently.org/2021/04/progress-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T16:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The bombshell article of the week is from Alex Russell of Google/Chrome. Alex has long been super critical of Apple, particularly about how there is literally no option to run any other browser than Safari on iOS. This article isn&#8217;t &#8230;
The post Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Vendor Prefixing Dead?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339518</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-vendor-prefixing-dead/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T14:18:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let‘s take a quick stroll down memory-lane to revisit how vendor prefixing CSS properties came to be. I hope I don’t trigger PTSD for anyone!
It‘s not clear who started prefixing, or when it began exactly. What is clear, is &#8230;
The post Is Vendor Prefixing Dead? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob O'Leary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The fight for Hartlepool – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/05/the-fight-for-hartlepool-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/05/the-fight-for-hartlepool-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hartlepool has sent a Labour MP to parliament in every election since 1964. But as old allegiances fray, Anushka Asthana looks back at how this previously thriving shipbuilding town has lost out over successive governments and wonders if the ‘red wall’ seat could be about to go blue at tomorrow’s byelection
During the 2019 election campaign the formerly safe Labour seat of Hartlepool became the focus of a three-way fight. The Conservatives, who swept away much of Labour’s ‘red wall’ on election day, did not…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana; produced by Joshua Kelly and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339455</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/16px-or-larger-text-prevents-ios-form-zoom/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:16:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a great &#8220;Today I Learned&#8221; for me from Josh W. Comeau. If the font-size of an &#60;input&#62; is 16px or larger, Safari on iOS will focus into the input normally. But as soon as the font-size is &#8230;
The post 16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339867</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-backup-roll-back-your-woocommerce-site-without-losing-orders/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:15:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a dilemma: what happens if your WooCommerce site has a problem and the quickest and best way to fix it is to roll back to a previous version? The dilemma is, if you roll back the database, you would &#8230;
The post Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Async Await Tutorial – With Asynchronous JavaScript Examples]]></title>
        <id>609011fd8eb3fb07cf09a034</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-js-async-await-tutorial-with-asynchronous-javascript-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A complete guide to Node.js async await]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy a Directory in Linux – How to cp a Folder in the Command Line in Linux and Unix (MacOS)]]></title>
        <id>608f5ad48eb3fb07cf099ddb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/copy-a-directory-in-linux-how-to-cp-a-folder-in-the-command-line-in-linux-and-unix-macos/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To copy files or directories in Unix-based operating systems (Linux and MacOS), you use the cp command. The cp command is a relatively simple command, but its behavior changes slightly depending on the inputs (files vs directories) and the options you pass to it. To view the documentation or manual]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339449</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/lets-use-x-x-x-x-for-talking-about-specificity/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was just chatting with Eric Meyer the other day and I remembered an Eric Meyer story from my formative years. I wrote a blog post about CSS specificity, and Eric took the time to point out the misleading nature &#8230;
The post Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Colorful, Smart Shadows]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339742</id>
        <link href="https://www.kirupa.com/html5/creating_colorful_smart_shadows.htm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bona fide CSS trick from Kirupa Chinnathambi here. To match a colored shadow with the colors in the background-image of an element, you inherit the background in a pseudo-element, kick it behind the original, then blur and filter it. &#8230;
The post Creating Colorful, Smart Shadows appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United fans: what do you plan to do next?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/04/manchester-united-fans-plan-next-protests-glazers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/04/manchester-united-fans-plan-next-protests-glazers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T11:25:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from fans about their protests against the Glazers and how they want the club to change
Manchester United fans have wanted the club’s owners, the Glazer family, to sell up for years. The club’s recent attempt to join the European Super League has given fans fresh momentum in their bid to drive the owners out of the club. Hundreds of supporters joined a protest against the Glazers on Sunday, forcing United’s match against Liverpool to be postponed.
Yet, despite the strength of oppositio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 8: CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339419</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/chapter-8-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T21:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In June of 2006, web developers and designers from around the world came to London for the second annual @media conference. The first had been a huge success, and @media 2006 had even more promise. Its speaker lineup was pulled &#8230;
The post Chapter 8: CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Hoffmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Fetch Data in React from a GraphQL API]]></title>
        <id>6090187c8eb3fb07cf09a060</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/5-ways-to-fetch-data-react-graphql/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T17:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go through the five best ways that you can fetch data with React from a GraphQL API. While there are a couple of popular libraries which are made to interact with GraphQL APIs from a React application, there are many different ways to fetch data with GraphQL. I've included]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Mistakes React Developers Make – And How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>608f553c8eb3fb07cf099da7</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/common-mistakes-react-developers-make-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T16:40:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we'll see some of the common mistakes that React developers make, and how you can avoid them. So let's get started. Don't Forget that Every Route Change Mounts and Unmounts a ComponentWhenever you're using routing in a React application, you declare routes inside the Switch component. This]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swipey Image Grids]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339384</id>
        <link href="https://www.cassie.codes/posts/swipey-image-grids/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T14:35:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope people think of SVG as a vector format that is good for drawing things. There is plenty more to know, but here&#8217;s one more: SVG is good for composition. You draw things at very specific coordinates &#8230;
The post Swipey Image Grids appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums&nbsp;


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heroin to Holyrood? Man behind 'illegal' drug van runs for Scottish parliament – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Krykant, who operates a van in Glasgow where people can safely take illegal drugs, is running for Holyrood as part of a campaign calling for the Scottish government to establish legal sites.&nbsp;
A former&nbsp;heroin&nbsp;addict, he is pushing for drug reform in Scotland, which has a reported drug deaths rate 15 times higher than the European average. "People are dying out there,' says Krykant, who is able to treat addicts who overdose in his van. Could interventions such as his change Scotland's sta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Cherry, Maeve Shearlaw and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early &mdash; when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[George Floyd: a landmark moment for justice in America? – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/apr/22/george-floyd-a-landmark-moment-for-justice-in-america-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/apr/22/george-floyd-a-landmark-moment-for-justice-in-america-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T11:28:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The murder trial of Derek Chauvin drew the attention of the world to Minneapolis, the focal point of the Black Lives Matter movement after the murder of George Floyd. In some parts of the city people have reclaimed the streets, while others are under military occupation. With the area reeling from yet another recent police killing, Oliver Laughland and Tom Silverstone spent time with activists, lawyers, witnesses and members of the Floyd family to see how this landmark moment in American racial justice is s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland, Tom Silverstone, Amudalat Ajasa, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the UK government sidestepped the data on coronavirus – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T11:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This time last year, NHS bosses asked doctors and nurses to ‘wear aprons’ and&nbsp;work without protective full-length gowns&nbsp;when treating Covid-19 patients, as hospitals were within hours of running out of supplies.
This is just one example of how the UK government has been slammed for its handling of the pandemic, through a series of missteps, U-turns, lockdowns, denials – and more than 150,000 deaths.
Twelve months on, the Guardian's Pamela Duncan looks at three major areas where officials were out …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Duncan, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Mistakes To Avoid In Your Technical Interviews]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the technical interview process leaves something to be desired; it’s often riddled with anxiety and stress. In this article, we’ll take a look at seven of the most common mistakes candidates make in their technical interviews and explore ways you can avoid them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Emma Bostian)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Get Web Design Clients Fast (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Selling is key to growing your web design business, but it doesn’t have to be complicated! With clear goals, customer research, and proven closing techniques, anyone can find new clients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephen Roe)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Cats With Love: New Navigation, Guides And Workshops]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Smashing, we’ve been busy over the last few months. We’ve set up new workshops, redesigned our navigation, refined performance and improved accessibility. There are subtle UX changes coming in, and we’d love to share what we’ve been cooking.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overflow Issues In CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-14T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we will explore the causes of overflow issues and how to solve them. We will also explore how modern features in the developer tools (DevTools) can make the process of fixing and debugging easier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ahmad Shadeed)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Video Streaming App With Nuxt.js, Node And Express]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be building a video streaming app using Nuxt.js and Node.js. Specifically, we’ll build a server-side Node.js app that will handle fetching and streaming videos, generating thumbnails for your videos, and serving captions and subtitles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Deven Rathore)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To HTML Email]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently we’ve covered CSS generators, SVG generators and accessible front-end components. This time we look into HTML email, with tools, templates and guides for designers and developers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growing UX Maturity In Organizations: Education And Training (Part 3)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/growing-ux-maturity-in-organizations-part-3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/growing-ux-maturity-in-organizations-part-3/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-09T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UX practitioners can play an important role in growing the UX maturity of the organizations and product teams they work with. This final article in a three-part series presents two additional tactics: education of staff on UX principles and processes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Victor Yocco)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>