<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-21T00:33:26.289Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-21T00:33:26.289Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Open final round: Rahm leads Oosthuizen in battle for trophy – live!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2021/jun/20/us-open-golf-2021-final-round-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2021/jun/20/us-open-golf-2021-final-round-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T00:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hole-by-hole updates from Torrey Pines
Check out the official US Open leaderboard
And you can email Scott with your thoughts

 1.23am BST 
Oosthuizen makes his birdie putt to end with a 71. Folk will probably wonder why he didn’t throw caution to the wind and go for the green with his second shot, but there it is. Yet another second-place finish at a major for the South African. Unlike 2015 at Chambers Bay, at least he’s got second to himself this time. Par meanwhile for Mackenzie Hughes, whose shoulders understandably sagged after his ball got stuck up a tree at 11. He signs for 77.
-6: Rahm
-5: Oosthuizen
-3: English
-2: Migliozzi, Koepka, Morikawa
-1: Grace, Berger, Casey, Schauffele, Scheffler, McIlroy
 1.19am BST 
Jon Rahm, US Open champion, is immediately interviewed by NBC! “I’m a big believer in karma. After what happened a couple of weeks ago, I stayed really positive, knowing big things were coming. I didn’t know what it was going to be, but I knew we were coming to a special place, I know I got my breakthrough win here, and it’s a very special place for my family. The fact my parents were able to come, I got out of Covid protocol early, I just felt like the stars were aligning. I can’t even believe I made the first two putts! This was definitely for Seve. I know he tried a lot, and wanted to win this one most of all. I just don’t know how to explain it! I don’t know why, but every time we land here, we are happy. We’re in our spot!”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nine children die in Alabama crash as tropical storm Claudette sweeps south]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/claudette-storm-life-threatening-flash-flooding-warnings-us-south-east</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/claudette-storm-life-threatening-flash-flooding-warnings-us-south-east"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten people died in 15-vehicle crash, including eight children from youth home, and two more people died when a tree fell on their house

Eight children travelling in a van from a home for abused or neglected children have been killed in a multi-vehicle crash that also killed a man and his baby in another vehicle as tropical depression Claudette claimed 13 lives in Alabama.
The crash happened on Saturday about 35 miles (55km) south of Montgomery and was likely caused by vehicles hydroplaning in very wet conditions, authorities said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weightlifter Laurel Hubbard will be first trans athlete to compete at Olympics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/olympics-tokyo-laurel-hubbard-trans-weightlifter-new-zealand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/olympics-tokyo-laurel-hubbard-trans-weightlifter-new-zealand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hubbard has been included in New Zealand’s weightlifting team
‘I am grateful and humbled,’ says 43-year-old in statement

The New Zealand weightlifter Laurel Hubbard is set to make history and headlines, plus an enormous amount of controversy, after being confirmed as the first transgender athlete to ever compete at the Olympic Games.
The 43-year-old will be a live medal contender when she competes in the
women’s super heavyweight category on 2 August. But Hubbard’s inclusion
will also frustrate those who believe she has an unfair advantage
over her rivals, having gone through male puberty before transitioning in
2012.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wales road trip goes on despite defeat in Rome – Euro 2020 Football Daily]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/21/wales-italy-switzerland-turkey-euro-2020-football-daily</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/21/wales-italy-switzerland-turkey-euro-2020-football-daily"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:11:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Rushden is joined by Nicky Bandini, Jamie Jackson, Barney Ronay, Ben Fisher and Manon Steffan Ros to discuss Wales reaching the last 16

We start by analysing Wales’ 1-0 defeat to Italy in Rome, which was good enough for them to qualify for the last 16 for the second consecutive European Championships. How far can Wales go? And are Italy in perfect shape to go all the way after three wins from three?

Next, we touch upon Switzerland’s 3-1 win over Turkey, which will probably see them through to the latter stages. We celebrate some lovely goals in Baku, and ponder again over why Turkey failed miserably to live up to expectations.
Finally, we chat to Barney Ronay about why England fans shouldn’t panic, and also laud Torquay’s goalkeeper for scoring a 95th equaliser in the National League play-off final. Sadly for him, the Gulls still lost the penalty shootout to Hartlepool.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Max Rushden with Nicky Bandini, Jamie Jackson, Ben Fisher, Barney Ronay and Manon Steffan Ros. Produced by Samuel James.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High stress may make ‘broken heart syndrome’ more likely, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/21/high-stress-may-make-broken-heart-syndrome-more-likely-takotsubo-cardiomyopathy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/21/high-stress-may-make-broken-heart-syndrome-more-likely-takotsubo-cardiomyopathy"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Condition also known as takotsubo cardiomyopathy is brought on by an acute emotional shock
Two molecules associated with high stress levels have been implicated in the development of broken heart syndrome, a condition that mainly affects post-menopausal women and is usually brought on by severe stress, such as the loss of a loved one.
The syndrome, formally known as takotsubo cardiomyopathy, is characterised by weakening of the heart’s main pumping chamber and was first identified in 1990 in Japan. It looks and sounds like a heart attack and is consequently often confused for one.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Civic life is under assault – theatres can play a vital role in restoring it | Dan Hutton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/21/theatre-change-civic-function-dan-hutton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/21/theatre-change-civic-function-dan-hutton"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drama instigates debate and changes lives. With venues open again, this is a chance to build a truly civic theatre culture
Theatre may not seem like a natural place to go in order to understand the forces of climate emergency, nationalism, financial upheaval and a deadly pandemic. In a world dominated by Netflix, Google, Facebook, Apple, Twitter and any number of other online platforms, the idea of using theatre to drive change and inform our political and public life may seem naive, even quaint.
But theatre offers something different: space. Physical, oxygen-filled space, occupied by living, breathing, thinking people. Space is our secret weapon, and the way in which theatre changes lives, cities, countries and continents. It is also, contrary to what Peter Brook espouses, never “empty” – rather, as Ngũgĩ wa Thiong’o has pointed out, it is “always the site of physical, social and psychic forces”. Which makes it welcoming, thick with stories and ripe for exploiting at a civic level.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Hutton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Team GB cyclists target winning ‘in the right way’ at Tokyo Olympics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/team-gb-cyclists-target-winning-in-the-right-way-at-tokyo-olympics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/team-gb-cyclists-target-winning-in-the-right-way-at-tokyo-olympics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British Cyling has ‘moved on’ after Richard Freeman case
Laura and Jason Kenny spearhead 26-strong squad

The British Cycling performance director, Stephen Park, has promised his riders will win “in the right way” at the Tokyo Olympics in the wake of the devastating guilty verdict against the former team doctor Richard Freeman this year.
Park also vowed that British Cycling had moved on from the old regime, under which Freeman was found to have purchased banned testosterone knowing it was to dope an unnamed rider, as he named a 26-strong squad for Tokyo.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[House asking prices hit record levels across Great Britain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/house-asking-prices-hit-record-levels-across-great-britain-covid-boom</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/house-asking-prices-hit-record-levels-across-great-britain-covid-boom"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rightmove data shows largest June increase since 2015 but economists suggest Covid boom may be fading

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

House asking prices have hit record levels across every region of Great Britain, according to latest figures, although some experts have questioned whether the pandemic boom is finally starting to wane.
The price of properties coming to market rose by 0.8% month on month in June to a third consecutive record of £336,073, according to data from Rightmove, a property listings website.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK reports 9,284 Covid cases on day before lockdown was due to end]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/uk-reports-9284-covid-cases-on-day-before-lockdown-was-due-to-end</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/uk-reports-9284-covid-cases-on-day-before-lockdown-was-due-to-end"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T23:01:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1m jabs booked on Friday and Saturday after all adults in England invited to get vaccine

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

More than 9,200 Covid cases were reported in the UK on Sunday, the day before it was originally planned that all remaining Covid restrictions in England would be lifted.
It came as figures revealed that more than 1m Covid jabs were booked in two days following the invitation on Friday for all adults in England to come forward for vaccination.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis and Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government ordered to release secret pandemic planning files]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/government-ordered-to-release-secret-pandemic-planning-files</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/government-ordered-to-release-secret-pandemic-planning-files"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T22:59:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whitehall had refused to publish documents from 2016 simulation exercise that warned health system would not cope

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Whitehall has been ordered to release confidential documents warning that the UK’s health system could not cope with a pandemic.
 Related: People in UK with both Covid jabs may not have to quarantine, says scientist 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Gilbody-Dickerson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Bracing minus 2C’: expeditioners in Antarctica mark winter solstice 2021 with icy polar plunge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/bracing-minus-2c-expeditioners-in-antarctica-mark-solstice-with-icy-polar-plunge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/bracing-minus-2c-expeditioners-in-antarctica-mark-solstice-with-icy-polar-plunge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T22:43:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Year’s shortest day and longest night celebrated in period when sun only appears for two and a half hours a day
Antarctic-based Australian expeditioners have taken a sub-zero polar plunge to mark the winter solstice, keeping an icy tradition alive.
Each year expeditioners at Australia’s three research stations in Antarctica and on sub-Antarctic Macquarie Island celebrate the year’s shortest day and longest night by taking a dip in sea ice or the ocean.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Australian Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea change: Prada show celebrates post-Covid re-emergence at the beach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/20/sea-change-prada-show-celebrates-post-covid-re-emergence-at-the-beach</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/20/sea-change-prada-show-celebrates-post-covid-re-emergence-at-the-beach"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T22:13:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A sunkissed Sardinian shore replaced the runway for the Italian fashion house’s spring/summer menswear show
For a brand known for its angular, urban and emotionless aesthetic, it’s quite something to see a Prada show take place on a joyful, life enhancing beach.
And yet, here we are for the brand’s spring/summer 2022 show. The latest collection from fashion dream team Raf Simons and Miuccia Prada sees models leaving the suffocating confines of a tunnel-like underground club-cum-runway lit in devilish red, for the aquamarine shores of a heavenly, sunkissed Sardinian beach.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Patrick Vallance handed tech role to build on vaccine success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/sir-patrick-vallance-national-technology-adviser</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/sir-patrick-vallance-national-technology-adviser"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T21:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chief scientific adviser will head new government body looking at big bets in science and technology
The government’s chief scientific adviser, Sir Patrick Vallance, has been asked by Boris Johnson to investigate whether the UK’s successful vaccine procurement programme can be replicated in other areas of technology.
Vallance, who has become a household name following his appearances at coronavirus press conferences, will take on the new title of national technology adviser, serving alongside his current roles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raheem Sterling shuts out the noise and takes positives from Southgate | David Hytner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/euro-2020-england-raheem-sterling-gareth-southgate-scotland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/euro-2020-england-raheem-sterling-gareth-southgate-scotland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T21:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winger says post-Scotland criticism is ‘an overreaction’ and insists the mood inside the England camp is relaxed
Amid the doom-mongering, a note of perspective. Actually, a few of them, mainly from Raheem Sterling, the England squad’s most experienced player with 63 caps, but one via him from Gareth Southgate, too.
Sterling does not run from the disappointment of last Friday’s 0-0 draw with Scotland in the second set of Euro 2020 group-phase ties. He knows that the team’s use of the ball was poor, they did not embrace the occasion correctly. But the Manchester City winger also knows that, when last Sunday’s 1-0 win over Croatia is factored in, England remain well set to advance and they are even in a better position at this stage of the competition than previous winners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Handmaid’s Tale season four review – hope at last in the most harrowing show on TV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/20/the-handmaids-tale-season-four-review-hope-at-last-in-the-most-harrowing-show-on-tv</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/20/the-handmaids-tale-season-four-review-hope-at-last-in-the-most-harrowing-show-on-tv"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T21:10:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elisabeth Moss has always made this impressive if horrifying TV. But as the new series turns June into queen of the rebels, it has a shot of new life
I am not sure if “enjoyment” is quite the right word in relation to watching The Handmaid’s Tale (Channel 4). It has been, at various points over the last three seasons, either a harrowing slog or an extremely harrowing slog. But at its best, it is impressive, inventive drama that pushes unfamiliar buttons with great skill. It had a magnificent, haunting first season, which largely stuck to the plot of Margaret Atwood’s classic novel, but afterwards it struggled under the weight of its own misery. June (Elisabeth Moss) escaped from Gilead, and was captured, ad infinitum, which made it feel like a gruesome hall of mirrors in which hope was pointless. It made me wonder whether continuing to watch was pointless, too. But a diversion into global politics gave it a shot of new life, and season four continues to explore new ground. It needed it, and it works.
The lengthy recap at the beginning is useful, given that the pandemic delayed production. According to its showrunner, Bruce Miller, the logistics of shooting in Canada also had a direct effect on shaping the story. June organised a cohort of rebels, pulling together an underground network of Marthas and Handmaids, to smuggle 86 children out of Gilead, saving them from life under a brutal regime. The Waterfords have been arrested by the Canadian government and are in captivity, but at the end of season three, it looked as though June may have run out of luck. Still, without her, this is Handmaids’ Tales, rather than The Handmaid’s Tale. If the question is, how much more can one woman endure, then the answer comes quickly: using no anaesthetic, Janine cauterises the shotgun wound in June’s abdomen with a red-hot poker. Welcome to season four.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Democrats’ domestic agenda faces setbacks by Republican obstructionism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/biden-domestic-agenda-setbacks-republican-obstruction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/biden-domestic-agenda-setbacks-republican-obstruction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T20:06:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Key issues such as election reform and voting rights, and efforts to curb gun control have seen Republican push back
Joe Biden’s far-reaching domestic agenda in the US is facing serious setbacks on a range of issues as the political quagmire of a tightly contested Senate is seeing Democratic ambitions sharply curtailed in the face of Republican obstruction.
On a number of key fronts such as pushing election reform and voting rights, efforts to curb gun control and to moving forwards on LGBTQ civil rights, there has been an effective push back by Republicans – and a handful of conservative Democrats – that is forcing Biden and the wider Democratic party on to the back foot.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joachim Löw’s Germany recast as Euro 2020’s popular entertainers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/joachim-lows-germany-recast-as-euro-2020s-popular-entertainers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/joachim-lows-germany-recast-as-euro-2020s-popular-entertainers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T20:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The current side have shed their long-held reputation for sober reliability to become the fun team of the tournament
“The tournament can begin,” as Toni Kroos drily observed. And certainly after the disappointment against France on Tuesday night it was impossible to watch Germany’s breezy, brassy win over Portugal on Saturday without wondering whether it might just be the start of something: a stirring, an awakening, a team and a system and perhaps even an idea twitching belatedly to life.
As the goals piled up, as Germany’s flying wing-backs sliced and shredded the defending champions – Rúben Dias, Pepe and all – on their way to a 4-2 triumph, the temptation was to declare that this was a film we had all seen before. Right on cue, and with perfect timing, The Germans (and for some reason it always is The Germans, never just Germany) have finally turned up. The Germans are coming. Never, ever write off The Germans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Velvety Verratti adds a sprinkling of magic to make Italy the team to fear | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/20/verratti-magic-italy-wales</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/20/verratti-magic-italy-wales"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T19:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Returning midfielder added A-list class to the tournament’s standout team as they secured top spot against Wales
Well, that was tense. Kind of. On a gruelling afternoon in Rome Wales qualified for the last 16 of Euro 2020. Thanks to the vagaries of the format they did so through a shifting fog of almost-drama, a whirl of semi-excitement, as Group A did its best to conjure some genuine final-round tension out of Uefa’s self-own of a 24-team Euros.
Not that anyone in red cared. It is now two out of two for Wales: two European Championships and two knockout-stage runs, a wonderful achievement for this high-craft, brilliantly likable generation of players and for the caretaker manager, Robert Page.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers urge Boris Johnson to consult cabinet on key decisions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/ministers-urge-boris-johnson-to-consult-cabinet-on-key-decisions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/ministers-urge-boris-johnson-to-consult-cabinet-on-key-decisions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T19:18:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embattled prime minister pressed to abandon top-down approach to government as difficult autumn nears
Cabinet ministers including Rishi Sunak will this week urge Boris Johnson not to keep sidelining his ministers, as officials warn of a difficult autumn ahead with pressures over hospital waiting lists, social care reform and court backlogs.
Johnson will face a tricky few days after the landslide loss in the byelection in Chesham and Amersham, a defeat that many of his own MPs put down to his controversial planning changes and which Labour will seek to exploit in a debate and vote on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Florida Pride parade crash that killed one appears unintentional, officials say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/florida-pride-parade-crash-unintentional-accident</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/florida-pride-parade-crash-unintentional-accident"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T19:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Statement clarified initial speculation that it was a hate crime directed at the gay community
A member of a men’s chorus group unintentionally slammed into fellow chorists at the start of a Pride parade in South Florida, killing one member of the group and seriously injuring another, the group’s director said Sunday.
The statement clarified initial speculation that it was a hate crime directed at the gay community.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Slap in the face’ for Macron as French voters shun local elections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/slap-in-the-face-for-macron-as-french-voters-shun-local-elections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/slap-in-the-face-for-macron-as-french-voters-shun-local-elections"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T19:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstention rate estimated at 68%, and exit polls suggest Le Pen’s National Rally failed to get expected support
Emmanuel Macron’s centrist party received what one of its own MPs called a “slap in the face” in regional and department elections on Sunday.
The president and his government failed to mobilise supporters, with an estimated 68% of voters shunning the polling stations – an unprecedented rate of abstention. If there was any consolation for the ruling party it was that exit polls suggested Marine Le Pen’s far-right National Rally had failed to garner its expected support.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on Bolsonaro’s handling of the Covid pandemic in Brazil– cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/20/ben-jennings-on-bolsonaros-handling-of-the-covid-pandemic-in-brazil-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/20/ben-jennings-on-bolsonaros-handling-of-the-covid-pandemic-in-brazil-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T19:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kyle Jamieson stands tall as New Zealand gain WTC final edge over India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/india-new-zealand-world-test-championship-final-day-three-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/india-new-zealand-world-test-championship-final-day-three-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T18:48:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WTC final, day three: India 217 all out, New Zealand 101-2
Jamieson takes five for 31 in immaculate bowling display

The sounds of the Bharat Army’s drummers rung around the Ageas Bowl on the third day of the World Test Championship final and in the end this energy finally told, India striking moments before bad light ended proceedings at 6.27pm to peg back New Zealand’s march towards a position of strength.
It was Ishant Sharma, the old warhorse of Virat Kohli’s attack, who claimed this precious breakthrough. Devon Conway had become the first batsman to register a half-century in what is proving a low-scoring affair, only to chip a ball on his pads to mid-on and terminate an otherwise resolute 54 from 153 balls.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin at the Ageas Bowl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saracens take no prisoners to seal escape from Championship purgatory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/saracens-championship-ealing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/saracens-championship-ealing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T18:20:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark McCall’s men beat Ealing in final by an aggregate score of 117-15 in a warning shot to next season’s Premiership rivals
With just less than half an hour left of the second leg of the Championship final, and with an aggregate lead of more than 80 points, the Saracens director of rugby, Mark McCall, saw fit to haul off his five British & Irish Lions. If it was good news for Warren Gatland, it was anything but for Ealing Trailfinders.
Saracens added another four tries without their star names on the field to rubber-stamp their return to the Premiership with another drubbing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher at StoneX Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matteo Pessina ensures Italy top group but 10-man Wales go through in second]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/italy-wales-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/20/italy-wales-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T18:01:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half an hour before kick-off, when the team sheets were read aloud for the first time, the loudest Roman roar was reserved for the Italy manager, Roberto Mancini. On the front of Gazzetta dello Sport’s pullout last week, Mancini was mocked up in the dugout alongside Albert Einstein but a third successive victory, which extended their unbeaten run to a record-equalling 30 matches, required little genius. In fact, they barely broke sweat on a muggy evening on which Matteo Pessina scored the only goal to beat Wales.
Wales, who had Ethan Ampadu sent off 10 minutes into the second half, became their latest victims but Italy’s failure to press home their one-man advantage ensured Robert Page’s side will qualify from Group A in second place, teeing up a last-16 date in Amsterdam on Saturday. Italy’s supporters enjoyed themselves and by the end there was a carnival atmosphere as a Mexican wave made its way around this cavernous stadium. It was an outcome that suited both teams, even if Ampadu’s red card will rankle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at Olimpico in Rome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morrisons’ rejection of £5.5bn offer may spark bidding war for grocer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/morrisons-rejection-of-55bn-offer-may-spark-bidding-war-for-grocer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/morrisons-rejection-of-55bn-offer-may-spark-bidding-war-for-grocer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:53:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move also raises concerns that private equity could buy up other UK supermarket groups

An unsolicited £5.5bn private equity bid for Morrisons, swiftly rejected by the supermarket chain, could spark a bidding war for Britain’s fourth biggest grocer and has raised concerns that other supermarket groups could be sold off to private equity.
On Saturday night Morrisons said it had rebuffed a preliminary takeover bid worth just over £5.5bn from the US firm Clayton, Dubilier & Rice (CD&R), which had offered to pay 230p a share in cash. Morrisons’ share price closed at 178.45p on Friday, valuing the company at £4.3bn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reading terror attack victims remembered at memorial one year on]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/reading-terror-attack-victims-remembered-at-one-year-memorial</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/reading-terror-attack-victims-remembered-at-one-year-memorial"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:46:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Families and friends share memories of three men killed in Forbury Gardens last June
Family and friends of the three men killed in a terror attack in Reading have told of their heartache at a memorial service.
James Furlong, a 36-year-old history teacher, Dr David Wails, a 49-year-old scientist, and Joseph Ritchie-Bennett, 39, who worked for a pharmaceutical company, were murdered in Forbury Gardens on 20 June last year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Max Verstappen triumphs in pulsating duel with Lewis Hamilton at French GP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/f1-max-verstappen-lewis-hamilton-french-grand-prix</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/20/f1-max-verstappen-lewis-hamilton-french-grand-prix"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:42:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Bull driver hunts down rival to overtake in penultimate lap
Sergio Pérez completes podium with Bottas fourth

The French Grand Prix for once was the stuff of great saga, a titanic struggle that had it all as the two top teams and their two best drivers locked horns across the full race distance at Paul Ricard. Max Verstappen and Red Bull came out on top but only after a race that ebbed and flowed and could not be called until Verstappen passed Lewis Hamilton’s Mercedes for the lead on the penultimate lap.
A closely fought affair, both drivers’ skills were gloriously displayed as were the roles of their colleagues in the pits. This time it was Red Bull’s engineers who held the advantage, landing a striking blow on several levels. Verstappen now has a 12-point lead over Hamilton in the championship and with Sergio Pérez also taking third from Valtteri Bottas in fourth, his team a 37-point advantage over Mercedes in the constructors’.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards at Paul Ricard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Mummy: Brendan Fraser and Rachel Weisz’s adventurous romp catches lightning in an urn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/the-mummy-brendan-fraser-and-rachel-weiszs-adventurous-romp-catches-lightning-in-an-urn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/the-mummy-brendan-fraser-and-rachel-weiszs-adventurous-romp-catches-lightning-in-an-urn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tightly written and perfectly cast, this goofy late-90s horror-comedy about an Egyptian curse is the perfect comfort watch
• The Mummy, The Mummy Returns, and The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor are streaming in Australia on Stan. For more recommendations of what to stream in Australia, click here
I love The Mummy. In a pinch, I’m pretty sure I could close my eyes, clear my mind and play the entire movie in my head from start to finish. I’ve watched it that many times. 
It started when I was 10, when my family all crowded into my grandfather’s apartment to watch the then new-ish movie on VCD. There were murders, dead bodies coming back to life, and a monster that could command sand into a huge version of its own face, big enough to swallow a plane! It was absolutely terrifying. I couldn’t wait to watch it again, and it’s been basically playing on loop, in the background of my life, ever since.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Flux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All in all, is Chesham and Amersham just another brick in the ‘blue wall’? | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/all-in-all-is-chesham-and-amersham-just-another-brick-in-the-blue-wall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/all-in-all-is-chesham-and-amersham-just-another-brick-in-the-blue-wall"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:28:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pete Dorey thinks the middle class feel increasingly alienated, betrayed and frightened, while Andrew Grant-Adamson believes anti-government votes are consolidating behind the candidate most likely to win. Plus letters from Jeremy Beecham, Stephen Jakobi, Derek Schofield, Daniel Scharf and John Whitfield
Although there have previously been remarkable Liberal and Lib Dem byelection victories that failed to lead to a longer-term challenge to the Conservatives, the Chesham and Amersham byelection might still herald a weakening of middle-class support for the Conservative party, and a crumbling of the “blue wall” (Senior Tories warn Boris Johnson ‘blue wall’ is at risk after byelection defeat, 19 June).
Increasing sections of the middle class are suffering the downsides to free-market capitalism and corporate power, which the working class have always suffered: stagnant earnings or pay cuts, while their employers and shareholders get obscenely richer every year; loss of creativity or flexibility in the workplace due to micro- or macho-management and top-down performance targets; increasing job insecurity due to fixed-term contracts and repeated redundancies (the precariat); longer or more unsocial working hours, so less time with family, friends or engaging in community activities; constant attacks on “unaffordable” occupational pensions; up to £50,000 of debt for a university education, which until relatively recently was free; unaffordable housing or exorbitant rents for their young adult offspring; and the need to sell the family home to pay for nursing home fees in old age – so no inheritance for their children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If football and cricket fans are allowed to sing, why can’t choirs? | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/if-football-and-cricket-fans-are-allowed-to-sing-why-cant-choirs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/if-football-and-cricket-fans-are-allowed-to-sing-why-cant-choirs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:25:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Robinson, Paul Hill and Ian Wells on the continuing restrictions on choral singing under coronavirus regulations
Our small local choir was working hard towards a performance of Vivaldi’s Gloria for Easter 2020 when the pandemic struck. We immediately shut up shop, and have continued to follow government guidelines as to possible resumption dates, now postponed by a further four weeks (PM announces four-week delay to Covid lockdown easing in England, 14 June). Since March 2020, not a note have we sung.
We are an ageing choir and many members will not return when we do resume. The choir may be unviable by the time singing is allowed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Sunak’s spending: time to rip up the March budget | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/the-guardian-view-on-sunaks-spending-time-to-rip-up-the-march-budget</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/the-guardian-view-on-sunaks-spending-time-to-rip-up-the-march-budget"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:23:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The idea that the country could spend less on key frontline services than what was planned before the pandemic needs to be discarded
Last week the chancellor, Rishi Sunak, claimed in a TV interview that the government cash being spent to keep the economy running during the pandemic was not his money to spend but the viewers’ money. The subtext was that Covid-19 bills would have to be paid for. Mr Sunak was channelling his inner Margaret Thatcher, who in 1983 told her party conference that there is “no such thing as public money; there is only taxpayers’ money”. It is rhetoric frequently used by those who wish to suggest that the government faces the same budget constraints as a household. It is also economically illiterate.
The UK is not going to run out of money. The Bank of England is financing Covid spending by buying up huge amounts of Treasury debt under quantitative easing. Lord Turner of Ecchinswell, a former City regulator, told peers earlier this year that QE “is lubricating a fiscal expansion and making it easy for the government to run large fiscal deficits without the danger of setting a rise in interest rates”. We are living in an era of cheap money. Boris Johnson’s apparent repudiation of his own party’s austerity policies cannot be squared with real-terms cuts to some department budgets. The Treasury remains committed to balancing the books in mean-spirited ways: whether it is paying nurses a miserly 1% extra or cutting aid to the poverty-stricken parts of the globe. However demotic the slogans used by Mr Johnson, his words all too often betray the party’s real instincts. While Mr Sunak won’t find the cash to pay for catch-up lessons, his boss praises rich parents who buy private tuition because they “work hard”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on famine in Ethiopia: food must not be a weapon | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/the-guardian-view-on-famine-in-ethiopia-food-must-not-be-a-weapon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/the-guardian-view-on-famine-in-ethiopia-food-must-not-be-a-weapon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:22:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People are starving in the Tigray region. The culprit is the devastating war
In the early 1980s, as a terrible famine claimed between 400,000 and 1 million lives in Ethiopia, the international community responded to what was widely misunderstood and misreported as a natural disaster. Famines are never just a matter of drought. Human Rights Watch later noted that Ethiopia’s repeated crises – especially the devastating one of 1983-85 – “were in large part created by government policies, especially counter-insurgency strategies”. Tigray was “the very nadir of the famine”, as a destructive army offensive was accompanied by the deliberate blocking of aid.
Now famine has reached Tigray again – and once more, it is because an Ethiopian government is at war with the Tigray People’s Liberation Front. The federal government wants to celebrate the beginning of twice-delayed parliamentary elections on Monday, portraying them as the advent of democracy. But the polls are overshadowed by questions over electoral conditions and multiple crises, most of all in Tigray (where there will be no voting). Over 350,000 people in the region are in famine conditions, and 2 million more are on the brink – more than a third of the region’s population. They include 33,000 children at imminent risk of death.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Download Pilot review – a joyful noise for fans and bands]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/download-pilot-review-donington-park-rock-metal-festival-test-event</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/download-pilot-review-donington-park-rock-metal-festival-test-event"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:09:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Donington Park, Leicestershire 
Exuberant scenes at the rock and metal festival test event find its 10,000 guinea pigs leaving Covid blues far behind
When was the last time rock’n’roll felt this important? With the world starved of concerts, all eyes are on Download Pilot to roadmap the future of live music post-Covid. Granted, the three days are a shell of the festival’s usual fare; only 10,000 – one-11th of Donington Park capacity – descended upon a shrunken site this year, with the number of stages halved to two.
However, within the arena itself, the normality feels overwhelming. Masks and social distancing have been rendered archaic – every attendee has submitted proof of a negative lateral flow test – replaced by a hunger for heaviness that pervades the air every year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Mills</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End ‘snobbery’ over degrees in civil service recruitment, says Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/end-snobbery-over-degrees-in-civil-service-recruitment-says-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/end-snobbery-over-degrees-in-civil-service-recruitment-says-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T17:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Rayner says academic awards should only be considered where directly related to the post
Labour has said the government should end the consideration of academic qualifications for civil service jobs apart from where directly related to the post, to end the “snobbery” over degrees.
Labour’s deputy leader, Angela Rayner, said degrees and A-levels should only be taken into account where they are a genuine occupational requirement, such as science qualifications.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raisi’s election victory raises difficulties as Iran nuclear deal talks resume]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/iran-nuclear-deal-talks-resume-after-ebrahim-raisi-election-as-president</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/iran-nuclear-deal-talks-resume-after-ebrahim-raisi-election-as-president"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T16:59:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hardliner president-elect has caused alarm in some countries, though Iran and the US say agreement can still be found
World powers attempting to revive the Iran nuclear deal have warned of complications on the path to an agreement as they met for the first time since the election as Iranian president of Ebrahim Raisi, a hardline conservative cleric deeply antagonistic towards the west.
Jake Sullivan, the US national security adviser, said the arrow was pointing in the right direction, but he refused to say if sanctions imposed on Raisi by the Trump administration would be lifted. The German government’s human rights commissioner, Bärbel Kofler, said it was concerning that Raisi had not distanced himself clearly from human rights abuses. A European diplomat meanwhile warned the talks could not be open-ended, hinting strongly they needed a deal before Raisi took power in early August.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stones that sparked ‘diamond’ rush in South Africa are just quartz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/stones-sparked-diamond-rush-quartz-tests-reveal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/stones-sparked-diamond-rush-quartz-tests-reveal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T16:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up to 3,000 people flocked to remote village of KwaHlathi, but experts say value of the crystals is very low
Unidentified stones that lured thousands of fortune seekers to a rural South African village were not diamonds as hoped, officials said on Sunday, but quartz stones with relatively low if any value.
People from across South Africa travelled to KwaHlathi in eastern KwaZulu-Natal province where villagers had been digging with picks and shovels since 12 June after a herder discovered the first stone in an open field and put out the word.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Johannesburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Burnham blasts SNP for hypocrisy over Covid travel ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/andy-burnham-blasts-snp-covid-travel-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/andy-burnham-blasts-snp-covid-travel-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T16:07:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mayor says Manchester being treated with contempt while infection rates match parts of Scotland

Coronavirus latest updates

The Greater Manchester mayor, Andy Burnham, has accused the Scottish government of “hypocrisy” after it announced a travel ban to parts of the north-west.
Nicola Sturgeon said on Friday all non-essential travel to Manchester and Salford would be banned from Monday, with the Labour mayor saying the move came “out of the blue”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California authorities hunt suspect behind ‘atrocious’ attacks on Pelicans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/california-pelican-attacks-broken-wings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/california-pelican-attacks-broken-wings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T15:37:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thirty-two of the slow-flying water birds were found in Orange county, with all but 10 showing fractures to their wings

Authorities in California are looking for a suspected human culprit behind attacks on more than two dozen brown pelicans who have been found seriously injured in the south of the state.
In an alert issued last week, the Wetlands & Wildlife Care Center in Orange county said 32 of the slow-flying water birds have been found between San Clemente and Huntington Beach, with all but 10 showing compound fractures to their wings.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s in your fridge? New York’s mayoral race descends to salmon and sneakers | Emma Brockes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/new-york-mayoral-race-scandal-new-yorkers-mayor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/new-york-mayoral-race-scandal-new-yorkers-mayor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T15:10:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scandal isn’t always a problem for New Yorkers, who tolerate a certain amount of eccentricity in their mayor
It is hard to pick a favourite moment from the New York mayor’s race, entering its final stage of the primaries this week. It could be the episode in which two candidates – Shaun Donovan and Ray McGuire – were asked to guess the average house price in Brooklyn and answered $100,000, which would have been correct in 1985. (For those operating in 2021, the correct answer is $900,000).
It could have been the implosion of the Dianne Morales campaign, the most progressive candidate by far, predictably destroyed from within when staffers complained she’d created a “hostile” environment and that the work, presumably stuffing envelopes, was “repetitive and unstructured”. Meanwhile, it is hard not to love the storyline still playing out around Eric Adams, Brooklyn borough president and current frontrunner in the primary and therefore the election: that he secretly lives in New Jersey.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Brockes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Irish teenager Charlie Reid lands major film role with Olivia Colman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/20/irish-teenager-charlie-reid-lands-major-film-role-with-olivia-colman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/20/irish-teenager-charlie-reid-lands-major-film-role-with-olivia-colman"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T15:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fourteen-year-old from County Kildare to play opposite Oscar winner in feelgood film Joyride
An Irish teenager has been plucked from obscurity and cast alongside Olivia Colman, one of the industry’s most sought-after actors, as the lead characters in a feature film that begins shooting this month.
Fourteen-year-old Charlie Reid, from County Kildare, is said to be “absolutely thrilled” to have been picked to play a 13-year-old “scallywag” opposite Colman, who won an Oscar for her portrayal of Queen Anne in The Favourite and whose acclaimed performances include Queen Elizabeth in the Netflix hit The Crown.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dalya Alberge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rural house prices in England and Wales rise twice as fast as in cities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/rural-house-prices-in-england-and-wales-rise-twice-as-fast-as-in-cities</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/rural-house-prices-in-england-and-wales-rise-twice-as-fast-as-in-cities"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T14:43:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fears grow of affordability crisis for young people as property prices in countryside soar by 14.2% a year 

Rural house prices in England and Wales are increasing twice as fast as in cities, triggering a fresh affordability crisis for young people, with hot spots flaring up across the country from Lincolnshire to Lancashire as people seek more space post-pandemic.
Prices are rising 14.2% a year in countryside locations on average compared with less than 7% in urban areas, figures analysed by Hamptons estate agency for the Guardian show. It is compounding existing affordability problems in places such as Cornwall and Devon, but the biggest percentage increases of up to 30% were in Broxtowe in Nottinghamshire, around Lancaster, in Arun in West Sussex and Amber Valley in Derbyshire.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Two Americas’ may emerge as Delta variant spreads and vaccination rates drop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/us-covid-delta-variant-spreads-vaccination-rates-drop</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/us-covid-delta-variant-spreads-vaccination-rates-drop"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T14:27:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s 70% vaccination target by Fourth of July likely to fall short as efforts to entice people to get shots have lost their initial impact 
With Covid vaccination penetration in the US likely to fall short of Joe Biden’s 70% by Fourth of July target, pandemic analysts are warning that vaccine incentives are losing traction and that “two Americas” may emerge as the aggressive Delta variant becomes the dominant US strain.
Efforts to boost vaccination rates have come through a variety of incentives, from free hamburgers to free beer, college scholarships and even million-dollar lottery prizes. But of the efforts to entice people to get their shots have lost their initial impact, or failed to land effectively at all.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘He’s never spoken up about Muslims’: Keir Starmer leaves Batley voters disaffected]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/muslims-keir-starmer-leaves-batley-voters-disaffected-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/muslims-keir-starmer-leaves-batley-voters-disaffected-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T14:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Muslim voters say unhappiness with Labour leader means they will place votes elsewhere for first time
When Keir Starmer shifted Labour’s position on Kashmir in the first weeks of his leadership last year, he may not have realised that his stated intention of preventing “issues of the subcontinent to divide communities here” could cost the support of some of its most loyal voters.
Canvassing outside Jamia Masjid in Heckmondwike on Friday, the Labour candidate in the Batley and Spen byelection, Kim Leadbeater, received a hostile reception from voters who are unhappy with the party’s stance on foreign policy issues such as Palestine and Kashmir, amid a perception that the party takes some forms of racism more seriously than others.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson and Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black and Blue by Parm Sandhu review – home truths about life in the Met]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/20/black-and-blue-by-parm-sandhu-review-home-truths-about-life-in-the-met</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/20/black-and-blue-by-parm-sandhu-review-home-truths-about-life-in-the-met"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T14:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The police force’s former highest ranked BAME officer tells of her 30-year fight against entrenched racism and sexism
In August last year, when the Metropolitan police ended its active investigation into the murder of Stephen Lawrence after 27 years, the Met’s commissioner, Cressida Dick, gave an interview in which she rejected the idea that institutional racism still persists in the force. Former chief superintendent Parm Sandhu, the highest-ranked BAME (her preferred term) woman in the Met, begs to differ. Black and Blue is her account of a 30-year career that saw her break through multiple glass ceilings, but which ended in her resignation in 2019 after charges of gross misconduct and a spate of damaging media stories.
Her alleged offence was to have lobbied on her own behalf for honours, a technical breach she concedes, but she points out that she could not rely on the old boys’ network that benefits her white male colleagues. She was later exonerated, and notes that black and minority ethnic officers are twice as likely to be investigated for misconduct as their white counterparts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephanie Merritt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dean Blunt: Black Metal 2 review – instantly familiar yet utterly unknowable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/dean-blunt-black-metal-2-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/dean-blunt-black-metal-2-review"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T14:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Rough Trade)
The former Hype Williams frontman has polished his rap-alt-rock aesthetic to the point of perfection
Dean Blunt’s first band stole the name of celebrated rap video director Hype Williams and became infamous for playing the sort of gig where no one present was entirely sure it was really happening. They peaked with 2010’s The Throning, a deranged Sade cover. Since Blunt’s 2013 solo album, The Redeemer, the prolific Londoner has made music that finds surprising concord between rap and alt-rock. He samples anyone from the Pastels to A$AP Rocky, swaddles strings with defiantly lo-fi beats and adds vocals with winning vulnerability. He is often longing for something he can’t quite get, thwarted by the twin sirens of drugs and sex.
The cover art of Black Metal 2 reprises 2014’s Black Metal, just using a graphic figure “2” from Dr Dre’s 2001 cover, while the songs similarly build nests of references to Blunt and his rapper peers. It’ll never be for everyone, but Blunt has polished his fragmentary, magpie aesthetic to the point of perfection. Mugu is a lovely, scattered thing, then Semtex travels the wilder edges of trip-hop. Last track The Rot is almost as delicately discombobulated as his masterpiece The Narcissist. Songs instantly familiar yet utterly unknowable.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There are no real winners in Iran’s ‘engineered’ presidential elections | Mohammad Ali Shabani]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/iran-elections-president-elect-ebrahim-raisi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/iran-elections-president-elect-ebrahim-raisi"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:58:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Legitimacy concerns will haunt the new president, Ebrahim Raisi, after non-voters outnumbered voters for the first time
The first thing you need to know about Iran’s recent elections is that while they produced a new president, there are no real winners. “Engineered” – yes, an actual term in usage in Iran – to pave the way for an ayatollah-approved leadership succession, the polls have achieved what has long eluded the Islamic Republic’s foes: effective regime change in Tehran. Only, with hardliners now firmly in charge, it is not the type of change that many in the west had sought.
Reaching his twilight years, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been looking for a successor. To the 82-year-old head of state, the ideal successor is a pliant loyalist who could emulate his own journey from the presidency to the top position in the land. On paper, this is precisely what is unfolding. However, as always, the devil is in the detail.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohammad Ali Shabani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minister may intervene in Parole Board’s decision to free child killer Colin Pitchfork]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/minister-may-intervene-in-parole-board-decision-to-free-child-killer-colin-pitchfork</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/minister-may-intervene-in-parole-board-decision-to-free-child-killer-colin-pitchfork"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:41:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Justice secretary has 21 days to request formal reconsideration of decision in case of double murderer

The UK justice secretary is considering intervening over the Parole Board’s decision to approve the release of the child killer and rapist Colin Pitchfork.
The double murderer was jailed in 1988 after raping and strangling 15-year-olds Lynda Mann and Dawn Ashworth in Leicestershire in 1983 and 1986.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Body discovered after search for Belgian far-right soldier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/body-discovered-after-search-belgian-far-right-jurgen-conings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/body-discovered-after-search-belgian-far-right-jurgen-conings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:26:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Initial evidence indicates body found in woods is that of Jurgen Conings
Belgian police have said a body has been found in the search for a fugitive far-right soldier who was the target of a huge manhunt.
Hundreds of security forces scoured a swath of north-east Belgium after the disappearance on 17 May of Jurgen Conings, who was on an anti-terrorism watchlist, had threatened a senior virologist involved in the country’s Covid-19 programme and had hoarded heavy weaponry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we show our compassion for refugees, it will help to change minds | Ellie Mae O’Hagan and Sonya Sceats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/world-refugee-day-attitudes-refugees-compassion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/world-refugee-day-attitudes-refugees-compassion"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:25:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Messages that lead with values encourage people to identify with people seeking asylum, rather than see them as ‘other’
In October last year, it was reported that the home secretary, Priti Patel, had been looking into the use of offshore detention facilities to house people who come to Britain seeking asylum. In practice, this would mean that people arriving in Britain in need of safety would be shipped to some kind of detention centre on islands far away from mainland UK. We are both people with close personal ties to Australia and know all too well the grotesque consequences of such a system. Australia’s offshore detention has denied people their basic rights and caused incalculable suffering. Indeed Australia’s system was so cruel, the British government actually condemned it at the United Nations in 2015.
But although the current UK government likes to mimic Australian-style migration policies, this World Refugee Day is marked by a turning point in both countries, with grassroots activists, concerned citizens and refugees themselves joining together to demand a fair and efficient asylum system that processes people quickly and allows them to rebuild their lives in our communities.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ellie Mae O’Hagan and  Sonya Sceats</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: is ignorant bliss better than knowledgeable gloom?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/readers-reply-is-ignorant-bliss-better-than-knowledgable-gloom</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/readers-reply-is-ignorant-bliss-better-than-knowledgable-gloom"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
Happier people live longer, more pleasant lives. Informed people are weighed down with the woes of the world. So, is ignorant bliss better than knowledgeable gloom? Mary Shider, Macclesfield
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oil firm led by Tory donor investigated over alleged bribes in nine countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/oil-firm-led-by-tory-donor-investigated-over-alleged-bribes-in-nine-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/oil-firm-led-by-tory-donor-investigated-over-alleged-bribes-in-nine-countries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T13:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK-based Petrofac accused of making payments over more than 15 years  to secure contracts
A multinational oil firm which was led by a major Conservative donor has been under investigation for allegedly paying million-pound bribes to secure contracts in nine countries.
The anti-corruption agency the Serious Fraud Office (SFO) has been examining allegedly suspicious payments made by the UK-based firm Petrofac.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Evans and David Pegg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Referrals to UK gaming addiction clinic triple in year of lockdowns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/gaming-disorders-triple-among-young-during-year-of-uk-lockdowns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/gaming-disorders-triple-among-young-during-year-of-uk-lockdowns"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sharp rise attributed to young people spending more time at home during Covid pandemic
The number of children and young adults entering treatment for gaming addictions and disorders tripled over the last year, and experts believe that the pandemic and lockdowns played a key role in the increase.
The UK’s first specialist clinic to treat children and young adults who are addicted to playing video games opened in 2019, a year after the World Health Organization recognised “gaming disorder” as a medical condition.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children of obese mums at higher risk of fatty liver disease – study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/children-of-obese-mums-at-higher-risk-of-fatty-liver-disease-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/children-of-obese-mums-at-higher-risk-of-fatty-liver-disease-study"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:55:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say influences in the womb may play a role in increasing the risk of developing the condition
Children of obese mothers have a greater risk of developing fatty liver disease in their 20s, according to researchers who say policymakers need to do more to tackle the promotion of poor-quality food and drink.
Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) can be caused by obesity. If it progresses it can lead to serious health problems such as cirrhosis and liver cancer, while high levels of fat in the liver are also associated with a greater risk of type 2 diabetes and heart disease.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The weekend’s best photos: Royal Ascot and underwater boxing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/20/the-weekends-best-photos-royal-ascot-protests-and-underwater-boxing-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/20/the-weekends-best-photos-royal-ascot-protests-and-underwater-boxing-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:46:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pejman Faratin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[McDonald’s to hire 20,000 workers in UK and Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/mcdonalds-to-hire-20000-workers-in-uk-and-ireland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/mcdonalds-to-hire-20000-workers-in-uk-and-ireland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fast food chain plans to open 50 new restaurants over the next year 
McDonald’s is to recruit 20,000 workers and open 50 new restaurants in the UK and Ireland.
The fast food chain plans to employ additional staff and set up new franchises over the next 12 months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson under growing Tory pressure over planning reforms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/boris-johnson-under-growing-tory-pressure-over-planning-reforms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/20/boris-johnson-under-growing-tory-pressure-over-planning-reforms"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:23:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservatives urge prime minister to change course ahead of debate and in wake of shock byelection defeat

Boris Johnson faces a fresh headache over planning reforms, with Conservative MPs urging the prime minister to change course in the wake of the party’s shock defeat in the Chesham and Amersham byelection.
Pressure is expected to build on Johnson on Monday in a parliamentary debate called by Labour on the changes, as MPs demand better protections for communities to have their say over planning applications.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mykki Blanco: ‘I’ve helped to push open some closed doors. It’s a cool feeling’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/mykki-blanco-broken-hearts-beauty-sleep-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/20/mykki-blanco-broken-hearts-beauty-sleep-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rapper has worked with Kanye and Madonna and blazed a trail for black queer pop. Their new mini album, they say, feels like the start of a new chapter…
Mykki Blanco has just moved to Hollywood, and five minutes into our conversation, the 35-year old rapper’s beloved mother calls. “She needs to chill out. Like, I don’t work?” laughs Blanco. “She’s helping me pick out furniture and she’s gone crazy about the whole thing.” There is something pure about one of hip-hop’s most experimental figures having their mother help them decorate. The non-binary musician (who uses the pronouns they/them) has been living outside the US for the past five years, residing mostly in Europe: London and Portugal’s countryside. They also lived in Paris during the city’s second lockdown in late 2020 – an experi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kadish Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of Britain’s best lidos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/20/10-best-britains-lidos-outdoor-public-swimming-pools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/20/10-best-britains-lidos-outdoor-public-swimming-pools"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T12:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Devon to Derbyshire, these glorious outdoor swimming pools make for an invigorating dip
Another clear winner in the British seaside lido beauty parade. Built in 1935 in a semi-circular shape heading out to sea, Tinside Lido has striped blue tiling and retains the original changing rooms. It also has a backdrop of Plymouth Hoe. It’s open all summer, with a wide sun terrace, fountains and a pleasing sense of frivolity along with lifeguards and essential post-swim oriented cafe.
• Adults £5, juniors £4, everyoneactive.com
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Turner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer festivals are crying out for help – but the Tories don’t want to hear it | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/music-festivals-tories-arts-culture</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/music-festivals-tories-arts-culture"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T11:18:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic has revealed the Johnson government’s attitude to the arts: a mixture of indifference and hostility
Human beings need to regularly gather together. Over the past 15 or so months, the fact that we have largely been deprived of such opportunities has been a key reason why so many people have felt so listless and disoriented – and, for that matter, why some have been driven to break the rules. Obviously, to understand what they have done is not to condone it, but there is something in all those stories of illicit parties and so-called raves that highlights a need for communality and shared pleasure that will always finds cracks to grow in, like weeds on the driest of pavements.
The best example of what we have missed centres on the UK’s outdoor festivals. Amid corporate sponsorship and phone-charging tents, these events may not necessarily look like the modern version of ancient rites involving dancing, singing and feasting (and intoxication), but it is not hard to see them as exactly that. They also highlight what the performing arts bring to the world, and how much people value them. In 2019, 26% of British adults were reckoned to have gone to at least one festival in the past 12 months; before the pandemic struck, the sheer number of British events – from vast mega-festivals to compact local versions – spoke volumes about people’s appetite for them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clues and claws: meet the ace pet detectives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/meet-the-new-breed-of-pet-detectives-who-can-help-track-down-stolen-animals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/meet-the-new-breed-of-pet-detectives-who-can-help-track-down-stolen-animals"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T11:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Animal thefts surged alarmingly during the pandemic. But for heartbroken owners around the world, a new breed of dedicated sleuth is ready to 
 help track down your missing pet
I’ve always preferred animals to people. I’ve never met an animal I didn’t like, whereas there are plenty of humans I could do without. As a young girl growing up in rural Queensland, I had my own Lassie dog – Sam – stolen from me, when I was six. My siblings were older, and Sam was my best friend. He went missing before microchips and registrations – I’m almost certain we found the family who took him, but that was never proved. It always stayed with me; I never got closure. I felt like I’d failed him, which is why I dedicate my life to tracking down other pets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Segalov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man finds ‘guardian angel’ who saved him from stroke]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/man-finds-guardian-angel-who-saved-him-from-stroke-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/20/man-finds-guardian-angel-who-saved-him-from-stroke-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:35:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Twitter appeal Mathew O’Toole’s family makes contact with Danielle who stopped on London street to help
The family of a man who had a stroke on a street in central London has found the “guardian angel” who saved his life after an appeal on Twitter.
Mathew O’Toole, 47, was sitting on a bench outside a coffee shop on Wigmore Street in Mayfair on 10 June when he began vomiting and sweating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stars aligned: Sheila Atim and Ivanno Jeremiah on reviving a mind-bending classic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/20/sheila-atim-ivanno-jeremiah-constellations-vaudeville-theatre-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/20/sheila-atim-ivanno-jeremiah-constellations-vaudeville-theatre-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eight big-name actors are rebooting the award-winning love story Constellations in London’s West End. The first couple discuss their parallel careers - and their hotly disputed encounter as children
“In the quantum multiverse, every choice, every decision you’ve ever made and never made exists in an unimaginably vast ensemble of parallel universes.” So says quantum physicist Marianne in Nick Payne’s award-winning two-hander, Constellations. It follows that Sheila Atim, who plays Marianne in the latest revival of the play, may or may not have been bullied by her co-star Ivanno Jeremiah when they met at a party in real life as children. The encounter may, or may not, have happened at a big cook-up in south London, thrown in the early 00s by families of northern Ugandan Acholi heritage, which both actors share. Jeremiah was 11 or 12, Atim a couple of years younger. Twenty years on, the conversation goes like this:
Atim: “He picked on me. And it’s funny, because I remember the event really vividly, but I didn’t remember that it was him.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Armitstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shore things: the 22 best places to eat seafood around the UK coast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/20/shore-things-the-22-best-places-to-eat-seafood-around-the-uk-coast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/20/shore-things-the-22-best-places-to-eat-seafood-around-the-uk-coast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From crab shacks to beach hotels, top chefs share their favourite places to find great fish and sea views
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Molly Tait-Hyland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seafood recipes from around the UK coast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/20/recipes-from-around-the-uk-coast-fish-seafood-sandwich-mussels-staycation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/20/recipes-from-around-the-uk-coast-fish-seafood-sandwich-mussels-staycation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mussels with sherry and burnt cream, plaice and cauliflower pickle, and the ultimate fish-finger sandwich – chefs share their favourite dishes

The 22 best places to eat on the UK coast
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Holly O'Neill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t slash Covid benefit uplift, former Tory minister urges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/dont-slash-covid-benefit-uplift-former-tory-minister-urges</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/dont-slash-covid-benefit-uplift-former-tory-minister-urges"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Architect of universal credit says government must rethink plans to end £20 a week payment increase

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The former minister who oversaw the introduction of universal credit has called on the government to maintain key benefit increases introduced during the pandemic, lamenting that it had taken a global health crisis for the welfare system to be provided with adequate funding.
In a rare interview, David Freud, regarded as the architect of the controversial benefit, told the Observer he battled against “massive cuts” demanded by the Treasury and had considered resigning.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We will not stop’: pipeline opponents ready for America’s biggest environmental fight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/line-3-pipeline-indigenous-environmental-justice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/line-3-pipeline-indigenous-environmental-justice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activists have traveled from all over the US to protest against the construction of Line 3, a giant project that crosses Indigenous land
As the sun set, more than a dozen young people carried a wooden bridge toward a narrow section of the Mississippi River. The bridge allowed the group to cross more easily from their camp to where the immense oil pipeline was being built on the other side.
They were cited for trespassing – but they had symbolically laid claim to the marshy landscape.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sheila Regan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jamie Hawkesworth: ‘Everyone I photograph is as important as everyone else’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/jamie-hawkesworth-photography-the-british-isles-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/jamie-hawkesworth-photography-the-british-isles-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From his portraits of supermodels to suburban strangers, a democratic approach is key to the photographer’s work. He talks about capturing the ease and awkwardness of a situation and his new book on contemporary Britain
“I came quite late to photography,” says Jamie Hawkesworth, “and I learned by going out and doing it.” That self-taught apprenticeship began in earnest when he spent countless hours hanging around Preston bus station forcing himself to approach strangers to ask if they would mind being photographed. The resulting work first appeared in a newspaper-style zine produced by the local creative collective Preston Is My Paris in 2010, and, in 2014, was published in book form as Preston Bus Station.
Since then, Hawkesworth’s star has risen and he is now an in-demand fashion photographer for the likes of Vogue and the New York Times, his portraits of models in expensive clothes somehow retaining his signature style, which is a defiantly traditional merging of documentary and street portraiture. On first glance, his pictures can often appear casual, even mundane, but they are informed by an acute attention to light and colour, as well as a quietly observant eye. He uses an analogue film camera – a Mamiya RB67 mounted on a tripod – and spends long hours in a darkroom making his own prints. The results tend towards the everyday sublime: ordinary people bathed in warm, natural light; landscapes rendered almost romantic through his fondness for deeply hued reds, greens and browns. “I don’t really know why,” he says, “but in the darkroom, I always want my prints to look and feel optimistic, even if they were taken on a freezing-cold winter’s day in the Shetlands.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean O’Hagan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN blasts world leaders for failing to seal £72bn-a-year deal on climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/un-blasts-world-leaders-for-failing-to-seal-72bn-a-year-deal-on-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/un-blasts-world-leaders-for-failing-to-seal-72bn-a-year-deal-on-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Financial aid ‘critical’ to help developing countries limit fossil fuels – and make Cop26 a success, says UN
The head of climate change at the UN has warned that world leaders are still “far away” from securing a deal to limit the disastrous effects of global heating, with less than five months to go before a key summit in Glasgow.
Time is now running out, said Patricia Espinosa, who was formerly foreign minister of Mexico but now leads the UN on climate policy. She told the Observer that although advances had been made at the G7 meeting in Cornwall last weekend, progress had not been made on honouring past commitments to find $100bn (£72.5bn) a year to help developing countries invest in green technologies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm &amp; Robin McKie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Death of a Black Man review – an impassioned dispatch from 70s black Britain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/20/the-death-of-a-black-man-hampstead-theatre-alfred-fagon-dawn-walton-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/20/the-death-of-a-black-man-hampstead-theatre-alfred-fagon-dawn-walton-review"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hampstead theatre, London
The ingenious struggle of a new generation of entrepreneurs is charted in Dawn Walton’s bright revival of Alfred Fagon’s prescient 1975 play
Alfred Fagon’s play, first staged at Hampstead in 1975, has acquired new resonance over the years. Declamatory and bristling with harshness, it provides an impassioned report on what it was to be black in Britain in the 70s – when the West Indies cricket team was triumphing and Enoch Powell’s rants had poisoned the air.
The title hovers over the action like a bird of prey. The death is that of a musician, who does not appear on stage but whose life and talent influence the plot. Some unusually useful programme essays suggest that the last days of this character, loosely based on the Jamaican jazz saxophonist Joe Harriott, have a terrible parallel with the dramatist’s own death: Fagon was cremated as a pauper at the age of 49. Yet watching The Death of a Black Man now, the most striking extinction is unheralded. It is not that of a man. This is an evening that suggests how full history is of overlooked lives and how each generation may discover different neglectfulness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Susannah Clapp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thigh society: why men’s shorts are getting shorter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/20/thigh-society-why-mens-shorts-are-getting-shorter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/20/thigh-society-why-mens-shorts-are-getting-shorter"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This summer is officially sexy – and the hottest look for men is short shorts. But are we ready for this much male flesh?
In April the US actor Milo Ventimiglia, star of This Is Us, was photographed leaving the gym in a sleeveless vest and a pair of shorts so short you could barely tell they were there: two thumb-sized rims of black material gave way to legs so round and meaty they could be shoved in the oven for three hours at 180C.
It was one innocuous paparazzi photo that broke a dam of desire. The image was reshared on social media tens of thousands of times, users claiming: “Every thought in my head has been replaced with these images.” 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Wolfson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new, rebalanced UK could be the happy legacy of a shift to working from home | Rowan Moore]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/new-rebalanced-uk-happy-legacy-shift-to-working-from-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/20/new-rebalanced-uk-happy-legacy-shift-to-working-from-home"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the government contemplates making it easier for workers to stay away from the office, could this revitalise poorer parts of the country?
Here’s the dream. From now on, more people will work from home more of the time, which means that, for the same total commuting time per week, they can live further from the big, pressurised, expensive metropolitan centres, especially London, but also cities such as Manchester, Bristol or Edinburgh.
Such workers can find cheaper locations where they can afford more space, perhaps a garden, assets that among other things become more important if you’re working from home. For many, it might make the difference between being able to buy a home and forever chasing the impossible mirage of ownership in the overpriced capital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rowan Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dad’s the word: how the pandemic got men talking about fatherhood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/dads-the-word-how-the-pandemic-got-men-talking-about-fatherhood</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/dads-the-word-how-the-pandemic-got-men-talking-about-fatherhood"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T08:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More men than ever are joining fathers’ groups and showing an interest in what it means to be a dad
When Elliott Rae started his dads’ group Music Football Fatherhood back in 2016, it was just him and a couple of men from work. He didn’t face any negativity exactly, people just didn’t really understand what he was doing, or why he was doing it.
But the last 12 months has seen a massive rise in interest in fatherhood and dads’ groups, he says, as fathers in the UK spend more time with their children and look to other dads to help them navigate a path through the twists and turns of parenting.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Topping</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clothing banks warn of families in crisis as demand soars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/clothing-banks-warn-of-families-in-crisis-as-demand-soars</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/20/clothing-banks-warn-of-families-in-crisis-as-demand-soars"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T08:15:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charity is giving away 33% more bedding and clothes as pandemic hits incomes hard

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

“I’ve been trying to make my baby daughter’s vests bigger by stretching them while wet,” Carly Smith, a 26-year-old single mother of three, explains. “I can’t afford new clothes, so she’s just been wearing a nappy in the pram.” Her 11-year-old son had to return to school in home clothes, having grown out of his uniform, and is now wearing his grandfather’s T-shirts. “I’ll be honest, it’s embarrassing,” she says.
Before Covid, Smith (not her real name) had been given credit to buy clothing when she needed it by a kind shopkeeper, but the shop closed down during the pandemic. What’s more, Smith – a domestic violence victim – was forced to move home and leave her support network (and hand-me-downs supply) when her abusive ex-partner was released early from prison.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fleur Britten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giles Yeo: ‘Let’s consider the type of food we eat, and not fixate on calories’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/giles-yeo-why-calories-dont-count-diet-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/giles-yeo-why-calories-dont-count-diet-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T08:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The scientist and broadcaster discusses the drawbacks of calorie-counting and BMI in measuring obesity, and how our growing understanding of genetics is leading to new treatments
Since the dawn of the 20th century, almost all weight loss guidelines have used calories as a simple measure of how much energy we’re consuming from our food. But according to Giles Yeo, a Cambridge University research scientist who studies the genetics of obesity, there’s one problem: not all calories are created equal. In his new book, Why Calories Don’t Count, Yeo explains that what really matters is not how many calories a particular food contains, but how that food is digested and absorbed by your body.
Can you explain why you feel calorie-counting is a flawed approach to weight loss?
There was an American chemist in the 19th century called Wilbur Olin Atwater who calculated the calorie numbers for different foods, by working out the total energy intake you get from them. But his calculations never took into account the energy it takes our cells to metabolise food in order to use it. This is important. It’s why for example a calorie of protein makes you feel fuller than a calorie of fat, because protein is more complex to metabolise. For every 100 calories of protein you eat, you only ever absorb 70.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘When is this going to end?’: US factory town devastated by jobs moving overseas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/west-virginia-viatris-plant-jobs-overseas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/20/west-virginia-viatris-plant-jobs-overseas"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T07:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Viatris plant in West Virginia has been making pharmaceuticals since 1965 – but it’s closing down and laying workers off
“Disbelief. Distraught and traumatized.”
Just some of the words United Steelworkers Local 8-957 president Joe Gouzd used to describe how he and hundreds of other workers felt after their 56-year-old pharmaceutical plant in West Virginia was shut down, sending between 1,500 and 2,000 jobs to India and Australia.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Sainato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[QAnon and on: why the fight against extremist conspiracies is far from over]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/qanon-conspiracy-theories-pizzagate-infowars-storm-is-upon-us-mike-rothschild</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/qanon-conspiracy-theories-pizzagate-infowars-storm-is-upon-us-mike-rothschild"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T06:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far-right conspiracies ran unchecked online in the Trump years. It’s all gone quiet since the Capitol riot, but author Mike Rothschild believes there’s a radicalised audience waiting for a new rallying point
On 7 January this year, a day after the mob stormed the Capitol in Washington DC, a curious exchange occurred in the netherworld of global conspiracy. Alex Jones, the rasp-voiced mouthpiece of fake news for the past decade, was in conversation with the most visible leader of the previous day’s shocking events: Jacob Chansley, the self-styled “Q Shaman” who featured on the world’s front pages, in buffalo horns, animal skins and face paint.
Jones, on his fake-news platform Infowars, with its million-plus viewers and sharers, had for years been the loudhailer of unhinged stories that included the belief that Hillary Clinton was the antichrist, that Michelle Obama was a man, that the Pentagon and George Soros had detonated a “homosexual bomb” that turned even frogs gay, that 9/11 had been a “false flag” operation and, most viciously, that the Sandy Hook school murders, in which 20 children and six teachers died, were staged by “crisis actors” to promote gun control. Jones had inevitably been among those who addressed the restive crowd at Donald Trump’s “Stop the Steal” march (having donated $50,000 for the staging of the rally) and calling for supporters to “get on a war footing” to defend the president. Two days later, however, when faced with the rhetoric of Chansley, whom he had invited on to his show to explain the insurrection, it seemed even he, America’s conspirator in chief, finally couldn’t take the lies any more.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: sun’s out, bums out! Isle of Wight festival,1969]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/the-big-picture-isle-of-wight-festival-1969-david-hurn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/the-big-picture-isle-of-wight-festival-1969-david-hurn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T06:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Hurn’s photograph captures the last hurrah of a decade of freedom
A hundred and fifty thousand people camped out at the 1969 Isle of Wight festival to see Bob Dylan return to a live stage for the first time in three years. The photographer David Hurn, then 35, got a few pictures of Dylan’s set, but he was more interested in turning his camera on the crowd than the performers. That year’s festival, at the end of August, came a couple of weeks after Woodstock and was perhaps the closest Britain’s festivalgoers ever came to the authentic spirit of the summer of love.
Hurn, who grew up in Wales, had been on the frontline of much of the 1960s; as well as documenting indelible images of early Beatlemania, he had shot the film posters for Sean Connery’s James Bond in From Russia With Love and Jane Fonda’s Barbarella. The 1969 festival, which came a month after the moon landing and the death of Brian Jones, felt like a last hurrah for the decade. Hurn slept near the beach without a tent with the other festivalgoers and when hundreds of people plunged bare-arsed into the sea on the Sunday morning he felt he ought to join in and get naked himself. No other photographer was around to capture this scene, which, for all the cheerful nudity, is made by the presence of the boat at anchor, making the festivalgoers appear like a recently discovered, and distinctly hedonistic, island tribe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squad goals: Ocasio-Cortez warns Biden patience is wearing thin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/democrats-alexandria-ocasio-cortez-squad-congress</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/20/democrats-alexandria-ocasio-cortez-squad-congress"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T06:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cold reality intrudes on Biden’s first few months as leftist Democrats frustrated with president’s agenda stalling in Congress
They were pointed questions, not personal criticisms. But they will have conveyed a warning to Joe Biden that the patience of the left of the Democratic party and its leaders in ‘the Squad’ of progressive politicians is not infinite.
“Are we passing the deal that helps working people the most?” asked Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, the firebrand New York congresswoman and best known member of the squad. “Are we passing the deal that makes the most jobs? Are we passing a deal that brings down the most climate emissions? Are we passing a deal that raises wages and actually improves our infrastructure for the next generation?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vultures, tongue orchids: why are rare species here in UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/vultures-tongue-orchids-why-are-rare-species-here-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/vultures-tongue-orchids-why-are-rare-species-here-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T05:45:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Egyptian birds are one of a number of foreign visitors, but why have these continental drifters fled north?
Boats have been chartered. Weekend arrangements cancelled. And hundreds of twitchers – whose aim is to see very rare birds in Britain – have been praying the latest arrival stays long enough for them to see it in the flesh.
The bird in question is an Egyptian vulture. This is the smallest member of its family in Europe, yet still sports a 1.7-metre wingspan, not much smaller than a golden eagle. The reason for all the excitement is because this is only the third Egyptian vulture ever seen in the wild in Britain; and, incredibly, the first since 1868. That one, found in Essex, was shot by a farm worker who saw “a strange bird” amongst some geese.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Moss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Head of Independent Sage to launch international climate change group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T05:01:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir David King hopes to emulate success of British Covid advisory body by issuing monthly reports on environmental crisis
Several of the world’s leading scientists plan to launch an independent expert group this week to advise, warn and criticise global policymakers about the climate and nature crises.
The new body has been inspired by Independent Sage – the cluster of British scientists who have held UK ministers and civil servants to account for their lack of transparency and mishandling of the Covid pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Watts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My sex life has dropped off. Is my marriage at risk?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/my-sex-life-has-dropped-off-is-my-marriage-now-at-risk-philippa-perry-replies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/20/my-sex-life-has-dropped-off-is-my-marriage-now-at-risk-philippa-perry-replies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T05:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How often you have sex is not what counts, what really matters is the attention that you pay to each other
The question I have been with my husband for 10 years. We have two children and are very happy and enjoy being together. But one area does bother me: our sex life has dwindled, particularly since we had children. We used to have sex daily and it was great. But, as time went on and our children arrived, I find that we’re just too tired to have sex as often.
Our first child was born prematurely and spent time in neonatal intensive care. We both found that difficult and I think that I am still traumatised by it. My husband says it’s the past and that we should not dwell on that trauma. He’s right, but I can’t seem to help it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philippa Perry</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[He pledged unity. But now PM hopes to tighten grip on war-torn Ethiopia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/he-pledged-unity-but-now-pm-hopes-to-tighten-grip-on-war-torn-ethiopia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/20/he-pledged-unity-but-now-pm-hopes-to-tighten-grip-on-war-torn-ethiopia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T04:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elections this week could give PM even greater power, despite a regional conflict and a ‘man-made’ humanitarian crisis
Tens of millions of Ethiopians are expected to vote on Monday in crucial elections that could provide a launchpad for controversial prime minister Abiy Ahmed to consolidate his increasingly authoritarian rule.
Abiy, who won the Nobel peace prize two years ago after concluding a peace deal with neighbouring Eritrea, will face voters at the ballot box for the first time in Africa’s second most populous nation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke and Patrick Wintour</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Juneteenth gallery – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/jun/19/juneteenth-gallery-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/jun/19/juneteenth-gallery-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T21:47:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People across the US came together to celebrate 19 June 1865, the day which  commemorates the end of slavery in America


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘From denial to delay’: a forehead-slapping week in Australian climate policy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/from-denial-to-delay-a-forehead-slapping-week-in-australian-climate-policy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/from-denial-to-delay-a-forehead-slapping-week-in-australian-climate-policy"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T20:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Australia sees a high-profile show of political backing for gas even as world leaders and investors exert pressure to shift away from fossil fuels
It took a major international investment group with $279bn under its control to break through the climate-laden rhetoric of geopolitics last week.
You may not have heard of Robeco Institutional Asset Management, but on Thursday the Netherlands-based asset manager made a stunning declaration, singling out Australia as a country with a “particularly high-risk profile” that it wants to pressure to transition out of fossil fuels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Readfearn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two years on since Hong Kong’s pro-democracy protests – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/20/two-years-on-since-hong-kongs-pro-democracy-protests-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/20/two-years-on-since-hong-kongs-pro-democracy-protests-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T20:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What started as a reaction against an extradition bill in the summer of 2019 morphed into months of sometimes violent mass protests in an unprecedented challenge to Beijing’s authority
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The blue wall: what next for the Tories after a shock byelection defeat?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/19/the-blue-wall-what-next-for-the-tories-after-a-shock-byelection-defeat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/19/the-blue-wall-what-next-for-the-tories-after-a-shock-byelection-defeat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T18:33:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After their extraordinary Amersham win, can the Lib Dems break through in the rest of the Tories’ southern heartland? And how worried should Boris Johnson be?
It was during an emergency trip to the local B&Q last Thursday that a Lib Dem staffer was faced with the final and most bizarre decision of a long and gruelling byelection campaign: which mallet?
Constituents were still casting their votes and the party was by no means confident of victory. Yet late on Wednesday evening, party chiefs had decided that should the Lib Dems pull off a genuine byelection shock in Chesham and Amersham, an image of leader Ed Davey bashing down a blue wall with an orange mallet was just too good an opportunity to pass up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage, Toby Helm and James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tour of Black London – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/19/a-tour-of-black-london-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/19/a-tour-of-black-london-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T18:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nelson Mandela, Mary Seacole and Thierry Henry are some of the highlights of the tour of Black London from a new book by Avril Nanton and Jody Burton which celebrates Black history, culture and art in the capital. Andy Hall photographed a selection of the statues, murals and plaques

From Tudor courts to BLM, a new book brings London’s black history to life
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[American history all sewn up – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/19/american-history-all-sewn-up-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/19/american-history-all-sewn-up-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once a luxury item, since the 17th century quilts have evolved into a democratic art form that celebrates collaboration. Fabric of a Nation, a new book, brings together quilts spanning more than 300 years from the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. It’s a snapshot of America – Native American history, women’s suffrage, the construction of the railway, the civil rights movement. “Quilts are incredibly accessible objects,” says Jennifer M Swope, who curated the book and exhibition running in Boston. “They have been made and treasured by so many – rich and poor; women and men; urban and rural; white makers and artists of colour. In this way, quilts speak to many threads of the story of America.”
Fabric of a Nation: American Quilt Stories (MFA Publications, £35) is out now; the exhibition will be at Museum of Fine Arts, Boston later this year
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341511</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-the-outline-property-as-a-collapsable-border/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T20:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outline property in CSS draws a line around the outside of an element. This is quite similar to the border property, the main exception being that outline isn’t a part of the box model. It is often used for …
The post Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carter Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TCP vs UDP – Which Protocol is Faster?]]></title>
        <id>60b46dbd11ffb70827ef9dea</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/tcp-vs-udp-which-is-faster/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is TCP?TCP is an acronym for Transmission Control Protocol. It is a transport layer protocol that allows packets to be sent from one location to another.  TCP is a connection-oriented protocol, which means it establishes the connection before any communication between the network’s computer units. Because we]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Specialisation Courses for Advanced ML Practitioners]]></title>
        <id>60cc5a904dc1a607ed7b4c54</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-specialisation-courses-for-advanced-ml-practitioners/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, you don’t need to go to a university or a college to pursue a career in machine learning or any data-driven domain. But you do need a plan and a roadmap to guide your studies. Once you have charted your own learning roadmap with a goal in mind,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Sorting Algorithms]]></title>
        <id>60cca3294dc1a607ed7b4c76</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/understanding-sorting-algorithms/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:56:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every programming language uses sorting algorithms. While programming languages have easy-to-use sorting methods, it can be helpful to understand how they work. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you some of the most popular sorting algorithms! Haris Iftikhar developed this course. Haris]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342326</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied the fonts of the top 1000 websites. Here’s what I learned. — Michael Li brings the data. San-serif has total dominance. “[…] it is rare to go below 10px or above 24px.” And poor <h5> always being the 
…
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why brutal protests have been sweeping across Colombia – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T11:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the Amazon to the Caribbean coast, several weeks of protests have swept Colombia – dozens have died as demonstrators have faced sometimes deadly retaliation from police. 
The catalyst was a proposed tax hike, since withdrawn, in response to the coronavirus crisis. Demands expanded to calls to end inequality, economic disparity and police violence in Colombia – in almost two months, demonstrations have caused food and goods shortages.
Protest leaders have temporarily suspended in-person demonstrations due to a rise in Covid cases, but Joe Parkin Daniels, reporting for the Guardian, explains why this widespread discontent is unlikely to end


 ‘This is a revolution’: the faces of Colombia’s protests
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels, Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why England’s footballers are so determined to keep taking the knee - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/18/why-englands-footballers-are-so-determined-to-keep-taking-the-knee-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/18/why-englands-footballers-are-so-determined-to-keep-taking-the-knee-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T02:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England’s footballers will take the knee before their match against Scotland at Wembley tonight in an anti-racism protest that has divided supporters. Liam Rosenior and Paul MacInnes reflect on how football became enmeshed in the culture wars
When England’s footballers took to the pitch for their first match of Euro 2020 last Sunday they felt the weight of expectation as one of the tournament’s hotly tipped sides. But after a loudly bellowed national anthem, the team dropped to one knee on the Wembley turf for the anti-racism act that has become a mainstay of English football for the past year. Some of their own supporters loudly booed before the majority drowned them out in applause. 
Liam Rosenior, a former professional footballer currently on the coaching staff at Derby County, tells Anushka Asthana of his sadness but not surprise at the booing. He takes apart the argument that the players are making an overtly political statement and chastises politicians who he believes have sought to use the issue to inflame existing tensions. The Guardian’s sports reporter Paul MacInnes delves into the history of the gesture itself, which gained traction in the US on the back of the long-running anti-racism protest made by NFL quarterback Colin Kaepernick. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Liam Rosenior and Paul MacInnes;  produced by Joshua Kelly, Courtney Yusuf and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341948</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/perfect-tooltips-with-css-clipping-and-masking/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clipping and masking have been around for a while now in CSS and even have pretty decent browser support. I recently worked on a project that needed to use a clipping technique for tooltips showing above links in text.
Those …
The post Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Hoebregts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342257</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/start-serving-optimized-images-in-vue/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have become extremely important to the effectiveness of websites. They speak a 1000 words, attract attention, and stimulate emotions.
However, web performance is also a growing problem for most websites. And images are at the heart of many web …
The post Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ImageEngine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Azure AI Fundamentals Certification (AI-900) – Pass the Exam With This Free 4 Hour Course]]></title>
        <id>60c2aa56d3126007592d6226</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/azure-data-fundamentals-certification-ai-900-pass-the-exam-with-this-free-4-hour-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T12:02:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is the Azure AI Fundamentals Certification?The Azure AI Fundamentals Certification is for those seeking a Machine Learning role such as AI Engineer or Data Scientist. In the last decade companies have been collecting vast amount of data surrounding their service and product offerings. The successful companies of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: were you affected by the 2011 England riots?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is 10 years since the riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester. We would like to hear from those who witnessed them
This year marks the tenth anniversary of the 2011 riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester which followed protests after the police shooting of Mark Duggan. We would like to hear from those affected – including witnesses, former police officers, and people who participated. How did the riots affect you? What is your perspective now?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small businesses: have you given up the office permanently?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/17/smes-have-you-ditched-the-office-permanently</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/17/smes-have-you-ditched-the-office-permanently"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from small businesses who have given up on office-working since the pandemic – or are thinking about it – in favour of working from home
After the pandemic hit, the proportion of people working from home in the UK more than doubled.
We’d like to hear from small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) who have shifted to remote-working from home and are now planning to ditch the office for good.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is the truth out there? The US government prepares its landmark report on UFOs - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/17/is-the-truth-out-there-the-us-government-prepares-its-landmark-report-on-ufos-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/17/is-the-truth-out-there-the-us-government-prepares-its-landmark-report-on-ufos-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T02:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A hotly anticipated US government report on decades of mysterious sightings of UFOs is due for release this month. The Guardian’s Adam Gabbatt and former Ministry of Defence employee Nick Pope investigate
In December 2020, just before Donald Trump left the White House, the CIA was given six months to release all of the evidence it had gathered in the last 14 years about UFOs. So later this month a highly anticipated report will be released. 
Guardian reporter Adam Gabbatt tells Anushka Asthana that in recent years a series of government videos showing unidentified objects have been released, including footage from a navy F-18 fighter jet which showed an oblong object flying through the sky near San Diego in 2004. The wave of recent videos and the imminent release of the government report has ignited excitement around unidentified flying objects not seen for years. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Adam Gabbatt and Nick Pope; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are Bookmarklets? How to Use JavaScript to Make a Bookmarklet in Chromium and Firefox]]></title>
        <id>60c88bbc4dc1a607ed7b2ffa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-are-bookmarklets/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T00:53:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bookmarklets are browser bookmarks that execute JavaScript instead of opening a webpage. They're also known as bookmark applets, favlets, or JavaScript bookmarks. Bookmarklets are natively available in all major browsers, including Mozilla Firefox and Chromium-based browsers like Chrome or Brave. Scripting with JavaScriptLearning how to write scripts provides many benefits,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Split – How to Split a String into an Array in JS]]></title>
        <id>60c088e5d3126007592d56f1</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-split-how-to-split-a-string-into-an-array-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:19:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In general, a string represents a sequence of characters in a programming language.  Let's look at an example of a string created using a sequence of characters, "Yes, You Can DO It!". In JavaScript, we can create a string in a couple of ways: Using the string literal as a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inline Styles as Classes (lol)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342358</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inline-styles-as-classes-lol/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re abhorred by using inline styles, just move that style to the class attribute! And then make sure you have CSS in place that, ya know, does what it says on the box. 
I've revolutionized CSS. pic.twitter.com/1AWCldyCwP
— Sam 

…
The post Inline Styles as Classes (lol) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skewness and Kurtosis – Positively Skewed and Negatively Skewed Distributions in Statistics Explained]]></title>
        <id>60b8cb0aacb62507dd1d82ea</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/skewness-and-kurtosis-in-statistics-explained/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:56:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll explain two important concepts in statistics: skewness and kurtosis. And don't worry – you won't need to know very much math to understand these concepts and learn how to apply them. What are Density Curves?Let's first talk a bit about density curves, as skewness and kurtosis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Better React Apps with These Simple Tricks]]></title>
        <id>60ca25704dc1a607ed7b408c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-better-react-apps-with-these-tricks/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a list of amazing tricks that you can use to improve your React applications instantly. These tips will not only make your code cleaner and more reliable, but they also aim to make your development experience easier and overall more enjoyable.  Give these techniques a try in your React]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful and Useless Code Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/useful-and-usless-code-comments/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Nielsen: 
If somebody says a comment isn’t adding any value, I would ask: to whom?
Personally, I’ve never liked the advice that writing obvious comments is bad practice—probably because I write obvious comments all the time.
Jim showed …
The post Useful and Useless Code Comments appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teach Yourself Data Analytics in 30 Days]]></title>
        <id>60ca30af4dc1a607ed7b4197</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/teach-yourself-data-analytics-in-30-days/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:19:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can learn the basics of Data Analytics with 30 days of practice.  We just released a Data Analytics course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. The course includes a 40-minute video, as well as a website and Jupyter notebooks. If you follow the plan laid out in these course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342353</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-i-used-the-waapi-to-build-an-animation-library/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Animations API lets us construct animations and control their playback with JavaScript. The API opens the browser’s animation engine to developers and was designed to underlie implementations of both CSS animations and transitions, leaving the door open to …
The post How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okiki Ojo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitality workers: how are you coping without cash tips?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/hospitality-workers-how-are-you-coping-without-cash-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/hospitality-workers-how-are-you-coping-without-cash-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:43:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from waiters and other hospitality workers about how they have been coping without cash tips since the pandemic
Cash tips make up a significant part of the income of waiters and other hospitality workers in the UK. We would like to hear from employees about how they have been coping without these tips since the pandemic. Have you lost income as a result? Has your employer done anything to address this issue? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care home workers: share your thoughts on mandatory Covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from care home staff on their thoughts about vaccines among reports ministers will make them mandatory
Ministers are planning to announce that Covid vaccinations are to become mandatory for care home staff in England, with them considering extending the move to all NHS staff.
We would like to hear from care home workers on their thoughts about mandatory vaccines and what their experiences have been like.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel’s unlikely coalition: is this the end for Netanyahu?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/16/israels-unlikely-coalition-is-this-the-end-for-netanyahu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/16/israels-unlikely-coalition-is-this-the-end-for-netanyahu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T02:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israel has a new coalition government made up of eight very different parties. But having ousted Benjamin Netanyahu, can it hold together?
Israel’s longest-serving leader, Benjamin Netanyahu, was ousted from office on Sunday by a coalition of rival parties from across the political spectrum. Yair Lapid, a centrist former TV news anchor, won a confidence vote in parliament by 60 to 59 seats giving the new coalition a razor-thin majority.
The Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, Oliver Holmes, tells Rachel Humphreys that Netanyahu’s downfall was marked by jubilant celebrations from his political opponents. But the new coalition of eight parties is far from stable. Dahlia Scheindlin tells Rachel that despite the momentous week in Israeli politics it may not produce a significant change of course on the biggest issues facing the country. And it may not be the last act for Netanyahu in Israeli politics. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Oliver Holmes and Dahlia Scheindlin; produced by Ned Carter Miles and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detect Unused Classes in… HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342198</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/detect-unused-classes-in-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T23:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, when “unused” comes up in conversation regarding CSS, it’s about removing chunks of CSS that are not used in your site or, at least, the styles not currently in use on a specific page. The minimal amount of CSS …
The post Detect Unused Classes in… HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps Engineering Course for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>60c91b2b4dc1a607ed7b389a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/devops-engineering-course-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T21:33:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps is one of the highest-paying roles you can get at a software company. And even if you aren't working as a DevOps, knowing how it works will make you a more productive developer. We just published a DevOps Engineering course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. Learn all about]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Media Queries in Times of @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342519</id>
        <link href="https://mxb.dev/blog/media-queries-in-times-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T19:51:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Böck took me up on my challenge to look through a codebase and see how many of the @media queries could ultimately become @container queries.
I took the bait and had a look at some of my projects – 
…
The post Media Queries in Times of @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just How Niche is Headless WordPress?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342248</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/just-how-niche-is-headless-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T14:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wonder where headless WordPress will land. And by “headless” I mean only using the WordPress admin and building out the user-facing site through the WordPress REST API rather than the traditional WordPress theme structure.
Is it… big? The future …
The post Just How Niche is Headless WordPress? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342294</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-tables-with-sticky-header-and-footers-got-a-bit-easier/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It wasn’t long ago when I looked at sticky headers and footers in HTML <table>s in the blog post A table with both a sticky header and a sticky first column. In it, I never used position: sticky on …
The post Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342229</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-tricks-chronicle-xxxx/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a little link roundup of some off-site stuff I’ve done recently. As I’m wont to do from time to time. 
DevJourney Podcast
#151 Chris Coyier from ceramics to CSS-Tricks and CodePen‘
Chris took us from playing on 
…
The post CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342070</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/securing-your-website-with-subresource-integrity/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you load a file from an external server, you’re trusting that the content you request is what you expect it to be. Since you don’t manage the server yourself, you’re relying on the security of yet another third party …
The post Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khari McMillian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My partner wants to move to the country, but I don’t – what should we do?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/see-if-its-time-to-sell/2021/jun/14/my-partner-wants-to-move-to-the-country-but-i-dont-what-should-we-do</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/see-if-its-time-to-sell/2021/jun/14/my-partner-wants-to-move-to-the-country-but-i-dont-what-should-we-do"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:11:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writer Andrzej Łukowski is very happy with his family-sized flat in London. But his wife Rachael dreams of moving to the country. Can they resolve their differences without a mediator? 
I say: ‘It took me 28 years to move to London – I want to stay here’ 
OK, I never actually thought the streets were paved with gold. But London is the place I always wanted to live. I grew up in beautiful Birmingham – did you know it has more canals than Venice? – but I spent endless hours reading about theatre shows and gigs happening in the Big Smoke. I was the last of my friends to make the move here and when I finally did, it did not disappoint. I’d easily go out every single night in a week.
Although being married and having children changes that lifestyle, I still go to the theatre a lot. Having a family and a decent flat with a roof terrace is honestly more than I ever hoped for. Having said that, my wife Rachael would prefer that we had a proper garden, which I have no objection to, and we could all do with a bit more space – our sons currently share a bedroom.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrzej Łukowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342429</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/safari-15-new-ui-theme-colors-and-a-css-tricks-cameo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a 33-minute video (and resources) over on apple.com covering the upcoming Safari changes we saw in the WWDC keynote this year in much more detail. Look who’s got a little cameo in there:
Perhaps the most noticeable thing there …
The post Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Possibilities of Syndication]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342237</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-possibilities-of-syndication/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s the one word that isn’t an adjective in the acronym RSS. 
Really Simple Syndication.
Update: Lol there are literally two mistakes there. RSS is an initialism not an acronym, and “Really” is an adverb not an adjective. 
RSS …
The post The Possibilities of Syndication appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘For the first time, I can see my future’: why I’m tempted to sell up and leave London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/see-if-its-time-to-sell/2021/jun/02/for-the-first-time-i-can-see-my-future-why-im-tempted-to-sell-up-and-leave-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/see-if-its-time-to-sell/2021/jun/02/for-the-first-time-i-can-see-my-future-why-im-tempted-to-sell-up-and-leave-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:23:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic made many of us reconsider how we want to live – and what we want from our homes. Now that lockdown has lifted, Francesca Brown and her family are preparing to make good on their promise to leave London for more space and quiet

Being locked down in a cramped London flat with small children and no garden proved to be a testing time – especially for our long-suffering and very polite downstairs neighbours.
When I originally bought my flat more than a decade ago, I was young, single and out all the time. The place seemed vast back then. Even when my boyfriend and I settled down here together and had kids, the bijou nature of it didn’t bother us as we’d happily be out at work, school, nursery. On the weekend, trips to museums, swimming and soft play, or to friends’ much bigger houses filled our time. The flat was simply a stop-off point on our way to other things.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesca Brown</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>