<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-13T00:33:55.852Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-13T00:33:55.852Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police arrest one suspect, hunting for another after Austin shooting leaves 14 injured]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/austin-texas-shooting-injured</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/austin-texas-shooting-injured"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T00:24:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incident occurred in early hours in entertainment district
Two victims in critical condition as one more suspect sought

Police in Austin, Texas, say they have arrested one man and are searching for another in connection with a shooting early on Saturday that injured 14 people in the city’s downtown entertainment district.
The Austin police department said in a news release that the US Marshals Lone Star fugitive task force assisted in making the arrest, but it provided no other details other than to say it is continuing to follow up on leads for the suspect still at large.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Austin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ban ministers from lobbying for five years, Greensill review to propose]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/ban-ministers-from-lobbying-for-five-years-greenill-review-to-propose</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/ban-ministers-from-lobbying-for-five-years-greenill-review-to-propose"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T23:28:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Evans to call for tougher rules to stop former ministers using contacts and expertise for private gain 
Ministers could face a five-year ban from lobbying after leaving office and face fines if they break the rules.
Lord Evans, chair of the committee on standards in public life, will propose the tougher measures following an emergency review carried out in the wake of the Greensill scandal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Connett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Halfords on a roll as Britons ride out the pandemic on bikes and in cars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/13/halfords-on-a-roll-as-britons-ride-out-the-pandemic-on-bikes-and-in-cars</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/13/halfords-on-a-roll-as-britons-ride-out-the-pandemic-on-bikes-and-in-cars"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T23:05:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But faced with online rivals, the company is switching focus from sales to servicing, especially of electric cars
Halfords, Britain’s biggest bicycle and motoring parts retailer, has been a beneficiary of lockdown as the country got on its bike and used its car to take domestic holidays.
On Thursday the company expects to report a surge in pre-tax profits to between £90m to £100m for the year to April, beating analysts’ £70m estimates. Its profits were just under £56m last year and £59m in 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We love: Fashion fixes for the week ahead – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/12/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/12/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T22:55:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Champion sportswear gets an embroidery makeover, pearl jewellery for men, and 20 years of Stella McCartney.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All aboard: get the nautical look for men – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/12/all-aboard-get-the-nautical-look-for-men-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/12/all-aboard-get-the-nautical-look-for-men-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T22:45:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Menswear has long looked to the sea for practical fashion inspiration, from fisherman jumpers to Breton stripes. So what’s the best way to dip in, without going full ‘shipster’?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All hot air: UK commits to climate action but not to new funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/all-hot-air-uk-commits-to-climate-action-but-not-to-new-funding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/all-hot-air-uk-commits-to-climate-action-but-not-to-new-funding"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T21:31:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson announces £500m for ‘blue planet fund’, but pledge was contained in 2019 Conservative manifesto

Environmental campaigners stage ‘festival-type’ protests at G7
G7 summit protests – in pictures

Boris Johnson has set out his intention to “build back better for the world”, to protect the natural environment and wildlife, and tackle the climate crisis, at the G7 summit in Cornwall. But he committed no new funds to the initiative, and other G7 leaders showed little sign of coming forward with the cash commitments that campaigners said were needed to help developing countries cope with the climate emergency.
Announcing £500m to be spent on a “blue planet fund”, for the protection of the oceans and coastal areas in poor countries, he said: “As democratic nations, we have a responsibility to help developing countries reap the benefits of clean growth through a fair and transparent system. The G7 has an unprecedented opportunity to drive a global green industrial revolution, with the potential to transform the way we live.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey &amp; Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denmark coach Kasper Hjulmand: ‘I can’t praise my players enough’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/denmark-coach-kasper-hjulmand-i-cant-praise-my-players-enough</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/denmark-coach-kasper-hjulmand-i-cant-praise-my-players-enough"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:58:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teammates stood in protective circle around Christian Eriksen
‘We are reminded what the most important thing in life is’ 

The Denmark coach, Kasper Hjulmand, paid tribute to his players after they completed their Euro 2020 group match against Finland despite witnessing Christian Eriksen being given CPR on the pitch shortly before half-time.
The players formed a protective circle around their teammate as he was resuscitated, but then, after a suspension of more than an hour and half, agreed to complete the match, once word had come through that Eriksen was awake and talking in hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lukaku scores twice and sends message to Eriksen in Belgium’s win over Russia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/belgium-russia-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/belgium-russia-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To the extent that a night this fraught with worry could provide a moment of poetry, Romelu Lukaku found exactly what was required. Nothing could be more confronting to a footballer than seeing one of their own fight for his life on the pitch and, for a handful of Belgium’s players, the horror of events in Copenhagen held an even more personal dimension. Christian Eriksen has played with several of them at club level and, if any evidence were required of just how traumatic the build-up to this game had become, it was offered within 10 minutes of the start.
Lukaku and Eriksen have just won Serie A together with Internazionale and achievements of that stature create bonds for life. In Belgium’s first real attack against a shoddy Russia he was given a clear sight of goal by Andrei Semenov’s comical error and the finish was almost an afterthought. He sprinted straight to the touchline camera after finding the far corner of the net, only one person on his mind, and the emotions spilled out. “Chris, Chris, I love you,” Lukaku shouted while cupping the lens, a simple sentiment but one loaded with barely articulable meaning.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denmark’s Christian Eriksen given chest compressions after he collapsed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/denmark-v-finland-match-suspended-after-christian-eriksen-collapses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/denmark-v-finland-match-suspended-after-christian-eriksen-collapses"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Midfielder, 29, required urgent CPR on the pitch during match against Finland but is now stable

Danish international footballer Christian Eriksen was given chest compressions by medics during the Euro 2020 clash against Finland in Copenhagen on Saturday.
Eriksen, 29, collapsed face first into the pitch while running to collect a throw-in with no other player near him. His teammates and Finnish players nearby quickly signalled to English referee Anthony Taylor that Eriksen, a former Tottenham Hotspur favourite, needed urgent medical attention.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Connett and Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share-housing in your 60s: ‘Six of us wanted to do retirement in an extraordinary way’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/share-housing-in-your-60s-six-of-us-wanted-to-do-retirement-in-an-extraordinary-way</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/share-housing-in-your-60s-six-of-us-wanted-to-do-retirement-in-an-extraordinary-way"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of group holidays, three couples decided to take their cohabitation arrangement full time
We are three couples who decided on living together, 16 years ago, in our retirement. The word “retirement” is a loose description as we, like many seniors are incredibly busy, wringing as much as we can out of what’s likely to be­ – what Michael calls – our last quarter.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eve Grzybowski for Tonic Magazine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opposition forces Orbán into U-turn over Chinese campus plan in Budapest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/opposition-forces-orban-into-u-turn-over-chinese-campus-plan-in-budapest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/opposition-forces-orban-into-u-turn-over-chinese-campus-plan-in-budapest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a general election due next year, Hungary’s government has put the divisive project in the capital’s heart on hold
Protests against the construction of a Chinese university in Budapest have energised the Hungarian opposition ahead of elections next year, and forced the government into a rare U-turn.
Outrage at plans to build a campus of Shanghai’s Fudan University became a rallying cry for the opposition, drawing thousands to protest in defiance of government regulations
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Graham-Harrison</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Defamation nation: why are Australian politicians so quick to sue?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/defamation-nation-why-are-australian-politicians-so-quick-to-sue</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/defamation-nation-why-are-australian-politicians-so-quick-to-sue"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T20:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not exactly new to the nation’s political culture but the litigation business is booming – and social media has added fuel to the fire
 When he was attorney general, Christian Porter told the National Press Club Australia’s defamation laws didn’t strike the right balance.
After extensive consultation, states agreed to make the laws more defendant-friendly, promising to introduce a new public interest defence and a threshold of serious harm to weed out trivial claims.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Karp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zahid Quaraishi confirmed as first America’s Muslim federal judge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/zahid-quaraishi-first-muslim-american-federal-judge-confirmed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/zahid-quaraishi-first-muslim-american-federal-judge-confirmed"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:53:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Appointment draws mixed emotions from Muslim community
Quarashi worked for Ice and served with US army in Iraq

The United States has appointed its first Muslim American federal judge in Zahid Quraishi, a historic confirmation that is eliciting mixed emotions from the Muslim community.
 Related: Trump’s revenge: tilting of supreme court to the right poised to bear fruit 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erum Salam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delay ending lockdown: majority of public back Boris Johnson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/delay-ending-lockdown-majority-of-public-back-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/delay-ending-lockdown-majority-of-public-back-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Observer poll reveals most people believe prime minister should wait past proposed 21 June date

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The majority of the public back delaying the end of legal restrictions on social contact in the wake of rising cases of a more transmissible Covid variant, according to a new poll.
With Boris Johnson poised to announce a delay to his plan to remove the remaining restrictions on 21 June, an Opinium poll for the Observer found that 54% think the move should be postponed, up from 43% from a fortnight ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sold! Bidder pays $28m for spare seat on space flight with Jeff Bezos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/12/jeff-bezos-space-auction-28m-spare-seat-blue-origin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/12/jeff-bezos-space-auction-28m-spare-seat-blue-origin"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:24:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bids in 10-minute auction started at $4.8m for 20 July trip on Blue Origin spacecraft with Bezos and his brother.
Jeff Bezos’s Blue Origin has sold the spare seat of the company’s 20 July New Shepard space rocket blast-off for $28m, the company announced on Saturday.
 Related: Rocket men: Bezos, Musk and Branson scramble for space supremacy 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We want to take the next step’: John Carver backs Scots for Euros progress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/scotland-euro-2020-john-carver-steve-clark-england-croatia-czech-republic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/scotland-euro-2020-john-carver-steve-clark-england-croatia-czech-republic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The assistant coach is confident of Scotland’s qualification from Group D, where they face Czech Republic, England and Croatia
John Carver always listened intently when Bobby Robson reminisced about managing England at international tournaments but little did the former Newcastle coach know he would one day prove a key figure behind Scotland’s return to the European stage.
Carver’s installation as Steve Clarke’s assistant last September coincided with a marked upswing in the team’s performances, culminating in their qualification for a first major tournament since France 98.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louise Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit bust-up torpedoes Johnson’s bid to showcase ‘global Britain’ at G7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/brexit-bust-up-torpedoes-johnsons-bid-to-showcase-global-britain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/brexit-bust-up-torpedoes-johnsons-bid-to-showcase-global-britain"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:10:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland border row hits summit in Cornwall as prime minister tells other leaders UK is ‘a single country’

 Boris Johnson reiterates threat to suspend Northern Ireland protocol

Boris Johnson was embroiled in an extraordinary public spat with EU leaders over Northern Ireland on Saturday as tensions over Brexit boiled over at the G7 summit in Cornwall.
After a series of tense bilateral meetings at which the French president, Emmanuel Macron, the German chancellor, Angela Merkel and the European commission president, Ursula von der Leyen, told their summit host the UK must implement the Brexit deal in full, an unrepentant Johnson said he had urged his EU colleagues to “get it into their heads” that the UK is “a single country”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart &amp; Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Americans are heaven for us’: the surge in US visitors throwing Greece a lifeline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/americans-are-heaven-for-us-a-surge-in-us-visitors-throws-greece-a-lifeline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/americans-are-heaven-for-us-a-surge-in-us-visitors-throws-greece-a-lifeline"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T19:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Country confounds post-Covid predictions as transatlantic holidaymakers flood in ready to spend

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A fresh wind blows down Adrianou. Seated in front of his rug store on the street that cuts through the heart of ancient Athens, Theo Iliadis takes in the scene. At 47, the owner of The Loom has seen “a lot of bad stuff” in recent years. The global pandemic couldn’t have come at a worse time for Greece, already gutted by prolonged economic crisis.
But barely a month after the tourist-dependent country opened its doors, the entrepreneur is in ebullient mood. There’s a glint in his eye and a lightness in the air of the carpet-stacked cavern behind him. “Americans are in town,” he smiles. “Business is good, The Loom is good and I’ve got drinks on ice.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five fertility clinic patients awarded $15m after failure of freezing tank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/fertility-clinic-freezing-tank-failure-california</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/fertility-clinic-freezing-tank-failure-california"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T18:43:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Storage tank maker knew of defect before California incident
Case likely to increase calls for regulation of $37bn industry

Five patients of a California fertility center have been awarded a total of $15m after a freezing tank failed, rendering some of more than 3,500 frozen human embryos and eggs unviable.
While the extent of the damage from the accidental thaw is unclear, jurors awarded the sum to clients of the Pacific Fertility Center in San Francisco after finding that the storage tank maker, Chart Industries, knew about a defect that prevented accurate temperature monitoring and had not warned the center about the problem.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England on brink of defeat as Neil Wagner turns the screw for New Zealand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/england-on-brink-of-defeat-as-neil-wagner-turns-the-screw-for-new-zealand-second-test-day-three</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/england-on-brink-of-defeat-as-neil-wagner-turns-the-screw-for-new-zealand-second-test-day-three"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T18:42:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Second Test day three: England 303 & 122-9; New Zealand 388
Mark Wood top-scores with 29 as England’s batsmen fall short

Bataclysm. Batastrophe. There is simply not a hole this England lineup cannot bat itself into. If nothing else, they are experts in turning a crack into a crater, a tiny cut into a full-blown chasm. And on a sun-kissed Saturday afternoon at Edgbaston they donned gloves, strapped on pads and took themselves caverning.
New Zealand, for all that they had dominated the match, led by a demure 85 at the end of their first innings. Somehow, beyond all reason, England were in this game: all they needed was a decent opening partnership and they would be on their way. The innings break was the most enjoyable 10 minutes of the day for them, a time when the sun shone, all was calm and the future was plump with potential.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Burnton at Edgbaston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In waging culture wars, Boris Johnson can count on a cabinet of mercenaries | Nick Cohen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/in-waging-culture-war-boris-johnson-can-count-on-a-cabinet-of-mercenaries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/in-waging-culture-war-boris-johnson-can-count-on-a-cabinet-of-mercenaries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No dispute is too trivial for ministers to ignore, an obsession that will harm them
When Napoleon marched on Moscow in 1812, the Russian general Mikhail Kutuzov ordered his forces to sit back. They abandoned their capital and conserved their energies until Napoleon, his supply lines fatally extended, had to retreat and see winter, disease and guerrilla attacks destroy his army and his reputation for invincibility.
The Tories might have sat back and let a vicious left destroy itself. Instead, they have gone on the offensive. No dispute is too trivial to ignore now. No scab too small to pick. Like all swaggering hard cases, they look for fights and if a real conflict isn’t on offer they will pick one with any passerby.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four charged with murder after teenager stabbed in south London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/four-charged-with-after-teenager-stabbed-in-south-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/four-charged-with-after-teenager-stabbed-in-south-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T18:20:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Metropolitan police have now made 11 arrests in connection with the incident in Streatham
Four people have been charged with murder following the fatal stabbing of a teenager in south London.
The Metropolitan police has made a total of 11 arrests in connection with the incident in Streatham, which happened on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Page happy for Wales to ‘put tin hats on’ in opening Switzerland draw]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/robert-page-happy-for-wales-to-put-tin-hats-on-in-opening-switzerland-euro-2020-draw</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/robert-page-happy-for-wales-to-put-tin-hats-on-in-opening-switzerland-euro-2020-draw"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:45:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moore’s second-half equaliser salvages point in Baku
Page: ‘It feels like a win in the changing room’

Robert Page has said his Wales players are happy to “dig a trench and put tin hats on” in their quest to reach the European Championship knockout stages after eking out a crucial point in their Group A opener against Switzerland. Kieffer Moore cancelled out Breel Embolo’s second-half header and Page urged Wales to build on the draw when they face Turkey here in Baku on Wednesday.
 Related: Sluggish Wales make point but leave much room for improvement | Paul Doyle 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at Baku Olympic Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Israeli coalition government seeks to put an end to the Netanyahu era]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/new-israeli-coalition-government-seeks-to-put-an-end-to-the-netanyahu-era</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/new-israeli-coalition-government-seeks-to-put-an-end-to-the-netanyahu-era"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:40:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The opposition-led administration will be sworn in on Sunday if it can prevail in a confidence vote in the Knesset
Benjamin Netanyahu is due to be ousted from office on Sunday by a new Israeli government formed with the primary aim of dethroning the country’s longest-serving leader.
A motley grouping of politicians, including former Netanyahu allies turned foes, have set aside bitter differences to put an end to the prime minister’s historic run in power. If successful, it will also break a political stalemate that has seen four snap elections in the country since 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Josh Bayliss with final flourish as Bath beat Northampton to seal Europe spot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/josh-bayliss-with-final-flourish-as-bath-beat-northampton-to-seal-europe-spot</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/josh-bayliss-with-final-flourish-as-bath-beat-northampton-to-seal-europe-spot"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:39:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wasps and Leicester also qualify for Europe
Bristol top Premiership after Covid cancellation

As so often these days, in rugby, sport and society, a pesky virus played an unsatisfactorily influential role, but the Premiership’s final day finished with the teams who had started in the top eight remaining there to qualify for Europe.
Wasps, Bath and Leicester were the teams who could have been denied, had they not collected the various points required. Happily, these days are also marked by an abundance of tries, so the various bonus points were duly collected, Bath’s in spectacular fashion at the very end of their home match against Northampton, who were already qualified.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Aylwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate and England have become victims of the blame game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/gareth-southgate-and-england-have-become-victims-of-the-blame-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/12/gareth-southgate-and-england-have-become-victims-of-the-blame-game"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:35:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is a schism between players, manager and the team’s core fanbase but a win against Croatia may buy some goodwill
“These were the new horror days of a nation that was all played out, a nation of riot and yobbery, a nation with a ridiculous government, an economy in a tailspin – England, whatever the hell happened to England?”
There is probably some comfort to be found that these words were written three decades ago, coda to another epic tournament, another moment of cultural shift that seemed, at the time, to be oddly bound up with England football.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My God, I’m in a whale’s mouth’: lobster diver on brush with hungry humpback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/whale-mouth-lobster-diver-humpback-cape-cod</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/whale-mouth-lobster-diver-humpback-cape-cod"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:27:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Packard, 56, was spat out after half a minute but expert says experience would have been ‘totally freaky’ for the whale
A New England lobsterman has described the moment he realised he was trapped in the mouth of a humpback whale off the coast of Cape Cod.
“Oh my God, I’m in a whale’s mouth and he’s trying to swallow me. I thought to myself, ‘hey, this is it. I’m finally going to die. There’s no getting out of here,’’’ Michael Packard told a local news station in Provincetown, Massachusetts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exeter secure home play-off semi-final as thrilling comeback sinks Sale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/exeter-sale-premiership-rugby-union-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/exeter-sale-premiership-rugby-union-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:27:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exeter 20-19 Sale 
Cowan-Dickie and Townsend score late tries for 14-man Chiefs

This uniquely demanding Premiership season has seen some remarkable contests but few more extraordinary than this one. Having been a distant second for much of the game 14-man Exeter staged the most stunning of comebacks from 19-3 down and will now enjoy home advantage when these two sides meet here again in next Saturday’s semi-finals.
Early in the second half Sale had appeared to be on course for a home semi themselves thanks to tries from Byron McGuigan, AJ MacGinty, and Arron Reed. All they needed was a fourth try to secure an all-important extra bonus point, the dismissal of Sam Skinner for a high challenge on the diminutive Faf de Klerk with 25 minutes left having seemingly sunk the home side without trace.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson at Sandy Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brandon Taylor: ‘I grew up reading my aunt’s nursing-home manuals and bodice-rippers’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/12/brandon-taylor-i-grew-up-reading-my-aunts-nursing-home-manuals-and-bodice-rippers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/12/brandon-taylor-i-grew-up-reading-my-aunts-nursing-home-manuals-and-bodice-rippers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Booker-shortlisted novelist on teaching himself to read, critics who say he’s not nice enough to white people, and why the Bible still haunts him
Brandon Taylor, 32, grew up in Alabama and studied at the Iowa Writers’ Workshop. He was shortlisted for last year’s Booker prize with his debut, Real Life, a campus novel about a gay black biochemist. His new book, Filthy Animals, is a series of linked stories loosely centred on the sexual tension between Lionel, a black maths postgraduate, and two white dance students, Charles and Sophie. The writer Paul Mendez has called Taylor “a phenomenon… the laureate of young, expensively educated people... pleasuring and harming themselves and each other”. He spoke to me over Zoom from his home in Iowa City.
Did you consciously set out to broaden you…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anthony Cummins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What the special relationship looks like today – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/12/what-the-special-relationship-looks-like-today-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/12/what-the-special-relationship-looks-like-today-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T17:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson and Joe Biden put a brave face on it at the G7 summit


• You can order your own copy of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15-year-old boy charged with murder of teenager stabbed in west London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/15-year-old-boy-charged-with-of-teenager-stabbed-in-west-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/15-year-old-boy-charged-with-of-teenager-stabbed-in-west-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T16:34:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jalan Woods-Bell, also 15, died from his injuries in Hayes on Friday morning
A 15-year-old boy appeared in court on Saturday charged with the murder of a teenager, named for the first time as Jalan Woods-Bell, who died after being stabbed in west London during the Friday morning school run.
Police were called to reports of a fight on Blyth Road in Hayes just before 8.35am. Woods-Bell, also 15, was found with stab injuries and died at the scene.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not quite ready to rock … festivals’ return hit by lack of loos and tents]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/not-quite-ready-to-rock-festivals-return-hit-by-lack-of-loos-and-tents</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/not-quite-ready-to-rock-festivals-return-hit-by-lack-of-loos-and-tents"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T16:32:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A critical shortage of both equipment and crew has left organisers scrambling to prepare for summer events
Over the past year, the traditional sounds of the festival summer – the drone of guitar feedback, the smack of drumstick on snare – have been silenced by the pandemic.
On Friday, they’ll finally be blowing the dust off the amps at Donington Park, where 10,000 people will be rocking and camping at the Download pilot – an event the industry hopes will herald the return of live music.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Catalans’ comeback thwarts Leigh’s quest for first Super League win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/catalans-comeback-thwarts-leighs-quest-for-first-super-league-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/catalans-comeback-thwarts-leighs-quest-for-first-super-league-win"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T16:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leigh 30-36 Catalans 
Visitors run in six tries and go top of table

Leigh Centurions are finding out the hard way just how tight the margins are between success and failure in Super League. Since opting to remove their coach, John Duffy, 10 days ago, the Centurions have delivered back-to-back performances against Wakefield and Catalans which have been commendable to say the least.
But as we approach the midway point of the regular season, there is little doubt that it is victories, not performances, which Leigh require if they are to extend their time in Super League into a second successive season in 2022. Ten games in, and 10 consecutive defeats. That statistic alone does little to inspire confidence in terms of survival, but all is not yet lost for Leigh on several counts, you feel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Bower at Leigh Sports Village</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harassment of girls at school just reflects back the world of adults | Barbara Ellen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/harassment-of-girls-in-schools-just-reflects-back-the-adult-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/harassment-of-girls-in-schools-just-reflects-back-the-adult-world"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T16:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Half the population watches porn so it’s no surprise that it has installed itself in our children’s lives too
Does the pornification of school culture in the UK merely reflect the adult world back at us?
Ofsted reports that sexual harassment and online sexual abuse are so routine for schoolchildren that they barely bother reporting it; 90% of girls and 50% of boys have been sent explicit pictures (“dick pics”). Girls, the biggest targets of harassment, report everything from unwanted touching, rape jokes and upskirting to being asked for nude images and having nudes shared on SnapChat and WhatsApp “like a collection game”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barbara Ellen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ellie & Abbie (& Ellie’s Dead Aunt) review – lesbian romcom could do better]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/12/ellie-abbie-ellies-dead-aunt-review-lesbian-romcom-could-do-better</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/12/ellie-abbie-ellies-dead-aunt-review-lesbian-romcom-could-do-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T16:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well-intentioned gay coming-of-age ghost story haunted by a naive storyline and an easily avoided 15 certificate
It could have been a sweet, gay coming-of-age story about a girl whose sexual awakening is complicated by unwelcome gay mentorship from the ghost of her lesbian aunt. But there’s a disconnect between the naive but well-intentioned storytelling and the explosive swearing that ensures a 15 certificate and places the film out of reach of the younger teen audience who might, otherwise, have been its most receptive. Still, as Ellie and Abbie respectively, Sophie Hawkshaw and Zoe Terakes make light work of a somewhat heavy-handed screenplay.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wendy Ide</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Museum of the Home reopens to protests over statue of slave ship owner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/museum-of-the-home-reopens-to-protests-over-statue-of-slave-ship-owner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/museum-of-the-home-reopens-to-protests-over-statue-of-slave-ship-owner"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:51:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diane Abbott among those saying statue of Robert Geffrye should be removed from east London building
The reopening of the Museum of the Home in London was met with protests on Saturday calling for the removal of a statue of slave ship owner Robert Geffrye following an intervention by the culture secretary to keep it in place.
The museum, in Shoreditch, east London, wanted to take down the statue of the 17th-century trader and former lord mayor of London, who made part of his fortune from the slave trade, from the front of its building.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 summit protests – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/12/g7-summit-protests-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/12/g7-summit-protests-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:29:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters turn out in support of a range of causes as the leaders of Group of Seven nations meet for the forum’s 47th summit in Cornwall

Environmental campaigners stage ‘festival-type’ protests at G7
All hot air: UK commits to climate action but not to new funding
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid lockdown: should England open up on 21 June?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/should-england-open-up-on-21-june-the-factors-johnson-must-consider</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/should-england-open-up-on-21-june-the-factors-johnson-must-consider"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister has a host of problems to weigh up before deciding to remove all legal restrictions on social contact

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The key issue is the extent to which infections of the Delta variant first detected in India will lead to hospitalisations and deaths. The problem is that it’s too early to say. Because of the lag between cases and admissions to hospital, many experts say a short delay could be a major benefit to understanding that relationship. “With the current knowledge about Delta, we can’t really predict the size of that wave,” said Anne Cori of Imperial College London’s modelling group. “Delaying the easing allows time to accumulate more evidence about the characteristics of Delta. And I hope in a few weeks, we would be in a better position to predict what the epidemic may look like in the next few weeks or months.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbora Krejcikova beats Anastasia Pavlyuchenkova to win French Open]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/barbora-krejcikova-beats-anastasia-pavlyuchenkova-to-win-french-open-title</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/barbora-krejcikova-beats-anastasia-pavlyuchenkova-to-win-french-open-title"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:11:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Czech player prevails 6-1, 2-6, 6-4 at Roland Garros
Title represents first grand slam crown for Krejcikova

Over the past two weeks in Paris, Barbora Krejcikova has competed in just the fifth grand slam singles main draw of her career, her third as a direct entrant. She has not even made it to Wimbledon or the US Open as a singles player, yet when she finally does she will make her debut in those events as a grand slam singles champion.
In a wonderful display of toughness and guile, the unseeded Krejcikova defeated Anastasia Pavlyuchenkova, the 31st seed, 6-1, 2-6, 6-4 to win the French Open. After a run that has included one match point saved, numerous battles and ample beat-downs across matches against five seeded players, Krejcikova has become the second Czech woman to win at Roland Garros, after Hana Mandlikova in 1981.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Eagleman: ‘The working of the brain resembles drug dealers in Albuquerque’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/12/david-eagleman-the-working-of-the-brain-resembles-drug-dealers-in-albuquerque</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/12/david-eagleman-the-working-of-the-brain-resembles-drug-dealers-in-albuquerque"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The neuroscientist, broadcaster and author on the evolution of the brain, the mystery of consciousnesss, and why the next generation will be much smarter than us
David Eagleman, 50, is an American neuroscientist, bestselling author and presenter of the BBC series The Brain, as well as co-founder and chief executive officer of Neosensory, which develops devices for sensory substitution. His area of speciality is brain plasticity, and that is the subject of his new book, Livewired, which examines how experience refashions the brain, and shows that it is a much more adaptable organ than previously thought.
For the past half-century or more the brain has been spoken of in terms of a computer. What are the biggest flaws with that particular model?
It’s a very seductive comparison. But in fact, what we’re looking at is three pounds of material in our skulls that is essentially a very alien kind of material to us. It doesn’t write down memories, the way we think of a computer doing it. And it is capable of figuring out its own culture and identity and making leaps into the unknown. I’m here in Silicon Valley. Everything we talk about is hardware and software. But what’s happening in the brain is what I call livewire, where you have 86bn neurons, each with 10,000 connections, and they are constantly reconfiguring every second of your life. Even by the time you get to the end of this paragraph, you’ll be a slightly different person than you were at the beginning.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Anthony</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbara Thompson’s Paraphernalia with NYJO: Bulletproof review – fresh takes on old favourites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/12/barbara-thompsons-paraphernalia-with-nyjo-bulletproof-review-fresh-takes-on-old-favourites</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/12/barbara-thompsons-paraphernalia-with-nyjo-bulletproof-review-fresh-takes-on-old-favourites"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Temple Music)
The musician breathes new life into familiar material in a captivating collaboration
Barbara Thompson, saxophonist, flautist, composer and one of Europe’s finest and certainly most popular jazz musicians, led her band, Paraphernalia, between 1978 and 2015. Now aged 76, she has been forced to stop performing by Parkinson’s disease. For this captivating album she assembled three former members of Paraphernalia, plus most of the National Youth Jazz Orchestra (Nyjo), to play 10 of her favourite compositions, freshly arranged. The young musicians take to them all with what sounds like easy familiarity – including the title number, which is 10 minutes of unrelenting pressure. It’s fascinating to hear improvised solos from two of the veterans, Peter Lemer on keyboards and Billy Thompson (no relation) on violin, beside Nyjo’s Tom Ridout on tenor saxophone and Luke Vice-Coles on trumpet. All four come up with surprising ideas that light up the whole piece, and there’s certainly no sign of the difference in age. The music here is typically wide-ranging, from the catchy Sax Rap to Ode to Sappho, based on a fragment of ancient Greek music, but it’s all unmistakably Thompson, and true originality such as hers doesn’t date.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Gelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing home the bacon: retaining character in a converted pigsty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/bringing-home-the-bacon-retaining-character-in-a-converted-pigsty</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/bringing-home-the-bacon-retaining-character-in-a-converted-pigsty"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The previous residents left the building in a state, but this rare Victorian pig pen is now a joy to behold
For a builder to have a penchant for Grandma’s 1950s dainty, flowery teacups is somewhat peculiar, but for New Zealander Martin Gane and his English wife, the interior designer Elle Kemp, seeking out the traditional has always been preferable to the new-fangled.
Their family home, a listed Victorian pigsty in Gloucestershire, is a masterclass in traditional techniques and design. When they discovered it, eight years ago, the building was little more than a neglected ruin. A range of crumbling internal brick walls held up a leaky roof and the floor was bare soil. The few doors that were attached had been well gnawed by the previous residents, and most of the brickwork was worn away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Newton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignored, bullied, patronised: why loyalists in Northern Ireland say no to Brexit ‘betrayal’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/ignored-bullied-patronised-why-loyalists-in-northern-ireland-say-no-to-brexit-betrayal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/ignored-bullied-patronised-why-loyalists-in-northern-ireland-say-no-to-brexit-betrayal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the often volatile marching season approaches, bitter tensions over the EU protocol grow, along with a belief that NI is being cast adrift by a duplicitous British government
They gathered in their thousands at the top of the Shankill Road with banners and drums to send a message to the far side of the Irish Sea, where a treacherous prime minister played his charade in a kingdom no longer fully theirs.
Some waved union jack flags, others had union jack masks, one had a union jack balaclava, and they tramped behind marching bands with drums, flutes and cymbals, a percussive shockwave in the Belfast dusk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clamour for wealth tax grows after revelations about super-rich’s affairs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/12/clamour-for-wealth-tax-grows-after-revelations-about-super-richs-affairs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/12/clamour-for-wealth-tax-grows-after-revelations-about-super-richs-affairs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data leak published by ProPublica fuels calls to tighten up system which sees ultra-wealthy pay little or no tax
The revelation last week that the 25 richest US billionaires have paid very little tax even as their fortunes have soared has reignited demands for wealth taxes on both sides of the Atlantic.
 An unprecedented leak of “a vast trove” of 15 years of Internal Revenue Service (IRS) data to the investigative news site ProPublica has provided a staggering insight into the legal strategies the very rich deploy to avoid tax.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not that Noel Gallagher’s looking back in anger. Well, not much | Rebecca Nicholson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/not-that-noel-gallagher-looking-back-in-anger-well-not-much</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/not-that-noel-gallagher-looking-back-in-anger-well-not-much"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Other performers can learn from the irreversible break-up that made Oasis one of the greats
In an age of celebrity blandness, where famous people usually decline to say much of interest in public, Noel Gallagher is reliably forthright in doling out his opinions. Last week, doing the rounds, he let rip at hard-to-hit targets such as Prince Harry (“woke snowflake”) and Little Mix (“not in the same league as Oasis”). So familiar are his “better in my day” grumbles that they’re essentially white noise now; they should make a relaxation app out of them, to soothe sleep-troubled woke snowflakes who are unbearably anxious about the prospect of Little Mix not winning a Brit next year.
But in among all the “Dad, put your phone down” stuff, there was wisdom. On the Sky Arts documentary Noel Gallagher: Out of the Now, he dug into the Oasis split, explaining that their break-up was “the best thing for me and for the band”. Prior to that, he said, they were “not lauded as one of the greats of all time”. I saw them trudge through a handful of joyless festival sets in the 00s, which were, like Little Mix, “not in the same league as Oasis”. Calling it a day made them into greats, because it meant they never quite had the chance to become fully spoiled.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Brother is still watching you and he goes by the name Facebook]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/big-brother-is-still-watching-you-and-he-goes-by-the-name-facebook-john-naughton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/big-brother-is-still-watching-you-and-he-goes-by-the-name-facebook-john-naughton"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The social media giant’s offer of free internet access ensures that mobile users stay where it can keep an eye on them 
The security guru Bruce Schneier once famously observed that “surveillance is the business model of the internet”. Like all striking generalisations it was slightly too general: it was strictly true only if by “the internet” you meant the services of a certain number of giant tech companies, notably those of Facebook (including WhatsApp and Instagram), Google (including YouTube), Twitter and Amazon.
The trouble is (and this is what gave Schneier’s aphorism its force) that for a large chunk of networked humanity, especially inhabitants of poorer countries, these walled gardens are indeed what people regard as “the internet”. And that’s no accident. Although Chinese smartphones are pretty cheap everywhere, mobile data tends to be prohibitively expensive in poor countries. So the deal offered by western tech companies is that data charges are low or zero if you access the internet via their apps, but expensive if you venture outside their walled gardens.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson faces legal action over peerage for billionaire Tory donor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/12/boris-johnson-faces-legal-action-over-peerage-for-billionaire-tory-donor-peter-cruddas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/12/boris-johnson-faces-legal-action-over-peerage-for-billionaire-tory-donor-peter-cruddas"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T14:58:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Appointment of Peter Cruddas, who donated £500,000 to party after taking seat, is ‘unlawful’, say campaigners

Boris Johnson is facing legal action over his decision to give a peerage to a billionaire party donor in defiance of advice from the watchdog for appointments to the Lords.
Electoral Commission records show that Peter Cruddas, a former Conservative party treasurer, gave the Tories a further £500,000 just three days after taking his seat in the upper chamber last February.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Devastating’ fire destroys recreated iron age dwelling on Loch Tay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/devastating-fire-destroys-recreated-iron-age-dwelling-on-loch-tay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/devastating-fire-destroys-recreated-iron-age-dwelling-on-loch-tay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T14:52:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Director of Scottish Crannog Centre thanks community for support after fire on Friday night
A large fire that destroyed a recreated iron age roundhouse on the shore of Loch Tay has been described as “devastating” by the trust which runs the site.
The Scottish Crannog Centre, which is also a museum of life in ancient Scotland, burned down on Friday night.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’d like to make a complaint... Why some of us are so good at making a fuss]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/id-like-to-make-a-complaint-why-some-of-us-are-so-good-at-making-a-fuss</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/id-like-to-make-a-complaint-why-some-of-us-are-so-good-at-making-a-fuss"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T14:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Were you the child whose indignant letter yielded a free bar of chocolate? Séamas O’Reilly puts pen to paper to reveal why we are a nation of complainers
The biscuit was only barely covered. If I’d had to guess, I’d have said 30% of its surface had chocolate applied, and that’s being charitable. Certainly more charitable than the manufacturer of the Jaffa Cake in question, who I pictured as God’s perfect miser; a Scrooge-like figure toiling in a candle-lit factory, peering over their bifocals to smear homeopathic levels of chocolate on one sorry corner of my favourite tea snack. I was 10 years old, and had never had a particularly strong sense of myself as a consumer champion, but this biscuit, this disgrace, roused something inside me.
“Dear McVitie’s,” I wrote, addressing the entire company in my missive. “I was shocked and appalled to discover this Jaffa Cake (enclosed) in such a state.” In hindsight, I was savvy enough to moderate my speech to sound adult, but not perhaps worldly enough to consider enclosing the foodstuff itself in plastic before popping it in with my letter. By the time I posted it the following day, I remember already noticing some of its soft greasiness had permeated the envelope, but I reckoned this was probably just the way things were done. Evidently it was, as two weeks later I received a letter apologising for my suboptimal experience, along with an invitation to tour a factory, and two whole boxes of Jaffa Cakes. These, I am happy to report, were perfectly chocolated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Séamas O’Reilly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s this season’s must-have Hermès bag. And it’s made from fungus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/12/its-this-seasons-must-have-hermes-bag-and-its-made-from-fungus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/12/its-this-seasons-must-have-hermes-bag-and-its-made-from-fungus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T14:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The luxury label is the latest to adopt pioneering technology as designers shift to plant-based fabric. Is this the end of leather?
It’s fair to say that Hermès knows handbags. The luxury fashion house’s Birkin and Kelly bags are among the most expensive ever sold; demand outstrips supply by so much that you can’t even join a waiting list. Acquiring one is a matter of luck and contacts. So when Hermès announced this season’s handbag would be made from plant leather, it marked a new era in designer accessories.
The autumn/winter 2021 Hermès Victoria (prices start from about £3,500 for its previous leather version) will be made from Sylvania, a leather grown from fungus, before being crafted in France into a perfect Hermès handbag. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On my radar: Shirley Manson’s cultural highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/on-my-radar-shirley-manson-garbage-cultural-highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/12/on-my-radar-shirley-manson-garbage-cultural-highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T14:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The singer on her obsession with The Bureau, the revolutionary Lil Nas X and her seafood pilgrimage to East Lothian
Born in Edinburgh in 1966, Shirley Manson is the frontwoman of alternative rock band Garbage and was previously a member of bands Goodbye Mr Mackenzie and Angelfish. Garbage released their self-titled debut in 1995 and in 1999 recorded the theme song for Bond movie The World Is Not Enough. Manson has also acted in US sci-fi series Terminator: The Sarah Connor Chronicles and Nickelodeon animated series Top Wing. Since 2019, she has presented The Jump, a podcast in which she interviews musicians such as Karen O and Matt Berninger. Garbage’s seventh album, No Gods No Masters, is out now on Infectious Music. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea eagles spotted at Loch Lomond for first time in over a century]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/sea-eagles-spotted-at-loch-lomond-for-first-time-in-over-a-century</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/sea-eagles-spotted-at-loch-lomond-for-first-time-in-over-a-century"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T13:49:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature bodies in Scotland have put exclusion zone in place to protect the area where the birds were seen
Sea eagles have appeared on Loch Lomond for the first time in more than a century.
A pair of white-tailed eagles, commonly known as sea eagles, were first spotted at Loch Lomond national nature reserve in early March this year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No joint news conference after Biden-Putin summit: White House]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/biden-putin-summit-no-joint-press-conference</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/biden-putin-summit-no-joint-press-conference"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T13:21:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden will speak to press alone after Geneva meeting
Trump caused outcry by accepting Putin denials at Helsinki

Joe Biden will give a solo news conference after his meeting next week with his Russian counterpart, Vladimir Putin, the White House has said.
Putin and Biden will meet in Geneva on Wednesday. The White House has said Biden will bring up ransomware attacks emanating from Russia, Moscow’s aggression against Ukraine, the jailing of dissidents and other issues that have irritated the relationship.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sasha Johnson shooting: second teenager charged]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/sasha-johnson-shooting-second-teenager-charged-devonte-brown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/sasha-johnson-shooting-second-teenager-charged-devonte-brown"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T13:09:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Devonte Brown, 18, of Southwark, charged with conspiracy to murder over shooting of BLM activist
A second teenager has been charged with conspiracy to murder over the shooting of the Black Lives Matter activist Sasha Johnson, the Metropolitan police said.
The 27-year-old remains in a critical condition in hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’ve all got our fingers crossed’: brides and grooms across UK face agonising wait]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/weve-all-got-our-fingers-crossed-brides-and-grooms-across-uk-face-agonising-wait</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/weve-all-got-our-fingers-crossed-brides-and-grooms-across-uk-face-agonising-wait"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T12:45:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The threat of further postponement to planned nuptials is fraying nerves for the 50,000 couples hoping to tie the knot 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Elliott Brown – “groom number two” as he describes himself – is feeling a little nervous about the 95 invitations to his wedding next month that were sent out after the government announced its “roadmap to freedom” back in February.
Brown and his bride-to-be, Samantha, were due to marry last summer but the pandemic put paid to that. His brother Gareth – “groom number one” – got married in a small ceremony last weekend after postponing twice. A third brother, Alex, will tie the knot in August on his fifth attempt. All three ceremonies are at Ripley register office in Derbyshire, with their father, Andy Brown, the deputy registrar, officiating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four teenagers arrested over death of man in Shropshire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/four-teenagers-arrested-over-death-of-man-in-shropshire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/four-teenagers-arrested-over-death-of-man-in-shropshire"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T12:43:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One boy of 14 and three of 15 held on suspicion of murder, and two adults on suspicion of assisting offenders
Four teenage boys have been arrested after the death of a man in Shropshire.
West Mercia police said a man and a woman in their 40s were also being held on suspicion of assisting offenders.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia bans foreigners from hajj over Covid concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/saudi-arabia-bans-foreigners-from-hajj-over-covid-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/saudi-arabia-bans-foreigners-from-hajj-over-covid-concerns"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T12:14:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Annual pilgrimage will be restricted to 60,000 vaccinated adults from within the kingdom

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Saudi Arabia has announced that this year’s hajj pilgrimage will be limited to 60,000 vaccinated people from within the kingdom because of the coronavirus pandemic.
The kingdom ran a reduced pilgrimage last year, but still allowed a small number of people to take part in the annual event.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Riyadh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We are democratising the right to laziness’: the rise of on-demand grocery deliveries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/the-rise-of-on-demand-grocery-deliveries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/the-rise-of-on-demand-grocery-deliveries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T11:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Companies are springing up all over the UK promising to deliver whatever you want in as little as 10 minutes. But what could we lose by never popping out for milk again?
One Friday afternoon in May, Glenn Cobane, 40, who lives with his wife and two cats in Salford, did some grocery shopping: a loaf of bread, bananas, an avocado, cat food, chocolate brownies and some cans of beer. Rather than going to a nearby corner shop or walking a mile to the large Tesco Extra, he bought the food and drink from a new app called Weezy. He placed the order at 2.19pm. “I just sent the order, typed an email and then it arrived.” he says. It is now 2.27pm, and I’m standing on his doorstep beside the courier.
“This is the third or fourth time I’ve used them in the past fortnight,” Cobane says. The Weezy delivery rider might have shaved a few minutes off the mile-long journey from the warehouse to Cobane’s house on his e-bike if he hadn’t had to wait for me to keep up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Wallop</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[True to nature: Robert Macfarlane, Helen Macdonald and more on the children’s books that inspired them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/12/true-to-nature-robert-macfarlane-helen-macdonald-and-more-on-the-childrens-books-that-inspired-them</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/12/true-to-nature-robert-macfarlane-helen-macdonald-and-more-on-the-childrens-books-that-inspired-them"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T11:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Watership Down to The Animals of Farthing Wood, leading nature writers discuss the children’s classics that made them want to write about the natural world

A couple of years ago I found myself gazing at the cover of a book I’d loved as a child: the 1942 Carnegie medal-winning The Little Grey Men, by the naturalist, illustrator and sportsman Denys Watkins-Pitchford, who wrote under the name BB. The charge it carried felt electric, and even opening the cover felt risky; I braced myself in case its magic had faded in the 40 years since it had been read to me at bedtime.
The Little Grey Men was published during the misery of the second world war, with destruction all around and a sense – familiar to us today – of a world in terminal decline. I remembered it as an utterly luminous evocation of spring, summer and autumn in the countryside, seen through the eyes of the very last gnomes in Britain: “honest-to-goodness gnomes, none of your baby, fairy-book tinsel stuff, and they live by hunting and fishing like the animals and birds, which is only proper and right,” as BB wrote. As a child I loved that businesslike tone, with its flattering dismissal of other, “babyish” stories; I loved BB’s illustrations, the precise and detailed rendering of the natural history in the book, and most of all the feeling it gave me of a secret world to which I was being granted privileged access.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Harrison</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sex and the City cast begin work on revival episodes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/12/sex-and-the-city-cast-begin-work-on-revival-episodes-and-just-like-that</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/12/sex-and-the-city-cast-begin-work-on-revival-episodes-and-just-like-that"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T10:54:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Jessica Parker, Cynthia Nixon and Kristin Davis start production on And Just Like That ...
The cast of Sex and the City have reunited as production began on a revival of the series called And Just Like That …
Sarah Jessica Parker, who plays Carrie Bradshaw, shared a picture of herself with co-stars Cynthia Nixon and Kristin Davis in New York.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters in London and Glasgow call for halt to Osime Brown deportation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/protesters-in-london-and-glasgow-call-for-halt-to-osime-brown-deportation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/protesters-in-london-and-glasgow-call-for-halt-to-osime-brown-deportation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T10:18:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[22-year-old autistic man faces being sent to Jamaica after serving time for crime he and others say he did not commit
Campaigners are calling for a halt to the deportation of a 22-year-old autistic man to Jamaica at demonstrations in London and Glasgow on Saturday.
Osime Brown was jailed for stealing a friend’s mobile phone, a crime that he and others say he did not commit. He was sentenced to five years for robbery, attempted robbery and perverting the course of justice. Now that he has been released from prison he faces deportation to Jamaica, a country he left at the age of four to settle in the UK with his mother, Joan Martin.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Catholic prime minister in No 10 is a watershed moment | Catherine Pepinster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/catholic-prime-minister-no-10-watershed-moment-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/catholic-prime-minister-no-10-watershed-moment-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T10:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It would have once been unthinkable, but Boris Johnson’s conversion to Catholicism shows how far we’ve come
There’s a quip that both Boris Johnson and David Cameron have used – one that shows they are aware of the pitfalls of signing up to a specific religion in secular Britain while also wanting to keep co-religionists on side. Both have said that their Christian faith is a bit like the signal for Magic FM in the Chilterns: it comes and goes. But while Cameron the Christian is a typical nominal Anglican – church is for hatching, matching and dispatching, Christmas and Remembrance Sunday – Johnson’s involvement with religion has been far more topsy-turvy and dramatic. Who would have thought, when he became prime minister in 2019, that he would stop the balancing act and instead become a standard bearer for Roman Catholicism as the first occupant of No 10 to practise the religion?
Johnson’s religious life has been as chequered as his political career. Baptised as a baby into the Roman Catholic faith of his mother, Charlotte Johnson Wahl, he veered off at Eton into Anglicanism and was confirmed into the Church of England. Little is known of Johnson’s faith in the years that followed, apart from that Chilterns gag: he was busy editing the Spectator, becoming an MP, performing tripwire stunts as mayor of London, and developing a reputation for a rackety private life. But now the radio signal seems to be coming through loud and clear, although it’s been retuned to the old ways – a sort of religious equivalent of rediscovering the Home Service. He’s back in the Catholic fold.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Catherine Pepinster</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harry Dunn death: Johnson and Biden discuss virtual trial for US diplomat’s wife]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/harry-dunn-death-johnson-and-biden-discuss-virtual-trial-for-alleged-killer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/harry-dunn-death-johnson-and-biden-discuss-virtual-trial-for-alleged-killer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T10:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Idea being pursued by Dominic Raab might allow Anne Sacoolas to face punishment in US
Britain is pressing for the wife of a US diplomat to go on virtual trial over the death of Harry Dunn, who was killed when a car crashed into his motorbike outside a US military base in Northamptonshire two years ago.
The UK foreign secretary, Dominic Raab, is pursuing the idea of a virtual trial, which would possibly allow Anne Sacoolas to face some form of punishment in the US rather than being extradited back to the UK. The solution was proposed at a meeting on Thursday between the UK prime minister, Boris Johnson, and the US president, Joe Biden.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man held in Italy over UK Vietnamese migrant deaths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/man-held-in-italy-over-uk-vietnamese-migrant-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/man-held-in-italy-over-uk-vietnamese-migrant-deaths"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T09:46:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Damian Dragos, 28-year-old Romanian citizen, is accused of providing truck in people-smuggling case
Italian police have arrested a man wanted by the UK in connection with a people-smuggling plot that led to the death of 39 Vietnamese migrants in the back of a lorry.
Stefan Damian Dragos, a 28-year-old Romanian citizen, is accused of having provided the truck that transported the migrants to England, according to a police statement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Rome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Enjoying yourself?': Queen jokes with G7 leaders in family photo – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/jun/12/enjoying-yourself-queen-jokes-with-g7-leaders-in-family-photo-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/jun/12/enjoying-yourself-queen-jokes-with-g7-leaders-in-family-photo-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T09:08:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen caused G7 world leaders to break out into laughter as she cracked a joke when they posed for a photo at an evening reception hosted by the monarch on Friday. ‘Are you supposed to be looking as if you're enjoying yourself?’ she asked as they posed for photographers, to which Boris Johnson could be heard replying: ‘Yes, definitely. We have been enjoying ourselves in spite of appearances’

All the Queen’s presidents: Biden joins long line of US leaders to meet royal
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Did they give life? No! So how can they take it?’: on the frontline of knife crime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/did-they-give-life-no-so-how-can-they-take-it-on-the-frontline-of-knife</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/12/did-they-give-life-no-so-how-can-they-take-it-on-the-frontline-of-knife"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T09:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As stabbings surged across London, Ciaran Thapar became a mentor to young boys whose lives were in danger. One of his mentees, Jhemar Jonas, showed him how a life beset by violence can still provide hope

Jhemar got home from school at 5pm. His mum and dad were out. He threw his bag down in his room and started playing Gran Turismo Sport on his PlayStation in the living room. He kept thinking about how he and his older half-brother Michael were going to catch up on Sunday. He hadn’t seen him in months; he was counting down the days.
His mum arrived home from work at 8.30pm.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ciaran Thapar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dog daycare: who will look after your pet when you go in to work?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/dog-daycare-who-will-care-for-your-pet-when-you-go-in-to-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/dog-daycare-who-will-care-for-your-pet-when-you-go-in-to-work"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T08:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dogs became used to owners being around more in Covid lockdowns but there are ways to make being apart easier and cheaper
Over the past year, dogs have provided locked-down owners with comfort, company and a reason to head out for long restorative walks. There are 12 million of them in the UK, according to data from the Pet Food Manufacturers’ Association. And because of the coronavirus pandemic, a whole generation of puppies have never spent any time alone, while older dogs have got used to always having someone around. Now that we can leave the house again, that may be about to change.
“Our biggest concern as people start returning to work outside the home is that pets will need to adapt to a very different routine and may experience some anxiety around being separated from the owners they’ve spent every day with during lockdown,” says Daniella Dos Santos, a vet and the senior vice-president of the British Veterinary Association. “Owners should spend time gradually getting pets used to being left alone or in different settings and make sure these experiences are positive.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Haurant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixing Britons’ food with politics invariably leaves a bad taste | Pen Vogler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/britons-food-politics-brexit-sausage-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/12/britons-food-politics-brexit-sausage-war"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T08:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Brexit sausage war is nothing new: it follows an inglorious lineage that stretches all the way back to Hogarth’s Gin Lane 
It’s summer at last! Time to gather a few neighbours round, start a fire, and throw another sausage war on to the flames. This one is about the complicated triangulation between the EU, Northern Ireland and Westminster over frictionless trade. Still awake? Let’s put it in terms “the public” can understand and, as former Brexit chief negotiator David Frost did, thunder about the right of “the shopper in Strabane” to get their favourite sausages or chicken nuggets. In fact, from Hogarth’s Gin Lane, right through to the pasty tax, politicians have scored political points around food, as a distraction from more important matters, such as whether children get fed.
If you were of telly-watching age in 1984, there might be a familiar whiff to Frost’s words. In Yes, Minister the not overly competent but endlessly fortunate minister, Jim Hacker, grappled with a rumoured proposal from Brussels to have the British sausage renamed the “emulsified high-fat offal tube”. Westminster is traditionally reluctant to get involved in our personal relationship with our shopping baskets and arteries. It still feels the pain of burnt fingers from the “hot pasty tax”; or Edwina Currie’s throwaway 1988 remark about the prevalence of salmonella in British egg production, which crashed consumer confidence overnight (it was reported that the industry had to slaughter four million hens). The knotty issues around processed meat products are delegated to food and health campaigners who would like Britons to eat a lot fewer, for the sake of our health, our waistlines and the welfare of the animals who end up in them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pen Vogler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden’s reforming agenda at risk of dying a slow death in Congress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/joe-biden-reforming-agenda-slow-death-congress</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/12/joe-biden-reforming-agenda-slow-death-congress"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:45:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transformational change, such as a huge infrastructure bill and voting rights protections, are hamstrung by antiquated procedures that give an effective veto to the minority
Joe Biden’s first hundred days surpassed progressive expectations with the scope of their ambition. His second hundred days are being mugged by reality: the one that says Washington DC is a place where dreams go to die.
A once-in-a-generation investment in infrastructure and the climate crisis has hit a wall. Reforms on gun safety, immigration and police brutality are in limbo. Legislation to expand voting rights and reduce the influence of money in politics appears doomed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘There’s a concerted backlash’: Ibram X Kendi on antiracism under attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/ibram-x-kendi-antiracism-backlash-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/ibram-x-kendi-antiracism-backlash-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservatives have made the whitewashing of US history the latest front in the culture wars, picking the author of How to Be an Antiracist as a scapegoat
A whitewashing of history is under way in red state America. Republican officials are proposing numerous laws to ban school teachers from emphasizing the role of systemic racism in shaping the nation.
And every reactionary backlash needs a scapegoat. Conservatives have settled on two prominent people of colour to accuse of indoctrinating American children: Nikole Hannah-Jones, a journalist who oversaw the 1619 Project, and Ibram X Kendi, author of the influential book How to Be an Antiracist.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Murray: ‘Don’t be sad for me! I like doing this – no one’s forcing me to play’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/andy-murray-dont-be-sad-for-me-i-like-doing-this-no-ones-forcing-me-to-play</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/12/andy-murray-dont-be-sad-for-me-i-like-doing-this-no-ones-forcing-me-to-play"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been a tumultuous five years for Andy Murray: countless injuries, a new metal hip, four children and a bout of Covid. Can the former world No 1 really battle his way back to brilliance at Wimbledon? 
Is he or isn’t he? One minute Andy Murray, one of Britain’s greatest living athletes, tells me he’ll be back on the court at Wimbledon this month, playing well in the tournament that made his name. And the next, he doesn’t sound so sure. “The test is being on court with the best players,” he says in a break in training, “and that’s something that, right this second, is difficult to give a definitive answer to.”
The joy of sport is its unpredictability, but Murray’s not talking about that. His body has been through such immense stress and strain – throughout his career, but especially over the past few years – that he can’t rely on it. He genuinely doesn’t know what it can do.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alt ice-cream enters mainstream as UK sales rise with the temperature]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/12/alt-ice-cream-enters-mainstream-as-uk-sales-rise-with-the-temperature</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/12/alt-ice-cream-enters-mainstream-as-uk-sales-rise-with-the-temperature"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may use peas or coconut and not cow’s milk but experts say plant-based ice-cream now makes up 14% of the market
It is ice-cream but not as you know it. From instagrammable lollies bursting with fruit to treats made from coconut and peas rather than cow’s milk, an explosion of choice will see Britons spend an extra £100m on ice-cream this year.
Industry experts said with sales of plant-based foods booming around the worldalt ice-cream was now entering the mainstream as brands did a better job mimicking the creamy taste of dairy despite using alternative ingredients such as coconut cream, oats, almonds and peas in their recipes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a Sin: Colin’s death inspired by my husband’s, says Russell T Davies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/12/my-husbands-death-inspired-its-a-sin-scene-says-russell-t-davies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/12/my-husbands-death-inspired-its-a-sin-scene-says-russell-t-davies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In new Guardian podcast, TV dramatist tells Grace Dent about writing character’s final hours
Russell T Davies, the writer of It’s a Sin, the Channel 4 drama about the HIV/Aids epidemic in the late 1980s, has revealed that the death of Colin, one of show’s characters, was partly based on the death of his partner.
Speaking to the food writer Grace Dent on a new Guardian podcast, Comfort Eating, which launches on Tuesday, Davies said he had drawn on the experience of watching his husband, Andrew Smith, die from brain cancer in 2018 to write the scenes featuring Colin’s death.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’re causing our own misery’: oceanographer Sylvia Earle on the need for sea conservation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Queen of the Deep’ says it is not too late to reverse human-made damage to oceans and preserve biodiversity
The world has the opportunity in the next 10 years to restore our oceans to health after decades of steep decline – but to achieve that, people must wake up to the problem, join in efforts to protect marine areas and stop eating tuna, according to the oceanographer and deep sea explorer Sylvia Earle.
“We are at the most exciting time maybe ever to be a human, because we’re armed with knowledge,” said Earle, also known as the Queen of the Deep and “her Deepness”. Earle has also set numerous records for deep sea diving, and was the first woman to serve as chief scientist of the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every year, I take a long walk with friends. it's one of life's greatest pleasures | Marcel Theroux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/12/walking-with-friends-marcel-theroux-lifes-simplest-greatest-pleasures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/12/walking-with-friends-marcel-theroux-lifes-simplest-greatest-pleasures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T06:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For 16 years, I have met up with five friends for an annual yomp in the English countryside – and we are enjoying that companionship more than ever

On the first weekend of May this year, I met up with five of my oldest male friends at Waterloo station, took a train to Milford in Surrey, walked 12 miles across Bagmoor Common and the Devil’s Punch Bowl, stopped for lunch at The Three Horseshoes in Thursley, caught the train back to London from Haslemere, drank too much beer under an awning on the South Bank and went home. At the end of the day, the step counter on my phone said 42,235.
For the past 16 years, we’ve been doing something similar roughly every year. When we inaugurated this accidental tradition, smartphones weren’t a thing, Tony Blair was still prime minister and my friends had much more hair. The first walk we did was a three-day ramble along the Coleridge Way in Somerset and north Devon. It was a fantastic route: 50 miles of moorland and rolling hills. But at the time, there was still a faint air of incredulity about what we were doing. Going walking seemed like an absurdly grown-up activity.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcel Theroux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blind date: ‘She said I could be Justin Trudeau’s younger brother’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/blind-date-luca-charlie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/12/blind-date-luca-charlie"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T05:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Luca, 24, medical librarian, meets Charlie, 26, executive assistant
What were you hoping for?
I moved to London during lockdown so was looking to meet new people and have a fun night out. (Maybe also secretly looking for “the one”.)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain’s right unites in fury as PM considers Catalan pardons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/spain-right-unites-fury-sanchez-considers-catalan-pardons</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/spain-right-unites-fury-sanchez-considers-catalan-pardons"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T04:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rightwing parties condemn prime minister’s call to work for ‘co-existence’ with separatists
On Sunday thousands of people, among them the leaders of the three parties on Spain’s right, will once again gather in the Madrid square that boasts the world’s largest Spanish flag to protest against the Socialist-led government’s handling of the Catalan independence crisis.
In February 2019, in a deeply controversial moment immortalised in photographs of the occasion, the conservative People’s party (PP), the centre-right Citizens party and the far-right Vox party joined forces in the Plaza de Colón to accuse the prime minister, Pedro Sánchez, of betraying Spain, and to call for an early election.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is a Disaster Recovery Plan? How to Use RTO and RPO to Protect your Business]]></title>
        <id>60b72d5facb62507dd1d777b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/disaster-recovery-plan-what-are-rto-and-rpo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T22:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're in the world of tech, you will inevitably run into a work-related disaster now and then. These setbacks come in many forms such as cyber-attacks, theft, leaks, and corruption. And every business must be ready to face these things and plan for them. Sir Benjamin Franklin famously said,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342429</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/safari-15-new-ui-theme-colors-and-a-css-tricks-cameo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a 33-minute video (and resources) over on apple.com covering the upcoming Safari changes we saw in the WWDC keynote this year in much more detail. Look who’s got a little cameo in there:
Perhaps the most noticeable thing there …
The post Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Queen’s birthday list honours key figures in UK Covid vaccine drive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/11/queens-birthday-list-honours-uk-covid-vaccine-taskforce-kate-bingham</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/11/queens-birthday-list-honours-uk-covid-vaccine-taskforce-kate-bingham"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taskforce chief Kate Bingham gets damehood and Oxford research leaders also rewarded
Key figures in the battle against Covid-19 and Britain’s vaccine success have been rewarded in the Queen’s birthday honours list, with vaccines taskforce chair Kate Bingham getting a damehood.
Honours are also bestowed on two leaders of the research teams at the Oxford Vaccine Centre who developed and manufactured a vaccine backed by the pharmaceutical giant AstraZeneca. Prof Sarah Gilbert, Saïd professor of vaccinology at the Jenner Institute, becomes a dame while Prof Andrew Pollard, professor of paediatric infection at the University of Oxford, gets a knighthood.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Possibilities of Syndication]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342237</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-possibilities-of-syndication/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s the one word that isn’t an adjective in the acronym RSS. 
Really Simple Syndication.
RSS isn’t just about RSS readers. Even though, gosh if I don’t love RSS readers. It’s about putting content in a format that is …
The post The Possibilities of Syndication appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Center Anything in CSS Using Flexbox and Grid ✨]]></title>
        <id>6063b9189618b008528a9d81</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-center-objects-using-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T20:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I'm gonna show you how you can center and align your content with CSS. Along the way, we'll look at various alignment techniques. So, let's get started! 🥇 Table of Contents -> How to Use Flexbox to center anything horizontally center anything vertically center both horizontally & Vertically How]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/11/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/11/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T20:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aftermath of the conflict in Gaza and Israel; the crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region; the 77th anniversary of D-day and the election in Peru: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Design Keyboard Accessibility for Complex React Experiences]]></title>
        <id>5f9c97e9740569d1a4ca1768</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/designing-keyboard-accessibility-for-complex-react-experiences/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How you can design an inclusive and accessible org chart experience and solutions to common development challenges you will face.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Quite a show’: G7 razzmatazz in the air as Carbis Bay hosts world leaders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/quite-a-show-g7-razzmatazz-in-the-air-as-carbis-bay-hosts-world-leaders</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/quite-a-show-g7-razzmatazz-in-the-air-as-carbis-bay-hosts-world-leaders"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:52:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Opinions are divided about the impact the summit is having on the lives and businesses of St Ives in Cornwall
It was a day of strange juxtapositions and curious culture clashes. The children playing beach cricket paused from time to time to gaze out at the naval ship looming out of the mist or peer skywards when a helicopter clattered over. Holidaymakers ate fish and chips and drank pints as thousands of eco protesters marched past the harbour-side restaurants, banging drums, blowing whistles, chanting and singing.
A group of teenagers took selfies in front of a burly Royal Navy bomb disposal expert while a character dressed as Batman with the sign: “Give peace a chance” pinned to his back cycled past.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on an Atlantic charter: new rules for new threats | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/11/the-guardian-view-on-an-atlantic-charter-new-rules-for-new-threats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/11/the-guardian-view-on-an-atlantic-charter-new-rules-for-new-threats"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:39:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden sees an increasingly dangerous world which in some ways resembles the 1930s. He’s right to update the way democracies cooperate
Before the second world war, states acted as they wished in international affairs, limited only by their resources and power. These circumstances began to change in August 1941, before America joined the allied cause. On a battleship off the coast of Newfoundland, the US president Franklin Roosevelt and the British prime minister Winston Churchill issued the Atlantic charter at a time when Nazi Germany appeared to be decisively winning the European war. A few months later, America, Britain, the Soviet Union and 23 other governments declared in the name of “United Nations” an intention to regulate the postwar world based on three revolutionary principles: free trade, non-aggression and democracy.
Eighty years later, Joe Biden and Boris Johnson have signed a new Atlantic charter, to reflect a world of different threats and one in which the UK is a much diminished power. Mr Biden looks out and sees an increasingly dangerous world. In some ways the vista resembles the 1930s – with populists, nationalists and demagogues on the rise, European powers divided, and democracy vulnerable to foreign manipulation. There’s no mention of China in the 604-word charter, but it is the undeclared target of many of the policies regarding debt transparency, freedom of navigation and protecting the west’s “innovative edge”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on children’s homes: no place for profit | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/11/the-guardian-view-on-childrens-homes-no-place-for-profit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/11/the-guardian-view-on-childrens-homes-no-place-for-profit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:39:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Treating the most vulnerable young people as a money-making opportunity is wrong. The care review must lead to change
It is impossible, even for an appointee regarded by critics as too close to government and with overly restricted terms of reference, to look at children’s homes without being appalled by what is going on. That is the conclusion to be drawn from remarks this week by Josh MacAlister, who is several months into a long-awaited review of children’s social care. He warned that the sector is broken and that operators must cut “indefensible” levels of profit and improve young people’s experiences.
Recent years have seen numerous reports and complaints by official bodies about a dysfunctional system, in which councils on the verge of bankruptcy pay ever increasing prices (up 40% since 2013, to about £200,000 a year per child) while profits soar. Private companies are making an estimated £250m profit annually out of 16,000 children who live in children’s homes in England, Wales and Scotland (a much larger number of children, around 65,000, live in foster care).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ask Good Technical Questions – the Ultimate Guide]]></title>
        <id>60bc0444acb62507dd1d9a31</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-ask-good-technical-questions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:39:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing how to ask effective technical questions is an essential skill every software engineer should have.  You may be stuck with a bug, unable to figure out why your program isn't working correctly, or you might be having trouble learning how to implement a certain algorithm. In all of these]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Level Up Your React Conditionals]]></title>
        <id>60c24cf8d3126007592d61d5</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-react-conditionals/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T16:04:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you write conditionals correctly within your React applications?  Good conditionals are an essential part of any React application. We use conditionals to show or hide elements or components in our applications.  In short – to be an effective React developer, you must know how to write good conditionals. Let's go]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is the UK sleepwalking into authoritarian rule? | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/11/is-the-uk-sleepwalking-into-authoritarian-rule</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/11/is-the-uk-sleepwalking-into-authoritarian-rule"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:57:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jeremy Cushing on how the government is attacking and undermining the institutions of democracy, Blaine Stothard on ministers’ demands for total conformity of beliefs and values, and Pat Farrington on the Tories’ cynical attempts to keep hold of power
Another verdict goes against the government (Covid contract for firm run by Cummings’ friends unlawful, finds judge, 9 June). Amid much discussion of the Good Law Project’s activities, however, one question goes unanswered: given that democracies need a lively independent scrutiny of government, what is the sanction?
The government reacts, as we have now come to expect, with lies and threats. The GLP itself is the target of accusations that it is “misusing crowdfunding”, and the government uses taxpayers’ money to run up huge costs, which the GLP is at risk of having to pay. The court is under the threat of legislation to curb the use of judicial review.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last chance to reverse the UK’s shameful international aid cuts | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/last-chance-to-reverse-the-uks-shameful-international-aid-cuts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/last-chance-to-reverse-the-uks-shameful-international-aid-cuts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:52:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desmond Whyms on the opportunity this weekend’s G7 meeting presents for global leaders to put pressure on the British government. Plus, Henrietta L Moore on what leaders must do to genuinely ‘Build Back Better’
World leaders are meeting this weekend a few miles from my home in Penzance, Cornwall, in what could be our best and last chance to reverse the UK’s destructive aid cuts that followed the Foreign Office takeover of the Department for International Development last year.
Up to March of this year, I was proud to work for DfID, having spent many years supporting health systems and confronting disease in some of the most challenging settings in the world. Most recently, I was senior health adviser in Malawi, one of the world’s poorest countries, where our support was vital to confronting Covid-19 and ensuring women can access reproductive health services. The shameful and heartbreaking prospect of having to dismantle this vital support led me to resign and seek more worthwhile employment elsewhere.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 leaders in Cornwall – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/11/g7-leaders-in-cornwall-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/11/g7-leaders-in-cornwall-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:26:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 leaders have opened their first in-person talks in nearly two years. Welcomed by Boris Johnson to the beachside summit venue in Carbis Bay, Cornwall, the leaders posed for a photograph before opening their first session of talks
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wish you were here? 13 photos that reveal what the G7 summit is really like]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/wish-you-were-here-13-photos-that-reveal-what-the-g7-summit-is-really-like</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/wish-you-were-here-13-photos-that-reveal-what-the-g7-summit-is-really-like"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T14:46:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jill Biden and Carrie Johnson play happy families, Justin Trudeau channels Laurence Llewelyn-Bowen, giant Pikachus descend on a beach – and more
It’s that time again – the G7 summit. It was previously the G8 summit, until the Russians went full Russia and, rather than receiving coordinated international condemnation and effective sanctions, were kicked out of this faintly ridiculous rigmarole as “punishment”.
This year’s is being held in Carbis Bay, Cornwall. Very rarely are things achieved at these summits. The best thing about them is the opportunity to laugh at the photographs, which somehow are even more excruciating than the usual political photo ops.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Jane Parkinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342164</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/adding-shadows-to-svg-icons-with-css-and-svg-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would we need to apply shadows to SVG?
Shadows are a common design feature that can help elements, like icons, stand out. They could be persistent, or applied in different states (e.g. :hover, :focus, or :active) 
…
The post Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Olawanle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bake Off to Inside No 9: what to watch instead of the Euros]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/11/euro-alternative-bake-off-inside-no-9-zelda-time-katla</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/11/euro-alternative-bake-off-inside-no-9-zelda-time-katla"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T12:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A football-free cultural guide to the week ahead, from comedy podcasts to Sean Bean dramas
Listen, I’m with you. I have no interest in Euro 2020 either. But luckily, over the years I’ve perfected the art of finding other things to do. Here’s a day-by-day alternative viewing guide for the first week of the tournament (after that, you’re on your own).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your ingenious holiday packing hacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T11:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on what to pack and how to maximise your wardrobe while travelling
For those of us lucky enough to be able to go on holiday this summer, there’s always one issue: what to pack? And more importantly, how to pack efficiently.
With this in mind, we want to hear about your best packing hacks. Perhaps you’ve discovered the secret to maximising your wardrobe? Or maybe you swear by soap and shampoo bars over liquid toiletries, to avoid leakage in your luggage? Whether it’s a must-have gadget, or a space-saving tip, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[António Guterres on the climate crisis: ‘We are coming to a point of no return’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/11/antonio-guterres-interview-climate-crisis-pandemic-g7</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/11/antonio-guterres-interview-climate-crisis-pandemic-g7"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T04:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UN secretary general says he’s concerned that the richest nations have pumped billions more into fossil fuels than clean energy since the pandemic
Wealthy countries risk an “unforgivable lost opportunity” by not emerging from the Covid-19 pandemic with newly green economies to address the climate crisis, the United Nations secretary general has warned.
Before meeting the leaders of the world’s major economic powers at the G7 summit in the UK, António Guterres said he was concerned that the richest nations have pumped billions of dollars more into fossil fuels than clean energy since the pandemic, despite their promises of a green recovery.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News enters the culture war - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T02:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To its critics, it is a British Fox News; to its creators, it is a vital correction to a liberal London-centric media. Can Andrew Neil’s upstart news channel change the face of British broadcasting?
For years, Britain’s rolling news landscape has been dominated by Sky and the BBC. On Sunday, a new rival, GB News, is entering the fray – and although its chairman and most famous face, Andrew Neil, insists that any comparisons to Fox News are idiotic, many see an echo in its plan to use outspoken presenters to discuss the most controversial issues of the day. 
But Neil insists that the plan is not to tack to the right, but to address an audience which he says has been let down by the existing broadcasters – and which he believes is crying out for a channel that addresses its concerns. As the channel’s newly hired team race to be ready for their debut, Anushka Asthana asks the Guardian’s media editor, Jim Waterson, whether GB News is bound to be a participant in the so-called culture war – and whether a British audience really wants to see a radical departure from the more traditional model that dominates today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Jim Waterson; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put a Background on Open Details Elements]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342050</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/put-a-background-on-open-details-elements/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T00:16:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One thing that can be just a smidge funky about the <details> element is that, when open, it’s not always 100% clear what is inside that element and what isn’t. I’m not saying that always matters or that it’s a …
The post Put a Background on Open Details Elements appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Takeaway food and drink litter dominates ocean plastic, study shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/takeaway-food-and-drink-litter-dominates-ocean-plastic-study-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/takeaway-food-and-drink-litter-dominates-ocean-plastic-study-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:41:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just 10 plastic products make up 75% of all items and scientists say the pollution must be stopped at source
Plastic items from takeaway food and drink dominate the litter in the world’s oceans, according to the most comprehensive study to date.
Single-use bags, plastic bottles, food containers and food wrappers are the four most widespread items polluting the seas, making up almost half of the human-made waste, the researchers found. Just 10 plastic products, also including plastic lids and fishing gear, accounted for three-quarters of the litter, due to their widespread use and extremely slow degradation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341894</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/equal-columns-with-flexbox-its-more-complicated-than-you-might-think/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As awesome as flexbox is, what it’s doing under the hood is actually a little strange because, by default, it is doing two things at once. It first looks at the content size which is what we would get if by declaring width: max-content on an element. But on top of that, flex-shrink is also doing some work allowing the items to be smaller, but only if needed.
Let’s break those two down and see how they work together.
The post Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-headless-cms-with-fauna-and-vercel-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will learn and use headless CMS, Fauna, and Vercel functions to build a blogging platform, Blogify After that, you can easily build any web application using a headless CMS, Fauna and Vercel functions.
The post Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ikeh Akinyemi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar eclipse 2021: the crescent sun – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:27:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From New Jersey to Milton Keynes, skygazers in the northern hemisphere were able to see a partial solar eclipse, witnessing a crescent sun in an eclipsed sunrise in some parts of the world

Solar eclipse 2021: spectacle visible across UK and Ireland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A breathing space’: photo exhibition tells the story of a Cardiff park]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-breathing-space-photo-exhibition-tells-the-story-of-a-cardiff-park</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-breathing-space-photo-exhibition-tells-the-story-of-a-cardiff-park"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:40:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heath Park adjoins University hospital of Wales, Wales’ biggest hospital, and is used by NHS staff and locals from north Cardiff. Young photographers Tomos Kay and Tom Gower capture some of the park’s regulars. The park has over 10 football pitches, large wooded areas, ponds, a small golf course, tennis courts and a large model railway.
A Park for Our Time outdoor exhibition in Heath Park, Cardiff runs from Friday 11 June to Sunday 13 June
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Photographs: Tomos Kay and Tom Gower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Azure Data Fundamentals Certification (DP-900) – Pass the Exam With This Free 4.5-Hour Course]]></title>
        <id>60b93afaacb62507dd1d8915</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/azure-data-fundamentals-certification-dp-900-pass-the-exam-with-this-free-4-5-hour-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can learn everything you need to know to earn the Azure Data Fundamentals certification by completing this free 4.5 hour course. What is the Azure Data Fundamentals Certification?The Azure Data Fundamentals Certification is for those seeking a data-related role such as Data Analyst, Data Engineer, or Data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 and a crucial moment for the climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T02:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s richest democracies will come together in Britain this week with global heating high on the agenda. Can they match big promises with concrete action? 
The damage wrought by the coronavirus pandemic has been huge, but it pales in comparison to the potential risks associated with the climate crisis. With the world coalescing around the importance of limiting temperature rises to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, the next 10 years are the last chance to meet that goal - and with the Cop26 summit in Glasgow later this year, the G7 summit in Cornwall this week is the next staging post in a crucial six months to settle on a way forward.
But even as many countries set out significant pledges to do their part, the reality of their policies is often far behind. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s environment correspondent, Fiona Harvey, about what must happen to catch up with those commitments – and what this summit will tell us about the likelihood of making changes that are crucial to averting catastrophe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Fiona Harvey; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Slums of Mumbai to a Rented Apartment – My 30-Year Developer Journey]]></title>
        <id>60b357ad11ffb70827ef9a90</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-journey-into-tech-from-slums-of-mumbai-to-my-own-apartment/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year I tweeted about how I was moving from a Slum where I lived for 29 years to a multi-story rented apartment.  The tech community on Twitter responded with nothing but love. Dan Wahlin posted that he would love to hear more about my story. It's not going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cornucopia of Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340967</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-cornucopia-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know about y’all, but my feeds have been flooded with articles about CSS Container Queries these past few weeks. The buzz about container queries actually started back in December after Miriam Suzanne posted a proposal (picking up on …
The post A Cornucopia of Container Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Skills You Need to Start Freelancing as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60c0ccbed3126007592d5781</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-skills-you-need-to-start-freelancing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's the bottom line: you don't need much to get started as a freelance developer.  The biggest obstacle developers face when they're thinking about getting started is that they tend to overcomplicate things.  Most are intimidated by the sheer number of different paths or skills deemed necessary by various blog]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Bootstrap 5 and SASS by Building a Portfolio Website]]></title>
        <id>60c10a1dd3126007592d5988</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-bootstrap-5-and-sass-by-building-a-portfolio-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap is one of the most popular CSS frameworks and Sass is one of the most popular preprocessors for CSS. We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you about Bootstrap 5 and Sass by building a portfolio website. Patrick Muriungi developed this course.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[target=blank]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341916</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/targetblank/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does that make your eye twitch a little bit? Like… it’s a typo. It should be target="_blank" with an underscore to start the value. As in…
<a target="_blank" href="https://codepen.io"Open CodePen in a New Tab
</a
Welp, that’s correct syntax!…
The post target=blank appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have an example of UK car-led town planning you want to change?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of examples of car-led redevelopment where you live 
We’d like to find out how your UK town or city was redesigned for road vehicles.
From the 1950s onwards many towns and cities across the UK adopted car led planning in line with rising car ownership. Today, many residents in urban areas hope to have more environmentally friendly spaces and cleaner air which is at odds with past car led redevelopment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of your amazing sheds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about the impressive garden sheds you have built and customised
During lockdown some people have taken to sprucing up their sheds, whether it’s to give them a new lease of life or to create a haven away in the garden.
We would like to hear about your amazing sheds, however humble, and what they mean to you. If you have customised yours, what inspired you? What do you use it for?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The interrogation of Matt Hancock - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T02:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two weeks after Dominic Cummings told MPs that the health secretary was a serial liar who lost the trust of No 10, Matt Hancock will face the same committee to defend himself. Heather Stewart explains what is at stake, and what it could mean for the next stage of the pandemic
When Dominic Cummings appeared before MPs to set out his account of what went wrong in the early stages of the Covid pandemic, he attempted a political assassination. But a fortnight later, Matt Hancock, the health secretary, is still limping on. So far, Hancock has been able to bat away questions from journalists, and at the dispatch box, without much trouble, and has retained the support of the prime minister. But a grilling by MPs, who will have much more time and the chance to follow up on their questions, will present him with a far greater challenge.
Hancock’s day of reckoning comes with the 21 June planned unlocking still uncertain, and the number of cases rising again, so his future will have profound consequences for the country. Rachel Humphreys spoke to the Guardian’s political editor, Heather Stewart, about the questions he is likely to face, the light his answers could shed on what went wrong, and why Boris Johnson appears determined to stick with his man — for now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Heather Stewart; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy Your freeCodeCamp Project on AWS – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide to the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>60bfa4d4d3126007592d5160</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-your-freecodecamp-project-on-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T23:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One night in June, 2017 I stumbled across a website called freecodecamp.org. I was a teacher at the time who was looking for a career change. But I assumed being a programmer was out of my reach. After all, I didn’t consider myself a math whiz, never went]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341982</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/looking-at-wcag-2-5-5-for-better-target-sizes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever experienced the frustration of trying to tap a button on a mobile device only to have it do nothing because the target size is just not large enough **and it’s not picking up on your press? Maybe …
The post Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Todd Libby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341884</id>
        <link href="https://alex.party/posts/2021-05-31-css-trickz-an-experiment-with-netlify-s-on-demand-builders/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress sites have an API by default. Wanna see this site’s most recent posts, with just a specific set of data… in JSON format? Here ya go. Alex Riviere made a joke site using that.
At first, the site …
The post CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you planning on joining protests at the G7 summit?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from people who’re planning on demonstrating during this week’s G7 summit in Cornwall 
 Later this week, world leaders will be attending the G7 summit, at Carbis Bay, near St Ives in Cornwall, to discuss global issues including the Covid pandemic and climate change.
The coalition comprises seven countries; the UK, Japan, US, Italy, Germany, Canada and France.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katie Piper and Candice Brathwaite on how emotions affect their complexions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you break out in a rash when you’re stressed, you’re not alone. Find out how two women in the public eye cope when anxiety affects their skin – and discover the science behind the spots
Spots, rashes and flushing can often affect your emotions, making you self-conscious or even embarrassed. But did you know that, conversely, heightened emotions can aggravate your skin, making it vulnerable to breakouts – and that this is scientifically recognised?
“It’s been shown, on a molecular level, that there are changes to the chemicals in the skin when we get stressed,” says consultant dermatologist Dr Justine Hextall. “The blood vessels dilate and then you often get a flushed red face.” Stress will change the skin barrier, the outer layer of skin cells and the ceramides, cholesterols and fatty acids that hold them together, making inflammation more likely.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fielding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>