<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-14T00:30:17.613Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-14T00:30:17.613Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paulo Fonseca agrees to become the new manager of Tottenham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/paulo-fonseca-agrees-to-become-the-new-manager-of-tottenham-hotspur</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/paulo-fonseca-agrees-to-become-the-new-manager-of-tottenham-hotspur"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:11:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portuguese manager to sign three-year deal this week
Tottenham turned to Fonseca after move for Conte collapsed

Tottenham are set to appoint Paulo Fonseca as their new manager this week on an expected three-year deal. Spurs’ new director of football, Fabio Paratici, made a move for the former Roma manager following the collapse of talks with former Chelsea and Inter manager Antonio Conte.
 Related: Daniel Levy the common denominator in Tottenham’s endless managerial farce | Jonathan Liew 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Romano and Marcus Christenson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectator in ‘serious condition’ after fall from Wembley stand at England match]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/spectator-in-serious-condition-after-fall-from-wembley-stand-at-england-match</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/spectator-in-serious-condition-after-fall-from-wembley-stand-at-england-match"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:02:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spokesperson from stadium and Uefa say fan fell just after kick-off and was given medical attention before being taken to hospital

A football fan was taken to hospital in what was said to be a “serious condition” after falling from the stands at Wembley stadium during England’s match against Croatia on Sunday afternoon.
A spokesperson from the stadium and Uefa said that the spectator fell just after kick-off and was given medical attention at the ground before being taken to hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adventures With the Painted People review – romantic revenge on a roamin’ Roman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/14/adventures-with-the-painted-people-review-romantic-revenge-on-a-roamin-roman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/14/adventures-with-the-painted-people-review-romantic-revenge-on-a-roamin-roman"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:01:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pitlochry Festival theatre
A Caledonian witch holds a Roman officer captive in David Greig’s drama of attraction and philosophical opposites 
Pitlochry Festival theatre already has a claim to be the most beautifully situated in the country. Now, with the advent of an outdoor amphitheatre deep in the neighbouring gardens, it has one of the most idyllic stages.
The amphitheatre is a perfect fit for the theatrical premiere of David Greig’s two-hander, set 20 miles along the Tay in Kenmore. Here, a Roman officer is held captive by a local witch from the self-styled “salmon people”. The colonisers’ contention that Caledonia is “barren” seems all the more ignorant as we sit in this verdant treescape.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware is biggest online threat to people in UK, spy agency chief to warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCHQ cybersecurity boss sounds alarm over extortion by hackers who are mostly based in former Soviet states
Ransomware represents the biggest threat to online security for most people and businesses in the UK, the head of GCHQ’s cybersecurity arm is to warn.
Lindy Cameron, chief executive of the National Cyber Security Centre, will say in a speech that the phenomenon, where hackers encrypt data and demand payment for it to be restored, is escalating and becoming increasingly professionalised.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh Defence and security editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News review – Andrew Neil’s alternative BBC? Utterly deadly stuff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/13/gb-news-review-andrew-neils-alternative-bbc-utterly-deadly-stuff</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/13/gb-news-review-andrew-neils-alternative-bbc-utterly-deadly-stuff"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T22:36:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ‘anti-woke’ news channel had Andrew Neil and Alan Sugar, but no Piers Morgan – and the opening night felt like the furthest thing from appointment TV imaginable. I give it a year
“Now is the time to do news differently,” said Andrew Neil as GB News went live on Sunday night. “We are committed to covering the people’s agenda, not the media’s agenda.” Not in the first hour you weren’t. Instead, Neil spent it introducing his new colleagues while – be still irony – indicting the woke numpties from traditional news channels stuck in the narcissistic Westminster bubble. There may have been news breaking during the hour (indeed it was scrolling on a ticker at the bottom of the screen) but it went unreported.
No matter. First up was Neil Oliver, former BBC archaeology presenter turned GB News current affairs presenter, whom Neil introduced as the King of Scotland. An ill-omened title, given that the last title holder was Idi Amin. “I seem to have come to the fore with opinions,” he told Andrew Neil. “People talk to me all the time. They come up to me when they’re walking the dogs. They no longer feel their voices or voices like theirs are out in the mainstream.” The thing to do, Neil baby, is not to slow down.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southgate’s England shows a tired Croatia who’s boss – Euro 2020 Football Daily]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/13/southgates-england-shows-a-tired-croatia-whos-boss-euro-2020-football-daily</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/13/southgates-england-shows-a-tired-croatia-whos-boss-euro-2020-football-daily"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T22:15:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Rushden is joined by Jonathan Wilson, Paul Macinnes and Barney Ronay to discuss England’s opening game win in the Euros.
Rate, review, share on Apple Podcasts, Soundcloud, Audioboom, Mixcloud, Acast and Stitcher, and join the conversation on Facebook, Twitter and email.
When Raheem Sterling scores, England win. Kalvin Phillips and Tyrone Mings justified Gareth Southgate’s selections with excellent performances that quietened – a bit – the clamour for Jack Grealish to be unleashed. Barney Ronay was at the game, and we ask Jonathan Wilson if there was anything about England’s performance which couldn’t be attributed to the genius of Marcelo Bielsa.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Max Rushden with Barney Ronay, Paul MacInnes and Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid cases fall across US but experts warn of dangers of vaccine hesitancy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/coronavirus-covid-19-cases-fall-vaccination-infection</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/coronavirus-covid-19-cases-fall-vaccination-infection"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T21:13:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health experts emphasize need for even those who have had disease to get inoculated
New cases of Covid-19 are declining across most of the US, even in some states with vaccine-hesitant populations.
But almost all states where cases are rising have lower-than-average vaccination rates and experts warned on Sunday that relief from the coronavirus pandemic could be fleeting in regions where few people get inoculated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dumfries heads Netherlands to 3-2 win and denies Ukraine’s dream comeback]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/netherlands-ukraine-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/netherlands-ukraine-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T20:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pulsating five-goal second half of this Group C match lit up day three of the tournament, as Ukraine staged a comeback from two behind with 12 minutes remaining, before Denzel Dumfries snatched a memorable headed winner moments from the final whistle. It forced bitter disappointment down Ukraine’s throat and gave the Netherlands the perfect start to a 10th European Championship challenge. Their victory in Amsterdam gave Frank de Boer’s Oranje three points to match those Austria picked up in Bucharest earlier in the day.
“This is the team that I would like to see,” said De Boer. “We played very balanced and also dominated. We can be proud and hopefully we can make some more steps like we have been doing so far.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Jackson at the Johan Cruyff Arena</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AOC suggests Justice Breyer should retire with Democrats in power]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/stephen-breyer-retire-supreme-court-alexandria-ocasio-cortez</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/stephen-breyer-retire-supreme-court-alexandria-ocasio-cortez"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T20:28:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congresswoman says she ‘leans toward’ backing the departure of the supreme court judge this summer
The Democratic congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez added her voice on Sunday to those of liberals who think the US supreme court justice Stephen Breyer should retire this summer.
Some liberals are keen to give Joe Biden the opportunity soon to pick a younger judge to bolster the left-leaning wing of the bench as it weathers a dominant conservative majority achieved under the Trump administration, and while the Democrats hold power in the White House and Congress.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Walters in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the world’s most fertile fishing ground is facing a ‘unique and dire’ threat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/why-the-worlds-most-fertile-fishing-ground-is-facing-a-unique-and-dire-threat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/why-the-worlds-most-fertile-fishing-ground-is-facing-a-unique-and-dire-threat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China’s Pacific fishing fleet has grown by 500% since 2012 and is taking huge quantities of tuna

Read more of our Pacific Plunder series here

Since long before the steel-hulled fishing boats from foreign countries arrived in the South Pacific its people have had their own systems for sharing the ocean’s catches.
In the New Zealand colony of Tokelau, in the middle of the region, the 1,400 people living on its three atolls practise a system called inati, which ensures every household gets fish.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Field</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delaying England’s Covid reopening ‘could keep thousands out of hospital’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/experts-back-four-week-delay-lifting-covid-restrictions-england-more-people-vaccinated</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/experts-back-four-week-delay-lifting-covid-restrictions-england-more-people-vaccinated"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T19:33:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Research backs four-week delay on lifting restrictions to allow more people to get jabs

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers have been told that a four-week delay to easing all Covid restrictions would probably prevent thousands of hospitalisations, as Boris Johnson prepares to tell the English public they will have to wait up to another month for “freedom day”.
The government roadmap out of lockdown earmarks 21 June for the last remaining coronavirus restrictions to be lifted in England, but the prime minister is expected to announce on Monday that the timetable will be pushed back by two to four weeks amid a rapid rise in cases of the Delta variant first detected in India.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on Joe Biden and Boris Johnson meeting at G7 – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/13/ben-jennings-joe-biden-boris-johnson-g7-summit-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/13/ben-jennings-joe-biden-boris-johnson-g7-summit-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T19:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pelosi: ‘beyond belief’ that Trump DoJ chiefs didn’t know of secret subpoenas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/trump-justice-department-phone-data-democrats-pelosi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/trump-justice-department-phone-data-democrats-pelosi"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T18:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[House speaker says reported seizure of Democrats’ private phone data undermined ‘rule of law’
The House speaker, Nancy Pelosi, said on Sunday it was “beyond belief” that the three top justice department officials of Donald Trump’s administration had been unaware of secret subpoenas seeking private data from the former president’s political opponents.
Jeff Sessions, Trump’s first pick as attorney general, his successor, William Barr, and the long-serving deputy attorney general Rod Rosenstein have all claimed to have no knowledge of the alleged attempts by their department to harvest information covertly from leading Democrats during the investigation into whether Donald Trump and his campaign utilized links with Russia during the 2016 election, according to CNN.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raheem Sterling supplies catharsis in England’s sun-kissed reemergence | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/raheem-sterling-brings-catharsis-to-englands-sun-kissed-reemergence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/raheem-sterling-brings-catharsis-to-englands-sun-kissed-reemergence"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T18:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Returning crowds supplied a boisterous human touch to an encouraging Euro 2020 opener for Gareth Southgate’s team
And, breathe. It was tight, slow-burn and even a little angsty at times. But as the final whistle blew a great rolling cheer came crackling around Wembley’s vast open tiers from a 18,497 crowd drunk on sun, drunk on England’s 1-0 defeat of Croatia and also, it must be said, drunk.
At the end of which England’s men have made a surefooted start to their Euro 2020 campaign, beating the most dangerous opponents in their group with strength in reserve and knots in the team still to be untangled.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay at Wembley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 partners survive small talk at ultimate office awayday | Helen Pidd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-partners-survive-small-talk-at-ultimate-office-awayday</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-partners-survive-small-talk-at-ultimate-office-awayday"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T18:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some summit spouses must have trust issues – why else would they turn up?
It could be said that anyone who voluntarily attends their partner’s office party is either a masochist or has trust issues. So, why, then, do the spouses of world leaders feel obliged to turn up to global summits?
Ordinarily, it appears that their only duty is to make small talk with their fellow spare parts while their other halves chew over the big issues of the day. At the G7 meeting in Cornwall this weekend, the Wags and Habs were also required to admire Boris Johnson’s latest child when he was rolled out before their beachfront BBQ.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Austria see off North Macedonia to earn first-ever European Championship win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/austria-north-macedonia-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/austria-north-macedonia-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:59:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Austria’s manager, Franco Foda, hailed his history makers after a 3-1 win over North Macedonia. Late goals from the substitutes Michael Gregoritsch and Marko Arnautovic in Bucharest earned the country their first victory at a European Championship.
Stefan Lainer had given Austria the lead, only for Goran Pandev to equalise for North Macedonia in the 28th minute on their first appearance at a major tournament.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli coalition ousts Netanyahu as prime minister after 12 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/benjamin-netanyahu-ousted-israel-prime-minister-coalition-12-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/benjamin-netanyahu-ousted-israel-prime-minister-coalition-12-years"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:58:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far-right former settler leader Naftali Bennett to be installed as prime minister

Benjamin Netanyahu: the former commando who became King Bibi

Israel’s longest-serving leader, Benjamin Netanyahu, has been ousted from office by a loose coalition of rivals from across the political spectrum, united by their wish to end his 12-year run in power.
The opposition leader, Yair Lapid, a centrist former TV news anchor, won a confidence vote in the Knesset, Israel’s parliament, by a razor-thin advantage of 60-59 seats on Sunday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saracens crush Ealing to close in on immediate return to Premiership]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/ealing-saracens-championship-play-off-first-leg-rugby-union-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/ealing-saracens-championship-play-off-first-leg-rugby-union-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Championship final first leg: Ealing 0-60 Saracens
Away side score eight tries including two for Billy Vunipola

Saracens have all but secured their return to the Premiership after a thumping eight-try victory at Ealing Trailfinders in the first leg of the Championship final. They take a 60-point lead back to their StoneX Stadium for nextSunday’s second leg which will be a mere formality. With Billy Vunipola to the fore and Owen Farrell imperious, put simply, they dished out a lesson to Ealing and perhaps sent a message to the Premiership sides that Saracens will not be making up the numbers next term.
 Related: Ealing dispute RFU ruling on failure to meet Premiership stadium criteria 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher at Trailfinders Sports Club</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson doesn’t quite get his big moment in the Cornish sunshine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-summit-boris-johnson-doesnt-quite-get-his-big-moment-cornish-sunshine-analysis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-summit-boris-johnson-doesnt-quite-get-his-big-moment-cornish-sunshine-analysis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:55:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: an unseemly spat over Brexit derailed the UK prime minister’s chance to impress on the global stage

 G7 summit: latest news and reaction

Delivering his closing press conference in the Carbis Bay hotel on Sunday, pale golden sand and azure sea visible behind him, Boris Johnson sought to play down the unseemly diplomatic spat that had marred his moment on the world stage.
“Actually, what happened at this summit was that there was a colossal amount of work on subjects that had absolutely nothing to do with Brexit,” he insisted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewing feud between France’s Kylian Mbappé and Olivier Giroud goes public]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/brewing-feud-between-frances-kylian-mbappe-and-olivier-giroud-goes-public</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/brewing-feud-between-frances-kylian-mbappe-and-olivier-giroud-goes-public"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:51:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Giroud comments after friendly deemed a swipe at Mbappé
Mbappé upset remarks made publicly and not to his face

A brewing feud between the France strikers Kylian Mbappé and Olivier Giroud has gone public, potentially threatening team unity before their opening Euro 2020 match against Germany.
It began on Tuesday after France’s 3-0 victory against Bulgaria in a friendly when Giroud suggested he was not getting the service he deserved – considered by some to be a swipe at Mbappé.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden reveals Queen asked about Putin and Xi during tea at Windsor Castle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/queen-hosts-joe-biden-for-tea-at-windsor-castle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/queen-hosts-joe-biden-for-tea-at-windsor-castle"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:47:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US president gives insight into his discussions with monarch in short visit after G7 summit in Cornwall
Joe Biden revealed the Queen had asked him about his Russian and Chinese counterparts, Vladimir Putin and Xi Jinping, during their 45-minute talk over tea at Windsor Castle, in the aftermath of the G7 summit on Sunday.
It was an exceptionally rare, if limited, insight into political discussions involving the British monarch: the contents of her regular weekly audiences with the British prime minister of the day are kept confidential.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh and Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Go Big: Ed Miliband on transforming Britain  | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/the-guardian-view-on-go-big-ed-miliband-on-transforming-britain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/the-guardian-view-on-go-big-ed-miliband-on-transforming-britain"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The former Labour leader lost an election but his opponents have gone on to adopt his ideas
If any Labour leader can claim to have won the argument and lost the election, it is surely Ed Miliband. In 2015, the Conservatives mocked “Red Ed” for proposing crazy socialist policies, such as nationalising railways, and said he was living in a Marxist universe for suggesting energy prices should be capped. Both measures have been adopted by Boris Johnson, and no communist spectre haunts Britain. Mr Miliband’s signature policies – such as opening a national investment bank, targeting regional infrastructure and encouraging business investment with tax incentives – continue to be pinched by the current government. The country we are living in owes as much to Mr Miliband’s leftwing economics as it does to Mr Johnson’s social conservatism.
When Mr Miliband points out in the Commons that the Tories have appropriated his ideas without the size of his ambition, cabinet ministers chuckle that “we are all revolutionaries now”. That is why a new book by Mr Miliband is an important political event. Whether to “Go Big”, as he proposes, or not is contested within Keir Starmer’s Labour party. The shadow business, energy and industrial secretary is right, however, to argue that only sweeping changes can remake societies so that they are fairer, more secure and more prosperous. Market-driven instability and the environmental crisis are profound challenges that require equally large solutions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British backing for Israel helps to sustain the unbearable status quo | Rafeef Ziadah]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/british-backing-israel-unbearable-status-quo-palestinians</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/british-backing-israel-unbearable-status-quo-palestinians"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:29:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diplomatic and military support – and a thriving arms trade – make the UK complicit in the oppression of Palestinians
I often tell my first-year politics students that the study of politics is the study of power. And what we saw last month, above all, was the glaring disparity in power between Israel and the Palestinians.
When Palestinians in Gaza and around the world celebrated the news of a ceasefire, breathing a sigh of relief, many commentators hailed it as a return to calm. For Palestinians, however, “calm” means a status quo of occupation, blockade, and repression.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rafeef Ziadah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Catalonia’s jailed separatists: time for magnanimity | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/the-guardian-view-on-catalonias-jailed-separatists-time-for-magnanimity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/the-guardian-view-on-catalonias-jailed-separatists-time-for-magnanimity"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:25:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spain’s prime minister, Pedro Sánchez, would be doing the right thing by pardoning the organisers of 2017’s illegal referendum
Madrid’s Plaza de Colón is home to the largest Spanish flag in the world, making it a natural focal point for demonstrations of rightwing patriotic fervour, particularly on matters related to Catalonia. On Sunday, it was packed again. Thousands of protesters made their feelings clear following reports that Spain’s socialist prime minister, Pedro Sánchez, is about to pardon the 12 Catalan politicians who were convicted over their roles in the illegal independence referendum of 2017.
The imprisonment of leading separatists such as Oriol Junqueras, the president of the Republican Left of Catalonia party (ERC), was a draconian response to an episode of foolhardy brinkmanship by the pro-independence movement. The jail sentences handed out to Mr Junqueras and eight other separatist leaders two years ago ranged from nine to 13 years. But a majority of Spaniards are in no mood for showing clemency. The Plaza de Colón demonstration may have been attended by Spain’s three main rightwing parties, but a recent poll found that fully 61% of respondents, and 53% of socialist voters, opposed the idea of pardons. Fewer than 30% were in favour. The failure of the jailed politicians to express any regret for their actions has hardened public opinion and was not lost on the judges of the Spanish supreme court, which has stated that issuing pardons would be “unacceptable”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novak Djokovic rallies to beat Stefanos Tsitsipas in epic French Open final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/french-open-final-report-novak-djokovic-stefanos-tsitsipas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/french-open-final-report-novak-djokovic-stefanos-tsitsipas"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:24:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Djokovic wins 6-7 (8), 2-6, 6-3, 6-2, 6-4
Serb claims his 19th grand slam title with Paris win

After the sheer willpower and strength it took to topple Rafael Nadal on his surface and his court on Friday, Novak Djokovic was charged with returning to the scene two days later and summoning his prime form once more against the second-best clay‑courter of the season.
For a fair amount of time during this match it was reasonable to ask if this was a challenge too far, as his own waning energy and the force that is Stefanos Tsitsipas combined to create a two-set deficit for the Serb. Instead, Djokovic pulled off the type of manic recovery he has made look routine for over a decade, recovering to force five sets and eventually defeat Tsitsipas 6-7 (6), 2-6, 6-3, 6-2, 6-4 and win his second French Open title.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[London boat dwellers protest against plans they say could leave them homeless]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/london-boat-dwellers-protest-against-plans-to-drive-them-from-their-homes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/london-boat-dwellers-protest-against-plans-to-drive-them-from-their-homes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T17:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boaters fear that the Canal and River Trust’s plans to trial ‘water safety zones’ will lead to a big reduction in mooring spaces

The sun shone, the water sparkled and the trumpets blared as a flotilla of boat dwellers staged a protest in east London on Sunday about proposals they say will drive them out of their homes.
Dozens of boats, bearing banners with slogans such as “Boats are homes” and “Stop the boat cull”, contributed to a carnival atmosphere as they made their way along the River Lea in Hackney. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This G7 reflects our G-zero world, ruled by self-interest instead of global ambition | Tom Kibasi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/g7-g-zero-world-national-self-interest-parochially</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/g7-g-zero-world-national-self-interest-parochially"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:57:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just when leadership is required, those nations with the capacity to do so are thinking parochially 
The Atlantic charter of 1941, signed by then prime minister, Winston Churchill, and US president, Franklin D Roosevelt, set out the principles that would govern the postwar world. From self-determination to international trade to “a world free from want and fear”, its ambitions were lofty and its goals expansive. We live today with its legacy.
Some 80 years on, Boris Johnson and Joe Biden signed what was termed a “new Atlantic charter” ahead of the G7 meeting in Cornwall. But the new Atlantic charter reflects the diminished status of both the US and Britain in the 21st century. It set out some sensible areas for bilateral cooperation – from quantum computing to air travel – but there was little of lasting note. These were not two world leaders charting the future for humankind, nor indeed for post-Brexit Britain: there was not even a promise of a US-UK trade deal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Kibasi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero-hours contracts ‘trapping women of colour on low pay‘]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/zero-hours-contracts-trapping-women-of-colour-on-low-pay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/zero-hours-contracts-trapping-women-of-colour-on-low-pay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:37:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minority ethnic women almost twice as likely to be on zero-hours contracts as white men, report shows
Women of colour are almost twice as likely to be on zero-hours contracts as white men and almost one and a half times more likely than white women, according to new research.
The joint report from the Trades Union Congress and the equality organisation Race on the Agenda (Rota) warned that far from providing greater flexibility, zero-hours contracts were trapping women from black and minority ethnic (BAME) backgrounds in low pay and insecure work, leaving them struggling to pay bills and plan their lives.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin Community affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cynical, shameful and disastrous: Johnson’s handling of Northern Ireland | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/cynical-shameful-and-disastrous-boris-johnsons-handling-of-northern-ireland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/cynical-shameful-and-disastrous-boris-johnsons-handling-of-northern-ireland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:24:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit ministers always intended to ignore the agreement they signed and blame the EU for the consequences, argues Adrian Ward. Plus letters from Mike Pender, Steve Fildes, Chris Webster and Amin Kassam 
If you make an agreement with someone, you have to honour it (Boris Johnson to face pressure from EU on Northern Ireland, 12 June). If you unilaterally decide to change the terms, you have broken the agreement and the other party will not trust you to keep your word in future and may penalise you.
But Boris Johnson and his ministers knew exactly what they were doing in December 2019 to “get Brexit done” and never had any intention of sticking to the agreement over Northern Ireland – get it signed, then just ignore it and blame the EU for all the repercussions. Johnson’s political playbook, page one. 
Adrian Ward
Le Bez, France
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Guardian-reading over-70s are staying active | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/13/how-guardian-reading-over-70s-are-staying-active</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/13/how-guardian-reading-over-70s-are-staying-active"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:11:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sheila Hunt, Patrick Russell, Michael Shipman and Bob Hely respond to Christian Wolmar’s letter on his non-locked-down life
Re Christian Wolmar’s letter (8 June), at 84 my daily activity both during and after lockdown has been an hour’s walk with my dog. I am able to enjoy this partly because of knee replacements 15 years ago and partly because of a walk around where I live that is accessible to wheelchairs and anyone who has walking difficulties. It includes some lovely views and is partly along the banks of the Wear. I was part of a group that set this up years ago when, for me, a 10-mile walk was an every-weekend activity. Keeping active requires more that just wanting to.
Sheila Hunt
Wolsingham, County Durham
• I can’t match Christian Wolmar’s sporting prowess, but I am halfway through a master’s degree in history at Wolfson College, Cambridge. I am 71.
Patrick Russell
Ealing, London
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson defends G7 deal amid criticism of final communique]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/johnsons-g7-after-all-the-hype-what-was-actually-achieved</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/johnsons-g7-after-all-the-hype-what-was-actually-achieved"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green campaigners and anti-poverty groups say Cornwall summit failed to address challenges facing the world 
Boris Johnson has sought to defend the deal struck by G7 leaders at the Cornwall summit, as green groups and anti-poverty campaigners said the rich nations’ club had failed to match the scale of the challenges facing the world.
The final communique contained no early timetable to eradicate coal-fired emissions, offered only 1bn extra coronavirus vaccines for the world’s poor over the next 12 months and made no new binding commitments to challenge China’s human rights abuses.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour and Heather Stewart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England look lost as fans’ laughter defines painful defeat to New Zealand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/cricket-england-new-zealand-second-test-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/cricket-england-new-zealand-second-test-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dispiriting Test series loss was confirmed amid mirth from the Edgbaston crowd as England try to find a path forward
The boos that reverberated around the Oval in 1999 were replaced by guffaws at Edgbaston on Sunday, as the final wicket of a sorry England batting performance fell at 10.59am. Trent Boult zipped the first ball of the day across Olly Stone, kissed the edge of a shy bat and the few thousand who had taken their seats instinctively chose wry mirth over misery. If you don’t laugh you’ll cry.
This wasn’t the end of a Test already well set on a path towards New Zealand’s first series win in England for 22 years; that came an hour later when Tom Latham dabbed the winning runs down to third man to knock off a paltry target of 38. But it was still a reflection of where England find themselves at present and, volume‑wise, matched only by the cheers that met the announcement after the handshakes that just 11 overs of cricket meant a full refund for ticket-holders.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin at Edgbaston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK government admits ministers can use self-deleting messages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/uk-government-admits-ministers-can-use-self-deleting-messages</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/uk-government-admits-ministers-can-use-self-deleting-messages"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Civil servants also able to delete messages instantly, as fears grow about accountability 
Ministers and civil servants are allowed to set messages to delete instantly, the government has admitted, amplifying concerns about its transparency and accountability.
The confirmation comes as concerns grow that self-destructing messages are being used to avoid scrutiny of decision-making processes, including on key issues such as the government’s coronavirus response.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jailing of Afghans for Lesbos migrant camp fire a ‘parody of justice’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/jailing-afghans-for-lesbos-moria-migrant-camp-fire-parody-of-justice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/jailing-afghans-for-lesbos-moria-migrant-camp-fire-parody-of-justice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T15:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawyers criticise 10-year terms given to four asylum seekers, saying three should have been tried in juvenile court
Draconian prison sentences handed down to four Afghan youths found guilty of starting the fire that destroyed the Moria migrant camp on the Greek island of Lesbos last year have been described as a “parody of justice”.
Defence lawyers called the penalties “unfair”, saying three of the accused were under the age of 18 at the time and should have been tried before a juvenile court. The asylum seekers received 10-year jail terms each.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith  in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[James Crawford obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/james-crawford-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/13/james-crawford-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T15:20:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Energetic public international lawyer who advised many countries and reshaped the rules on wrongdoings between them
In 1996, the UN international law commission asked James Crawford to codify the rules on the wrongdoings of states. Half a century after its initiation, the project was mired in controversy, with failure in the air. Five years later, in 2001, he delivered a final text, the ILC Articles on the Responsibility of States for Internationally Wrongful Acts, along with a commentary in his crisp and concise prose. These articles and commentary are among the most significant texts in modern international law, cited daily by courts and tribunals, practitioners and scholars.
A few years earlier, James had achieved a similar outcome with the ILC’s interminable efforts to create an international criminal court, paving the way for the adoption of the Rome statute in 1998. His combination of forensic and diplomatic skills brought completion to seemingly fruitless tasks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philippe Sands</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In brief: The Cure for Good Intentions; Widowland; The Moth and the Mountain – reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/13/in-brief-the-cure-for-good-intentions-widowland-the-moth-and-the-mountain-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/13/in-brief-the-cure-for-good-intentions-widowland-the-moth-and-the-mountain-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An eye-opening memoir of leaving journalism for medicine; a gripping counterfactual novel about 1950s Britain; and the moving story of a daring attempt to climb Everest
Sophie Harrison
Fleet, £16.99, pp271
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Larman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland Yard taskforce chief fears violence will rise as lockdown lifted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/scotland-yard-taskforce-chief-fears-violence-will-rise-as-lockdown-lifted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/13/scotland-yard-taskforce-chief-fears-violence-will-rise-as-lockdown-lifted"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:56:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DSI Lee Hill says force anticipating increase in violent crimes from release of ‘pent-up aggression’ 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The head of Scotland Yard’s violent crime taskforce has said he fears the easing of lockdown will lead to a rise in violence.
DCS Lee Hill told the Guardian: “As we start to come out of lockdown, we do anticipate there will be an increase in violence. There are a number of reasons, such as pent-up aggression. Where young people have been cooped up together, and as restrictions lift, people are more mobile.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 partners’ trip to theatre backfires after minister’s gaffe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/g7-partners-trip-to-theatre-backfires-after-ministers-gaffe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/13/g7-partners-trip-to-theatre-backfires-after-ministers-gaffe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:53:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver Dowden wrongly boasts that Minack received emergency government funding

G7 summit: latest news and reaction

A visit to a beautiful open-air clifftop theatre in Cornwall by partners of the G7 leaders ended in embarrassment for the UK government after the culture secretary wrongly claimed it had received emergency funding during the Covid crisis.
Following the hugely successful visit to the Minack theatre, perched dizzyingly above the Atlantic, the culture secretary, Oliver Dowden, tweeted that he was delighted that Jill Biden and Carrie Johnson had visited the “stunning” theatre.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘He was gone’: Christian Eriksen had cardiac arrest, Denmark doctor says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/he-was-gone-christian-eriksen-had-cardiac-arrest-denmark-doctor-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/13/he-was-gone-christian-eriksen-had-cardiac-arrest-denmark-doctor-says"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:26:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Midfielder resuscitated with defibrillator on pitch
Eriksen smiling in hospital, says Denmark coach

Christian Eriksen had a cardiac arrest and “was gone” before being swiftly resuscitated on the pitch, Denmark’s the team doctor, Morten Boesen, revealed on Sunday.
“He was gone,” Boesen said. “We started the resuscitation and we managed to do it. How close were we to losing him? I don’t know, but we got him back after one defib [defibrillation], so that’s quite fast.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Christenson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The push to archive the history of jungle and drum’n’bass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/13/the-push-to-archive-the-history-of-jungle-and-drumnbass</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/13/the-push-to-archive-the-history-of-jungle-and-drumnbass"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:21:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Historians aim to document small labels, record shops, pirate radio stations and clubs that helped scene thrive
Chingford Sainsbury’s may be an unlikely setting for an encounter that helped capture a key part of British cultural history, but MC Navigator’s weekly shopping trip to his local supermarket would prove crucial.
Navigator, one of the leading figures in the jungle and drum’n’bass scene in the 1990s, bumped into Uncle 22 – another important player – who had been under the radar for years and was picking up some bits with his mum.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lanre Bakare Arts and culture correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland’s first female astronomer royal looks to open the universe to all]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/13/catherine-heymans-scotland-first-female-astronomer-royal-looks-open-up-universe-for-all</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/13/catherine-heymans-scotland-first-female-astronomer-royal-looks-open-up-universe-for-all"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:10:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Renowned astrophysicist Prof Catherine Heymans hopes to broaden the appeal of her white male-dominated field
“I’m always shocked that it’s 2021 and we’re still having ‘first female’ stories,” says Prof Catherine Heymans. Nevertheless, it is an unavoidable fact that, with her appointment two weeks ago, the renowned astrophysicist not only became the first female astronomer royal for Scotland, but also the only woman to have held any of the astronomer royal positions in the UK.
“It’s very hard to aspire to be something if you can’t see someone who looks like you in that job,” she says, recalling that she did not encounter her first female physics lecturer, her mentor Katherine Blundell, until she began her PhD.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enough ‘autism awareness’. The necessity now is action | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/reason-i-jump-autism-new-voice-film-naoki-higashida-book</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/reason-i-jump-autism-new-voice-film-naoki-higashida-book"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Progress has been made, but the release of the profound film, The Reason I Jump, shows how much further we need to go
A film comes out this month that is among the most profound, thought-provoking and moving feats of documentary-making I have ever seen. It is about autism, and a state of being that far too many people either misunderstand or ignore. But as it ranges across lives played out in Japan, Britain, the US, India and Sierra Leone, it also shines a light on parts of the autistic experience millions of us would recognise in ourselves. In doing so, the film shows how little we still know about the human mind, but how much more we understand than we did even a decade ago.
The Reason I Jump draws on the revelatory book of the same name, written by the Japanese author Naoki Higashida when he was only 13 and first published in 2007. Diagnosed with “autistic tendencies” when he was six, Higashida had always displayed the deep difficulties with spoken communication common to many autistic people. But when he learned to use a computer connected to an alphabet grid, he began to map out his world in rich, aphoristic prose that rarely wasted a word.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pi’erre Bourne: The Life of Pi’erre 5 review – digital overload]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/13/pierre-bourne-the-life-of-pierre-5-review-digital-overload</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/13/pierre-bourne-the-life-of-pierre-5-review-digital-overload"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Interscope)
The super-producer pulls out all the earworm tricks on his second album, but fails to find much real emotion 
Pi’erre Bourne is the super-producer behind some of the biggest rap tracks of the past decade, including Playboi Carti’s Magnolia and 6ix9ine’s Gummo. The Life of Pi’erre 5 is Bourne’s latest attempt to resurface as something greater than other people’s beatmaker, as an artist who can rival his melody-rapping peers such as Trippie Redd and Travis Scott.
His second studio album is saturated with his idiosyncratic earworm tricks: mid-tempo wavy beats, inebriated syncopated synths and gloomy piano arrangements. Both Biology 101 and Retroville are buoyant tracks that vibrate with instrumentals reminiscent of 90s video games. The gravity-free Hulu, a song about god, the galaxy, girls and his grandma, features breathy ad-libs and the velvetiness of ethereal cloud rap.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kadish Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The weekend’s best photos: high dives and a rare-breed dog – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/13/weekend-best-photos-high-dives-rare-breed-dog-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/13/weekend-best-photos-high-dives-rare-breed-dog-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T13:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Blason</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No lights, no camera: UK TV producers face equipment shortage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/13/no-lights-no-camera-uk-tv-producers-face-equipment-shortage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/13/no-lights-no-camera-uk-tv-producers-face-equipment-shortage"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T13:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Film and television industry struggles with surge in demand for high-end shows fuelled by lockdown binge viewing

Britain’s high-end film and television producers are facing a shortage of cameras and other key equipment as the industry struggles to keep up with unprecedented demand for new shows caused by lockdown-induced drama binges.
The public’s seemingly insatiable desire for new content to watch – and a backlog of filming that was delayed because of the pandemic – has led to a chronic lack of trained crew members and the kit they require, with global giants such as Amazon and Netflix able to outbid independent rivals.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanish right rallies against plans to pardon Catalan separatists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/spanish-right-rallies-against-plans-to-pardon-catalan-separatists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/spanish-right-rallies-against-plans-to-pardon-catalan-separatists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T13:03:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protest at Plaza de Colón in Madrid draws 25,000 people, including leaders of three rightwing parties 
Tens of thousands of people, including the leaders of the three parties on Spain’s right, have rallied in Madrid to protest against the government’s deeply divisive moves to pardon the 12 Catalan independence leadersconvicted over their parts in the failed secession attempt almost four years ago.
The event on Sunday, held beneath the enormous Spanish flag in the capital’s Plaza de Colón, came almost two and a half years after a similar demonstration against the Socialist government’s handling of the Catalan independence crisis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: how do we know we’re not living in a simulation like the Matrix?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/readers-reply-how-do-we-know-were-not-living-in-a-simulation-like-the-matrix</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/readers-reply-how-do-we-know-were-not-living-in-a-simulation-like-the-matrix"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T13:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts


How do we know we’re not living in a simulation like the Matrix? Jack Freedom, Bristol
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbora Krejcikova doubles up at French Open to make mark on history]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/barbora-krejcikova-doubles-up-at-french-open-to-make-mark-on-history</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/barbora-krejcikova-doubles-up-at-french-open-to-make-mark-on-history"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:57:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Krejcikova and Katerina Siniakova win women’s doubles title

Czech is first player to win both Paris titles since Mary Pierce

Not since the 2000 edition of the French Open, when Mary Pierce followed her poignant, emotional singles revival by victoriously teaming up with the great Martina Hingis in doubles, had anyone done the double, winning singles and doubles titles at Roland Garros.
But over the past few days, Barbora Krejcikova has made the feat look easy. One day after a life-changing afternoon in her tennis career when she beat Anastasia Pavlyuchenkova to win a surprise first singles grand slam title, the Czech returned to the same court with her longtime partner, Katerina Siniakova, and they defeated Bethanie Mattek-Sands and Iga Swiatek 6-4, 6-2 in a match between the two most recent singles champions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 leaders seek right balance in dealing with their China dilemma]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-leaders-seek-right-balance-dealing-with-china-dilemma-trade-human-rights-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/g7-leaders-seek-right-balance-dealing-with-china-dilemma-trade-human-rights-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:56:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: can the west confront Beijing on trade and human rights and cooperate on the climate crisis?
• G7 summit: latest news and reaction
In an extra-secure, 90-minute session, with the phones and wifi cut off, all designed to block any eavesdropping by a prying foreign state, leaders of the G7, with glorious St Ives sunshine outside, wrestled with an issue that will probably dominate the rest of their political lives – China and the right balance between extreme competition and necessary cooperative coexistence.
Kurt Campbell, Joe Biden’s Indo-Pacific policy director, describes the dilemma as presenting “complex coexistence paradigms”, something of which he says the US has had little previous experience.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Germany’s Greens back Baerbock for chancellorship despite dip in polls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/germany-greens-back-annalena-baerbock-chancellorship-despite-dip-in-polls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/germany-greens-back-annalena-baerbock-chancellorship-despite-dip-in-polls"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:31:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Party officially endorses co-leader and top candidate for September election to succeed Merkel
Germany’s Green party has said it remains confident of securing the chancellorship and succeeding Angela Merkel at the country’s autumn election despite a drop in the polls, as it officially endorsed its lead candidate for the job.
Setbacks in recent weeks have led to the Greens slipping to second place behind Merkel’s conservative Christian Democratic Union (CDU) after commanding the polls for the first time in years. But this did not dissuade delegates from wholeheartedly throwing their support behind Annalena Baerbock at the party’s annual gathering on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK airport passenger numbers drop 75% to 74m in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/13/uk-airport-passenger-numbers-drop-75-to-74-million-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/13/uk-airport-passenger-numbers-drop-75-to-74-million-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:24:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airport Operators Association says figures show the devastating impact of Covid-19 restrictions on aviation

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The number of passengers travelling through UK airports fell by 223 million last year, an annual decline of 75%, as governments imposed travel bans and restrictions because of the coronavirus pandemic.
About 74 million people passed through UK airports in 2020, less than a quarter of the 297 million recorded in 2019, according to PA Media’s analysis of annual Civil Aviation Authority data.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[L’Arc de Triomphe, Wrapped: Christo’s dream being realised]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/larc-de-triomphe-wrapped-christo-dream-bulgarian-artist</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/larc-de-triomphe-wrapped-christo-dream-bulgarian-artist"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:21:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Work begins next month to swathe monument in blue fabric a year after Bulgarian-born artist’s death
The Arc de Triomphe in Paris will be swathed in silvery blue fabric and red rope as a posthumous project planned by the artist Christo since the early 1960s finally becomes reality.
 Work will begin next month on L’Arc de Triomphe, Wrapped, a €14m installation at one of the world’s most recognised monuments. The arch will be swathed in 25,000 sq metres of recyclable polypropylene fabric, fixed with 3,000 metres of red rope, also recyclable.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Covid crisis mode is lifting, questions parked for a year are nagging once again | Emma Brockes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/covid-crisis-questions-pleasures-normal-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/covid-crisis-questions-pleasures-normal-life"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T12:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My newfound delight in the smallest pleasures is unlikely to survive the resumption of normal life
The weather is warm, and we’re heading into summer, with the assumption that this one will be better than the last: freer of lockdowns, less fraught with uncertainty and with a high probability that, when we come back in September, it will be to something like regular life. This is a great feeling in almost every way, except for a nagging anxiety – that, now the end is in sight and the limbo practically over, a reckoning is finally due.
The reflex to learn something from everything is, I guess, noble and human, but let’s face it, it’s also a pain in the arse. In New York at the moment, think pieces abound on how the city might come out of the pandemic a better, more equal place. Large thoughts attend patterns of work and how they may or may not have been permanently disrupted. These are worthwhile speculations at the social and political level, but at home, on the sofa, the creeping pressure to turn the pandemic experience into a spur for “growth” and renewal – in other words, to return to the pre-pandemic assumption that every life stage must be harnessed to rampant personal improvement – brings on a certain weariness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Brockes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-pupils who compiled sexual abuse dossier accused of blocking inquiry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/13/ex-pupils-who-compiled-sexual-abuse-dossier-accused-of-blocking-inquiry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/13/ex-pupils-who-compiled-sexual-abuse-dossier-accused-of-blocking-inquiry"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T11:35:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former students at Eltham college receive letter from school’s lawyers accusing them of obstructing investigation
Former pupils at a private school in south-east London who compiled a dossier of sexual harassment and misconduct allegations were shocked to receive a letter from the school’s lawyers accusing them of obstructing investigations into the incidents.
The students, who went to Eltham College in Bromley, said they expected to receive a compassionate response after they collected testimonies from pupils past and present alleging sexism, sexual harassment, abuse and assault, and forwarded them to the school, inspired by the Everyone’s Invited anti-rape movement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Raab accuses EU leaders of ‘offensive’ attitude to Northern Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/offensive-dominic-raab-chides-eu-leaders-over-northern-ireland-remarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/offensive-dominic-raab-chides-eu-leaders-over-northern-ireland-remarks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T11:21:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Foreign secretary says EU leaders suggest region is separate from UK, after reported Macron comments

G7 summit: latest news and reaction

The UK foreign secretary, Dominic Raab, has attacked EU leaders for making the “offensive” suggestion that Northern Ireland is not a proper part of the UK, as tensions over post-Brexit trading arrangements escalated at the G7 summit in Cornwall.
Asked about reported comments by the French president, Emmanuel Macron, during talks with Boris Johnson at the summit, he said: “Various EU figures, here in Carbis Bay, but frankly for months now and years have characterised Northern Ireland as somehow a separate country and that is wrong.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of Britain’s best pubs with rooms in spectacular walking country]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/13/travel-10-of-britains-best-pubs-with-rooms-set-in-spectacular-hiking-country</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/13/travel-10-of-britains-best-pubs-with-rooms-set-in-spectacular-hiking-country"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T11:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walk through gorgeous countryside, then head back for a pint, meal and somewhere to put your feet up
Usually heaving with fell walkers enjoying a post Scafell Pike-high, this famous mountaineers’ pub is one of the classic venues in the Lake District. The drinking booths of the Hikers’ Bar are built into the old cow stalls of the 300-year old farm and inn. It’s a little rough round the edges, Elle Deco isn’t going to be shooting the bedrooms anytime soon, but the Langdale Valley setting is incredible, and staying here is to become part of legend. Every British climber – from Chris Bonington to the earliest pioneers of the sport – has stayed at this longstanding focal point of British mountaineering. 
• Doubles from £120 B&B, singles from £58, odg.co.uk
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gemma Bowes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The male beauty myth: the growing acceptance of feeling comfortable looking good]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/the-male-beauty-myth</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/the-male-beauty-myth"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T11:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Men who want to look good used to be disparaged and labelled vain. But times are finally changing…
Until recently, male motivation for looking good or strong was often born from an inherent desire for us to feel and appear more successful, competitive, virile and powerful – what some now refer to as toxic masculinity.
Of course, there have always been men who’ve enjoyed discussing clothes, watches, even grooming regimes but, for many, this open appreciation of what they wore was often merely a game of one-upmanship disguised as an appreciation of the finer things in life. Think of the 1980s and its bullish Wall Street status stamps, such as pinstripe suits and red braces (Michael Douglas as Gordon Gekko); the scene in American Psycho where rival stockbrokers battle over business cards, like a game of Top Trumps. Or in the 1990s, when showing off got even easier and even off-duty symbols such as underwear, jeans and luggage were plastered with a riot of logos.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Langmead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After 16 years as a travelling fan, I know an England game is always political | Mark Perryman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/fan-england-football-game-political</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/13/fan-england-football-game-political"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T11:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I stood up for football supporters, and saw ingrained prejudices change over time through openness and dialogue
Take away the England football team and what kind of popular representations of England are we left with?
The historian Eric Hobsbawm made an observation that is never more relevant than when applied to us, the English: “The imagined community of millions seems more real as a team of eleven named people.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Perryman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’ve decided to stop apologising’: Lisa Taddeo on women and rage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/lisa-taddeo-i-am-angry-at-my-history-of-apology</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/lisa-taddeo-i-am-angry-at-my-history-of-apology"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:58:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a man acts in anger, we step aside, but a woman gets labelled ‘crazy bitch’. In a personal, ferocious treatise, the author says we need to change the script
My mother once told me – no that’s not true – my mother many times warned me: “If you ever sell any of my jewellery after I’m dead, I’ll come back from the grave and bite your toes.”
I don’t know if she meant she would nibble on my toes, or fully eat them, but I was petrified of her doing the things she threatened. My mother, after all, was a crazy bitch.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa Taddeo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frida Kahlo and me: how the artist shaped my life as an amputee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/13/frida-kahlo-and-me-how-the-artist-shaped-my-life-as-an-amputee-emily-rapp-black</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/13/frida-kahlo-and-me-how-the-artist-shaped-my-life-as-an-amputee-emily-rapp-black"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writer Emily Rapp Black lost her leg aged four. In her new memoir, Frida Kahlo and My Left Leg, she explains how the work of the Mexican artist, also an amputee, helped her develop a better relationship with her body 

Scroll down for a Q&A with Emily Rapp Black

Desnudo de Frida Kahlo by Diego Rivera hangs in a small museum in Guanajuato, Mexico. In this portrait, Frida’s torso is taut and slim; the sides of her waist curve inward, creating perfect hollows for each of your hands. Her breasts are slightly lifted, because her arms are clasped behind her head; her elbows are the pointed tips of wings. Her shoulders look solid, strong, able. This is a body that is loved, admired, desired.
This lithograph was made in 1930, after polio disfigured her right foot in 1913 when she was six years old; after the 1925 streetcar accident that broke her spinal column, her collarbone, her ribs, her pelvis, created 11 fractures in her already weakened leg, crushed her foot and left her shoulder permanently out of joint. During the 29 years between her accident and her death in 1954, Frida had 32 operations; was required to wear a corset every day from 1944 onward; and had her leg amputated because of gangrene in 1953. It was this final operation that likely led to the complications that eventually killed her. Speculation of suicide remains.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Rapp Black</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serpentine Pavilion 2021 review – a sophisticated chimera of light and depth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/serpentine-pavilion-2021-review-a-sophisticated-chimera-of-light-and-depth</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/serpentine-pavilion-2021-review-a-sophisticated-chimera-of-light-and-depth"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kensington Gardens, London
The youngest architect ever to design the annual temporary structure has created an airy gathering place inspired by diasporic London spaces
The Serpentine Gallery’s Pavilion, an architectural essay that appears in Kensington Gardens every summer, pandemics permitting, tends to be a bit of a sketch. Intriguing ideas by imaginative architects get blurred by the exigencies of project management. Details don’t always survive their first encounter with the building regulations. The pavilions are temporary and built at speed, which can give them a dashed-off feel. The intention can be more rewarding than the execution.
Less so this year’s edition, by the Johannesburg-based practice Counterspace, directed by Sumayya Vally. It has what you might call architecture: scale, detail, the articulation of mass and volume and of shadow and light. It is high ceilinged and airy. It has presence and depth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rowan Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten cooks who changed the way we eat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/gallery/2021/jun/13/ten-cooks-who-changed-the-way-we-eat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/gallery/2021/jun/13/ten-cooks-who-changed-the-way-we-eat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Rayner picks the cookbooks that have made a real difference to the British dinner table and explains why these are his go-to recipe books for home chefs 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Rayner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The quest to solve the mysterious ‘eerie’ hum of the Golden Gate Bridge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/golden-gate-bridge-hum-noise-san-francisco</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/golden-gate-bridge-hum-noise-san-francisco"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Engineers are working on a plan to quiet the ‘unbearable’ sound, which occurs when strong winds hit the bridge
Somewhere in a wind tunnel on the south-western side of Ontario, a group of the world’s leading bridge aerodynamics and acoustics experts are puzzling over a full-scale model of the railing of the Golden Gate Bridge.
The experts have been contracted to solve the mysterious problem of a strange humming sound that has been emanating from San Francisco’s famous bridge for the past year, driving some nearby residents to a state of madness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obstacles mount in Central America as Biden seeks cooperation over corruption]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/13/biden-harris-central-america-policy-migration-corruption</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/13/biden-harris-central-america-policy-migration-corruption"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The post-Trump landscape, geopolitical concerns and an economic paradox pose threat to White House hopes
Standing behind a podium next to the president of Guatemala during her first trip abroad this week, Vice-President Kamala Harris emphasized the renewed commitment of the United States to fighting corruption as part of efforts to confront the root causes driving migration from Central America.
But for many, the man standing beside her, Alejandro Giammattei, embodies the challenge in a region where past and current presidents have been accused of misdeeds ranging from embezzlement and bribery to authoritarianism and drug trafficking.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeff Ernst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children’s access to online porn fuels sexual harassment, says commissioner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/13/childrens-access-to-online-porn-fuels-sexual-harassment-says-commissioner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/13/childrens-access-to-online-porn-fuels-sexual-harassment-says-commissioner"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T09:45:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel de Souza warns use of websites partly to blame for normalising abuse in schools in England
Curbs on children’s access to online pornography need to be brought in urgently to stop the spread of an activity that is partly to blame for normalising sexual harassment in schools, according to the new children’s commissioner for England.
Dame Rachel de Souza is urging governments and tech companies to introduce age verification checks. She warned that access to hardcore pornography was shaping children’s expectations of relationships and was partly to blame for thousands of testimonies of sexual harassment by schoolchildren published on the Everyone’s Invited website over the last few months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall and Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We took up skydiving to escape’: Britain’s lockdown thrill-seekers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/we-took-up-skydiving-to-escape-britains-lockdown-thrill-seekers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/13/we-took-up-skydiving-to-escape-britains-lockdown-thrill-seekers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T09:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The extreme sport is booming after months of restrictions on people’s daily lives during the pandemic
Maddie Woodward and Olly Rodgers were supposed to be getting married this year. But when the wedding could not happen as they planned, because of government restrictions, they decided to do a skydive instead.
Skydiving centres have reported a surge in bookings as people grow desperate for post-lockdown excitement. Tony Butler, chief operating officer at British Skydiving, said the combination of good weather and the long time spent closed meant that centres were very busy, which was helpful as “they, like many businesses, would have had little income in the last year”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘People are so burned out’: US essential workers struggle as restrictions lifted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/us-essential-workers-burned-out-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/13/us-essential-workers-burned-out-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T09:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workers fight for permanent improvements to wages and benefits as many are concerned about safety and angry over working conditions
Workers who were deemed essential during the coronavirus pandemic and publicly praised for continuing to work in-person are now fighting for permanent improvements to working conditions, wages and benefits as safety protections are lifted and they still grapple with the impact of working through the long crisis.
Millions of essential workers contracted Covid-19 while working through the pandemic. Thousands died as a result or lost co-workers, friends and family members to the virus. Many who caught the virus still experience long-term symptoms and Covid-19 cases and deaths are still a concern in many areas of the US. This is especially true in low-income, predominantly Black and Latino communities where vaccination rates have been lagging despite these communities being hit hardest by the virus.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Sainato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the ‘Hanging Woman’ revealed truth of Bosnia’s mass killer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/how-the-hanging-woman-revealed-truth-of-bosnias-mass-killer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/how-the-hanging-woman-revealed-truth-of-bosnias-mass-killer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T08:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1996, our writer identified the suicide victim whose death symbolised the cruelty of Ratko Mladic. As his life sentence is upheld, she recalls a meeting with Ferida Osmanovic’s children
In July 1995, a photograph made newspaper front pages around the world. It showed a woman in a white skirt and red cardigan hanging from a tree in a wood outside Srebrenica in eastern Bosnia. The caption read: “The Hanging Woman”.
They say a picture is worth a thousand words, and this one said everything about the war in Bosnia-Herzegovina.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing ‘their worship’, the world’s first non-binary mayor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/owen-hurcum-bangor-wales-worlds-first-non-binary-mayor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/owen-hurcum-bangor-wales-worlds-first-non-binary-mayor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Student Owen Hurcum is ‘humbled’ to serve the oldest city in Wales, and aims to put Bangor’s peacocks on the map
When Owen Hurcum, a part-time archaeology master’s student at Bangor University, climbed to the stage to accept their position as the newly appointed mayor of Bangor, they felt “hugely humbled” to represent their community.
What is even more unique about Hurcum, 23, is who they are: non-binary, queer and agender. They made history in this year’s local and mayoral election by becoming the first openly non-binary mayor of any city in the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pride rainbow merchandise is everywhere, but who gets the pot of gold?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/pride-rainbow-merchandise-is-everywhere-but-who-gets-the-pot-of-gold</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/pride-rainbow-merchandise-is-everywhere-but-who-gets-the-pot-of-gold"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multicoloured themed products are hitting shops as June celebrations begin, but little profit goes to LGBTQ+ communities 
From Listerine mouthwash to Victoria Beckham T-shirts, every June sees a growing number of brands launch rainbow-themed merchandise to celebrate Pride month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hearts, pebbles, flags: handmade tributes mourn nation’s lost lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/hearts-pebbles-flags-handmade-tributes-mourn-nations-lost-lives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/hearts-pebbles-flags-handmade-tributes-mourn-nations-lost-lives"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T07:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People across Britain are creating their own ways to remember loved ones who have died from Covid ahead of an official permanent site

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

It began with simple hearts painted on a wall by the Thames. Now people across the UK are constructing their own Covid memorials, from rainbow-painted lawns to hundreds of flags on a Welsh mountainside.
Although Boris Johnson has pledged to create a permanent national memorial, and set up a commission on Covid commemoration, no further details have been made public.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper &amp; Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Ian McKellen: ‘What does old mean? Quite honestly I feel about 12’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/sir-ian-mckellen-what-does-old-mean-quite-honestly-i-feel-about-12</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/sir-ian-mckellen-what-does-old-mean-quite-honestly-i-feel-about-12"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T07:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s half a century since Sir Ian McKellen first played Hamlet. Now he’s starring as the Dane again – at 82. He talks about his extraordinary life, why he’ll never write his memoir – and his one lasting regret
Oh, birthdays,” Sir Ian McKellen growls, on the occasion of his 82nd. “At my age I don’t do birthdays.” The wider world has not yet been informed, however, and cheerful cards have come in stacks to McKellen’s London townhouse. Messages chime in on his computer and two landline phones ring on his desk, one after the other. “But, darling,” McKellen says, answering a call and interrupting a well-wisher mid flow, “I’m trying to avoid it all this year.” Guilt, he explains to me, later. He leads us through to a sitting room. “Actors don’t need this special attention, I’ve realised. We get cards and presents on first nights. Everyone makes a fuss of us. Birthdays are wonderful things for people who don’t get treated as special all year round.”
McKellen throws himself down in a winged armchair and croaks out an epic smoker’s laugh, one of those laughs that begins in silence (mimed really) and soon becomes an extended hum in the back of the throat, then a wheezy bark. Devoted to his cigs, he will step out on to his riverside balcony whenever he needs one, staring out over the Thames while he puffs, pulling on a tweedy overcoat if it’s cold. Between times he sucks on Polo mints. One goes into McKellen’s cheek, now. The rest of the packet he leaves perched on his tummy in reach. “Where were we?” he asks. “Birthdays?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Lamont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you wanted to know about the culture wars – but were afraid to ask]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-the-culture-wars-but-were-afraid-to-ask</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-the-culture-wars-but-were-afraid-to-ask"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T07:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Politicians like to provoke them, academics like to analyse them. Yet most people don’t even know what they’re all about
Last week produced an eventful but not untypical weather-front of news stories about culturally contentious issues. There was the microstorm about the Queen’s photo being taken down in the common room at Magdalen College, Oxford; the tiny tempest of Test cricketer Ollie Robinson being dropped for racist tweets dating from when he was a teenager; the squall over the England football team’s commitment to taking the knee; and the sudden shower of Oxford academics boycotting Oriel College over its decision to retain its reviled Cecil Rhodes statue.
These, along with the deathless headline “Law student cleared after saying women have vaginas”, were examples of what might also be called skirmishes in a larger and ongoing series of battles: the culture wars.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Anthony</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’ve had Biden’s security and US marines here’: Cornwall crowds enjoy G7 circus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/weve-had-bidens-security-and-us-marines-here-cornwall-crowds-enjoy-g7-circus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/weve-had-bidens-security-and-us-marines-here-cornwall-crowds-enjoy-g7-circus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T06:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Holidaymakers in the seaside town close to the summit were fascinated by the cavalcade of security. And local traders saw a chance to make some money

Environmental campaigners stage ‘festival-type’ protests at G7
G7 summit protests – in pictures

Asked to rate his holiday in St Ives, six-year-old Bertie did not hesitate: “Fifteen out of 10. I’ve liked everything.”
He’s loved playing on the sandy beach and paddling in the harbour, but also enjoyed the show created by the G7 summit taking place across the bay – the naval ships, the military helicopters, the police officers buzzing around on boats and jet-skis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris in St Ives</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrity buzz: how stars’ bedroom toys have got us all talking about sex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/celebrity-buzz-how-stars-bedroom-toys-have-got-us-all-talking-about-sex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/celebrity-buzz-how-stars-bedroom-toys-have-got-us-all-talking-about-sex"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T06:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With famous users leading a rebrand, pleasure accessories lose their stigma in a £90bn health and wellness boom
Lily Allen has one. Cara Delevingne has one. Dakota Johnson has developed her own range. Is the celebrity sex toy 2021’s answer to the celebrity perfume?
For some, getting busy has been the last thing on the menu during the pandemic. Study after study, from India to Italy, has revealed that lockdown libido loss is real and that stress has killed the buzz in the bedroom. Sexual wellness, on the other hand, has reached a dizzying peak. Not only has the conversation around sexual pleasure changed for generation Z, but the industry attached to it – from apps to toys, herbal supplements to specialist oils – is also booming.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nosheen Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No more emails: why I’m walking from Land’s End to John o’Groats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/13/why-im-walking-from-lands-end-to-john-ogroats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/13/why-im-walking-from-lands-end-to-john-ogroats"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T06:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a government civil servant, I was burnt out from working on Brexit and Covid and needed a change of scene. Trekking the length of Britain is just the tonic
It’s 7.30pm on 29 April and I’m standing alone on the highest hill in this part of Cornwall. The sun is bright and eager, dancing with dainty flashes on the waves west towards Newquay. But I’m wrapped in everything I have – two pairs of thick socks, leggings, trousers, T-shirt, two long-sleeved T-shirts, jumper, fleece, jacket, snood, hat – and still the wind reaches its long fingers down my neck to grip my spine. It is one degree above freezing; in less than a week it will snow on Dartmoor.
In fact, this is more than a hill. This is Castle an Dinas, one of those iron age forts to which schoolchildren are taken to be underwhelmed by ditches and mounds. The dog walkers who came up earlier weren’t cowed by antiquity: each allowed their charges to mess, tongues wagging. Watching the deposits stirs in me something I was repressing. For the four days I’ve been on the road, public toilets have been there when needed. A threshold is about to be crossed. I’m going wild.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Gingell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: Niall McDiarmid’s world on a plate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/jun/13/the-big-picture-niall-mcdiarmids-world-on-a-plate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/jun/13/the-big-picture-niall-mcdiarmids-world-on-a-plate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T06:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Scottish photographer’s shots of his breakfast table suggest planets in alignment at a moment when everything is in its right and proper place
Niall McDiarmid, a Scottish photographer based in London, has, as a daily preface to other projects, been taking photographs of his breakfast table for the past four years. The pictures, invariably sunlit, concentrate on the shifting geometries of bowl and plate, toast and cereal, and quietly assume the meditative qualities of still lifes. Collectively, in his new book, Breakfast, they invite a sense of possibility, newness, ritual.
“For me,” he says, “breakfast is a peaceful time, a time of reflection. It is also a time to contemplate the day ahead and to believe that better times are coming. As Ian Fleming wrote, ‘Hope makes a good breakfast. Eat plenty of it.’”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How did a £120 painting become a £320m Leonardo … then vanish?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/how-did-a-120-painting-become-a-320m-leonardo-then-vanish</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/13/how-did-a-120-painting-become-a-320m-leonardo-then-vanish"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T05:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A film about the disputed Salvator Mundi blames the National Gallery for its role in giving credibility to the claim that it was the artist’s lost work
The National Gallery is facing controversy over its role in the tangled story of how the world’s most expensive painting emerged from obscurity before being sold for a staggering £320m, only to vanish again from the public eye.
The gallery exhibited the Salvator Mundi in its Leonardo da Vinci exhibition a decade ago when it was an unknown work with doubts about its attribution, restoration and ownership.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dalya Alberge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are women more prone to long Covid?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/13/why-are-women-more-prone-to-long-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/13/why-are-women-more-prone-to-long-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T05:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While men over 50 tend to suffer the most acute symptoms of coronavirus, women who get long Covid outnumber men by as much as four to one 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

In June 2020, as the first reports of long Covid began to filter through the medical community, doctors attempting to grapple with this mysterious malaise began to notice an unusual trend. While acute cases of Covid-19 – particularly those hospitalised with the disease – tended to be mostly male and over 50, long Covid sufferers were, by contrast, both relatively young and overwhelmingly female.
Early reports of long Covid at a Paris hospital between May and July 2020 suggested that the average age was around 40, and women afflicted by the longer-term effects of Covid-19 outnumbered men by four to one.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farewell Mariella: ‘I wanted to say thanks’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/farewell-mariella-i-wanted-to-say-thanks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/13/farewell-mariella-i-wanted-to-say-thanks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T05:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After almost 20 years, our much-loved agony aunt is signing off. Here, our readers reveal how she’s helped them
Dear Mariella, I just wanted to let you know that not long after your column started I wrote to you. I was in utter despair as my husband had left and I think I was having a breakdown. I thought at the time your reply was quite harsh. However, you were right, I did need to get a grip and concentrate on my children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariella Frostrup</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Azerbaijan swaps 15 Armenian PoWs for map of landmines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/azerbaijan-swaps-15-armenian-pows-for-map-of-landmines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/azerbaijan-swaps-15-armenian-pows-for-map-of-landmines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T02:12:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2020 war over Nagorno-Karabakh region left minefields that have continued to inflict casualties, including three recent deaths
Azerbaijan says it has handed over 15 Armenian prisoners in exchange for a map detailing the location of landmines in Agdam, a region relinquished by ethnic Armenian forces as a part of a deal to end their short war of 2020.
Prisoners of war are a key issue for Armenia, while landmines continue to inflict casualties in Azerbaijan. Two journalists and a local official were killed on 4 June when a landmine exploded in Azerbaijan’s Kalbajar district on territory that was vacated by ethnic Armenian forces in November.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At least 18 die as hospital hit in shelling of Syrian city]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/at-least-18-die-as-hospital-hit-in-shelling-of-syrian-city</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/13/at-least-18-die-as-hospital-hit-in-shelling-of-syrian-city"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T01:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Children and hospital staff killed in attack on northern city Afrin, which is held by Turkish-backed rebels
Shelling of the rebel-held city of Afrin in northern Syria killed at least 18 people, many of them when a hospital was hit, a war monitor said.
The London-based Syrian Observatory for Human Rights said a doctor, three hospital staff, two women and two children died at al-Shifaa hospital, which is held by Turkish-backed rebels, on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All hot air: UK commits to climate action but not to new funding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/all-hot-air-uk-commits-to-climate-action-but-not-to-new-funding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/all-hot-air-uk-commits-to-climate-action-but-not-to-new-funding"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T21:31:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson announces £500m for ‘blue planet fund’, but pledge was contained in 2019 Conservative manifesto

Environmental campaigners stage ‘festival-type’ protests at G7
G7 summit protests – in pictures

Boris Johnson has set out his intention to “build back better for the world”, to protect the natural environment and wildlife, and tackle the climate crisis, at the G7 summit in Cornwall. But he committed no new funds to the initiative, and other G7 leaders showed little sign of coming forward with the cash commitments that campaigners said were needed to help developing countries cope with the climate emergency.
Announcing £500m to be spent on a “blue planet fund”, for the protection of the oceans and coastal areas in poor countries, he said: “As democratic nations, we have a responsibility to help developing countries reap the benefits of clean growth through a fair and transparent system. The G7 has an unprecedented opportunity to drive a global green industrial revolution, with the potential to transform the way we live.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey &amp; Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 summit protests – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/12/g7-summit-protests-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/12/g7-summit-protests-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:29:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters turn out in support of a range of causes as the leaders of Group of Seven nations meet for the forum’s 47th summit in Cornwall

Environmental campaigners stage ‘festival-type’ protests at G7
All hot air: UK commits to climate action but not to new funding
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid lockdown: should England open up on 21 June?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/should-england-open-up-on-21-june-the-factors-johnson-must-consider</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/12/should-england-open-up-on-21-june-the-factors-johnson-must-consider"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T15:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister has a host of problems to weigh up before deciding to remove all legal restrictions on social contact

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The key issue is the extent to which infections of the Delta variant first detected in India will lead to hospitalisations and deaths. The problem is that it’s too early to say. Because of the lag between cases and admissions to hospital, many experts say a short delay could be a major benefit to understanding that relationship. “With the current knowledge about Delta, we can’t really predict the size of that wave,” said Anne Cori of Imperial College London’s modelling group. “Delaying the easing allows time to accumulate more evidence about the characteristics of Delta. And I hope in a few weeks, we would be in a better position to predict what the epidemic may look like in the next few weeks or months.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Enjoying yourself?': Queen jokes with G7 leaders in family photo – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/jun/12/enjoying-yourself-queen-jokes-with-g7-leaders-in-family-photo-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/jun/12/enjoying-yourself-queen-jokes-with-g7-leaders-in-family-photo-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T09:08:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen caused G7 world leaders to break out into laughter as she cracked a joke when they posed for a photo at an evening reception hosted by the monarch on Friday. ‘Are you supposed to be looking as if you're enjoying yourself?’ she asked as they posed for photographers, to which Boris Johnson could be heard replying: ‘Yes, definitely. We have been enjoying ourselves in spite of appearances’

All the Queen’s presidents: Biden joins long line of US leaders to meet royal
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’re causing our own misery’: oceanographer Sylvia Earle on the need for sea conservation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Queen of the Deep’ says it is not too late to reverse human-made damage to oceans and preserve biodiversity
The world has the opportunity in the next 10 years to restore our oceans to health after decades of steep decline – but to achieve that, people must wake up to the problem, join in efforts to protect marine areas and stop eating tuna, according to the oceanographer and deep sea explorer Sylvia Earle.
“We are at the most exciting time maybe ever to be a human, because we’re armed with knowledge,” said Earle, also known as the Queen of the Deep and “her Deepness”. Earle has also set numerous records for deep sea diving, and was the first woman to serve as chief scientist of the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is a Disaster Recovery Plan? How to Use RTO and RPO to Protect your Business]]></title>
        <id>60b72d5facb62507dd1d777b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/disaster-recovery-plan-what-are-rto-and-rpo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T22:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're in the world of tech, you will inevitably run into a work-related disaster now and then. These setbacks come in many forms such as cyber-attacks, theft, leaks, and corruption. And every business must be ready to face these things and plan for them. Sir Benjamin Franklin famously said,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342429</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/safari-15-new-ui-theme-colors-and-a-css-tricks-cameo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a 33-minute video (and resources) over on apple.com covering the upcoming Safari changes we saw in the WWDC keynote this year in much more detail. Look who’s got a little cameo in there:
Perhaps the most noticeable thing there …
The post Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Possibilities of Syndication]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342237</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-possibilities-of-syndication/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s the one word that isn’t an adjective in the acronym RSS. 
Really Simple Syndication.
RSS isn’t just about RSS readers. Even though, gosh if I don’t love RSS readers. It’s about putting content in a format that is …
The post The Possibilities of Syndication appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Center Anything in CSS Using Flexbox and Grid ✨]]></title>
        <id>6063b9189618b008528a9d81</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-center-objects-using-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T20:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I'm gonna show you how you can center and align your content with CSS. Along the way, we'll look at various alignment techniques. So, let's get started! 🥇 Table of Contents -> How to Use Flexbox to center anything horizontally center anything vertically center both horizontally & Vertically How]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/11/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/11/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T20:08:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aftermath of the conflict in Gaza and Israel; the crisis in Ethiopia’s Tigray region; the 77th anniversary of D-day and the election in Peru: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Design Keyboard Accessibility for Complex React Experiences]]></title>
        <id>5f9c97e9740569d1a4ca1768</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/designing-keyboard-accessibility-for-complex-react-experiences/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How you can design an inclusive and accessible org chart experience and solutions to common development challenges you will face.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ask Good Technical Questions – the Ultimate Guide]]></title>
        <id>60bc0444acb62507dd1d9a31</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-ask-good-technical-questions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:39:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing how to ask effective technical questions is an essential skill every software engineer should have.  You may be stuck with a bug, unable to figure out why your program isn't working correctly, or you might be having trouble learning how to implement a certain algorithm. In all of these]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Level Up Your React Conditionals]]></title>
        <id>60c24cf8d3126007592d61d5</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-react-conditionals/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T16:04:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you write conditionals correctly within your React applications?  Good conditionals are an essential part of any React application. We use conditionals to show or hide elements or components in our applications.  In short – to be an effective React developer, you must know how to write good conditionals. Let's go]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342164</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/adding-shadows-to-svg-icons-with-css-and-svg-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would we need to apply shadows to SVG?
Shadows are a common design feature that can help elements, like icons, stand out. They could be persistent, or applied in different states (e.g. :hover, :focus, or :active) 
…
The post Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Olawanle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your ingenious holiday packing hacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T11:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on what to pack and how to maximise your wardrobe while travelling
For those of us lucky enough to be able to go on holiday this summer, there’s always one issue: what to pack? And more importantly, how to pack efficiently.
With this in mind, we want to hear about your best packing hacks. Perhaps you’ve discovered the secret to maximising your wardrobe? Or maybe you swear by soap and shampoo bars over liquid toiletries, to avoid leakage in your luggage? Whether it’s a must-have gadget, or a space-saving tip, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[António Guterres on the climate crisis: ‘We are coming to a point of no return’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/11/antonio-guterres-interview-climate-crisis-pandemic-g7</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/11/antonio-guterres-interview-climate-crisis-pandemic-g7"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T04:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UN secretary general says he’s concerned that the richest nations have pumped billions more into fossil fuels than clean energy since the pandemic
Wealthy countries risk an “unforgivable lost opportunity” by not emerging from the Covid-19 pandemic with newly green economies to address the climate crisis, the United Nations secretary general has warned.
Before meeting the leaders of the world’s major economic powers at the G7 summit in the UK, António Guterres said he was concerned that the richest nations have pumped billions of dollars more into fossil fuels than clean energy since the pandemic, despite their promises of a green recovery.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News enters the culture war - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T02:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To its critics, it is a British Fox News; to its creators, it is a vital correction to a liberal London-centric media. Can Andrew Neil’s upstart news channel change the face of British broadcasting?
For years, Britain’s rolling news landscape has been dominated by Sky and the BBC. On Sunday, a new rival, GB News, is entering the fray – and although its chairman and most famous face, Andrew Neil, insists that any comparisons to Fox News are idiotic, many see an echo in its plan to use outspoken presenters to discuss the most controversial issues of the day. 
But Neil insists that the plan is not to tack to the right, but to address an audience which he says has been let down by the existing broadcasters – and which he believes is crying out for a channel that addresses its concerns. As the channel’s newly hired team race to be ready for their debut, Anushka Asthana asks the Guardian’s media editor, Jim Waterson, whether GB News is bound to be a participant in the so-called culture war – and whether a British audience really wants to see a radical departure from the more traditional model that dominates today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Jim Waterson; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put a Background on Open Details Elements]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342050</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/put-a-background-on-open-details-elements/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T00:16:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One thing that can be just a smidge funky about the <details> element is that, when open, it’s not always 100% clear what is inside that element and what isn’t. I’m not saying that always matters or that it’s a …
The post Put a Background on Open Details Elements appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341894</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/equal-columns-with-flexbox-its-more-complicated-than-you-might-think/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As awesome as flexbox is, what it’s doing under the hood is actually a little strange because, by default, it is doing two things at once. It first looks at the content size which is what we would get if by declaring width: max-content on an element. But on top of that, flex-shrink is also doing some work allowing the items to be smaller, but only if needed.
Let’s break those two down and see how they work together.
The post Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-headless-cms-with-fauna-and-vercel-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will learn and use headless CMS, Fauna, and Vercel functions to build a blogging platform, Blogify After that, you can easily build any web application using a headless CMS, Fauna and Vercel functions.
The post Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ikeh Akinyemi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar eclipse 2021: the crescent sun – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:27:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From New Jersey to Milton Keynes, skygazers in the northern hemisphere were able to see a partial solar eclipse, witnessing a crescent sun in an eclipsed sunrise in some parts of the world

Solar eclipse 2021: spectacle visible across UK and Ireland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Azure Data Fundamentals Certification (DP-900) – Pass the Exam With This Free 4.5-Hour Course]]></title>
        <id>60b93afaacb62507dd1d8915</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/azure-data-fundamentals-certification-dp-900-pass-the-exam-with-this-free-4-5-hour-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can learn everything you need to know to earn the Azure Data Fundamentals certification by completing this free 4.5 hour course. What is the Azure Data Fundamentals Certification?The Azure Data Fundamentals Certification is for those seeking a data-related role such as Data Analyst, Data Engineer, or Data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 and a crucial moment for the climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T02:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s richest democracies will come together in Britain this week with global heating high on the agenda. Can they match big promises with concrete action? 
The damage wrought by the coronavirus pandemic has been huge, but it pales in comparison to the potential risks associated with the climate crisis. With the world coalescing around the importance of limiting temperature rises to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, the next 10 years are the last chance to meet that goal - and with the Cop26 summit in Glasgow later this year, the G7 summit in Cornwall this week is the next staging post in a crucial six months to settle on a way forward.
But even as many countries set out significant pledges to do their part, the reality of their policies is often far behind. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s environment correspondent, Fiona Harvey, about what must happen to catch up with those commitments – and what this summit will tell us about the likelihood of making changes that are crucial to averting catastrophe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Fiona Harvey; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Slums of Mumbai to a Rented Apartment – My 30-Year Developer Journey]]></title>
        <id>60b357ad11ffb70827ef9a90</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-journey-into-tech-from-slums-of-mumbai-to-my-own-apartment/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year I tweeted about how I was moving from a Slum where I lived for 29 years to a multi-story rented apartment.  The tech community on Twitter responded with nothing but love. Dan Wahlin posted that he would love to hear more about my story. It's not going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cornucopia of Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340967</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-cornucopia-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know about y’all, but my feeds have been flooded with articles about CSS Container Queries these past few weeks. The buzz about container queries actually started back in December after Miriam Suzanne posted a proposal (picking up on …
The post A Cornucopia of Container Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Skills You Need to Start Freelancing as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60c0ccbed3126007592d5781</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-skills-you-need-to-start-freelancing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's the bottom line: you don't need much to get started as a freelance developer.  The biggest obstacle developers face when they're thinking about getting started is that they tend to overcomplicate things.  Most are intimidated by the sheer number of different paths or skills deemed necessary by various blog]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Bootstrap 5 and SASS by Building a Portfolio Website]]></title>
        <id>60c10a1dd3126007592d5988</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-bootstrap-5-and-sass-by-building-a-portfolio-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap is one of the most popular CSS frameworks and Sass is one of the most popular preprocessors for CSS. We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you about Bootstrap 5 and Sass by building a portfolio website. Patrick Muriungi developed this course.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[target=blank]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341916</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/targetblank/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does that make your eye twitch a little bit? Like… it’s a typo. It should be target="_blank" with an underscore to start the value. As in…
<a target="_blank" href="https://codepen.io"Open CodePen in a New Tab
</a
Welp, that’s correct syntax!…
The post target=blank appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have an example of UK car-led town planning you want to change?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of examples of car-led redevelopment where you live 
We’d like to find out how your UK town or city was redesigned for road vehicles.
From the 1950s onwards many towns and cities across the UK adopted car led planning in line with rising car ownership. Today, many residents in urban areas hope to have more environmentally friendly spaces and cleaner air which is at odds with past car led redevelopment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of your amazing sheds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about the impressive garden sheds you have built and customised
During lockdown some people have taken to sprucing up their sheds, whether it’s to give them a new lease of life or to create a haven away in the garden.
We would like to hear about your amazing sheds, however humble, and what they mean to you. If you have customised yours, what inspired you? What do you use it for?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The interrogation of Matt Hancock - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T02:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two weeks after Dominic Cummings told MPs that the health secretary was a serial liar who lost the trust of No 10, Matt Hancock will face the same committee to defend himself. Heather Stewart explains what is at stake, and what it could mean for the next stage of the pandemic
When Dominic Cummings appeared before MPs to set out his account of what went wrong in the early stages of the Covid pandemic, he attempted a political assassination. But a fortnight later, Matt Hancock, the health secretary, is still limping on. So far, Hancock has been able to bat away questions from journalists, and at the dispatch box, without much trouble, and has retained the support of the prime minister. But a grilling by MPs, who will have much more time and the chance to follow up on their questions, will present him with a far greater challenge.
Hancock’s day of reckoning comes with the 21 June planned unlocking still uncertain, and the number of cases rising again, so his future will have profound consequences for the country. Rachel Humphreys spoke to the Guardian’s political editor, Heather Stewart, about the questions he is likely to face, the light his answers could shed on what went wrong, and why Boris Johnson appears determined to stick with his man — for now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Heather Stewart; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy Your freeCodeCamp Project on AWS – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide to the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>60bfa4d4d3126007592d5160</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-your-freecodecamp-project-on-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T23:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One night in June, 2017 I stumbled across a website called freecodecamp.org. I was a teacher at the time who was looking for a career change. But I assumed being a programmer was out of my reach. After all, I didn’t consider myself a math whiz, never went]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341982</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/looking-at-wcag-2-5-5-for-better-target-sizes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever experienced the frustration of trying to tap a button on a mobile device only to have it do nothing because the target size is just not large enough **and it’s not picking up on your press? Maybe …
The post Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Todd Libby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341884</id>
        <link href="https://alex.party/posts/2021-05-31-css-trickz-an-experiment-with-netlify-s-on-demand-builders/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress sites have an API by default. Wanna see this site’s most recent posts, with just a specific set of data… in JSON format? Here ya go. Alex Riviere made a joke site using that.
At first, the site …
The post CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you planning on joining protests at the G7 summit?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from people who’re planning on demonstrating during this week’s G7 summit in Cornwall 
 Later this week, world leaders will be attending the G7 summit, at Carbis Bay, near St Ives in Cornwall, to discuss global issues including the Covid pandemic and climate change.
The coalition comprises seven countries; the UK, Japan, US, Italy, Germany, Canada and France.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katie Piper and Candice Brathwaite on how emotions affect their complexions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you break out in a rash when you’re stressed, you’re not alone. Find out how two women in the public eye cope when anxiety affects their skin – and discover the science behind the spots
Spots, rashes and flushing can often affect your emotions, making you self-conscious or even embarrassed. But did you know that, conversely, heightened emotions can aggravate your skin, making it vulnerable to breakouts – and that this is scientifically recognised?
“It’s been shown, on a molecular level, that there are changes to the chemicals in the skin when we get stressed,” says consultant dermatologist Dr Justine Hextall. “The blood vessels dilate and then you often get a flushed red face.” Stress will change the skin barrier, the outer layer of skin cells and the ceramides, cholesterols and fatty acids that hold them together, making inflammation more likely.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fielding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>