<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-08T00:54:17.141Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-08T00:54:17.141Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Full Stack App with Supabase and Next.js]]></title>
        <id>60bbd28eacb62507dd1d99fb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-complete-guide-to-full-stack-development-with-supabas/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:33:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to build full stack serverless apps with Supabase and Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keira Knightley says every woman she knows has been harassed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/08/keira-knightley-says-every-woman-she-knows-has-been-harassed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/08/keira-knightley-says-every-woman-she-knows-has-been-harassed"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:31:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British actor tells magazine about precautions she takes walking home and says situation is ‘depressing’
Keira Knightley has spoken about how sexual harassment is such a big problem she “literally” does not know any woman who has not been subjected to it, including herself.
The British actor said that, from groping to being flashed, “everybody” has been harassed in some way.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kayaker rescued during California-to-Hawaii solo attempt: ‘It went from bad to worse’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/kayaker-rescued-california-hawaii-cyril-derreumaux</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/kayaker-rescued-california-hawaii-cyril-derreumaux"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:08:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyril Derreumaux was picked up six days after he set out amid rough seas and high winds, causing him to lose his sea anchor
Cyril Derreumaux set out from the coastal town of Sausalito, California, on 31 May, headed for Hawaii in what was supposed to be an epic 70-day voyage across the Pacific to Hawaii.
But his hopes of paddling solo from the mainland to the islands were cut short over the weekend by rough seas and high winds.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Powerful’ new watchdog will target unscrupulous employers, says No 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/08/powerful-new-watchdog-will-target-unscrupulous-employers-says-no-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/08/powerful-new-watchdog-will-target-unscrupulous-employers-says-no-10"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government claims body will enforce minimum wage and tackle modern slavery, but critics brand proposals ‘light on action’
A “powerful new watchdog” is to be created to tackle abuse by unscrupulous employers and name and shame big brands that turn a blind eye to exploitation of workers by their suppliers, the government has said.
However, the Labour party and the Trades Union Congress (TUC) criticised the “heavy on spin but light on action” proposals, saying the body would do little to change the insecure working conditions faced by many and highlighting that there was no timetable for its introduction.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Butler Social policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK retail sales in May saw highest rise since start of Covid crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/08/uk-retail-sales-in-may-saw-highest-rise-since-start-of-covid-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/08/uk-retail-sales-in-may-saw-highest-rise-since-start-of-covid-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shoppers returned to high street after lockdown measures were relaxed
UK retail sales surged in May by the most since the Covid-19 pandemic began as shoppers returned to high streets across the country after lockdown measures were relaxed, according to industry figures.
The British Retail Consortium said total sales increased by 10% in May compared with the same month in 2019, before Covid-19 hit consumer spending and tipped the UK into recession.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hilary Osborne and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK electoral officials announce biggest shake-up of boundaries in decades]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/08/uk-electoral-officials-announce-biggest-shake-up-of-boundaries-in-decades</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/08/uk-electoral-officials-announce-biggest-shake-up-of-boundaries-in-decades"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour leader among those affected by changes, which will increase the number of English constituencies at the expense of Scotland and Wales
Electoral officials have announced plans for the biggest shake-up of parliamentary constituencies in England in decades, one that critics immediately warned would break up many recognisable communities because of an overly strict set of rules.
Among those affected would be Keir Starmer. The initial plan for the Labour leader’s London seat of Holborn and St Pancras would see it significantly rejigged and renamed as Kentish Town and Bloomsbury.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker and Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of UK men to benefit after NHS approves prostate cancer drug]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/08/thousands-of-uk-men-to-benefit-after-nhs-approves-prostate-cancer-drug</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/08/thousands-of-uk-men-to-benefit-after-nhs-approves-prostate-cancer-drug"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Enzalutamide, which can be taken at home, is especially beneficial to those who cannot have chemotherapy
Thousands of men in the UK with advanced prostate cancer are to benefit from a new drug after it was approved for NHS use.
The National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (Nice) has recommended enzalutamide as an option for treating some types of prostate cancer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Las Vegas’s new strategy for tackling drought – banning ‘useless grass’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/las-vegas-drought-ban-useless-grass</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/las-vegas-drought-ban-useless-grass"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T22:48:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First-in-the-nation ban targets grass at office parks, street medians and housing development entrances that no one uses
In Sin City, one thing that will soon become unforgivable is useless grass.
A new Nevada law will outlaw about 40% of the grass in the Las Vegas area in an effort to conserve water amid a drought that is drying up the region’s primary water source: the Colorado River.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to take a good photograph of the moon on your phone or camera with the right settings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/how-to-take-a-photograph-of-the-full-moon-with-phone-photography-tonight-picture-night-sky-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/how-to-take-a-photograph-of-the-full-moon-with-phone-photography-tonight-picture-night-sky-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T22:43:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of photographing the moon
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately the moon is really challenging to get a great photo of.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paedophile’s ‘industrial scale’ blackmail scam targeted 2,000 victims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/paedophiles-industrial-scale-blackmail-scam-targeted-2000-victims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/paedophiles-industrial-scale-blackmail-scam-targeted-2000-victims"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T22:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abdul Elahi, who extorted adults and minors globally while posing as online sugar daddy, admits 158 charges
A paedophile who exploited and blackmailed almost 2,000 victims globally has admitted 158 charges in what has been described as “industrial-scale” offending.
Abdul Elahi, 26, admitted a host of charges – thought to be among the highest number of offences one individual has ever pleaded guilty to – after a lengthy investigation, the National Crime Agency (NCA) said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canadian man charged with murder after allegedly driving into Muslim family]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/canada-killings-london-ontario-motorist-targeted-muslims-police</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/canada-killings-london-ontario-motorist-targeted-muslims-police"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T22:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two women, a man and a girl were killed on Sunday when Nathaniel Veltman drove a pickup truck into pedestrians, police say
A 20-year-old Canadian man has been charged with four counts of first-degree murder and one of attempted murder after driving his pickup truck into a Muslim family in what police described as “a premeditated attack”.
Two women, aged 74 and 44, a 46-year-old man and a 15-year-old girl – a grandmother, mother, father and their teenage daughter – were killed on Sunday night when Nathaniel Veltman ploughed his black pickup truck into a group of pedestrians in the city of London, Ontario, police said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fatima Syed in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s lack of momentum and clarity eased by return of cavalry | David Hytner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/07/englands-lack-of-momentum-and-clarity-eased-by-return-of-cavalry-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/07/englands-lack-of-momentum-and-clarity-eased-by-return-of-cavalry-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T21:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate has been spinning plates in the warm-ups but Chelsea and Manchester City reinforcements are a boost
Tyrone Mings’s forearm smash on the Austria striker Sasa Kalajdzic. Jordan Henderson’s taking of a penalty away from the centre-forward Dominic Calvert-Lewin against Romania, and missing it. Any number of defensive slips, individually or collectively.
The thought has occurred all too frequently during England’s Euro 2020 warm-up games: thank goodness it was not the finals. Can you imagine if these kind of errors, some rooted in the all-consuming desire to impress, in players essentially losing their composure, had happened, say, against Croatia in the opening group game on Sunday?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris faces doubts over retooled US policy in Central America]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/us-guatemala-policy-kamala-harris</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/us-guatemala-policy-kamala-harris"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T21:22:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critics question whether push against corruption and human trafficking marks genuine change amid growing poverty
Kamala Harris, the US vice-president, has announced a new anti-corruption drive, economic aid and tougher enforcement against human trafficking during a visit to Guatemala.
But Harris, on her first foreign trip as vice-president, faced sceptical questions over whether the measures she announced would represent a real change in US policy in the region, at a time of worsening poverty and corruption.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smother review – Maeve Binchy-esque thriller is entirely addictive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/07/smother-review-maeve-binchy-esque-thriller-is-entirely-addictive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/07/smother-review-maeve-binchy-esque-thriller-is-entirely-addictive"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T21:10:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This new Irish drama expertly manages a large cast of characters, with seeds of suspicion, red herrings – and a monstrous patriarch left for dead
Smother (Alibi), a new County Clare-set thriller by novelist and television writer Kate O’Riordan, reminds me – and I have few higher compliments – of the work of Maeve Binchy, if she had ever turned her hand to whodunnits. It has a seemingly effortless mastery of a large cast of characters, warm intelligence pervading everything, and promotes the gorgeous general sense of being held for the duration in a very safe pair of hands indeed. Like Binchy, it is also entirely addictive.
It opens with an altercation on a clifftop that ends with a man dead on the beach below. Then, as is currently TV fashion, we spool back to earlier that night, as successful businessman Denis (Stuart Graham) hosts his wife Val’s (Dervla Kirwan) 50th birthday party. Their three daughters are there – Jenny (Niamh Walsh), a heavily pregnant single doctor who works eternally for Daddy’s approval, Anna (Gemma-Leah Devereux), who is in the final stages of a custody battle with her husband Rory’s ex-wife for the latter’s two sons, and Grace (Seána Kerslake), the fragile youngest, struggling with mental illness and currently off her medication.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kyle Sinckler eager to make most of late Lions call-up for South Africa tour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/kyle-sinckler-eager-to-make-most-of-late-lions-call-up-for-south-africa-tour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/kyle-sinckler-eager-to-make-most-of-late-lions-call-up-for-south-africa-tour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T21:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prop urges Warren Gatland to ‘put me on the field’
Sinckler was controversial omission from original squad

Kyle Sinckler has urged Warren Gatland to “put me on the field” after earning a British & Irish Lions reprieve with the Bristol and England prop determined to prove he deserves his place in the squad following his late call-up.
Sinckler was the shock omission from the original 37-man squad but when Ireland’s Andrew Porter was ruled out with a toe injury he received the call from Gatland on Sunday morning. By his own admission, Sinckler had written off any hopes of touring South Africa after processing the initial disappointment last month – plain for all to see in an emotional interview days after the squad announcement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DoJ reclaims millions paid to hackers after attack that hobbled US pipeline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/ransomware-pipeline-money-recovered-us-doj</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/ransomware-pipeline-money-recovered-us-doj"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:59:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operation to recover cryptocurrency from Russia-based hacking group is first undertaken by new ransomware taskforce
The US Justice Department has recovered the majority of a multimillion-dollar ransom payment to hackers after a cyberattack that caused the operator of the nation’s largest fuel pipeline to halt its operations last month, officials said Monday.
The operation to recover the cryptocurrency from the Russia-based hacker group is the first undertaken by a specialized ransomware taskforce created by the Biden administration, and reflects what US officials say is an increasingly aggressive approach to deal with a ransomware threat that in the last month has targeted critical industries around the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vivian Ho and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenCV and Python for Computer Vision and AI]]></title>
        <id>60be863cd3126007592d4c36</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opencv-and-python-for-computer-vision-and-ai/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a popular Python library for real-time computer vision. We just released a new OpenCV course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. This course comes directly from the creators of OpenCV and is the perfect course for beginners.  You will learn how to use OpenCV for Computer Vision and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple overhauls Siri to address privacy concerns and improve performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-overhauls-siri-to-address-privacy-concerns-and-improve-performance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-overhauls-siri-to-address-privacy-concerns-and-improve-performance"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:28:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistant will no longer send audio recordings to firm’s servers, instead processing requests ‘on device’
Apple will no longer send Siri requests to its servers, the company has announced, in a move to substantially speed up the voice assistant’s operation and address privacy concerns.
The new feature comes two years after the Guardian revealed that Apple staff regularly heard confidential details while carrying out quality control for the feature.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Springboks among Munster players burnt in fire pit accident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/springboks-among-munster-players-burnt-in-fire-pit-accident</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/springboks-among-munster-players-burnt-in-fire-pit-accident"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:23:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Munster coach Van Graan confirms injuries are not serious
De Allende and Snyman in South Africa squad to face Lions

Damian de Allende and RG Snyman, who were named last weekend in the South Africa squad to face the British & Irish Lions this summer, are among four Munster players to have sustained burns in a fire pit accident.
The Springbok pair are said to have sustained more substantial burns to their legs, hands and face and come off worse than CJ Stander and Mike Haley – the other two players involved in the incident last weekend.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple paid woman millions after technicians used her iPhone to post explicit videos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-settles-iphone-explicit-images</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-settles-iphone-explicit-images"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:22:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Videos uploaded by Apple-approved team falsely appeared to have been shared by Oregon woman herself, filing says

Apple has paid a multi-million dollar settlement to an Oregon woman after iPhone repair technicians uploaded explicit images and videos to the internet from a phone that she sent in for repair.
Legal filings, first reported on by the Telegraph, revealed the unnamed woman sent her iPhone for repair on 14 January 2016 to an Apple-approved repair contractor called Pegatron Technology Service in California. Technicians there then uploaded “extremely personal and private material” to the woman’s Facebook account and other internet locations, the documents said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and Amanda Holpuch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[24,000-year-old organisms found frozen in Siberia can still reproduce]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/07/24000-year-old-organisms-found-frozen-in-siberia-can-still-reproduce</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/07/24000-year-old-organisms-found-frozen-in-siberia-can-still-reproduce"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:47:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Russian scientists find bdelloid rotifers deep in remote permafrost
A microscopic worm-like creature, labelled an “evolutionary scandal” by biologists for having thrived for millions of years without having sex, has now been shown to persist for at least 24,000 years in Siberian permafrost and then reproduce, researchers have found.
Multicellular invertebrates that are solely female, bdelloid rotifers are already renowned for their resistance to radiation and ability to withstand rather inhospitable environments: drying, starvation and low oxygen. They’ve also existed for at least 35m years – and can be found today in freshwater lakes, ponds, streams and moist terrestrial habitats such as moss, lichen, tree bark and soil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lindsay Hoyle shows he’s not a complete pushover. He’s just a bit of one]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/lindsay-hoyle-shows-hes-not-a-complete-pushover-hes-just-a-bit-of-a-one</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/lindsay-hoyle-shows-hes-not-a-complete-pushover-hes-just-a-bit-of-a-one"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:11:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Speaker did not accept amendment on foreign aid, instead opting for a vote that would not be legally binding
Lindsay Hoyle is learning how to work an audience. When the Speaker announced that he would not be accepting Andrew Mitchell’s amendment to restore the government’s commitment to spend 0.7% of gross national income on overseas aid, you could almost hear the cheers in Downing Street. The potential for major embarrassment ahead of this weekend’s G7 meeting in Cornwall had been averted.
Or not. Because moments later, Hoyle went on to say that he would be open to an emergency debate the following day if one were to be requested. In a point of order, Mitchell needed no second invitation. He assured the house he had the necessary numbers to win by a majority of between nine and 20 and, though disappointed the vote would not now be legally binding, the debate would give parliament the chance to express its will on the government’s unilateral decision to break its manifesto commitment and cut overseas aid by 0.2%. Hoyle looked on in satisfaction. It felt good not to be the complete pushover that many had feared after all. Being a bit of a pushover was just fine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson likely to defy Tory rebels by ignoring order for vote on aid cuts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/johnson-likely-to-defy-tory-rebels-by-ignoring-order-to-hold-vote-on-aid-cuts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/johnson-likely-to-defy-tory-rebels-by-ignoring-order-to-hold-vote-on-aid-cuts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least 40 Conservative MPs are fighting on to get overseas funding restored after setback in Commons
Boris Johnson has set himself on a collision course with scores of his MPs as No 10 suggested it would defy an order by the House of Commons speaker to bring a vote on swingeing foreign aid cuts.
Between 40 and 50 Conservative MPs were said to be considering defying the government on Monday before an ambush in the Commons was thwarted, with rebels now exploring options including legal action.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[France and Belgium look strong but key at Euro 2020 will be improvisation | Philipp Lahm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/france-and-belgium-look-strong-but-key-at-euro-2020-will-be-improvisation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/france-and-belgium-look-strong-but-key-at-euro-2020-will-be-improvisation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[History shows the smaller teams have a better chance at the Euros – that is part of the special charm of the tournament
It is sometimes said that national teams are no longer in keeping with the times. In fact, the concept of nation is historically burdened, especially in Europe. But it is not only a suitable form that organises our coexistence well. Nation also creates identification.
And so a competition of nations, a European Championship, strengthens the European idea. Through the playfulness of football, it can even serve international understanding in the broadest sense, because everyone acts according to the same rules and many people from many different regions participate, whether as players or fans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philipp Lahm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning off building lights at night cuts bird collisions, study shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/turning-off-building-lights-at-night-cuts-bird-collisions-study-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/turning-off-building-lights-at-night-cuts-bird-collisions-study-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paper is based on 40 years of record-keeping involving 40,000 dead birds, started after an offhand remark
Turning off building lights at night can save migrating birds from crashing into buildings, a study based on decades of research has shown.
Scientists found that on nights when half the windows of a large building in Chicago were darkened, there were 11 times fewer bird collisions during spring migration and six times fewer collisions during autumn migration than when all the windows were lit.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on the England men’s football team taking the knee – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/07/steve-bell-england-football-team-taking-knee-booing-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/07/steve-bell-england-football-team-taking-knee-booing-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Studying maths beyond GCSEs helps brain development, say scientists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/studying-maths-beyond-gcses-helps-brain-development-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/studying-maths-beyond-gcses-helps-brain-development-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teenagers who stick with the subject have higher levels of chemical vital for brain plasticity, research shows
Students who drop mathematics at the age of 16 have lower amounts of a brain chemical that is critical for brain and cognitive development, compared with those who continue maths, a study has found.
Researchers at the University of Oxford found that those who stopped maths after their GCSEs had less gamma-aminobutyric acid, a chemical which is crucial for brain plasticity, than counterparts who pursued maths post-16.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mexico elections: President Amlo fails to win super-majority in midterms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/mexico-elections-midterms-amlo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/mexico-elections-midterms-amlo"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:57:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But president’s Morena party keeps its majority in the lower house of congress
Mexican voters have denied President Andrés Manuel López Obrador a mega-majority in midterm elections, though his Morena party kept its majority in the lower house of congress with the support of a controversial ally.
Voters also showed little enthusiasm for Mexico’s rightwing opposition, which remains reviled after its decisive 2018 defeat by López Obrador, who swept to power promising to curb corruption and put the poor first.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Agren in Mexico City</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Williamson attacks schools amid criticism of education catch-up plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/williamson-attacks-schools-amid-criticism-of-education-catch-up-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/williamson-attacks-schools-amid-criticism-of-education-catch-up-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:47:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Education secretary accuses schools of sending children home early as MPs criticise ‘disappointing’ Covid recovery plans
The education secretary has accused schools of cutting short lunch breaks and sending children home early as he came under sustained fire from opposition MPs angry about the government’s “disappointing” education recovery package.
In a tricky hour-long defence of the additional £1.4bn catch-up funding offer, which caused uproar when it was announced last week, Williamson attempted to placate his critics promising that more was to come including a review of the length of the school day to maximise on catch-up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 tax deal is welcome – but Treasury must now focus on unfair business rates | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/07/g7-tax-deal-treasury-business-rates-nils-pratley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/07/g7-tax-deal-treasury-business-rates-nils-pratley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:44:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bricks-and-mortar retailers have been losing out to online-only operators for too long
A global agreement on the taxation of multinationals, including the shape-shifting tech giants, seemed impossible until it came into view at the weekend.
There are hurdles to be cleared, of course. The G7 nations need to win support from elsewhere. Important details around how profits and profit margins are calculated need to be thrashed out. Meanwhile, the centrepiece – a global minimum tax rate of 15% – is not as ambitious as originally advertised. But one can say the accord is now more likely than not to bring about the first change in multinational taxation in a century. That is a major shift.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Is this about that article?’ Didsbury locals dismiss ‘no-go areas’ claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/is-this-about-that-article-didsbury-locals-dismiss-no-go-areas-claims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/is-this-about-that-article-didsbury-locals-dismiss-no-go-areas-claims"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:36:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester suburb held up as a ‘thriving community’ rather than example of religious apartheid

Walking down Burton Road on Monday afternoon, it is hard not to wonder if another Didsbury exists elsewhere after a report at the weekend described “no-go areas” where white people fear the threat of religious violence.
The Mail Online report claimed there were a number of towns with no-go areas for white people, and that Didsbury, along with Bradford, Blackburn and Bolton, was one of them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carey Mulligan and Zoe Kazan to star as reporters who exposed Weinstein]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/07/carey-mulligan-zoe-kazan-harvey-weinstein-she-said</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/07/carey-mulligan-zoe-kazan-harvey-weinstein-she-said"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:29:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actors will play New York Times reporters Megan Twohey and Jodi Kantor in an adaptation of the bestselling book She Said
Carey Mulligan and Zoe Kazan are set to take on the roles of the reporters who exposed Harvey Weinstein.
In She Said, the pair will play Megan Twohey and Jodi Kantor, the New York Times journalists whose landmark expose helped to bring down the movie mogul accused and ultimately convicted of sexual assault.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson refuses to condemn fans booing England taking the knee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/boris-johnson-refuses-to-condemn-fans-booing-england-taking-the-knee</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/boris-johnson-refuses-to-condemn-fans-booing-england-taking-the-knee"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:27:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM sends conflicting message over England’s anti-racism stance
Johnson urges ‘whole country’ to get behind team at Euro 2020

Boris Johnson has said he wants the “whole country” to get behind the England team but has refused to condemn those who booed players taking a knee, as a row over the anti-racism gesture threatens to overshadow the start of Euro 2020.
With a slew of Conservative MPs and right-wing commentators stirring up further controversy, fan groups called on those who jeered before two recent friendlies to stop. England play their opening Group D fixture against Croatia on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on foreign aid cuts: conservatism without compassion | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/the-guardian-view-on-foreign-aid-cuts-conservatism-without-compassion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/the-guardian-view-on-foreign-aid-cuts-conservatism-without-compassion"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:26:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government’s plan to slash £4bn from development spending is regressive and must be overturned 
Boris Johnson does not share the liberal belief in progress. “I think that history – societies and civilizations and nations – can rise and fall, and I think that things can go backwards,” he said recently in an interview for The Atlantic, an American magazine. There could be few neater demonstrations of this acceptance of historical regression than the government’s decision to cut the UK’s aid budget by £4bn, which dominated the news just hours after the article was published.
To those who believe the aim of politics must be a brighter and more stable future, in which poverty has been eliminated and the risks of runaway global heating contained, the UK’s promise to spend 0.7% of gross national income on foreign aid is a powerful symbol. It signals recognition of the obligations of rich nations and people to poorer ones, and a commitment to global cooperation. These ideas are widely shared, for reasons that range from a progressive internationalism to a belief that British “soft power” is part of its role as a former imperial power.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on footballers taking the knee: don’t boo, cheer | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/the-guardian-view-on-footballers-taking-the-knee-dont-boo-cheer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/the-guardian-view-on-footballers-taking-the-knee-dont-boo-cheer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Players are not obliged to keep their indignation about racism to themselves
The decision by the England football squad to “take the knee” was a landmark in recognising that racism is a pernicious blight on the game. This has been a slow process spanning decades, but it has gained momentum since the murder of George Floyd last year. There is a crisis in the sport: black players, who are over-represented on the pitch, are abused on and off it.
Non-white footballers in the world’s richest league face horrendous racism online. Racist match taunts have not disappeared. The England football team has debated walking off the pitch rather than putting up with abuse. Footballers in Euro 2020 ought to be congratulated for pre-match kneeling to show their opposition to racism.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leftist teacher holds razor-thin lead in Peru presidential election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/peru-elections-results-pedro-castillo-keiko-fujimori</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/peru-elections-results-pedro-castillo-keiko-fujimori"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:21:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Castillo is about 0.2% ahead of his far-right opponent, Keiko Fujimori, with more than 94% of the vote counted
The scion of a jailed autocrat and the son of illiterate peasant farmers are fighting vote by vote for the presidency of Peru, in an election which has thrown into sharp relief the Andean country’s deep fault lines of class and geography.
 Related: Peru faces poll dilemma: a leftist firebrand or the dictator’s daughter? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Collyns in Lima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Closures in JavaScript – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>5ff625967af2371468bb8645</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/closures-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Closures are a confusing JavaScript concept to learn, because it's hard to see how they're actually used.  Unlike other concepts such as functions, variables, and objects, you don't always use closures conscientiously and directly. You don't say: Oh! Here I will use a closure as a solution. But at the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The tech billionaire space race: who is Jeff Bezos up against?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/07/the-tech-billionaire-space-race-who-is-jeff-bezos-up-against</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/07/the-tech-billionaire-space-race-who-is-jeff-bezos-up-against"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:56:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Amazon founder prepares to jet off in his Blue Origin vessel, can he compete with Elon Musk’s SpaceX?

Jeff Bezos to go into space on first crewed flight of New Shepard rocket

Every billionaire needs something to spend their fortunes on. For Howard Hughes, it was the Spruce Goose; for Roman Abramovich, it’s Chelsea FC. And for the current crop of tech moguls, it’s space.
Jeff Bezos has led the charge. He founded his company, Blue Origin, in 2000, after a conversation with his friend, the science fiction author Neal Stephenson. And in July, 21 years later, the investment will pay off: Bezos will blast himself, his brother, and a third fee-paying guest 100km up in the company’s New Shepard rocket, brushing the edge of space until he comes back down to earth three minutes later.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prolonged impasse feared as parkrun in England faces further delay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/parkrun-return-in-england-set-to-be-delayed-once-again</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/parkrun-return-in-england-set-to-be-delayed-once-again"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many councils refusing to permit events
Organisers fear ‘impasse that could drag on’

It is the news that more than 200,000 weekly devotees of parkrun across England have been dreading: its return is almost certain to be delayed again despite three-quarters of events now having approval to restart.
The major stumbling block, the Guardian can reveal, is the low number of permissions from councils in several major cities. While 427 out of 564 events now have permission to resume, barely half the parkruns in London and Manchester have got the all clear. The situation in Newcastle and Middlesbrough is even worse, with no events currently allowed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson joins Oliver Dowden in ECB criticism over Ollie Robinson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/sports-minister-oliver-dowden-says-ecb-over-the-top-to-suspend-ollie-robinson-england-cricket</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/sports-minister-oliver-dowden-says-ecb-over-the-top-to-suspend-ollie-robinson-england-cricket"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Culture secretary says board’s action is ‘over the top’
England head coach says impossible to dismiss tweets

The prime minister, Boris Johnson, and the sports minister, Oliver Dowden, have both criticised the England and Wales Cricket Board’s decision to suspend the bowler Ollie Robinson from international cricket while it conducts an investigation into historic offensive tweets published in 2012 and 2013, with Dowden insisting the move was “over the top”.
Robinson excelled on debut in England’s first Test against New Zealand, which ended in a draw on Sunday, taking seven wickets and scoring 42 in the first innings, a total bettered only by the centurion Rory Burns. His performance was all the more impressive for having been played out amid the controversy caused by the tweets, which were rediscovered and widely distributed as play progressed on the opening day. His suspension was announced on Sunday night, ruling him out of the second match which starts in Birmingham on Thursday, and potentially beyond.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Burnton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put on the dog: four easy at-home spa treatments to care for your canine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/08/put-on-the-dog-four-easy-at-home-spa-treatments-to-care-for-your-canine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/08/put-on-the-dog-four-easy-at-home-spa-treatments-to-care-for-your-canine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From soothing paw balms to puppy-safe bath bombs, these DIY treatments make wash day a treat
Essential oils can have many healing and nurturing effects, not only on us humans but our dogs too. Dogs with generalised anxiety, noise phobias or separation anxiety may benefit from aromatherapy – specifically lavender essential oil.
It’s important to only use essential oils that are 100% pure and to choose essential oils that are safe for your dog. These treatments are no substitute for quality veterinary care, and you should consult with your vet before using any essential oil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Rigg and Jacqui Melville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccines are risky for me, but I don’t regret getting my Covid jab | Gemma Carey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/08/vaccines-are-risky-for-me-but-i-dont-regret-getting-my-covid-jab</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/08/vaccines-are-risky-for-me-but-i-dont-regret-getting-my-covid-jab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why did I get vaccinated as an immunocompromised person? The short answer is because of you
As someone with a complex autoimmune history, I consulted widely before making my Covid vaccine decision. I read all the research I could find, I spoke to all my specialists. I chose to have the AstraZeneca vaccine on the best medical advice and research available to me. Twenty-four hours later, I was in ambulance.
Back in 2012, I had a rare autoimmune disease called Guillain-Barré syndrome, which caused my immune system to shred my nervous system. Years later I have most of my arm and leg function back and only the odd bout of nerve pain. I’m considered one of the lucky ones. I didn’t die. But with such a twitchy immune system, vaccines are risky for me.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gemma Carey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gambling awards under fire over lack of diversity on judging panel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/gambling-awards-under-fire-over-lack-of-diversity-on-judging-panel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/gambling-awards-under-fire-over-lack-of-diversity-on-judging-panel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:29:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Global Gaming Awards judging panel of 52 people includes one woman and no black people 
One of the gambling sector’s most prestigious awards events has come under fire after it emerged that the judging panel of 52 people contains one woman and no black people.
The Global Gaming Awards, convened by industry publication Gambling Insider, honours the top companies and executives for their achievements during the year. The awards for 2020 will be judged by a 52-strong panel that “represents a dynamic cross-section of the global gaming industry”, according to a published shortlist of nominees.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England braced for backlash if Craig Overton replaces Robinson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/england-braced-for-backlash-if-craig-overton-replaces-robinson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/england-braced-for-backlash-if-craig-overton-replaces-robinson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:29:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All-rounder was suspended after 2015 incident
Second Test at Edgbaston starts on Thursday

Chris Silverwood has said he is braced to deal with any criticism should Craig Overton emerge as the player who replaces the suspended Ollie Robinson in England’s team for the second Test.
Robinson has been stood down from the squad to play New Zealand at Edgbaston in the match starting on Thursday pending the outcome of an investigation into the offensive tweets that emerged during his debut in the Lord’s draw last week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dido Harding to head the NHS? Her position would be untenable | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/dido-harding-nhs-test-and-trace-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/dido-harding-nhs-test-and-trace-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T17:12:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[She presided over the test-and-trace debacle. But it seems Boris Johnson is hellbent on embedding Torydom
They can shrink the state with fiscal austerity, but they can diminish it, too, by imposing state-shrinkers on its controlling heights. Not since the Victorians abolished patronage with open competition has any government so ruthlessly ushered its placemen into every nook and cranny of the public realm. To appoint Dido Harding as NHS England chief executive – she told the BBC’s Woman’s Hour that she’s considering applying – would signal a slide back to the dark ages of influence.
With a Downing Street nod, she’s in the running. From the world of business, with no NHS experience, she was made chair of NHS Improvement, overseeing all trusts. Again, without contest, she was put in charge of the test-and-trace project, possibly the most notorious public administration disaster in living memory.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mother of boy who drowned in Welsh river says she will sue if CPS fails to act]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/mother-of-boy-who-drowned-in-welsh-river-says-she-will-take-legal-action-if-cps-refuses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/mother-of-boy-who-drowned-in-welsh-river-says-she-will-take-legal-action-if-cps-refuses"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:56:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alina Joseph says death of son, Christopher Kapessa, 13, would have been treated more seriously if he had not been black
The mother of a 13-year-old boy who died after allegedly being pushed into a river has vowed to launch a private prosecution if the authorities continue to refuse to take action against the teenage suspect.
Alina Joseph, the mother of Christopher Kapessa, said she was certain that if her son had not been black, the police and Crown Prosecution Service (CPS) would have taken the case more seriously.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[France fines Google for abusing online advertising dominance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/france-fines-google-for-abusing-online-advertising-dominance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/france-fines-google-for-abusing-online-advertising-dominance"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:53:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tech giant will pay £189m after settlement found it unfairly favoured its own tools for buying and selling ads
Google has been fined €220m (£189m) by French competition regulators for abusing its dominance in the online advertising market in a landmark settlement that could rebalance the relationship between tech giants and digital publishers.
The settlement with the French competition authority, which found that Google unfairly favoured its own tools for buying and selling adverts online over those of rivals, marks the first time the Silicon Valley company has agreed to make changes to its practices as a result of the investigation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrate the beauty that comes with age | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/celebrate-the-beauty-that-comes-with-age</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/celebrate-the-beauty-that-comes-with-age"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:52:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ian Flintoff and Teresa McDonnell on notions of beauty, age and women in response to an article on Kate Winslet
Gaby Hinsliff (Kate Winslet shows there’s more to middle age than a saggy belly, 3 June) raises a question of massive importance to women, but also to us all. It is a myth that humans are less beautiful as they age – on the contrary. Years ago, to help me to understand things better, I got a season ticket to a Rembrandt exhibition. Many hours, day after day, taught me that, with the more truthful eyes of the artist, age is an etching of beauty on the more stereotyped images that are thrust upon us by adverts, pin-ups and porn. If the rosebush had eyes, it would peer at any human with wonder and exclaim: “How can anything of such wonder, beauty and complexity possibly exist?”
An analogy I often use is of the flashy cover on the latest novel in a bookshop, comparing this with the patina, beauty and handcrafting of an antique volume in a museum. Things – and people – lose beauty with age? No! The opposite is the case by any other than the most superficial standards of self-interest.
Ian Flintoff
Oxford
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t worry too much, Generation Z, we humans are a resilient species | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/dont-worry-too-much-generation-z-we-humans-are-a-resilient-species</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/dont-worry-too-much-generation-z-we-humans-are-a-resilient-species"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:51:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sue Ball and Phyll Hardie respond to the fears that young people have about their future following the pandemic
I am saddened that Ava Ayala Rosenbaum believes 70-year-olds live a locked-down life, with or without a pandemic (Gen Z special report, 2 June). It’s not something I recognise. Most of us have lives filled with purpose, direction, passion and social connections – maybe not as much as a 22-year-old, but still fulfilling. We may not spend much time musing, but we do quite a bit of doing. We may not qualify for a midlife crisis, but we can do a “silver swerve” if the mood takes us.
I hope Ava Ayala doesn’t spend the next 50 years dreading her 70s. It would be a waste of her obvious intelligence, drive and spirit, and do more damage than any pandemic.
Sue Ball
Brighton
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tribunal ‘deeply concerned’ by racism among Home Office contractors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tribunal-deeply-concerned-by-racism-among-home-office-contractors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tribunal-deeply-concerned-by-racism-among-home-office-contractors"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:50:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Black workers spoken of in derogatory way by colleagues at Mitie who handled deportations
An employment tribunal has said that it was “deeply concerned” about Home Office contractors who deport people from the UK having used the racist term “cotton pickers” to describe their black colleagues, but threw out a claim of race and disability discrimination.
The Home Office uses the contractor Mitie to deport people to destinations including Jamaica, Pakistan, India, Nigeria and Ghana along with European countries and other locations. The escorts are only allowed to do this work if they have received accreditation from the Home Office.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU to make Northern Ireland concessions but says patience is ‘wearing thin’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/brexit-row-deepens-between-frost-and-eu-over-northern-ireland-protocol</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/brexit-row-deepens-between-frost-and-eu-over-northern-ireland-protocol"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:37:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels points to UK’s repeated failure to live up to its obligations but will offer concessions in effort to find solution
Brussels is preparing to make concessions over Northern Ireland but has warned Lord Frost ahead of a key meeting that the EU’s “patience is wearing thin” over the UK government’s repeated failure to fulfil its obligations.
In response to claims from the Brexit minister in recent weeks that the bloc had been insufficiently flexible, EU officials pointed to a series of decisions by Downing Street that had eroded trust while signalling that it was prepared to bend on some issues.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric McGraw obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/eric-mcgraw-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/eric-mcgraw-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Penal reform campaigner who founded Inside Time, the national newspaper for prisoners
Without Eric McGraw, who has died aged 76, there would have been no Inside Time, the national newspaper for prisoners and detainees. McGraw, a social justice campaigner, created the title in the wake of the Strangeways riot in 1990.
At the time he was director of the prisoner befriending charity New Bridge, co-founded by the prison reformer Lord (Frank) Longford to provide supportive links between prisoners and the community. In that capacity McGraw attended the subsequent Woolf inquiry into the riot. “I was just sitting listening and learning and straight away it occurred to me that one of the reasons this had happened was that the prisoners had no voice,” he told me later. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erwin James</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Himalayan balsam: UK volunteers battle playboy of horticultural world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/himalayan-balsam-uk-volunteers-urged-to-help-to-battle-invasive-weed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/himalayan-balsam-uk-volunteers-urged-to-help-to-battle-invasive-weed"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cumbria is latest county to raise SOS as plant causes erosion and smothers other flowers
Himalayan balsam’s attractive exterior masks a deadly intent. Don’t be fooled by its soothing name, pink flowers and pleasant perfume – according to ecologists, this invasive species chokes our waterways, causes riverbank erosion and is smothering our wild flowers at a terrifying rate.
Determined to stop this nefarious weed from colonising even more of Britain’s lowlands, crack squads of “balsam bashers” have been out regularly since spring, hoping to pull up the evil herb before it has chance to flower.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top intimacy coach says too many TV bosses still do not value role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/07/top-intimacy-coach-ita-obrien-says-too-many-tv-bosses-still-dont-value-role</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/07/top-intimacy-coach-ita-obrien-says-too-many-tv-bosses-still-dont-value-role"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T16:07:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ita O’Brien says Bafta praise from Michaela Coel was a surprise and working with her was a joy
Too many film and television bosses still do not understand the value of intimacy coordinators and hire them purely as a box-ticking exercise, one of the industry’s leading figures has said.
Ita O’Brien was celebrated on Sunday by the actor and writer Michaela Coel, who dedicated her best actress Bafta to the “essential” work she did on I May Destroy You. Coel spoke powerfully of the “internal devastation” she had felt working on shows that had no intimacy coordinator.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Brown Arts correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third wave sweeps across Africa as Covid vaccine imports dry up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/third-wave-sweeps-across-africa-as-covid-vaccine-imports-dry-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/third-wave-sweeps-across-africa-as-covid-vaccine-imports-dry-up"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:55:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WHO says continent urgently needs more jabs as eight countries report rise of 30% in cases in a week

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

African countries face a last-ditch battle against a third wave of Covid infections, as the supply of vaccines to the continent “grinds to a halt”, top health officials have warned.
“The threat of a third wave in Africa is real and rising. Our priority is clear – it’s crucial that we swiftly get vaccines into the arms of Africans at high risk of falling seriously ill and dying of Covid-19,” said Dr Matshidiso Moeti, the World Health Organization (WHO) regional director for Africa.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke Africa correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FDA approves first new Alzheimer’s drug in almost 20 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/fda-announce-decision-new-alzheimers-drug-aducanumab</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/07/fda-announce-decision-new-alzheimers-drug-aducanumab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:55:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usefulness of aducanumab is disputed but US approval will trigger push to make it available globally

A controversial new drug for Alzheimer’s disease, the first in nearly 20 years, was approved in the US on Monday, which will trigger pressure to make it available worldwide in spite of mixed evidence over its efficacy.
While doctors, patients and the organisations that support them are desperate for treatments that can slow mental deterioration, the usefulness of the new drug, aducanumab, is disputed by scientists. Two trials were stopped in March 2019 because the drugs appeared not to work. The manufacturer, Biogen, said the drugs were unlikely to improve people’s memory and thinking.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hawaii bill seeks to gut funding aimed at protecting environment from tourism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/hawaii-bill-seeks-to-cut-funding-protect-environment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/hawaii-bill-seeks-to-cut-funding-protect-environment"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:38:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Legislature seeks to strip funding of Hawaii’s largest tourism agency, just as it refocuses on community and environment
Since 1998, the Hawaiian Tourism Authority (HTA) – the state’s leading agency to manage tourism – has had its focus largely on marketing Hawaii to the world. But in 2019, when the state hit a record of over 10 million tourists, the milestone taxed residents, and caused significant environmental impacts on trails, beaches and sacred sites.
During the pandemic, the agency’s new leader, John De Fries, called the time a “huliau”, which in Hawaiian means a time of transition. It was one that De Fries, the first Native Hawaiian in the role, felt would be the perfect moment to reset Hawaii in a way that would marry modern technology and Indigenous wisdom to protect the future of the island and promote its state-adopted sustainability goals by 2030.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Leonard in Hawaii</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naomi Osaka pulls out of Berlin tournament raising doubts over Wimbledon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/naomi-osaka-pulls-out-of-berlin-tournament-raising-doubts-over-wimbledon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/naomi-osaka-pulls-out-of-berlin-tournament-raising-doubts-over-wimbledon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:17:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Berlin WTA grass court tournament seen as Wimbledon tune-up
World No 2 has spoken of need to address her mental health

Naomi Osaka has officially withdrawn from the bett1open grass court tournament next week in Berlin, an event she had intended to compete in as a warm-up before Wimbledon. 
Her absence reflects uncertainty about whether she will compete at Wimbledon this month. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People in England aged 25 and over to be invited for Covid jab this week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/people-in-england-aged-25-and-over-to-be-invited-for-covid-jab-this-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/people-in-england-aged-25-and-over-to-be-invited-for-covid-jab-this-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:10:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock says government is ‘reassured’ that jab offers protection against Delta variant as he makes announcement

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Everyone aged 25 and over in England will be invited to get a coronavirus vaccine from Tuesday, Matt Hancock has announced, adding that the government is “reassured” that jabs still offer protection against the Delta variant discovered in India.
The health secretary said he was “cheered” by recent scenes of young people queueing to get their injections, telling the Commons: “The enthusiasm for the jab is not just the preserve of older generations.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin flicks: quantifying the Disney tattoo phenomenon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/07/skin-flicks-quantifying-the-disney-tattoo-phenomenon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/07/skin-flicks-quantifying-the-disney-tattoo-phenomenon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:09:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For reasons unclear, an online bingo site has decided to find out which Disney film the most people have tattooed on to themselves 

I do not have any tattoos. This is because I am afraid of pain, and also because I worry that permanently advertising one of my enthusiasms on my body would open me up even further to scorn and ridicule from strangers. However, many people do have tattoos, and many of those people have tattoos of licensed Disney properties.
Which begs the question: which Disney property has inspired the greatest number of tattoos? I’m glad you definitely asked, because the scientists employed by the website Online Bingo have worked it out, based on the number of Instagram hashtags that correlate with each Disney movie. Will this methodology provide us with the most accurate data? No. Why is an online bingo site wasting its precious resources on counting hashtags? Nobody knows. Will this change anybody’s life in the slightest? No it won’t. But, look, we’re already two paragraphs into this thing, so we might as well see it through.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular NgClass Example – How to Add Conditional CSS Classes]]></title>
        <id>60b136d911ffb70827ef912b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/angular-ngclass-example/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T15:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ngClass is a directive in Angular that adds and removes CSS classes on an HTML element. In this article, we are talking about ngClass in Angular only, not ng-class in angular.js. Prerequisites – What is Property Binding?Two things we have to understand first are property binding and interpolation in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tragic but true: how podcasters replaced our real friends]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/07/tragic-but-true-have-podcasters-replaced-our-real-friends</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/07/tragic-but-true-have-podcasters-replaced-our-real-friends"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:56:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic has seen audio shows fill a hole in our lives, providing companionship that is increasingly difficult to distinguish from the real thing
Some of my friends have no idea I even exist. These are people I know intimately, extensively, profoundly: I know what they had for dinner last night, the petty arguments they have at home, their obsessions, their insecurities, their fears, what time they wake up in the morning. No piece of minutiae is too minute, no idle thought too inconsequential, no detail too mundane: I want to hear it all.
If this is beginning to sound slightly alarming, I should point out that they tell me all of these things – and try to make me laugh in the process. I think of podcasters as my friends – and I am not alone.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Aroesti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you planning on joining protests at the G7 summit?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from people who’re planning on demonstrating during this week’s G7 summit in Cornwall 
 Later this week, world leaders will be attending the G7 summit, at Carbis Bay, near St Ives in Cornwall, to discuss global issues including the Covid pandemic and climate change.
The coalition comprises seven countries; the UK, Japan, US, Italy, Germany, Canada and France.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As the Delta variant spreads in England, our most vulnerable are losing protection | Christina Pagel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/delta-variant-covid-england-vulnerable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/delta-variant-covid-england-vulnerable"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:37:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Delta variant is surging, and the government’s failure to act quickly will likely cost lives

A new coronavirus variant that was first sequenced in India has been doubling about every eight days in England since early April. The Delta variant is now dominant in England, and according to a recent risk assessment from Public Health England (PHE), it has a substantially increased rate of transmissibility compared with the previously dominant variant Alpha, which was first sequenced in the UK. Having just a single dose of vaccination is less effective against Delta, and it may lead to a surge in hospital cases.
We always knew variants were a risk to England’s roadmap out of lockdown. In January, the science advisory group Sage warned that England’s red-list border policy of “geographically targeted travel bans” was unlikely to keep new variants out, not least because we didn’t know where the next one would come from. England spent the winter trying to keep out the Beta variant, first sequenced in South Africa, and the Gamma variant, first detected in Japan in travellers from Brazil. The effort mostly succeeded, but the government’s red-list policy entirely missed the rise of a dangerous new variant in India.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Pagel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[F Lee Bailey obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/f-lee-bailey-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/f-lee-bailey-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[American celebrity lawyer who was part of the ‘dream team’ that defended OJ Simpson during his murder trial
High-profile defence lawyers have often become celebrities in the US, starting with Daniel Webster and Abraham Lincoln and boasting ever more flamboyance since the days of Clarence Darrow.
F Lee Bailey, who has died aged 87, was one of the most aggressively self-promoting modern celebrity lawyers, achieving fame then maintaining it through the defence of notable clients. In the mid-1960s Bailey attracted headlines by winning a reversal for Sam Sheppard, a doctor convicted of the killing of his wife in one of US’s most important murder trials; one that provided the inspiration for the hit television show and film The Fugitive. He went on to represent, not always successfully, clients as notorious as the Boston Strangler, Albert DeSalvo, or as controversial as the heiress Patty Hearst.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Carlson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson prefers not to use term ‘special relationship’, says No 10]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/boris-johnson-prefers-not-to-use-term-special-relationship-says-no-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/boris-johnson-prefers-not-to-use-term-special-relationship-says-no-10"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spokesperson confirms PM not a fan of phrase recently used by Joe Biden to describe ties between UK and US
It is a phrase credited to Winston Churchill – and the state of it has been a source of endless anxiety for a string of prime ministers. But not, it seems, for Boris Johnson.
Downing Street confirmed on Monday that he is not a fan of the term “special relationship” as a way of describing the UK’s friendship with its most powerful ally. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[European Commission drops plan to ban UK from science projects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/ec-drops-plans-to-ban-uk-from-science-projects-after-backlash</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/ec-drops-plans-to-ban-uk-from-science-projects-after-backlash"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:09:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move comes after concerns from diplomats Britain was being treated as if it posed a similar risk to China

The European Commission has dropped plans for a blanket ban on UK involvement in EU research on space projects and supercomputers after a backlash from member states and leading scientists.
Thierry Breton, the former French finance minister who is now the EU internal market commissioner, had claimed the EU needed to keep control of intellectual property and that the UK’s involvement was an unacceptable security risk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men’s transfer window summer 2021 – all deals from Europe’s top five leagues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/07/mens-transfer-window-summer-2021-all-deals-from-europes-top-five-leagues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/07/mens-transfer-window-summer-2021-all-deals-from-europes-top-five-leagues"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All the summer’s Premier League, La Liga, Bundesliga, Ligue 1 and Serie A deals and club-by-club guides
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Garry Blight, Seán Clarke and Niall McVeigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Body found in Norway of 15-month-old boy who died crossing Channel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/body-found-in-norway-of-15-month-old-boy-who-died-crossing-channel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/body-found-in-norway-of-15-month-old-boy-who-died-crossing-channel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T13:58:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artin, previously listed as missing, died alongside his Iranian-Kurdish relatives when boat sank last October
A body that was found on a Norwegian shore several months ago has been identified as that of a 15-month-old child named Artin, who died alongside his relatives as they tried to cross the Channel to start a new life in the UK last October, local police have said.
The body was found near Karmøy in south-west Norway on New Year’s Day – more than two months after the vessel carrying the Iranian Kurds Rasul Iran Nezhad, Shiva Mohammad Panahi and their three children sank.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Peequal: will the new women’s urinal spell the end of queues for the ladies’?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/the-peequal-will-the-new-womens-urinal-spell-the-end-of-queues-for-the-ladies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/the-peequal-will-the-new-womens-urinal-spell-the-end-of-queues-for-the-ladies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T13:56:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Research shows women in the UK spend 34 times longer queueing for public loos than men do. Now, two young designers think they have the solution

Name: The Peequal.
Age: Brand new.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we made Three Lions: David Baddiel and Ian Broudie on England’s Euro 96 anthem]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/07/how-we-made-three-lions-david-baddiel-ian-broudie-england-euro-96-anthem-footballers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/07/how-we-made-three-lions-david-baddiel-ian-broudie-england-euro-96-anthem-footballers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T13:47:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I heard German fans singing it after they knocked England out. I had to resist throwing a TV out of the window’
I knew that New Order had done a football song [Italia 90’s World in Motion], but I was hesitant when the FA asked me to do Euro 96. Fantasy Football with Frank Skinner and David Baddiel was big on TV at the time, so I thought they should sing it and the band could go uncredited. But everybody was like, “No. It’s got to be the Lightning Seeds as well.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Baddiel and Rich Pelley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becky Downie left out of British gymnastics squad for Tokyo Olympics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/beckie-downie-left-out-of-british-gymnastics-squad-for-tokyo-olympics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/07/beckie-downie-left-out-of-british-gymnastics-squad-for-tokyo-olympics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T13:30:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gymnasts for Change talk of fear for whistleblowers 
Sister says ‘not a shock after way been treated this year’

GB Gymnastics has been accused of sending a sinister warning to whistleblowers by dropping the 2019 world silver medallist, Becky Downie, from its Olympic team for Tokyo. The surprise decision came less than a year after Downie spoke out about an “environment of fear” in the organisation.
Downie tweeted: “Winning an Olympic gold medal has always been my dream. I don’t have the words to describe how it feels now not being able to even try. This past year has been incredibly difficult, but this last month has been unimaginable. I’m not sure what will happen in terms of my future, but all I know is that I still love the sport, and I feel like I’m in the form of my life.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A victim of its own success: how Taiwan failed to plan for a major Covid outbreak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/a-victim-of-its-own-success-how-taiwan-failed-to-plan-for-a-major-covid-outbreak</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/a-victim-of-its-own-success-how-taiwan-failed-to-plan-for-a-major-covid-outbreak"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T13:19:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once a poster child for blocking coronavirus, Taiwan failed to fully prepare a pandemic response or vaccination rollout

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

While most of the world suffered through hundreds of millions of cases and millions of deaths from Covid-19, the 23.5 million people in Taiwan largely lived a normal life, thanks to a well-documented strong and early response that saw it go 250 days without a single local case. It lobbied for inclusion in the World Health Organization’s decision-making body off the back of its undeniable success and expertise under the slogan “Taiwan can help”.
But now the tables have turned and the island itself is in need of assistance, after an outbreak that started among airline staff in April spread across the island. The government appears to have been caught short by something it thought would never happen: the poster child for outbreak prevention had apparently failed to fully prepare an outbreak response.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voting in Peru and metro reopenings: Monday’s best photographs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/07/voting-in-peru-and-metro-reopenings-mondays-best-photographs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/07/voting-in-peru-and-metro-reopenings-mondays-best-photographs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T12:59:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressured by Biden, Johnson may finally face reality on Northern Ireland | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/northern-ireland-boris-johnson-uk-eu-trading-standards</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/07/northern-ireland-boris-johnson-uk-eu-trading-standards"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T12:46:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The US president should tell the British prime minister to honour the protocol or take the whole UK into the EU’s trading standards regime
This week’s planned G7 chat on Northern Ireland between the US president, Joe Biden, and British prime minister, Boris Johnson, can be brief. Biden should tell Johnson to stop being an idiot and honour the protocol.
Everyone knows there can be no erecting of a border across the fields of Ireland. Johnson knew that when he campaigned for Brexit. He knew it when he decided to leave the single market. If he promised Northern Ireland’s unionists something else, he was lying. He should get busy preparing EU-compatible customs barriers in Belfast, as required by the protocol. Biden might add that Johnson can forget any US/UK trade deal if he refuses, not that any deal agreed by Congress is ever likely to be in Britain’s interest.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dido Harding defends test and trace and says expectations too high]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/dido-harding-defends-test-and-trace-and-says-expectations-too-high</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/dido-harding-defends-test-and-trace-and-says-expectations-too-high"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T12:17:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tory peer and former TalkTalk boss confirms she is considering applying for top job at NHS England

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Dido Harding has confirmed she could apply to lead NHS England, and has defended her much-criticised record leading the Covid test-and-trace system, saying the main issue with the service was that “expectations were set too high”.
Covid testing in the UK was now “the envy of the world”, Harding told BBC Radio 4’s Woman’s Hour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker and Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Power dressing: which superhero has the best costume?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/07/which-superhero-has-the-best-costume</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/07/which-superhero-has-the-best-costume"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T12:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Superman’s Y-fronts to Hulk’s tattered shorts, superheroes have made their fair share of fashion faux pas – but whose outfit actually works?

Modern Toss on superhero attire

In the Guide’s weekly Solved! column, we look into a crucial pop-culture question you’ve been burning to know the answer to – and settle it, once and for all
When saving the planet, it’s important to dress the part. This isn’t like taking the bins out. You can’t hang off a chopper in a slanket and Crocs. Superheroes understand this. Unlike James Bond – who is permanently tuxed up as if he’s about to host a pharmaceutical industry awards bash – the offspring of Marvel and DC Comics have brought spandex, codpieces and vulcanised rubber out of the niche-interest sex-toy trade and into the multiplex. But which superhero has the best costume?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henry Yates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomasina Miers’ recipe for  clotted cream drizzle cake with macerated strawberries | The simple fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/07/thomasina-miers-recipe-clotted-cream-cake-elderflower-drizzle-macerated-strawberries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/07/thomasina-miers-recipe-clotted-cream-cake-elderflower-drizzle-macerated-strawberries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T12:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serve this jammy, creamy cake as an extremely English alternative to scones 
When I was little, clotted cream was a rare treat. I remember once, when my uncle came back from Devon with two precious pots of the stuff for us, I immediately set to baking a batch of scones, which we ate warm from the oven with jam, lashings of that amazing cream and butter (to this day, I always have my scones with cream and butter). So it was with delight, many years later on a blistering hot day in Tlacotalpan, Mexico, that I came across a woman selling a basket of cakes made from clotted cream. I can still taste them as I write this.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomasina Miers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The beat went on: what happened to Jan Kerouac, Jack’s forgotten daughter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/07/jan-kerouac-forgotten-child-of-jack-kerouac</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/07/jan-kerouac-forgotten-child-of-jack-kerouac"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the 25th anniversary of her death, the novelist Jan, who was free-spirited and self-destructive like her father, has almost been entirely erased from his story
The King of the Beats, Jack Kerouac, was renowned for laying bare his life in more than a dozen roman a clef novels, his most famous being On the Road, which documented the birth, rise and final days of an enduring counterculture.
But while larger-than-life characters such as Allen Ginsberg, William Burroughs and Neal Cassady wandered in and out of Kerouac’s works under a variety of pseudonyms, one important figure in the writer’s life is conspicuously absent: his daughter, Jan Kerouac, who died 25 years ago this week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Barnett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TV Baftas 2021: backstage with Michaela Coel, Paul Mescal and more – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/gallery/2021/jun/07/tv-baftas-2021-backstage-with-michaela-coel-paul-mescal-and-more-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/gallery/2021/jun/07/tv-baftas-2021-backstage-with-michaela-coel-paul-mescal-and-more-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T10:19:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Connell and Villanelle sharing a moment to Michaela Coel with her mum, The Guardian’s Sarah Lee had exclusive behind-the-scenes access to this year’s ceremony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘I’d had girlfriends. Being gay hadn’t crossed my mind’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/how-we-met-id-had-girlfriends-being-gay-not-crossed-my-mind</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/how-we-met-id-had-girlfriends-being-gay-not-crossed-my-mind"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T10:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark, 71, and Andrew, 73, met at university in Scotland and have been together for almost 50 years. They live in London
Mark was deeply unhappy when he started at St Andrews University in Scotland in 1967. He had grown up feeling conflicted about his sexuality, and though sex between two men had been decriminalised in England and Wales that summer, it remained illegal in the rest of the UK, and attitudes towards gay people remained extremely hostile. “Sex education taught me that my feelings were abnormal. I was waiting for the phase to end,” he says. In his first week, he met Andrew, who had moved from the US to study. “We didn’t know each other well. He was on the fringes of my social group,” says Mark, 71. Andrew found Mark attractive, but had never considered a relationship with another man. “I’d been in a fraternity and had girlfriends. Being gay hadn’t really crossed my mind,” he says.
After completing his degree, Mark moved to London in 1972 and found work in the film industry. “I realised my sexuality was nothing to be ashamed of and told all my friends,” he says. Andrew, 73, spent a year in Virginia after his studies, before moving to Edinburgh to complete a PhD. By the early 70s, he too had begun to explore his sexuality, and was secretary of the Edinburgh University GaySoc. “Some friends told me that Mark had come out. They said: ‘He’s done just about everything bar putting out a personal ad to tell everyone he’s queer.’” In the autumn of 1974, he called Mark. “I was going for dinner with a mutual friend of ours, so I invited him to come along,” says Mark. “I spotted Andrew on Shaftesbury Avenue and he looked totally different. He’d shaved off the Gilbert and Sullivan sideburns he’d had at university.” 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Roddy’s recipe for fried cheese with honey, oregano and vinegar | A kitchen in Rome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/07/rachel-roddy-recipe-fried-cheese-honey-oregano-vinegar</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/07/rachel-roddy-recipe-fried-cheese-honey-oregano-vinegar"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T10:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Melted, stringy cheese doused in a honey, vinegar and oregano dressing with just a hint of chilli: devour with bread and make the neighbours jealous
Caciocavallo is a formaggio a pasta filata, or stretched-curd cheese, and part of the family that includes mozzarella, scamorza, provolone and halloumi. To make it, cow’s milk curds are kneaded and stretched by hand in hot water until they look like a fabulously long scarf of white putty. The process at this point, by the way, is almost exactly the same as that of mozzarella, for which the lengths are squeezed into balloon-like balls and mozzate (cut). However, for caciocavallo, the stretched lengths are rolled into balls, then soaked in brine before being bound with rope in pairs, neck to neck, and hung to mature a cavallo, or straddled over …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Roddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK parents and teachers: what is currently happening in your school?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T09:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear what the situation is like in UK schools from the parental and teaching point of view

We’re keen to hear from parents, teachers and school leaders across the UK about the situation in schools.
Whether it’s exam preparations, the management of social distancing protocols, the provision of wraparound care or school closures due to rising infections in communities, we’d like to hear about it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We are running out of time to reach deal to save natural world, says UN talks chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/age-of-extinction-running-out-of-time-to-reach-deal-to-save-natural-world-says-un-talks-chair</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/age-of-extinction-running-out-of-time-to-reach-deal-to-save-natural-world-says-un-talks-chair"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T07:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Warning comes amid fears of further delays to Kunming summit, which aims to agree on curbing destruction of ecosystems
The world is running out of time to reach an ambitious deal to stem the destruction of the natural world, the co-chair of negotiations for a crucial UN wildlife summit has warned, amid fears of a third delay to the talks.
Negotiators are scheduled to meet in Kunming, China, in October for Cop15, the biggest biodiversity summit in a decade, to reach a hoped-for Paris-style agreement on preventing wildlife extinctions and the human-driven destruction of the planet’s ecosystems.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m paying off the mortgage on my flat – what’s the best way to buy a house?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/07/im-paying-off-the-mortgage-on-my-flat-whats-the-best-way-to-buy-a-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/07/im-paying-off-the-mortgage-on-my-flat-whats-the-best-way-to-buy-a-house"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m wondering if I should sell my current property, or try to keep it to bring in rental income 
Q I bought my flat with a mortgage about six years ago, scraping my way in as a first-time buyer just before any of the government’s help-to-buy schemes were available. I chose fairly low repayments and a long mortgage term, reflective of my financial circumstances at the time. Last year, I secured an amazing job with a much higher salary and it has changed my life. I’ve paid off all my other debts – apart from my student loan and mortgage – and now have savings and investments. My mortgage is a five-year fixed rate with an interest rate of 1.54% and 23 years left of the mortgage term.
I have calculated that between overpayments and reducing my mortgage term, on my current salary, I could be mortgage-free in the next five to seven years. My thinking is to reduce the balance while I am still in the fixed rate-period, and then just pay off the rest using my cash savings (since they are earning very little interest) when it moves to the standard variable rate (SVR).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Virginia Wallis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British ballerina at the Bolshoi Ballet Academy, Moscow – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/07/british-ballerina-at-the-bolshoi-ballet-academy-moscow-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/07/british-ballerina-at-the-bolshoi-ballet-academy-moscow-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Armstrong, from Northumberland, is due to graduate from the renowned Russian academy this month
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgenia Novozhenina/Reuters. Written by Tatiana Gomozova and Lev Sergeev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis to shrink G7 economies twice as much as Covid-19, says research]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/climate-crisis-to-shrink-g7-economies-twice-as-much-as-covid-19-says-research</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/climate-crisis-to-shrink-g7-economies-twice-as-much-as-covid-19-says-research"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T06:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 countries will lose $5tn a year by 2050 if temperatures rise by 2.6C
The economies of rich countries will shrink by twice as much as they did in the Covid-19 crisis if they fail to tackle rising greenhouse gas emissions, according to research.
The G7 countries – the world’s biggest industrialised economies – will lose 8.5% of GDP a year, or nearly $5tn wiped off their economies, within 30 years if temperatures rise by 2.6C, as they are likely to on the basis of government pledges and policies around the world, according to research from Oxfam and the Swiss Re Institute.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s a lifeline’: Cumbrian villagers raise £200,000 to save last shop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/its-a-lifeline-cumbrian-villagers-raise-200000-to-save-last-shop</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/its-a-lifeline-cumbrian-villagers-raise-200000-to-save-last-shop"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T06:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kirkoswald residents to reopen last remaining store as a community business run by volunteers 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The village high street in Kirkoswald, Cumbria, was once home to shops including a butcher’s, a greengrocer’s and a shoe shop. Now just one remains: a small convenience store that has became the hub of village life during the pandemic.
After its owner, the local philanthropist David Hodgkiss, died of Covid in March last year, the shop was put up for sale and was destined for closure until residents stepped in. In just six weeks they have raised nearly £200,000 to purchase and run the shop as a community business, and hope the doors could reopen in just a few weeks, staffed by volunteers from the local area.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pig whisperer: the Dutch farmer who wants to end factory farming]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/the-pig-whisperer-the-dutch-farmer-who-wants-to-end-factory-farming</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/07/the-pig-whisperer-the-dutch-farmer-who-wants-to-end-factory-farming"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T05:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A unique ‘pig toilet’ and a diet of organic leftovers are part of former vet Kees Scheepens’ plans to put animal welfare and sustainability first

“Oma, hoi! Hier! Hallooo,” Dr Kees Scheepens, a Dutch farmer known as the “pig whisperer”, is calling his two oldest pigs for some apricot snacks.
Oma or “granny”, a seven-year-old sow, lives with a Berkshire boar called Borough, who’s nine, off a quiet lane in the town of Oirschot, in the south of the Netherlands, on a farm called Hemelrijken – Dutch for “the realms of heaven”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Senay Boztas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Alice the rat was so special’: readers on their brilliant, beloved pet tattoos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/readers-pet-tattoos-cats-dogs-ferret-rat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/07/readers-pet-tattoos-cats-dogs-ferret-rat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T05:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the pandemic, every pet became an emotional support animal – and many people decided they wanted to commemorate them indelibly and incredibly 
Alice was a double rex rat we adopted from the local RSPCA. She was such a special girl and we had a great bond, so she was the natural choice for my first tattoo. Sadly, Alice died earlier this year, so I’m getting a second tattoo in tribute in a couple of weeks, on the spot where she loved to sit. 
Sarah, student, Greater Manchester
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why every statue should come down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/07/why-every-statue-should-come-down</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/07/why-every-statue-should-come-down"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Younge was glad to see the figure of Edward Colston removed in Bristol a year ago – but, he argues, even monuments to civil rights leaders are a distortion of how history really works 

How to listen to podcasts: everything you need to know

One year ago, the statue of the slave trader Edward Colston was brought down in Bristol, prompting jubilation among protesters and calls for a wider rethink of public memorials – but also a ferocious backlash.
Gary Younge, the former Guardian columnist who is now a professor of sociology at the University of Manchester, was delighted to see Colston come down – but all too aware of the controversy that would ensue, having previously found himself the subject of a Daily Mail campaign to erect a statue of the Queen Mother. He tells Anushka Asthana that the last year has highlighted the reluctance of some participants in the culture war over statues to grapple with the reality of Britain’s history. And, he argues, even figures of civil rights heroes such as Nelson Mandela and Rosa Parks misrepresent their role in bringing about social change – and underplay the crucial significance of the movements that lifted them up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Gary Younge and Chloe Peacock; produced by Courtney Yusuf and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The darkest days are coming’: Myanmar’s journalists suffer at hands of junta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/the-darkest-days-are-coming-myanmars-journalists-suffer-at-hands-of-junta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/the-darkest-days-are-coming-myanmars-journalists-suffer-at-hands-of-junta"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T00:11:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalism has been outlawed in all but name since the coup, with reporters and editors fleeing the country or leading double lives to survive
As a cyclone rolled over the Bay of Bengal on 24 May, American journalist Danny Fenster, 37, contemplated the brooding skies near a terminal window at Yangon international airport.
For a while, the threat of foreigners being seized at the airport by Myanmar’s military was real, but after watching international reporters exit the country safely in April, the Michigan native was more worried about turbulence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian reporter in Bangkok</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matters of life and death: Kneehigh theatre’s wild times – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/jun/07/matters-of-life-and-death-kneehigh-theatres-wild-times-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/jun/07/matters-of-life-and-death-kneehigh-theatres-wild-times-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The award-winning Kneehigh theatre company has announced it is closing down. Revisit its past hits including Rapunzel, A Matter of Life and Death and The Tin Drum 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: can Southgate's England take it one step further? – video preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/video/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-can-southgates-england-take-it-one-step-further-video-preview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/video/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-can-southgates-england-take-it-one-step-further-video-preview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate's England will be hoping to take it one step further as they go into Euro 2020 as one of the favourites. The question is whether the manager will favour his tried and trusted – Raheem Sterling, Harry Kane and Marcus Rashford – or whether it's time to pick the form players in Jack Grealish, Phil Foden and Jadon Sancho. England start off against Croatia, the team that ended their journey to the final at the World Cup in 2018, before games against Scotland and Czech Republic. The Guardian's Barney Ronay discusses England's chances of European glory
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay &amp; Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing lightning: a photographer’s pursuit of the elements – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will Eades is an award-winning photographer based on the mid north coast of NSW. His mission is to see and capture spectacular moments in nature, and to share these rare moments with others. A self-taught Nikon shooter, Will’s main focus is on storms and other weather phenomena as he strives to be present when the elements align for a great photograph
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Eades/ willeadesphotography</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A journey down WA’s mighty Martuwarra, raging river and sacred ancestor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Traditional owners are standing together to protect the Fitzroy – a ‘beautiful, living water system’. Just watch out for the bird-sized spiders …
A Nyikina man, Mark Coles Smith, and his fellow travellers began their 400km journey down the mighty Martuwarra (Fitzroy River) on a flood plain covered in giant spiders.
“Bird-sized” spiders were clinging to the canopy, jostling for space on branches protruding above flood water that stretched for kilometres in every direction.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorena Allam;  production: Carly Earl; photographs: Jackson Gallagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Search and Filter Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b3480c11ffb70827ef9a88</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/search-and-filter-component-in-reactjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're building a React app, you want your users to be able to search and get exact results. And if you are getting tons of items from an API, then you need to create a way for users to be able to find various items easily.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning in Python – The Top New Scikit-Learn 0.24 Features You Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60ba33d7acb62507dd1d9050</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-python-new-scikit-learn-features-you-should-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scikit-learn is one of the most popular open-source and free machine learning libraries for Python.  The scikit-learn library contains a lot of efficient tools for machine learning and statistical modeling including classification, regression, clustering, and dimensionality reduction. Many data scientists, machine learning engineers, and researchers rely on this library for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Recover from Deployment Hell – What I Learned After My Discord Bot Crashed on a 1000+ User Server]]></title>
        <id>60b8f5c7acb62507dd1d8500</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recovering-from-deployment-hell-what-i-learned-from-deploying-my-discord-bot-to-a-1000-user-server/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I deployed a Discord bot to a 1000+ user server. In the first hour, Deployment Hell struck and my bot crashed. In the next hour, I brought it back, surviving and even thriving in Deployment Hell. In this post, I'll show you how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn TypeScript Basics in this Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b2a4c611ffb70827ef9842</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-typescript-basics/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TypeScript has taken the development world by storm. No wonder it has over 15 million weekly downloads on npm. But what is TypeScript, and what do you need to know about it?  In this article, I am going answer those questions. By the end you'll have a grasp of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python for Bioinformatics: Use Machine Learning and Data Analysis for Drug Discovery]]></title>
        <id>60b98ebfacb62507dd1d8ec4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-for-bioinformatics-use-machine-learning-and-data-analysis-for-drug-discovery/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you looking for a way to apply Python and machine learning to a real-world application? You should consider Bioinformatics. Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data, in particular when the data sets are large and complex. We just released a course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s mouse plague - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Families and farmers in New South Wales are doing everything they can to fend off a biblical incursion of rodents. Guardian Australia’s Matilda Boseley has spent months reporting on the story – and hearing the experiences of those who have been affected
When mice started breeding in large numbers in New South Wales more than six months ago, residents went to war to repel them. Now they have reached a grim acceptance of their presence – and are counting the costs of a “plague” that has seen crops ravaged and homes ruined.
Rachel Humphreys spoke to Matilda Boseley, who has been reporting on the story, about how the mice came, what damage they have caused, and how difficult it is to get rid of them. And we hear residents’ accounts of what life is like with thousands of mice underfoot, in hay bales, and even in the washing machine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Matilda Boseley; produced by Hannah Moore and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Tutorial – How to Set Up a Front End Development Project]]></title>
        <id>60b11ff811ffb70827ef8f94</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-set-up-a-front-end-development-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T21:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you plan to build a website. Before you start, you want to set up a few tools to make your life easier. But which tools should you have? The JavaScript ecosystem is changing so fast that it can be overwhelming to pick the best tools to use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wuhan lab leak theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden has asked US intelligence services to urgently investigate the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, including the possibility that it began with an accident in a laboratory. The Guardian’s Peter Beaumont looks at the available evidence 
When Covid-19 first emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan, much of the focus of the initial investigation fell on a seafood market that also sold exotic animals for human consumption. But in the months since, no definitive link has been proven and the precise origin story remains unsolved. 
In the intervening period numerous conspiracy theories have spread: that somehow 5G phone signals could be involved, or that the virus is a hoax. Bracketed in with these was a theory that Covid-19 may have been released (accidentally or otherwise) from a lab. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Peter Beaumont; produced by Sami Kent and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the eviction ban ending?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from renters in England who are at risk from losing their home due to the lifting of the eviction ban
The eviction ban in England was lifted on 31 May leaving nearly two million private renters concerned about whether they will be able to find another property if they lose their home. 
We would like to hear from those who have been affected by the eviction ban ending.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences of the UK adult social care system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/25/tell-us-about-your-experiences-of-the-uk-adult-social-care-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/25/tell-us-about-your-experiences-of-the-uk-adult-social-care-system"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T16:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from you or the person you care for about your experiences of adult social care in the UK
The government has persistently refused to set out plans to reform the funding of adult social care, despite repeated promises.
In the meantime, almost nine out of 10 local authorities in England expect to make cuts in adult social care services this year, 2021-22. As the Kings Fund recently put it, while we wait for funding reforms “more families are being failed every day.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>