<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-03T01:31:53.506Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-03T01:31:53.506Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China Communist party ‘striving for people’s happiness’, says Xi Jinping, in call for charm offensive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/china-communist-party-happiness-xi-jinping-negative-image</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/china-communist-party-happiness-xi-jinping-negative-image"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:14:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China must tell the world a better story about itself, says president, as he seeks stronger ‘international voice’
China needs to improve the way it tells the world stories about itself, and convince people the ruling party is striving for the happiness of all Chinese people, Xi Jinping has said.
The Chinese president’s comments to a Communist party meeting on Tuesday come amid the country’s growing isolation in the global community, and tension with international media, largely driven by international concerns over human rights abuses.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Commit Signing in Git?]]></title>
        <id>60afce3011ffb70827ef869c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-commit-signing-in-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:14:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git has a feature to "sign" commits, but what is signing, and what are the benefits? TL;DR: If you don't care for the details, and just need to get commit signing setup quickly, skip to How to Sign Commits. Signing, or code signing specifically, is the process of using]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National Enquirer publisher fined over payment for Trump story]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/national-enquirer-publisher-fined-trump-campaign-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/national-enquirer-publisher-fined-trump-campaign-election"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:06:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Federal watchdog fines magazine’s owner $187,500 over story of former Playboy model who claimed she had affair with Trump
A federal election watchdog fined the publisher of the National Enquirer $187,500 for scuppering the story of a former Playboy model who claimed she’d had an affair with Donald Trump.
The Federal Election Commission (FEC) fined A360 Media, formerly known as American Media, for paying Karen McDougal $150,000 in August 2016, saying the payment was made to keep her story from becoming public before the presidential election.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate: England fans’ boos ‘feel like criticism’ of black players]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/03/gareth-southgate-england-fans-boos-taking-knee</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/03/gareth-southgate-england-fans-boos-taking-knee"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:03:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager angered by response to team taking knee
Alexander-Arnold faces wait after late injury scare

Gareth Southgate has hit out at the section of fans who booed when England’s players took the knee before their friendly win against Austria at the Riverside Stadium on Wednesday night.
Southgate cut an angry figure after the anti-racism gesture was greeted by loud boos just before kick-off. On a night when the right-back Trent Alexander-Arnold sustained a thigh injury during the closing stages – Southgate said he will be assessed in the next two days – the manager defended his players and stressed the act of taking a knee should not be seen as a political message.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Beckham buys stake in vehicle electrification firm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/03/david-beckham-buys-stakes-in-vehicle-electrification-firm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/03/david-beckham-buys-stakes-in-vehicle-electrification-firm"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lunaz specialises in classic cars but is set to start conversion of bin lorries to help transition away from fossil fuel

Snaps of David Beckham in expensive cars were a tabloid staple during the footballer’s days as a star player, but now his interest has taken a surprising turn: bin lorries.
The former Manchester United and Real Madrid midfielder has taken a 10% stake in Lunaz, a Silverstone-based company that electrifies classic cars from Rolls-Royce, Jaguar and Range Rover. Now it hopes to take the same engineering logic and apply it to refuse trucks and other specialist commercial vehicles, giving them a new lease of life in the transition away from fossil fuels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 7: Finland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/03/euro-2020-team-guides-part-7-finland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/03/euro-2020-team-guides-part-7-finland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Markku Kanerva’s debutants have fostered a remarkable team spirit and are capable of causing surprises
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
Looking back five years, there were not many signs that Finland would soon qualify for their first international tournament. The team did not win a single game in 2016 under Hans Backe, a former assistant of Sven-Göran Eriksson. After a demoralising year – two draws, nine defeats – they turned to Markku Kanerva, who had been caretaker manager twice before.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saku-Pekka Sundelin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Environment Variables in VanillaJS]]></title>
        <id>60b3a25211ffb70827ef9b39</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-environment-variables-in-vanillajs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T22:54:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you will learn about environment variables in Vanilla JavaScript. You'll also learn how to serve API keys to your application through the Netlify build command. What are JavaScript environment variables?Environment variables are very common when you're using JavaScript frameworks like React or Vue for creating frontend]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson risks shock defeat over ‘devastating’ foreign aid cuts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/boris-johnson-risks-shock-defeat-over-devastating-foreign-aid-cuts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/boris-johnson-risks-shock-defeat-over-devastating-foreign-aid-cuts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T22:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commons revolt led by former international development secretary Andrew Mitchell includes senior Tories and ex-ministers 
Boris Johnson could face a shock Commons defeat over plans to cut foreign aid after dozens of his own MPs backed an amendment to reverse the cuts, in a rebellion led by the former international development secretary Andrew Mitchell.
MPs tabled an amendment on Wednesday night backed by a number of senior Conservatives, including the former health secretary Jeremy Hunt, former Brexit secretary David Davis, the former Northern Ireland secretary Karen Bradley and the former immigration minister Caroline Nokes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nasa plans return to Venus with two missions by 2030]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/nasa-venus-return-two-missions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/nasa-venus-return-two-missions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T22:29:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nasa sets aside $1bn for two ventures, which will be first US exploration of the planet since 1989
Nasa is returning to Venus for the first time in more than three decades to gain a better understanding of the history of what scientists believe could have been the first habitable planet in the solar system.
Plans for two separate and ambitious deep space missions to Earth’s nearest neighbour were announced on Wednesday by the head of the US space agency, Bill Nelson. Launches were targeted for a 2028-2030 time frame, he said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicaragua police detain opposition leader and expected Ortega challenger]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/nicaragua-police-detain-opposition-leader-cristiana-chamorro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/nicaragua-police-detain-opposition-leader-cristiana-chamorro"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:24:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigation of Cristiana Chamorro seen as an attempt to stop her from challenging country’s autocratic leader in November elections
Police in Nicaragua have stormed into the house of a prominent opposition leader, one day after formally filing money laundering charges against her in what was seen as an attempt to stop an electoral challenge to the autocratic leader Daniel Ortega.
Cristiana Chamorro, 67, was detained at her home south of the capital Managua on Wednesday, 15 minutes before she was scheduled to give a virtual news conference to reporters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in Managua</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Design Your Own Learning Plan for Any Tech Stack]]></title>
        <id>60b3ccee11ffb70827ef9bc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-design-your-own-learning-plan-for-any-tech-stack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:18:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the most difficult things about getting started in a new career as a developer is figuring out exactly what you should be learning – and then translating that into an effective plan. There are so many resources out there for learning, so lack of information is not the problem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden announces ‘month of action’ to get 70% of Americans vaccinated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/joe-biden-covid-coronavirus-vaccine-americans-fourth-of-july</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/joe-biden-covid-coronavirus-vaccine-americans-fourth-of-july"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:01:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President dangles promise of a ‘summer of freedom’ to reluctant Americans and lays out plan to achieve Fourth of July target

US politics – live updates

Joe Biden has announced a national “month of action” to try to get at least 70% of Americans vaccinated against coronavirus before the Fourth of July holiday.
Touting the progress already made, and dangling the promise of a “summer of freedom” from Covid-19 to those reluctant to get a shot, the US president urged citizens, especially those under 40, to play a role in the “wartime effort” to defeat the virus.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe and Joan E Greve in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building Britain’s Biggest Nuclear Power Station review – so boring it’s a masterpiece!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/building-britains-biggest-nuclear-power-station-review-so-boring-its-a-masterpiece</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/building-britains-biggest-nuclear-power-station-review-so-boring-its-a-masterpiece"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a scene more dull than watching paint dry ... and yet somehow, this BBC documentary on a new nuclear reactor is a staggering, bravura-filled feat
This programme was so boring. How boring? Let’s put it this way. It dealt with a 130-metre-long boring machine that is boring three boreholes under the Bristol Channel’s Jurassic bedrock. It’s a machine even more boring than the one boring through the Chilterns to make the rail journey to or from Birmingham less boring. As if that were possible. The machine is so boring it doesn’t have a name, though if there were a public vote it would be called Borey McBoreface.
First, we saw the boring machine arriving by barge then loaded on to trucks and driven under police escort through Somerset lanes. This sequence was so devoid of incident it resembled that four-hour BBC film of a sleigh ride across the tundra in real time. At least the tundra film had huskies. Director Mat Stimpson only had an answer to the question “Where did all the interchangeable male engineers in hi-vis gilets and hard hats go?” Actually that’s not fair: there was a female engineer, whom we saw checking that the ambient temperature didn’t rise too fast to make concrete set too quickly. Which wasn’t boring at all.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amélie the Musical review – kindness, kooks and kissing cellos in the city of love]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/amelie-the-musical-review-criterion-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/amelie-the-musical-review-criterion-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Criterion, London
It irons out the eccentricities in Jean-Pierre Jeunet’s film but this show has a timely message and delights in small pleasures
Twenty years ago, Jean-Pierre Jeunet introduced us to Amélie Poulain, the Parisian waitress who loves skipping stones, cracking into creme brulee and craning her neck at the cinema to see the audience’s faces. Such is the novelty of theatre-going after lockdown, this musical adaptation of the hit film may provoke a similar impulse.
While it irons out a number of Jeunet’s eccentricities and has a sometimes insipid score, there is a wonderful lead performance by Audrey Brisson, who liberates her friends by engineering episodes of happiness and romance for them, while falling in love herself with photo-booth obsessive Nino. The real coup de foudre, however, comes with Madeleine Girling’s elegant, clever design. Bookended by upright pianos, the set conjures bistro chic and Métro anonymity, gives Amélie’s garret a warm glow, and hides surprises, including a cabinet of luminous dildos.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Wiegand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘There’s only one head coach’: Eddie Jones stands firm on England control]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/theres-only-one-head-coach-eddie-jones-stands-firm-on-england-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/theres-only-one-head-coach-eddie-jones-stands-firm-on-england-control"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jones insists he is in charge despite view his wings are clipped
Head coach defends his consultancy work in Japan 

England’s head coach, Eddie Jones, has insisted he remains in sole charge despite being placed under greater scrutiny by the Rugby Football Union while also defending his “information-sharing” consultancy work in Japan.
The RFU in April largely cleared Jones of blame for the dismal Six Nations campaign but pledged to keep his and England’s performances under review via a group of unnamed “external rugby experts”. Jones subsequently came in for widespread criticism when it emerged he was giving the All Blacks star Beauden Barrett “little pieces of gold” in his capacity as director of rugby at Suntory Sungoliath, just weeks after the Six Nations had finished.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland denied at the last as Memphis Depay rescues draw for Netherlands]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/netherlands-scotland-international-friendly-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/netherlands-scotland-international-friendly-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T20:51:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland have become so unaccustomed to preparation work for major finals that the significance of this draw with the Netherlands is difficult to determine. There was, though, plenty for Steve Clarke to be encouraged with, not least because of the Covid disruption that formed the backdrop to this fixture in the Algarve. Kevin Nisbet looked to have won the game for Scotland before a late, stunning intervention from Memphis Depay.
 Related: Saka fires England to win over Austria marred by Alexander-Arnold injury 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vimrc Configuration Guide - How to Customize Your Vim Code Editor with Mappings, Vimscript, Status Line, and More]]></title>
        <id>60a699b0906c5207e3a7f5ab</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/vimrc-configuration-guide-customize-your-vim-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T20:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Configuring your .vimrc file lets you use the full power of Vim. With a customized .vimrc file you can increase your Vim powers tenfold. In this article I will show you a few ways you can customize your .vimrc file. I will go over: Basic SettingsPluginsFoldingVimscriptStatus lineFirst create the following]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli opposition leader tells president he can form government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/yair-lapid-israel-president-government-naftali-bennett-benjamin-netanyahu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/yair-lapid-israel-president-government-naftali-bennett-benjamin-netanyahu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T20:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Under terms of Yair Lapid’s proposed deal, far-right politician Naftali Bennett would replace Benjamin Netanyahu as PM
The Israeli opposition leader has told the country’s president that he can form a government, a critical step that places Benjamin Netanyahu in his most precarious political position for more than a decade.
After days of frenetic negotiations, Yair Lapid told President Reuven Rivlin less than an hour before a midnight deadline that he had the support of a majority of opposition parties for what has been called a “government of change” – a mix of bitter ideological rivals united by a shared desire to oust Israel’s longest-serving leader.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ollie Robinson’s offensive tweets prove English cricket still has much to learn | Andy Bull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/02/ollie-robinsons-racist-tweets-prove-english-cricket-still-has-much-to-learn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/02/ollie-robinsons-racist-tweets-prove-english-cricket-still-has-much-to-learn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was possible to feel sympathy and scorn for the bowler as the fallout from grotesque remarks marred best day of his career
The clouds blew over Lord’s midway through the afternoon, when Ollie Robinson was deep into his second spell. He had bowled well, had won his first Test wicket that morning when he made Tom Latham play on, and was working away on his second, the great Ross Taylor, whom he soon dismissed leg before wicket. It all seemed so sweet but away from the middle it was already turning sour. There was no way for Robinson to know it then but around that same time screengrabs started circulating on social media, showing a series of offensive ‘jokes’ Robinson had Tweeted between 2012 and 2014, some racist, some sexist, all excruciating.
 Related: Devon Conway’s superb debut century puts New Zealand on top in first Test 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Bull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canada calls on pope to apologize after Indigenous children’s remains found]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/canada-indigenous-children-residential-school</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/canada-indigenous-children-residential-school"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government urges apology for role Catholic church played in residential school system after remains of 215 children discovered
Canada’s government has called on Pope Francis to issue a formal apology for the role the Catholic church played in Canada’s residential school system, days after the remains of 215 children were located at what was once the country’s largest such school.
Justin Trudeau’s government also pledged again to support efforts to find more unmarked graves at the former residential schools which held Indigenous children taken from families across the nation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AP in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fetch API – How to Make a GET Request and POST Request in JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>60b0f11411ffb70827ef8dbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-api-calls-with-fetch/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:39:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Often times you might want your system to communicate with other web servers to get information. For example, let's say a new user wants to sign up for an account on your website. And instead of having to manually fill out a form to send their information to your system,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US sets – and quickly suspends – tariffs on UK and others over digital taxes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/us-trade-tariffs-biden-administration</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/us-trade-tariffs-biden-administration"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:21:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden administration suspended duties to allow time for negotiations over digital-services taxes on US tech companies
The Biden administration announced 25% tariffs on over $2bn worth of imports from the UK and five other countries on Wednesday over their taxes on US technology companies, but immediately suspended the duties to allow time for negotiations to continue.
The US trade representative, Katherine Tai, said the threatened tariffs on goods from Britain, Italy, Spain, Turkey, India and Austria had been agreed after an investigation concluded that their digital taxes discriminated against US companies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump closes his ‘beacon of freedom’ website a month after launching it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/trump-closes-website-beacon-of-freedom</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/trump-closes-website-beacon-of-freedom"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:18:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jason Miller, senior aide to former president, confirms closing of the ‘From the Desk of Donald J Trump’ online communication tool
Donald Trump has discontinued the blog-type website he launched in a fanfare less than a month ago as “a beacon of freedom” and “a place to speak freely and safely”.
Jason Miller, a senior aide to the former US president, confirmed the closing of the “From the Desk of Donald J Trump” online communication tool in a statement to CNBC on Wednesday, just weeks after billing the venture as “a great resource” for his boss’s musings.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Migrate from Vue v.2 to Vue v.3 with a Simple Example Project]]></title>
        <id>60b4ff4711ffb70827ef9eb2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/migrate-from-vue2-to-vue3-with-example-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is Vue.js? Vue.js is a progressive JavaScript frontend framework written by Evan You. It's one of the most powerful and easy to learn frameworks, and it has over 9.5 million downloads per month.  In September 2020, Vue 3 core was released. The new Vue.js release]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man charged with murder of London flower seller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/man-charged-with-of-london-flower-seller</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/man-charged-with-of-london-flower-seller"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:11:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A 21-year-old man has been charged with the murder of Tony Eastlake who was fatally stabbed close to his stall in Islington
A 21-year-old man has been charged with the murder of a flower seller who was fatally stabbed close to his stall in north London, the Metropolitan police said.
Tony Eastlake, 55, died from a knife wound after being attacked on Essex Road in Islington just before 5.30pm on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serena Williams survives tough three-setter to make French Open third round]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/serena-williams-wins-tough-three-setter-to-make-french-open-third-round</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/serena-williams-wins-tough-three-setter-to-make-french-open-third-round"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:01:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Williams defeats Mihaela Buzarnescu 6-3, 5-7, 6-1
Daniil Medvedev fight back to beat Tommy Paul

It remains to be seen whether Serena Williams can play herself into form over the coming days and rise to become a true contender for the French Open title but her effort alone cannot be faulted. The three-times Roland Garros champion moved into the third round by punctuating an arduous three-setter with a strong finish, beating Mihaela Buzarnescu 6-3, 5-7, 6-1 to advance.
The victory, only her third of the clay season, may not have been convincing but during this uncertain period every victory marks a small step forward. After looking sublime in Australia, beating two top-10 players before losing in the semi-finals to the eventual champion, Naomi Osaka, she spent three months away and her absence has shown.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on row over England’s school catch up plan – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/02/martin-rowson-on-row-over-englands-school-catch-up-plan-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/02/martin-rowson-on-row-over-englands-school-catch-up-plan-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T19:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SEC watchdog says two Elon Musk tweets violated settlement agreement]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/02/elon-musk-tweets-tesla-sec-settlement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/02/elon-musk-tweets-tesla-sec-settlement"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:58:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla CEO and the Securities and Exchange Commission’s 2019 deal stipulated that Musk would vet any public communications
The US securities watchdog told Tesla last year that CEO Elon Musk had twice violated a settlement requiring his tweets to be preapproved by company lawyers, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.
Musk and the US Securities and Exchange Commission agreed in 2019 that the electric car maker would vet any material public communications Musk made regarding Tesla.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plans to build world’s deepest pool in Cornwall to train astronauts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/worlds-deepest-pool-could-be-built-in-cornwall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/worlds-deepest-pool-could-be-built-in-cornwall"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:57:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blue Abyss applies for permission to build £150m centre with pool that would reach depths of 50m
Plans have been submitted to build the world’s deepest artificial pool in Cornwall to train astronauts and help advance undersea robotics.
The project would be 40 metres by 50 metres at the surface, with a 16-metre wide shaft plunging to 50 metres at its lowest point – nearly as deep as Nelson’s Column is high – and would also be the world’s largest pool by volume.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Officials investigating why Iran warship caught fire and sank in Gulf of Oman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/iran-warship-has-caught-fire-and-sunk-in-gulf-of-oman-say-local-agencies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/iran-warship-has-caught-fire-and-sunk-in-gulf-of-oman-say-local-agencies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Kharg, the Iranian navy’s largest vessel, went down in the strait of Hormuz just after dawn on Wednesday
Military officials in the Gulf are investigating what caused the Iranian navy’s largest vessel to catch fire and sink in the latest mysterious incident to affect shipping linked to Tehran.
The support ship Kharg went down in the strait of Hormuz just after dawn on Wednesday, after a fire that had started 18 hours earlier reached the waterline. All crew members are reported to have survived.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Officer charged with murder of Dalian Atkinson feared for his life, court hears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/officer-charged-dalian-atkinson-feared-for-his-life-court-hears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/officer-charged-dalian-atkinson-feared-for-his-life-court-hears"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:40:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PC Benjamin Monk says former footballer was ‘very scary’ and told him he would ‘take him to the gates of hell’ during incident in 2016
The police officer on trial for murdering Dalian Atkinson has told the court he kicked the former footballer while he was on the ground because he feared being killed if he got up.
PC Benjamin Monk denies the murder or manslaughter of the former Aston Villa striker after being called to a disturbance outside the home of Atkinson’s father on 15 August 2016.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ai Weiwei accuses curators of rejecting artwork over Julian Assange content]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/ai-weiwei-accuses-curators-of-rejecting-artwork-over-julian-assange-content</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/ai-weiwei-accuses-curators-of-rejecting-artwork-over-julian-assange-content"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:37:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artist claims piece was rejected from exhibition for addressing imprisonment of the WikiLeaks founder
Ai Weiwei has accused the organisers of a large UK art exhibition of rejecting his artwork for the show because the piece addressed the imprisonment of the WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange.
The Chinese dissident artist and activist said the piece for The Great Big Art Exhibition featured an image of the treadmill which Assange used while seeking asylum in the Ecuadorian embassy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Batty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England to give quarantine-free status to ‘handful’ of new places, say sources]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/uk-to-give-quarantine-free-travel-status-to-handful-of-new-places-say-sources</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/uk-to-give-quarantine-free-travel-status-to-handful-of-new-places-say-sources"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portugal’s green list status under review as PM warns restrictions could be reimposed for some countries

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

People in England are unlikely to get the go-ahead for quarantine-free travel to major tourist destinations until days before the school holidays, with UK ministers considering reimposing restrictions on those returning from certain green list countries.
A source said ministers were set to discuss whether Portugal, given its uptick in cases, would remain on the green list, which allows travellers from those countries into England without having to self-isolate on arrival.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Aubrey Allegretti and Daniel Boffey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Austrian minister who danced with Putin at wedding lands Russian oil job]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/former-austrian-minister-given-seat-on-board-of-russias-rosneft</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/former-austrian-minister-given-seat-on-board-of-russias-rosneft"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:18:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karin Kneissl has been given seat on board of directors at Rosneft, which is controlled by the Russian state
A former Austrian foreign minister who danced with Vladimir Putin at her wedding has been given a seat on the board of directors of the Russian state-controlled oil industry giant Rosneft, the company has annnounced.
Karin Kneissl shot to infamy after she invited Putin to her wedding. Images of her dancing with the Russian leader in Gamlitz in the south-eastern state of Styria near the Slovenian border, went around the world in August 2018.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Etsy buys secondhand clothing app Depop to tap into gen Z]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/02/etsy-buys-second-hand-clothing-app-depop-to-tap-into-gen-z</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/02/etsy-buys-second-hand-clothing-app-depop-to-tap-into-gen-z"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US-based online sales app pays £1bn for marketplace with 30m users, 90% of whom are under 26
Etsy is buying Depop, the British secondhand fashion resale app, for $1.6bn (£1.1bn) to tap into the fast-growing trend of generation Z young people reselling clothes online.
Announcing the deal on Wednesday, Josh Silverman, the chief executive of Brooklyn-based Etsy said he expected the resale craze would continue long after the recovery from the pandemic, and that it would be led by Depop’s “passionate community” of fashion-conscious young people. “This [gen Z] is an enormous demographic and it’s the trendsetter demographic,” he told analysts on a call to discuss the deal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Treasury missed a green trick when it handed out Covid cash | Phillip Inman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/the-treasury-missed-a-green-trick-when-it-handed-out-covid-cash</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/the-treasury-missed-a-green-trick-when-it-handed-out-covid-cash"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:11:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commitments to a greener and healthier environment would have been a reasonable price to ask
When the government reacted to the coronavirus pandemic in 2020 with unprecedented rescue funds, ministers were urged to attach strings before the money disappeared out the door.
The strings would have forced employers to adopt policies they had resisted for years, most obviously cutting carbon emissions and promoting a healthier environment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Williamson's schools plan: yet another fiasco | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/the-guardian-view-on-williamsons-schools-plan-yet-another-fiasco</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/the-guardian-view-on-williamsons-schools-plan-yet-another-fiasco"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:07:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The paltry funding of a post-pandemic catch-up strategy needs upping by a factor of at least 10
Viewers of breakfast television may have experienced a disturbing sense of deja vu on Wednesday. Outside, glorious sunshine heralded another perfect summer’s day; on screen, the education secretary, Gavin Williamson, was defending a Covid schools announcement that had been greeted with immediate and almost universal criticism. It all felt very “summer of 2020”, when the exam-marking fiasco cast a shadow of ministerial incompetence over the end of the academic year.
Sadly, the government’s post-pandemic catch-up plans for pupils are very much a disaster of the present moment. Mr Williamson has unveiled a new £1.4bn programme to help English children regain lost ground, after 15 months of severe educational disruption and psychological strain. The money, mainly targeted at limited extra tutoring and teacher training, is about a tenth of the amount called for by Sir Kevan Collins, the government’s now-ex education recovery commissioner. The Education Policy Institute estimates that pandemic-related spending on English pupils adds up to £310 a head. That compares to equivalent figures of £1,600 in the US and £2,500 in the Netherlands. Having said, with heavy understatement, “more will be needed to meet the challenge”, Sir Kevan decided enough was enough and quit his post. It is not hard to see why.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philly DA: inside the fight to end mass incarceration in America]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/philly-da-larry-krasner-yoni-brook-mass-incarceration</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/philly-da-larry-krasner-yoni-brook-mass-incarceration"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T18:03:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In captivating new docuseries Philly DA, ‘progressive prosecutor’ Larry Krasner works with activists to tackle the highest incarceration rate in the world
America may be the land of the free but it also has the highest incarceration rate in the world. Its prisons contain more people than big cities such as Philadelphia or Dallas and express systemic racism in concrete and steel. But solutions do not necessarily lie with the White House.
 Related: ‘They track every move’: how US parole apps created digital prisoners 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devon Conway’s superb debut century puts New Zealand on top in first Test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/england-new-zealand-first-test-day-one-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/england-new-zealand-first-test-day-one-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:54:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First Test, day one: New Zealand: 246-3
Opener sets record for highest score by debutant at Lord’s

Test cricket’s return to Lord’s after a near two-year hiatus was a day to be savoured by the 6,500 or so spectators who sat dotted around the white stands like sprinkles on a 99 Flake. And for the three debutants on show, Devon Conway, Ollie Robinson and James Bracey, it was one they will certainly never forget.
Headlining the newcomers at stumps - cricket-wise, at least - was Conway. An impressive unbeaten 136 at the first attempt had seen the left-hander become the 14th New Zealand batsman to etch his name on to the honours board and, more importantly, driven the tourists to a commanding 246 for three with batting still to come.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin at Lord's</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expert expresses fears over Covid outbreaks at Bristol schools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/expert-expresses-fears-over-covid-outbreaks-at-bristol-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/expert-expresses-fears-over-covid-outbreaks-at-bristol-schools"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:42:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Schoolchildren could be becoming ‘canary in coalmine’ for rising number of Delta variant cases

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Outbreaks of the Delta variant at several schools across Bristol could signal that coronavirus infection rates in the city are higher than reported, an expert has said.
Around 11 primary and secondary schools are understood to be affected by the outbreak, with some cases confirmed as the variant first identified in India.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall and Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PM says no sign yet he should delay end of Covid rules as daily cases top 4,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/boris-johnson-says-no-sign-yet-he-should-delay-lifting-last-covid-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/boris-johnson-says-no-sign-yet-he-should-delay-lifting-last-covid-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:39:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson admits, however, that more time is needed to assess how effective vaccines are in stopping third wave 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

There are no signs “at the moment” that the final stage of lockdown easing in England needs to be scrapped or delayed, Boris Johnson has said, despite nervousness among scientists about daily cases rising above 4,000 to the highest point in two months.
Some experts have called for the government to push back on lifting all legal restrictions on social contact on 21 June given a warning the country is already at the start of a third wave and concerns about the Delta variant first identified in India, but the prime minister remained bullish.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m 24 and my life was pretty sorted out, until I fell deeply in love with a man of 51 | Leading questions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/03/im-24-and-my-life-was-pretty-sorted-out-until-i-fell-deeply-in-love-with-a-man-of-51</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/03/im-24-and-my-life-was-pretty-sorted-out-until-i-fell-deeply-in-love-with-a-man-of-51"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Staying with this man will mean bracing for uncomfortable questions, writes advice columnist Eleanor Gordon-Smith. But it’s what you feel, not what others think, that really matters
I am a 24-year-old lawyer. I like to think that my life is pretty sorted out but nine months ago, I fell deeply in love with a man of 51. This is hugely surprising to me – but it’s the most amazing relationship I could have imagined. He’s sensitive, kind, funny, generous and in my eyes, very good looking. The problem is ... the age gap! I wonder what I should think about this. I’m generally a conservative person who doesn’t like to shock public opinion.
Now, for the first time in my life, I’m facing a big decision: whether to go with this beautiful man or to give him up and go down a more traditional path. I should add: I don’t want children ever and nor does he.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eleanor Gordon-Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Diop wins International Booker for ‘frightening’ At Night All Blood Is Black]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/02/david-diop-wins-international-booker-for-frightening-at-night-all-blood-is-black</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/02/david-diop-wins-international-booker-for-frightening-at-night-all-blood-is-black"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Diop is the first French writer to win the prize for translated fiction – split with his translator Anna Moschovakis – for novel about a Senegalese soldier fighting for France in the first world war
David Diop has become the first French novelist to win the International Booker prize for translated fiction with At Night All Blood Is Black, his first novel translated into English.
Diop, the author of two novels, and his translator Anna Moschovakis, split the £50,000 annual prize, which goes to the best author and translator of a work translated into English. At Night All Blood Is Black follows Alfa Ndiaye, a Senegalese soldier fighting for France in the first world war, whose descent into madness after the death of a childhood friend on the frontline begins to show itself in extreme brutality against enemy German soldiers in the trenches.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sian Cain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charity records ‘horrific surge’ in antisemitic attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/02/charity-records-horrific-surge-in-antisemitic-attacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/02/charity-records-horrific-surge-in-antisemitic-attacks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:27:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community Security Trust records 351 incidents between 8 and 31 May, fueled by reaction to violence in Israel and Gaza

A charity that monitors antisemitism and provides security for British Jewish groups has recorded a “horrific surge” in racist attacks in the past month which campaigners said “surpassed anything we have seen before”.
The Community Security Trust (CST) recorded 351 antisemitic incidents between 8 and 31 May, more than for any single month since records began in 1986.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small boats carrying migrants across Channel hit record levels in May]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/small-boats-carrying-migrants-across-channel-hit-record-levels-in-may</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/small-boats-carrying-migrants-across-channel-hit-record-levels-in-may"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:26:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising numbers come as Home Office staff warn of 20-hour shifts and delays in Covid testing

The number of small boat arrivals in the UK from northern France reached record levels in May with 568 migrants crossing the Channel in the last four days of the month.
In the first four months of 2021, the number crossing – 2,108 – was more than double the 896 who crossed in that period in 2020.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on remembering Tiananmen 1989: mourning for those who cannot | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/the-guardian-view-on-remembering-tiananmen-1989-mourning-for-those-who-cannot</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/the-guardian-view-on-remembering-tiananmen-1989-mourning-for-those-who-cannot"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:25:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beijing’s attempts to obliterate the memory of the massacre are extending their reach 

When forgetting is compulsory, remembering can be a lonely business. Zhang Xianling’s 19-year-old son was shot in the head as Chinese troops bloodily suppressed the student-led protests that began in Tiananmen Square, Beijing, in 1989. In the 31 years since, she and other Tiananmen Mothers have campaigned in vain for an honest reckoning of the events of 4 June, while the Communist party’s imposed amnesia has made the subject utterly taboo on the mainland.
“So there is hope after all!” she exclaimed, when the scale and passion of Hong Kong’s annual vigil was described to her a few years ago. The event, attended by up to 180,000 at its peak, was the largest in the world and kept the memory of the killings alive on Chinese soil. But it will not happen this Thursday, and perhaps it will never happen again. The authorities have banned it for a second year running, purportedly due to coronavirus concerns – though other mass events continue, and authorities have warned that anyone who tries to participate could face five years in jail. Macau has acted similarly.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital soap Holby City to end after 22 years, BBC announces]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/hospital-soap-holby-city-to-end-after-23-years-bbc-announces</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/hospital-soap-holby-city-to-end-after-23-years-bbc-announces"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T17:22:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Broadcaster promises Casualty spin-off will ‘go out on a high’ in March 2022

The hospital TV soap Holby City will come to an end next year after 22 years on screen, with a former longstanding star of the show saying cast members were blindsided by the news.
Hugh Quarshie, who played the role of Ric for 19 years and was the longest-serving cast member in Holby City before leaving last year, said that he was “taken aback” to hear the news and that his former colleagues were “reeling too”, having effectively been given six months notice before they lose their jobs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can Biden’s Justice40 plan deliver a fairer environment for people of color?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/biden-justice40-plan-environmental-justice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/biden-justice40-plan-environmental-justice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:56:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Administration is pledging to route 40% of the benefits of climate and environment spending to disadvantaged communities, but getting it right will be difficult 
Indigenous farmers in the Isleta Pueblo, south of Albuquerque, New Mexico, have long relied on crops of corn and green chiles fed by the Rio Grande river, but amid a water crisis in the western US they are facing warnings to skip planting crops entirely –which could be devastating for the community’s 2,500 residents.
But a new national program could help those farmers and other disadvantaged communities. Introduced earlier this year by Joe Biden, the “Justice40” plan would steer 40% of the benefits of federal environmental investments to people most in need.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Green</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Education recovery chief quits in English schools catch-up row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/education-recovery-chief-kevan-collins-quit-english-schools-catch-up-row</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/education-recovery-chief-kevan-collins-quit-english-schools-catch-up-row"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:54:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Kevan Collins said to be dismayed that his long-awaited £15bn proposals were watered down to a £1.4bn package

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The government’s education catch-up chief has resigned in protest over the prime minister’s scaled-down recovery plan, warning it “does not come close” to meeting the needs of children whose education has been thrown into chaos by the pandemic.
In an emotional statement outlining why he could not remain in his post, Sir Kevan Collins said advising the government on the education recovery plan for England’s pupils had been the most important task of his professional life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naomi Osaka shames those who ignored her pleas for help | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/naomi-osaka-shames-those-who-ignored-her-pleas-for-help</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/02/naomi-osaka-shames-those-who-ignored-her-pleas-for-help"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:47:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The tennis champion has been let down by the grand slam organisers who have profited so greatly from her remarkable talent, writes Dr Nicholas Marlowe, while Kate Alley says she owes us no more than a game of tennis and Oli Senior questions the purpose of press conferences
In taking a stand on her mental health by refusing to attend post-match press conferences, Naomi Osaka stands for all of us (Naomi Osaka withdraws from French Open amid row over press conferences, 31 May). We all have issues with mental health by virtue of our humanity. No one is immune. Some of us are lucky enough to have stable upbringings; to encounter supportive teachers and mentors; to find the love of a partner or of friends; to find work in which we thrive; to not be deceived, bullied, doubted, or let down too many times; and some of us are not.
Those of us who are not so lucky must find the courage to ask for help; to make ourselves vulnerable in the hope that we will be listened to, cared for, and valued for who we are. When others respond in these ways, we learn to trust ourselves and to make choices that work for us rather than against us. We recover.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water in HS2 construction areas is safe and in good supply | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/water-in-hs2-construction-areas-is-safe-and-in-good-supply</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/water-in-hs2-construction-areas-is-safe-and-in-good-supply"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:45:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HS2 Ltd is doing a considerable amount of work to account for all potential impacts of construction, says the company’s environment director Peter Miller
I was disappointed by your article’s presentation of HS2’s extensive work to ensure good-quality drinking water in north London and Buckinghamshire (Fears raised over risks of water contamination as result of HS2 works, 1 June). The “internal papers” actually demonstrate that HS2 Ltd is doing a considerable amount of work to account for all potential impacts of construction and taking every possible precaution. The project has introduced the latest tunnel-boring technology, and has spent over £100m enhancing water treatment capacity in the region to ensure the highest water quality in these areas. People living near the HS2 route can be reassured that HS2 Ltd is working very closely with the Environment Agency and the local water company to ensure their water is safe and in good supply.
Peter Miller
Environment director, HS2 Ltd
• Have an opinion on anything you’ve read in the Guardian today? Please email us your letter and it will be considered for publication.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in four Londoners in temporary housing outside their local area]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/one-in-four-londoners-in-temporary-housing-outside-their-local-area</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/one-in-four-londoners-in-temporary-housing-outside-their-local-area"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:43:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some families placed in cities more than 200 miles away such as Manchester and Bradford
More than one in four Londoners in temporary accommodation due to homelessness are being rehoused out of their local area, with some placed in cities more than 200 miles away such as Manchester and Bradford, analysis shows.
At least 55,000 Londoners were in temporary housing outside their local areas at the end of 2020. Many are disabled or have mental health problems, or are in single-parent families with young children, and are awaiting a verdict on whether they are legally homeless or for settled accommodation to become available. 
More than one in five families are placed in other regions, a figure which has doubled since 2010, when one in 10 families were asked to relocate.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[English road left looking like a ‘horror film’ after tomato puree spillage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/english-road-left-looking-like-a-horror-film-after-tomato-puree-spillage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/english-road-left-looking-like-a-horror-film-after-tomato-puree-spillage"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:38:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stretch of A14 between Cambridge and Brampton closed after lorry crash leaves road covered in tomato
A 23-mile stretch of road in England was left looking like a scene from a “horror film” after a lorry crash spilled tomato puree across the tarmac on Tuesday.
The westbound carriageway of the A14 from Cambridge to Brampton was closed after the collision between two lorries. Cambridgeshire police tweeted:
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[English councils start banning smoking outside pubs and restaurants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/english-councils-start-banning-smoking-outside-pubs-and-restaurants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/english-councils-start-banning-smoking-outside-pubs-and-restaurants"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:32:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five local authorities take matters into own hands amid Covid outdoor eating culture
Five local authorities have banned smoking in pavement pubs, cafes and restaurants, and others are considering following suit, before a new push by the government to make England smoke-free in less than a decade.
The Covid outdoor eating culture has given the issue of smokers outside pubs and cafes a new visibility. Last summer there was an attempt to push through an amendment to legislation in the House of Lords to make pavements smoke-free, but it failed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boy, 14, ‘was racially abused’ before being stabbed to death in Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/dea-john-reid-boy-14-stabbed-death-racist-abuse-police-birmingham</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/dea-john-reid-boy-14-stabbed-death-racist-abuse-police-birmingham"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six people have been arrested following death of Dea-John Reid on Monday evening
A 14-year-old boy was subjected to racist abuse before being chased and stabbed to death in Birmingham, police have said, as he was named as Dea-John Reid.
Six people, four men in their 30s and two boys aged 13 and 14, have been arrested on suspicion of murder and remain in police custody.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray and Vikram Dodd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nothing can save you now! The death of Holby City is a huge loss to the BBC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/nothing-can-save-you-now-the-death-of-holby-city-is-a-huge-loss-to-the-bbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/02/nothing-can-save-you-now-the-death-of-holby-city-is-a-huge-loss-to-the-bbc"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T16:11:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running hospital soap is flatlining at last, never to be resuscitated. Let’s hope the final episodes are a tantalising finger up to the establishment 

The BBC’s announcement that Holby City will die next March will not have greatly concerned its most devoted viewers.
They will assume the show will be placed on a table, someone will shout “Stand clear!” and, after two shocks from the defibrillator, it will carry on as if nothing has happened. If that intervention failed, an eccentric surgeon – perhaps Mr Anton Meyer (George Irving) from the early days, or the current Henrik Hanssen (Guy Henry) – would improvise a pioneering bypass to BBC Two.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Lawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[English schools need more than superficial soundbites and short-term remedies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/02/english-schools-need-more-than-superficial-soundbites-and-short-term-remedies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/02/english-schools-need-more-than-superficial-soundbites-and-short-term-remedies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:40:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lack of planning by DfE means opportunity to help students recover from learning lost during Covid has been missed

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

For far too long schools in England have been expected to get along on a wing and a prayer. Now the need to help students recover from learning lost during the Covid pandemic has brought critical issues of educational funding into sharp focus.
Over the past 18 months the gap between the haves and the have-nots among our pupils has grown at a faster rate than previously seen. The paltry resources available to support vulnerable children – especially those with special educational needs and disabilities (Send) – have been cruelly exposed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jules White</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet, sincere and humanising: could Keir Starmer’s oh-so-serious student picture win votes?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/could-keir-starmer-student-picture-win-votes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/02/could-keir-starmer-student-picture-win-votes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:31:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Labour leader’s portrait from his Leeds University days reveals a young man with a vision, who might just appeal to that key electoral group: Joy Division dads
The torch of Labour leadership has truly passed to a new generation. Tony Blair’s student look was long hair and Jagger struts in his 70s student rock band Ugly Rumours. Keir Starmer’s image-conscious university photo from 1982, as seen in last night’s interview with Piers Morgan, brings us hurtling into the age of New Romanticism.
Blair failed in music, but turned politics into superstardom. Young Starmer seems to have shared a passion for subculture, at a moment in pop history when image and emotion were elegantly entwined. Can he recapture the youthful charm pictured here to make love tear Boris and the electorate apart (again)?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix reportedly plans push into video games market]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/netflix-reportedly-plans-push-video-games-market</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/netflix-reportedly-plans-push-video-games-market"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:26:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Streaming company said to have approached game industry executives with project at early stage
Apple, Microsoft, Sony and Google have all tried to create a “Netflix for games”, offering unlimited access to a library of titles for a flat monthly fee. But a growing number of reports suggest they may be about to face stiff competition from the streaming company itself.
Netflix has been approaching senior game industry executives about joining it to lead the creation of a subscription games service, according to reports from the tech news site the Information and Reuters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern Technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Victorian shepherds hut sold for £16,000 as shacks’ appeal grows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/02/victorian-shepherds-hut-sold-for-16000-soaring-demand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/02/victorian-shepherds-hut-sold-for-16000-soaring-demand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:19:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From a rundown original fetching 20 times its estimate to top-end new ones for £45k, huts are hot property
David Cameron wrote his memoirs in one; Prince George’s was a gift from his grandfather Prince Charles; and The Archers’ inimitable Linda Snell outraged Joe Grundy by installing a bespoke one in her Ambridge garden.
But if the trend for shepherd’s huts as a lifestyle accessory was already quietly growing, it has been turbo-charged by people working from home and taking staycations due to the pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU delays adding UK to Covid ‘white list’ over fears of Delta variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/eu-delays-adding-uk-to-covid-white-list-over-fears-of-delta-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/eu-delays-adding-uk-to-covid-white-list-over-fears-of-delta-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:12:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decision not to lift travel restrictions follows rise in cases linked to variant first identified in India

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The EU has delayed putting the UK on a “white list” of countries from where non-essential travel into the bloc is approved because of concerns about the rise in cases linked to the Delta variant first identified in India.
Japan, which is in an extended state of emergency during which there has been a sustained reduction in the number of new infections, has been added to the list, diplomatic sources said. The country is due to host the Olympic Games on 23 July.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Urban crime plummets during lockdowns in cities around world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/urban-crime-plummets-during-lockdowns-cities-around-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/urban-crime-plummets-during-lockdowns-cities-around-world"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impact on offences such as burglary and assault is revealed in 27 cities, but figures steadily rise as rules ease

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Urban crime ranging from vehicle theft and burglary to robbery and assault fell substantially during Covid lockdowns as stay-at-home orders around the world cleared the streets and ensured more houses were occupied in the daytime.
An analysis of crime reports from 27 cities in Europe, Asia and the Americas found overall urban crime fell by more than a third while lockdowns were in place and then steadily climbed back up when restrictions were lifted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis is suffocating the world’s lakes, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/climate-crisis-is-suffocating-the-worlds-lakes-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/climate-crisis-is-suffocating-the-worlds-lakes-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Falling oxygen levels harming already struggling wildlife and drinking water supplies, say scientists
The climate crisis is causing a widespread fall in oxygen levels in lakes across the world, suffocating wildlife and threatening drinking water supplies.
Falling levels of oxygen in oceans had already been identified, but new research shows that the decline in lakes has been between three and nine times faster in the past 40 years. Scientists found oxygen levels had fallen by 19% in deep waters and 5% at the surface.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘She had no fear mechanism’: the incredible, outrageous life of Miss Mercy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/02/miss-mercy-frank-zappa-the-gtos-music-memoir</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/02/miss-mercy-frank-zappa-the-gtos-music-memoir"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T15:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The life of the co-founder of Frank Zappa’s band GTOs and industry wild child is explored in a raucous new book
For many people, the notion of the groupie brings to mind something generic: a woman known solely for her relationship to her rock star of choice. But the most celebrated of the original groupies – the women who first inspired the term in the 1960s – had attitudes and styles that made them unique creatures, earning them an elevated place in the cutting-edge culture of the day.
 Related: 'Frank didn't adhere to any movements': behind the Zappa documentary 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Farber</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Async/Await Tutorial – Learn Callbacks, Promises, and Async/Await in JS by Making Ice Cream 🍧🍨🍦]]></title>
        <id>60b51f6e11ffb70827ef9f7c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-async-await-tutorial-learn-callbacks-promises-async-await-by-making-icecream/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:45:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we're going to build and run an ice cream shop and learn asynchronous JavaScript at the same time. Along the way, you'll learn how to use: CallbacksPromisesAsync / AwaitHere's what we'll cover in this article:What is Asynchronous JavaScript?Synchronous vs Asynchronous JavaScriptHow Callbacks Work in JavaScriptHow Promises Work in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antonio Conte holds Tottenham talks and is leading contender for job]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/antonio-conte-holds-tottenham-talks-and-is-leading-contender-for-managers-job</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/antonio-conte-holds-tottenham-talks-and-is-leading-contender-for-managers-job"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:41:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terms discussed with Conte, who quit Inter last week
Spurs trying to recruit Fabio Paratici as sporting director

Tottenham have opened talks with Antonio Conte about becoming their manager. Daniel Levy has overseen an extensive search to secure a permanent successor to José Mourinho, which has not been without its frustrations, and Conte is now considered to be the leading contender.
Levy has discussed personal terms with Conte, who left his job as the manager of Internazionale last Wednesday, three and a half weeks after leading the club to their first Serie A title in 11 years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/a-sacrificed-generation-psychological-scars-of-covid-on-young-may-have-lasting-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/a-sacrificed-generation-psychological-scars-of-covid-on-young-may-have-lasting-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:40:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Young people across Europe reveal how the pandemic has made them impatient for systemic change after bearing brunt of fallout

‘So many revolutions to lead’: Europe’s Gen Z on their post-Covid future
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z

Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Teenagers and young adults expressed profound anxiety about their future and accused governments of failing them as 15 months of lockdowns destabilised their mental wellbeing, education and job prospects. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Butler and Caroline Bannock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘So many revolutions to lead’: Europe’s Gen Z on their post-Covid future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/jun/02/so-many-revolutions-to-lead-europe-generation-z-on-their-post-covid-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/jun/02/so-many-revolutions-to-lead-europe-generation-z-on-their-post-covid-future"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of the Guardian’s 200th anniversary, we asked young people how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, hopes and dreams. Fifty from Europe’s Generation Z tell us how they see their future

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine ButlerCaroline BannockRachel ObordoJanise ElieDuarte Carrilho da Graça</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Queen’s platinum jubilee to be marked with four-day bank holiday in 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/queens-platinum-jubilee-to-be-marked-with-four-day-bank-holiday-in-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/queens-platinum-jubilee-to-be-marked-with-four-day-bank-holiday-in-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T14:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is part of a year of events to mark the first time a British sovereign has been on throne for seven decades
A four-day bank holiday weekend will mark the Queen’s platinum jubilee next summer to celebrate the monarch’s 70 years on the throne.
National events will include a live concert featuring some of the world’s biggest stars, a service of thanksgiving and, perhaps the Queen’s own highlight, a day at the races.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not just Naomi Osaka – no one really likes post-match interviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/its-not-just-naomi-osaka-no-one-really-likes-post-match-interviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/its-not-just-naomi-osaka-no-one-really-likes-post-match-interviews"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:58:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In pulling out of the French Open, the young tennis player has exposed a truth known to all players, fans and even journalists: the obligatory press conferences are pointless and often brutally boring
In the fallout from Naomi Osaka’s French Open walkout, everyone seemed to fall out with everyone else. I got a text from a TV producer. “Lol. Piers Morgan’s criticism of the tennis player not wanting to attend a press conference is rich given 99% of the TV presenters I’ve EVER worked with (usually male, including you) won’t attend debriefs and cry like babies if you dare say they didn’t have a great show. The male TV presenter is the most fragile ego in all showbiz.” And this is from a close friend, please note; imagine what I get from my enemies.
He makes a fair point. A debrief, a post-show meeting for a full and frank exchange of views, is on the face of it a good idea. You look at what’s gone well, what hasn’t, and what can be learned for next time. The trouble is, straight after coming off air, the heroes and villains of the hour are rarely in the right emotional place for constructive reflection. It can often turn into an orgy of cloying self-congratulation or, more often, an exercise in arse-covering. The blame for anything that’s gone wrong is parcelled up and passed around the room and everyone endeavours not to be holding it when the music stops. And, yes, I must admit I have often inwardly cried like a baby when anyone dares to say, or even merely intimate, that I haven’t had a great show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Chiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iggy Pop ascends to greatness: Tom Copi’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/iggy-pop-stage-dive-tom-copi-best-photograph</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/iggy-pop-stage-dive-tom-copi-best-photograph"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:56:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Iggy dived off the stage into the crowd, where he was lifted up by fans and stood above them in triumph. Someone handed him a jar of peanut butter and he smeared it on his chest’
Iggy Pop and I went to the same high school in Ann Arbor, Michigan, where I graduated a year ahead of him. I was not particularly into the local rock scene but I did photograph activities on and around the university campus, including a band called the Prime Movers, in which Jim Osterberg played drums. Later, Jim started a band called Iggy and the Iguanas, and thenceforth, he was Iggy.
I photographed Iggy’s new band the Stooges at the university’s Hill Auditorium. One of the pictures from that session in 1968 was later used on the movie poster to promote Jim Jarmusch’s 2016 documentary on the band, Gimme Danger: The Story of the Stooges.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Daniel Dylan Wray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Folk singer Mustafa: ‘I’m trying to preserve the memories of young Black Muslims’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/02/mustafa-folk-when-smoke-rises</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/02/mustafa-folk-when-smoke-rises"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The poet, a songwriter for artists including the Weeknd, explains how music helped him explore the loss of friends to inner-city violence: ‘Sorrow is meant to be experienced and felt’
Appearing on a Zoom call from his Los Angeles apartment, sporting the white, perforated kufi skullcap worn in mosques, 24-year-old Canadian musician Mustafa is a long way from Regent Park, the predominantly Black, working-class neighbourhood in downtown Toronto where he grew up. Regent Park is a place with a dual identity: one of camaraderie and community, the “building blocks for how I think, how I breathe and how I speak”, he says; the other deprivation and violence, where Mustafa’s adolescence was shaped by grief and death, including the murders of friends such as Ano, Santana, Ali, and the rapper Jahvante “Smoke Dawg” Smart.
Using the vulnerability of folk music – a genre that rarely makes space for the Black Muslim experience – Mustafa’s stunning debut long-form project, When Smoke Rises, is an elegy to these friends, a dialogue with those grieving and a love letter to his community. “Don’t crease your Air Forces, just stay inside tonight,” he begs his friends to a rhythm beaten out on acoustic guitar. Of Smoke Dawg, who was killed in 2018, he pleads, “Please come back, at least in my dreams”, over tender piano played by James Blake.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aina J Khan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The brilliance of brown lawns: why your grass shouldn’t always be greener]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/shortcuts/2021/jun/02/brown-lawns-grass-should-not-always-be-greener</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/shortcuts/2021/jun/02/brown-lawns-grass-should-not-always-be-greener"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:18:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watering our gardens is wasteful and mowing them a nightmare for biodiversity. So is it time to embrace long, brown grass or more radical options such as patchwork lawns?

Name: Brown lawns.
Colour: Brown, obviously.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A spacewalk and a Gilded Cage: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/02/spacewalk-and-a-gilded-cage-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/02/spacewalk-and-a-gilded-cage-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buckingham Palace banned ethnic minorities from office roles, papers reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/buckingham-palace-banned-ethnic-minorities-from-office-roles-papers-reveal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/02/buckingham-palace-banned-ethnic-minorities-from-office-roles-papers-reveal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Documents also shed light on Queen’s ongoing exemption from race and sex discrimination laws

The Queen’s courtiers banned “coloured immigrants or foreigners” from serving in clerical roles in the royal household until at least the late 1960s, according to newly discovered documents that will reignite the debate over the British royal family and race.
The documents also shed light on how Buckingham Palace negotiated controversial clauses – that remain in place to this day – exempting the Queen and her household from laws that prevent race and sex discrimination.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Pegg and Rob Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK stamp duty holiday extension prompts rise in mortgage demand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/uk-stamp-duty-holiday-extension-prompts-rise-in-mortgage-demand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/02/uk-stamp-duty-holiday-extension-prompts-rise-in-mortgage-demand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:41:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bank of England data shows rise in mortgage approvals in April, the first monthly increase since November
Rishi Sunak’s six-month extension of the government’s stamp duty holiday prompted a fresh surge in demand for home loans, according to the latest figures from the Bank of England.
Threadneedle Street data showed that in April – the month after the chancellor’s budget announcement – the number of mortgage approvals climbed from 83,400 to 86,900, the first monthly increase since November.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott Economics editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Worse day by day’: journalists speak out after Pakistani vlogger tortured]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/02/hamid-mir-journalists-speak-out-after-pakistani-vlogger-asad-toor-tortured</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/02/hamid-mir-journalists-speak-out-after-pakistani-vlogger-asad-toor-tortured"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:41:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Imran Khan’s government moves to outlaw virtually any criticism, media figures fear ‘darkest era’ of press freedom

Opinion: Imran Khan promised us press freedom in Pakistan. Now journalists are under attack

Gathered before a solemn crowd, Hamid Mir, one of Pakistan’s best-known journalists, spoke defiantly. “Do not ever enter the homes of journalists again,” he said. “We don’t have tanks or guns like you, but we can tell the people of Pakistan about the stories that emerge from inside your homes.”
Mir may have been addressing journalists in Islamabad on Friday, but his words were not directed at them; they were a clear message to Pakistan’s all-powerful military establishment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen in Delhi and Guardian reporter in Islamabad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cuprinol Shed of the Year 2021 entrants – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/02/cuprinol-shed-of-the-year-2021-entrants-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/02/cuprinol-shed-of-the-year-2021-entrants-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T11:26:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, 331 entrants are vying for the title of Cuprinol Shed of the Year, including a Catholic oratory, a Chitty Chitty Bang Bang-inspired ‘inventor’s workshop’ and a haven for bats 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An anti-Netanyahu coalition government would suggest Israelis are ready for change | Dahlia Scheindlin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/anti-netanyahu-coalition-government-israelis-ready-for-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/anti-netanyahu-coalition-government-israelis-ready-for-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T11:21:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A government led by Naftali Bennett would not be progressive, but political paralysis has only deepened the occupation

As Israel inches closer to ending two years of political stalemate and 12 consecutive years of Benjamin Netanyahu’s leadership, pressure on rightwing parties preparing to join a “change” coalition from pro-Netanyahu rightwingers, has reached a crescendo. Like other rightwingers in the “change” bloc, Naftali Bennett and Ayelet Shaked, leaders of the hardline Yamina party, have been called traitors and collaborators and received death threats throughout the last month for their planned defection from Netanyahu’s camp.
As so often in Israeli politics, there is an American parallel: Bennett and Shaked’s predicament recalls the unforgettable moment the US senator Lindsey Graham, days after the 6 January Capitol riots, was harangued by Trump-cult followers, unhinged by Graham’s denunciation of their leader. But it didn’t take long for Graham to revert to his pre-January, pro-Trump affinity. Will Yamina do the same? At the time of writing, the new coalition does not yet exist; in part because of Shaked’s demands in the negotiation process to help advance her rightwing agenda. Moreover, any number of tactics Netanyahu is devising may yet derail the new government in the coming week before it is sworn in.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dahlia Scheindlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ny Nourn: the woman convicted of murder and pardoned – who now fights for other battered women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/ny-nourn-the-woman-convicted-of-and-pardoned-who-now-fights-for-other-battered-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/ny-nourn-the-woman-convicted-of-and-pardoned-who-now-fights-for-other-battered-women"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T11:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nourn moved from Cambodia to the US as a child, and ended up in an abusive relationship that led to a man’s murder. After years in prison, she is now a powerful voice for those who face incarceration and deportation
When Ny Nourn entered Central California Women’s Facility, the largest women’s prison in the world, there was every reason to believe she would never walk free on American soil again.
She was just 21, and had been sentenced to “life without parole” for her part in a hauntingly brutal murder – a part she was forced into. Even if, at some distant date, a successful appeal commuted that sentence, her conviction made Nourn deportable – so when she had served her time, she was likely to be transported to another prison and ultimately to Cambodia, the country of her parents’ birth, a country she had never set foot in.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make fruit fool – recipe | Felicity Cloake's masterclass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/02/how-to-make-fruit-fool-recipe-felicity-cloake-masterclass</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/02/how-to-make-fruit-fool-recipe-felicity-cloake-masterclass"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T11:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are essentially four main steps to this popular dessert: chop fruit, cook fruit, whip cream and combine (unless you count devour greedily) 
You’d have to be a fool yourself not to make fool your go-to pudding at this time of year – not only is it delicious, it’s also stupidly quick and easy to knock up, which means it’s just the thing to make with young children. You can make it with just about any fruit you like, turn it vegan, dress it up for a special occasion or make it so healthy, you could even have it for breakfast. Fool: it’s surprisingly clever stuff.
Prep 15 min, + cooling
Cook 15 min
Serves 4
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felicity Cloake</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Waiting to happen’: the California region where masks are taboo – and cases are rising]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/covid-cases-northern-california</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/02/covid-cases-northern-california"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rural northern California has been forceful in its pushback against masks, business restrictions and vaccine mandates
Rural northern California is seeing a troubling rise in Covid-19 cases and hospitalizations, an alarming trend that comes as residents and businesses continue to protest against safety measures and vaccinations – with one Mendocino cafe threatening to charge customers $5 for wearing a mask.
While the region makes up a small proportion of the state’s population, the growth in its caseload has been considerable, and comes at a time when the state overall is enjoying some of the lowest rates of Covid in the country. After largely avoiding the worst of the pandemic, a block of far northern California counties now leads the state with nearly 40 cases per 100,000 residents over the past week, according to statistics maintained by the Los Angeles Times. Tehama county ranked the highest in the LA Times case ratings with 139 cases per 100,000 residents. Meanwhile 10 of the 21 total Covid deaths in nearby Siskiyou county have occurred since the beginning of May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick in Berkeley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Myanmar’s football in crisis as pull-outs and suspension threat follow coup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/myanmar-football-crisis-pull-outs-suspension-threat-follow-coup-japan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/myanmar-football-crisis-pull-outs-suspension-threat-follow-coup-japan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National team lost 10-0 in Japan after mainstays including an experienced goalkeeper refused the head coach’s call
Second-division games in Malaysia don’t make many international headlines but that changed in March when the Myanmar under-23 winger Hein Htet Aung gave a three-fingered salute after scoring for Selangor II. Popularised by The Hunger Games film franchise, this gesture of resistance was adopted by pro-democracy protesters in Thailand and Hong Kong in 2014 and then by Myanmar, after the military took back power in a coup on 1 February.
Before Myanmar’s 2022 World Cup qualifier against Japan last Friday, the goalkeeper Kyaw Zin Htet had called for players to copy Hein’s handiwork. “It would be good if some of them came out and gave the three-fingered salute to an international audience,” the 31-year-old told AFP.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Duerden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the eviction ban ending?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from renters in England who are at risk from losing their home due to the lifting of the eviction ban
The eviction ban in England was lifted on 31 May leaving nearly two million private renters concerned about whether they will be able to find another property if they lose their home. 
We would like to hear from those who have been affected by the eviction ban ending.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 easy walks in Britain for families with younger children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/02/10-easy-walks-in-britain-for-families-with-younger-children</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/02/10-easy-walks-in-britain-for-families-with-younger-children"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:30:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shorter distances, a dash of history, plus plenty of wildlife and nature make for fun family-friendly adventures 
Distance 2.5 miles
Start/finish Cothelstone Hill car park, Broomfield, Taunton
How to get there By car, 6 miles west of M5 junction 24
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jen and Sim Benson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I felt nauseous in Topshop’: why a fashion editor gave up buying new clothes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/02/i-felt-nauseous-in-topshop-why-a-fashion-editor-gave-up-buying-new-clothes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/02/i-felt-nauseous-in-topshop-why-a-fashion-editor-gave-up-buying-new-clothes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The truth about mass-produced dresses - that everything is commodified and nothing is sustainable – did for me. I decided that if I really wanted a new dress, it had to be old
It was April 2019. I was seven months pregnant and in Topshop, looking for something large in which to rehome my body.
I was wearing a maternity dress that, if you had seen me pregnant, you would have recognised – a cheap, pleated wraparound in a red floral print that expanded as I expanded. I imagined Issey Miyake, but increasingly looked more like an armchair. It had served me well, but I was determined to buy something, anything, to see me through the next few months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Morwenna Ferrier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you recently relocated from Hong Kong to the UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/tell-us-have-you-recently-relocated-from-hong-kong-to-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/tell-us-have-you-recently-relocated-from-hong-kong-to-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T08:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experiences of moving to the UK from Hong Kong
We’d like to hear from people who have recently relocated from Hong Kong to the UK.
There have been 34,000 applications for a new visa for people from Hong Kong seeking residency in the UK in just two months, the Home Office has revealed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave weapons that could cause Havana Syndrome exist, experts say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/microwave-weapons-havana-syndrome-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/02/microwave-weapons-havana-syndrome-experts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T08:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Russia and possibly China have developed technology capable of injuring brain and a US company made a prototype in 2004
Portable microwave weapons capable of causing the mysterious spate of “Havana Syndrome” brain injuries in US diplomats and spies have been developed by several countries in recent years, according to leading American experts in the field.
A US company also made the prototype of such a weapon for the marine corps in 2004. The weapon, codenamed Medusa, was intended to be small enough to fit in a car, and cause a “temporarily incapacitating effect” but “with a low probability of fatality or permanent injury”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remote working has been life-changing for disabled people, don’t take it away now | Frances Ryan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/remote-working-disabled-people-back-to-normal-disability-inclusion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/02/remote-working-disabled-people-back-to-normal-disability-inclusion"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T08:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the rush to go ‘back to normal’, must we sacrifice all the gains that have been made on disability inclusion?

Tables blocking the road. Chairs over flat curbs. Gazebos built on accessible parking. The surge in street dining since lockdown eased in England has been great for businesses, but not so much for wheelchair users and people with mobility conditions, who report being unable to get around their home towns due to the new blockages.
Many of these people have been stuck indoors for up to a year shielding, and on their first taste of freedom are now being blocked from getting to the shops or pub. “All I want to do is go and meet my friends and have a pint,” said Katie Pennick, a campaigner and wheelchair user, recently on BBC Radio 4. It’s not your typical civil rights slogan but it characterises the crunch of so much disability politics: disabled people deserve the right to have a life like everyone else.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Frances Ryan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong’s 4 June Tiananmen vigil over the years – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/02/hong-kong-4-june-tiananmen-vigil-over-the-years-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/02/hong-kong-4-june-tiananmen-vigil-over-the-years-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T07:49:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years, Hong Kong has been one of just two cities in China allowed to mark anniversaries of the deadly crackdown on pro-democracy protesters in Tiananmen Square in Beijing in 1989. This year, however, Hong Kong authorities banned the vigil for the second consecutive year, citing the coronavirus pandemic. Critics say the authorities are using the pandemic as an excuse to silence pro-democracy voices. Last year thousands of people gathered in Victoria Park despite the ban, and weeks later police arrested more than 20 activists who had taken part in the vigil. Organisers have urged people to mark the anniversary in private this year by lighting a candle at home
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can I tell my partner how I feel about her history of sex work without her feeling judged?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/02/how-can-i-tell-my-partner-how-i-feel-about-her-history-of-sex-work-without-her-feeling-judged</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/02/how-can-i-tell-my-partner-how-i-feel-about-her-history-of-sex-work-without-her-feeling-judged"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T07:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My partner was involved in pornography and other sex work, and I feel jealous and insecure. I don’t want to ruin our relationship – how can I talk to her about this?
I fell in love with a wonderful woman who used to do pornography and other sex work. I think of myself as progressive and I don’t want to pass judgment on anyone for their past. I think women who do sex work deserve respect. But I was raised in a very conservative Christian household, so my views on sexuality were rooted in modesty and shame. I love our sex life and she is my best friend. But I find myself feeling jealous or insecure about her past and I worry that I will let these feelings ruin an amazing relationship. How can I talk to her about my internal struggles without making her feel judged? How can I work through these feelings and find acceptance and security within myself? I know my feelings are wrong, but I don’t know how to overcome them and love her the way she truly deserves to be loved.
Feelings are never right or wrong. They just exist. Accept them as valid and ask her to do so as well. It is natural to have some jealousy or insecurity about a partner’s past, no matter what that might have been. I imagine she expects that you may harbour some of the feelings you describe, so if you think it will help to share them with her then perhaps you should. Ideally, start by reaffirming your positive feelings for her, then tell her your issues. Be sure to follow that by asking her for something you need – explanations, reassurances? Identify what help she could give and then ask specifically for it. It is always best to follow what could be taken as a criticism or complaint with a request that – if granted – could rectify the situation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[International Photography Contest of Mountain Activity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/02/international-photography-contest-of-mountain-activity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/02/international-photography-contest-of-mountain-activity"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T06:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The International Photography Contest of Mountain Activity (CVCEPHOTO), organized by the Club Vasco de Camping Elkartea, a mountaineering club in Basque country, has announced the winners of this year’s competition which brought together the work of 372 photographers from 58 countries
The awarded photographs will be exhibited in the CVCE club’s showroom from May 27 to July 31
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The heart of Harlem: Dawoud Bey’s innovative street photography – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/02/dawoud-bey-street-photography-harlem-new-york</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/02/dawoud-bey-street-photography-harlem-new-york"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T06:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A career retrospective at the Whitney shows how Bey’s work gave black subjects in New York a space to assert themselves and their presence in the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wexford’s hotels and attractions prepare for easing of Ireland’s Covid lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/02/wexfords-hotels-and-attractions-prepare-for-easing-of-irelands-covid-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/02/wexfords-hotels-and-attractions-prepare-for-easing-of-irelands-covid-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T05:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The shuttering is almost at an end, but as hotels reopen on 2 June, how will the county cope with domestic-only tourism?
Ireland has endured one of Europe’s longest lockdowns, so its hotels have been busy blowing away cobwebs, training staff and restocking the kitchen as they prepare to reopen today.
As with other Irish hotels, the Ferrycarrig on its south-eastern tip is hoping this landmark day will signal the beginning of a rebirth of a devastated tourism industry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad’s decade of destruction in Syria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T02:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Syria’s president, Bashar al-Assad, has presided over a devastating civil war that has caused the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. Martin Chulov describes a man who came back from the brink of defeat to strengthen his grip on a country deeply scarred by war
Bashar al-Assad succeeded his father as president of Syria in 2000. He was just 34, had studied in London, and some hoped he would open up the autocratic country. Instead, following the Arab spring uprising he has cracked down harder than ever on the Syrian people. In the decade-long civil war that followed, more than 500,000 people are thought to have died. 
The Guardian’s Middle East correspondent, Martin Chulov, tells Anushka Asthana that as Assad lost control of vast areas of Syria following the uprising, he was at maximum vulnerability. But the intervention of Iran and Russia proved decisive. Now, after a widely discredited election victory with 95% of the vote, Assad begins his fourth term as president of a country deeply scarred by war. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Martin Chulov; produced by Alice Fordham and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Discord AI Chatbot that Talks Like Your Favorite Character]]></title>
        <id>60b5025111ffb70827ef9ebe</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/discord-ai-chatbot/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:47:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's build an AI model that speaks just like your favorite character and deploy that model as a Discord chatbot. All the coding and deployment happen in the cloud (for free!), so you don't even need a local IDE to follow along.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Key species at risk if planet heats up by more than 1.5C, report finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/key-species-at-risk-if-planet-heats-up-by-more-than-15c-report-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/key-species-at-risk-if-planet-heats-up-by-more-than-15c-report-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WWF report finds puffins, penguins and many other species will face issues such as habitat loss and food insecurity
Corals will bleach, penguins will lose their Antarctic ice floes, puffins around the UK coast will be unable to feed their young, and the black-headed squirrel monkey of the Amazon could be wiped out if the world fails to limit global heating to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels.
Beyond a 1.5C rise, many species will face increasing problems finding food or surviving, according to a report from WWF on the effects of climate breakdown on 12 key species across the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kate Winslet says she refused offer to edit sex scene showing ‘bulgy belly’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/kate-winslet-says-she-refused-offer-to-edit-sex-scene-showing-bulgy-belly</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/kate-winslet-says-she-refused-offer-to-edit-sex-scene-showing-bulgy-belly"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Craig Zobel, director of Mare of Easttown, offered to show actor in a more flattering light but Winslet said: ‘Don’t you dare’
Kate Winslet has said she refused a director’s offer to edit a sex scene in which she showed a “bulgy bit of belly” for her latest television series.
The actor claimed Craig Zobel, the director of her new HBO series Mare of Easttown, had offered to show her body in a more flattering light.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Analytics with Pandas – How to Drop a List of Rows from a Pandas Dataframe]]></title>
        <id>60b1eed311ffb70827ef9504</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/drop-list-of-rows-from-pandas-dataframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T20:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Pandas dataframe is a two dimensional data structure which allows you to store data in rows and columns. It's very useful when you're analyzing data.  When you have a list of data records in a dataframe, you may need to drop a specific list of rows depending on the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Next.js and Make React Development Simpler]]></title>
        <id>60b668c0acb62507dd1d710b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js makes developing React applications simpler. It provides a common structure that allows you to build frontend React applications, and transparently handles server-side rendering for you. We just released a full course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you the basics of Next.js.  Kapehe developed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your stories and photos of extraordinary birds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/01/share-your-stories-and-photos-of-extraordinary-birds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/01/share-your-stories-and-photos-of-extraordinary-birds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:06:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Send us your pictures and stories of remarkable bird sightings – and we’ll publish a selection of them
Have you taken an extraordinary photograph of a bird that you’re particularly proud of? Send us your pictures and stories of remarkable bird sightings – and we’ll publish a selection of them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experience of Heathrow airport’s new ‘red list’ terminal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/share-your-experience-of-heathrow-airports-new-red-list-terminal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/share-your-experience-of-heathrow-airports-new-red-list-terminal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from travellers who have passed through Heathrow’s new dedicated terminal for arrivals from country’s on the UK’s coronavirus ‘red list’
From 1 June, passengers arriving in the UK from countries on the British ‘red list’ of destinations with a high risk of Covid-19 will pass through a separate terminal at London’s Heathrow airport.
Travellers arriving on direct flights from such a country will now transit through Terminal Three, in a bid to prevent the spread of new coronavirus variants in the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Tokyo really host a pandemic Olympics?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/01/will-tokyo-really-host-pandemic-olympic-games-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/01/will-tokyo-really-host-pandemic-olympic-games-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T02:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Games were meant to be a moment of national celebration but – with coronavirus cases rising in Japan – this summer’s postponed Olympics are the subject of recrimination and protest. Can widespread public opposition overcome huge commercial pressure to go ahead?
When Tokyo’s bid to host the Olympics succeeded eight years ago, a supportive public expected the 2020 Games to be a moment of national unity – and, after the Fukushima nuclear disaster, a declaration that the country was open for business. Instead, the coronavirus pandemic forced a delay to 2021.
With the rearranged Games due to take place in less than two months the expected respite from the pandemic has not materialised, and with vaccination rates in Japan stubbornly low, polls suggest that as much as 80% of the public wants to see them postponed again or even called off. Justin McCurry, the Guardian’s Tokyo correspondent, tells Anushka Asthana why the movement to cancel the Games is facing an uphill battle in the face of vast financial pressure to go ahead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Justin McCurry; produced by Joshua Kelly and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An act of terrorism America tried to forget – 360 video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T07:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This video is best viewed on YouTube. Click here.
On the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, artist Bayeté Ross Smith uses archival photos to create immersive 360 scenes of these events. He finds that the underlying political and economic injustices were not only never addressed, but repeated time and again over the past century.
This story was suppressed from history books and the white perpetrators were never held accountable. And it wasn't just Tulsa. Dozens of other racial terrorism events from 1917 to 1921 have also gone untold, even within the victims' families. 

This is part one of Red Summers, a 360 video series by artist and filmmaker Bayeté Ross Smith on the untold American history of racial terrorism from 1917 to 1921. The project is funded by Black Public Media, Eyebeam, Sundance Institute, Crux XR and the Open Society Foundations.

Read more

Essay: It was among the worst acts of violence in US history, and no one was held accountable – how much has changed in the last 100 years?
‘The loss is incalculable’: descendants of the Tulsa massacre on what was stolen from them 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bayeté Ross Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can the US avoid another Trump?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/31/can-the-us-avoid-another-trump-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/31/can-the-us-avoid-another-trump-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T02:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Obama adviser Ben Rhodes has travelled the world looking for clues to how the US came to elect Donald Trump and he found parallels everywhere. But is there a way of stopping it from happening again?
When Donald Trump won the US election in 2016 it upturned the assumptions of many in America about who was electable to the highest office in the land. It seemed obvious to many that Trump would lose to Hillary Clinton and yet he won a stunning victory. 
For the former Obama aide Ben Rhodes it was a moment to take stock and search for clues as to how it could have happened. He tells Anushka Asthana that his quest took him around the world to countries that had elected their own ‘strongman’ leaders. He asks what lessons can be learned to avoid another Trump-style presidency?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Ben Rhodes; produced by Alice Fordham and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>