<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-15T00:36:41.167Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-15T00:36:41.167Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.6.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progressive lawmakers call on US to recognize Palestinians’ human rights – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/14/liz-cheney-republicans-elise-stefanik-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/14/liz-cheney-republicans-elise-stefanik-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T00:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senator Bernie Sanders and representative Cori Bush made appeals
Joel Greenberg, associate of Matt Gaetz, pleads guilty to paying 17-year-old for sex
Members of Congress agree to commission on Capitol attack
Pro-Trump Elise Stefanik replaces Cheney as GOP conference chair

 1.00am BST 
– Lauren Aratani and Maanvi Singh
 12.25am BST 
Turns out campaigning across California with a 1,000lb bear is not a foolproof political plan.
John Cox, a candidate vying to replace Gavin Newsom in the state’s gubernatorial r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh in Oakland (now), Lauren Aratani and Joanna Walters (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of UK train services to be restored as Covid restrictions ease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/15/thousands-uk-train-services-restored-covid-restrictions-ease</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/15/thousands-uk-train-services-restored-covid-restrictions-ease"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T23:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addition of 2,500 extra services will mean rail network running at levels before start of December lockdown

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Thousands more train services will be restored to the UK rail schedules this weekend with more passengers expected to travel as coronavirus restrictions ease on Monday.
The addition of 2,500 extra services daily means that about 85% of the rail network will be running again, back to levels before the start of the last lockdown in December…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meera Sodha's vegan recipe for crispy chocolate and date slices | The new vegan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/15/meera-sodha-vegan-recipe-rice-krispies-chocolate-date-slices</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/15/meera-sodha-vegan-recipe-rice-krispies-chocolate-date-slices"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T23:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Super-simple, chewy, fruity, Rice Krispie chocolate slices that make a perfectly portable picnic treat 
Granny Jean was my husband’s grandmother, and I hear she was a force. She had a winsome smile and an extraordinary energy for bric-a-brac sales, tennis and gardening. The only time you’d see her sitting still was at 4pm, where nothing would get between her and tea-time. The rules were simple: tea was served (in cups, not mugs) and Granny would insist all were seated to enjoy one of her latest creations. T…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meera Sodha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Cheney: McCarthy should testify about Trump’s views on Capitol attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/democrats-republicans-commission-us-capitol-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/democrats-republicans-commission-us-capitol-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T22:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawmakers agree to create bipartisan commission to investigate breach but questions remain over GOP support
The Republican House minority leader, Kevin McCarthy, should testify before the commission to investigate the 6 January Capitol attack, the Wyoming representative Liz Cheney said on Friday, because he has “said publicly that he’s got information about the president’s state of mind that day”.
 Related: ‘It’s hard to look at’: Donald Trump makes National Portrait Gallery debut 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Oladipo and Martin Pengelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Gaetz scandal deepens as associate admits paying 17-year-old for sex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/matt-gaetz-scandal-joel-greenberg-sex-trafficking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/matt-gaetz-scandal-joel-greenberg-sex-trafficking"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T21:34:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joel Greenberg expected to plead guilty to federal charges and could be key witness if congressman faces trial
The scandal engulfing Matt Gaetz, one of Donald Trump’s brashest supporters in Congress, deepened on Friday after an associate admitted sex trafficking involving a minor and agreed to cooperate with investigators.
 Related: AOC says Marjorie Taylor Greene is ‘deeply unwell’ after 2019 video surfaces 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington, Martin Pengelly in New York and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California governor candidate under investigation over 1,000lb bear sidekick]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/california-john-cox-bear-investigation-recall-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/california-john-cox-bear-investigation-recall-election"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T21:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[John Cox may have violated city law when he brought campaign mascot Tag with him to San Diego
Turns out campaigning across California with a 1,000lb bear is not a foolproof political plan.
John Cox, a candidate vying to replace Gavin Newsom in the state’s gubernatorial recall vote, is under investigation for violating a San Diego city law that bans anyone, except zoos, from bringing wild animals – including lions and tigers and bears – into the area. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Cantor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Domina: this Roman epic fills a gory, horny, Game of Thrones-shaped hole]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/14/sky-atlantic-domina</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/14/sky-atlantic-domina"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T21:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The show has a great cast, a big budget and is full of carnage and backstabbing. Plus people say ‘My liege!’ a lot. What’s not to like?
The crucial moment in any epic drama series – and I do lump fantasy series in there, because even though I recognise the dragons-and-zombies fancy of Game of Thrones is separate to the grounded real-world source of, say, The Tudors, it doesn’t really matter when the colour palette is really grey and people say “Sire … my liege!” a lot, and “harbours” and “bays” are still de…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Golby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferran Torres hits hat-trick in madcap win for Manchester City at Newcastle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/ferran-torres-hits-hat-trick-in-madcap-win-for-manchester-city-at-newcastle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/ferran-torres-hits-hat-trick-in-madcap-win-for-manchester-city-at-newcastle"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:59:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talk about a timely reminder. With the Champions League final fast approaching Ferran Torres jogged Pep Guardiola’s memory by scoring a fabulous hat-trick comprised of three different varieties of volley.
One was utterly outrageous and all were far too good for Martin Dubravka to save as a refreshed Manchester City side studded with second stringers ultimately outclassed Newcastle in the most bewitchingly entertaining of supposedly meaningless games. Along the madcap way Guardiola’s newly crowned English Ch…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louise Taylor at St James' Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You&#8217;re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they &#8230;
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s hard to look at’: Donald Trump makes National Portrait Gallery debut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/donald-trump-national-portrait-gallery-photo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/donald-trump-national-portrait-gallery-photo"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:33:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo of ex-president will make way for a painted portrait as gallery says Trump’s team is considering artists
A picture is worth a thousand tweets. Donald Trump gained immortality of sorts on Friday when he made his debut at the National Portrait Gallery in Washington. But he also ran into some “good trouble”.
 Related: Rightwingers tried to discredit Trump ‘foes’ with honey trap plot – report 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is SendGrid? SMTP Email Newsletter Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>609d63e962ab9107fe5aa2ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-sendgrid-smpt-email-newsletter-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:31:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard of the term SMTP before, and wondered what it is. SMTP is a common method for handling email messages. Today I am going to explain what SMTP is, and how to use an SMTP provider such as SendGrid to send emails from your address. What Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React for Beginners: Complete React Cheatsheet for 2021]]></title>
        <id>609ea83362ab9107fe5aa920</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/react-for-beginners-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the React for Beginners guide. It's designed to teach you all the core React concepts that you need to know to start building React applications in 2021. I created this resource to give you the most complete and beginner-friendly path to learn React from the ground up. By]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proud Boys leader received Covid-19 stimulus loans worth $15,500]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/proud-boys-leader-enrique-tarrio-received-ppp-loans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/proud-boys-leader-enrique-tarrio-received-ppp-loans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:17:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Enrique Tarrio received two paycheck protection program loans intended for small businesses, for ‘security systems services’
Government records show that Enrique Tarrio, chairman of the far-right Proud Boys group, received two federal government-backed paycheck protection program (PPP) loans worth a total of $15,500, the Guardian can reveal.
Tarrio, based in Miami, Florida, was approved for an initial loan of $7,750 on 30 March, and a succeeding loan for the same amount on 16 April. The loans were issued to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The hermit kingdom: how a proudly multicultural country became ‘fortress Australia’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/14/the-hermit-kingdom-how-a-proudly-multicultural-country-became-fortress-australia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/14/the-hermit-kingdom-how-a-proudly-multicultural-country-became-fortress-australia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid wreaks havoc overseas Australia risks regressing culturally and economically if borders don’t reopen
Tony Sammartino has no idea when he will next hug his three-year-old daughter, but it’s almost guaranteed it won’t be for another year at the earliest.
“These are the best years of her life, and they should be the best of mine too. And they’re slipping away.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elias Visontay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recipes for Ramadan: Karima Hazim’s warak enab (stuffed vine leaves)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/15/recipes-for-ramadan-karima-hazims-warak-enab-stuffed-vine-leaves</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/15/recipes-for-ramadan-karima-hazims-warak-enab-stuffed-vine-leaves"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This elaborate dish may take hours – and a whole team of hands – to prepare. It’s a bonding experience, with delicious results
Warak enab is to Eid what turkey is to Christmas. For the majority of Muslims from Lebanon and the surrounding Levant, this dish of lamb and stuffed vine leaves traditionally graces the Eid table at the end of Ramadan.
After a month of fasting, the three-day festival of Eid al-Fitr literally means the festival of the breaking of the fast. Warak enab is usually made in such large qua…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karima Hazim for Recipes for Ramadan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s mouse plague: six months ago it was war, now whole towns have accepted their presence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/15/australias-mouse-plague-six-months-ago-it-was-war-now-whole-towns-have-accepted-their-presence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/15/australias-mouse-plague-six-months-ago-it-was-war-now-whole-towns-have-accepted-their-presence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Farmers and residents in NSW and Queensland are still battling surging rodent numbers but they fear the ordeal will stretch on for months
Warning: graphic images may disturb some readers
When the mouse plague began in regional New South Wales and Queensland, residents spoke like generals in a war. It was all about strategy, setting the cleverest traps, fortifying houses to keep the enemy out and outsmarting the tiny creatures as they attacked wave after wave.
But, six months on, with rodent numbers surging …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matilda Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Have a little empathy’: Bali tires of badly behaved foreign influencers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/have-a-little-empathy-bali-tires-of-badly-behaved-foreign-influencers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/have-a-little-empathy-bali-tires-of-badly-behaved-foreign-influencers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tourists threaten the island’s economic recovery by ignoring Covid protocols, including refusing to wear masks and even making a porn film 
A Russian Instagrammer who launched his motorbike off a dock, crashing into the sea. Two YouTube pranksters who fooled a supermarket guard with drawn-on face masks, violating the island’s health rules. A couple allegedly filming porn on a sacred mountain.
Bali has hosted a range of badly behaved influencers during the pandemic. And now it’s had enough.
 Continue reading…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Febriana Firdaus in Ubud</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pauline Tinsley obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/pauline-tinsley-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/pauline-tinsley-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T19:41:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soprano whose commanding presence in Wagner, Verdi and Strauss was better appreciated internationally than in Britain
The soprano Pauline Tinsley, who has died aged 93, was idolised by audiences and critics alike for her peerless performances in a wide range of repertoire, yet was consistently passed over by the operatic establishment.
The blazing intensity of her singing in such roles as Turandot, the Dyer’s Wife in Die Frau ohne Schatten, Elektra or any number of Verdi heroines could be searing and imprin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barry Millington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer appoints northern MP to build bridges with backbenchers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/keir-starmer-appoints-northern-mp-to-build-bridges-with-backbenchers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/keir-starmer-appoints-northern-mp-to-build-bridges-with-backbenchers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T19:24:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sharon Hodgson becomes Labour leader’s new parliamentary aide as he seeks to improve relations with MPs after troubled reshuffle
Keir Starmer has appointed well-respected north-east of England MP Sharon Hodgson as his new parliamentary aide, as he seeks to smooth relations with Labour backbenchers after last weekend’s fraught reshuffle.
Hodgson, the MP for Washington and Sunderland West since 2010, replaces Carolyn Harris, who resigned earlier this week amid claims that she had stoked up tensions between St…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russia officially dubs US and Czech Republic ‘unfriendly’ states]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/russia-us-unfriendly-czech-republic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/russia-us-unfriendly-czech-republic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T19:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government says US missions can no longer hire local staff following law Putin signed last month
The Russian government has officially deemed the United States and the Czech Republic “unfriendly” states, and announced that US diplomatic missions could no longer employ local staff while Czech missions could employ a maximum of 19.
Moscow first announced the ban on the US hiring local staff last month as part of its retaliation for a slew of new US sanctions against Russia for interfering in the 2020 US presi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cameron Bancroft on the ball-tampering scandal: ‘I lost control of my values' | Donald McRae]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/cameron-bancroft-on-the-australia-cricket-ball-tampering-scandal-i-lost-control-of-my-values</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/cameron-bancroft-on-the-australia-cricket-ball-tampering-scandal-i-lost-control-of-my-values"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T19:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As he settles into a new season at Durham, the Australian batsman reflects on how his nine-month suspension for using sandpaper on the ball during a Test match changed his views on life and cricket
Cameron Bancroft is out of quarantine and, after being “brutally cold” on his arrival in Durham last week, the Australian batsman is beginning to thaw out and open up to another season of English county cricket. “I wouldn’t say the mornings have been red-hot,” he says dryly at Durham’s serene Riverside ground, “b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald McRae</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson: going, going, gone – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/14/martin-rowson-going-going-gone-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/14/martin-rowson-going-going-gone-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:45:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buy a copy of this cartoon at our print shop
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/20-photographs-of-the-week-from-around-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/20-photographs-of-the-week-from-around-world"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:38:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The escalating conflict in Gaza and Israel, young migrants on the border between Mexico and the US, protests against the government in Colombia and the enduring impact of Covid-19: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Bashir quits BBC before release of Diana interview inquiry’s report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/martin-bashir-quits-bbc-amid-investigation-into-diana-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/martin-bashir-quits-bbc-amid-investigation-into-diana-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:21:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalist steps down as religion editor on health grounds before publication of investigation
Martin Bashir has quit the BBC on health grounds before the publication of an investigation into his conduct in securing a 1995 Panorama interview with Diana, Princess of Wales. He has been on sick leave for several months.
The BBC’s deputy director of news, Jonathan Munro, told staff: “Martin Bashir has stepped down from his position as the BBC’s religion editor and is leaving the corporation. He let us know of h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India variant could seriously disrupt lifting of lockdown, says Boris Johnson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/india-variant-could-seriously-disrupt-lifting-of-lockdown-says-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/india-variant-could-seriously-disrupt-lifting-of-lockdown-says-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM announces acceleration of Covid vaccine programme, saying race could become a ‘great deal tighter’

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The final stage of the lifting of coronavirus lockdown restrictions across England could face “serious disruption” due to the India variant, the prime minister has warned, as he announced plans to accelerate the vaccine programme to curb its spread.
Boris Johnson said the gap between the first and second Covid jab would be cut from 12 weeks to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti, Nicola Davis, Helen Pidd, Josh Halliday and Libby Brooks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[César Azpilicueta: ‘A bad FA Cup final feeling makes you want to come back’ | Jacob Steinberg]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/cesar-azpilicueta-a-bad-fa-cup-final-feeling-makes-you-want-to-come-back</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/cesar-azpilicueta-a-bad-fa-cup-final-feeling-makes-you-want-to-come-back"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea’s great survivor and captain has been revitalised under Tuchel and wants to make up for last year’s Wembley disaster
“I always had this mentality of being open to new ideas,” César Azpilicueta says. “I never felt that I was fully complete because in my career I played different positions and I always tried to get the most out of them. Also that allowed me to look into players from different parts of the pitch and create different relationships in the team. When you have to change you have to pick up…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘He’s so ready for Test rugby’: the remarkable rise of Marcus Smith]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/marcus-smith-ready-for-test-rugby-union</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/marcus-smith-ready-for-test-rugby-union"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jerry Flannery joins chorus raving about Harlequins fly-half – but will he beat George Ford to the England No 10 spot?
English rugby normally loves a caveat. Player X is potentially great but is his defence good enough? Player Y looks the business but what about his attitude? Which makes it all the more unusual to hear so many hard-bitten former professionals raving about Marcus Smith, the Harlequins fly‑half ripping it up for his club but still awaiting the call to represent his country.
Listen, for instan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brendan Rodgers’ record finally stacks up to the brand he has created | Jonathan Liew]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/brendan-rodgers-leicester-city-chelsea-fa-cup-final</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/brendan-rodgers-leicester-city-chelsea-fa-cup-final"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester’s manager has succumbed to his own hubris before but he now has ample evidence of the success of his methods
A quiz: which of these stories about Brendan Rodgers is true? Story A: when he was a youth-team coach at Chelsea he once tried to cheer up an out-of-form John Terry by commissioning a bespoke motivational poem, which he then had framed. Story B: when his Swansea side won promotion to the Premier League, he celebrated by going off to climb Mount Kilimanjaro with Chris Kamara. Story C: when h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccinate vulnerable global poor before children in rich countries, WHO says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/vaccinate-vulnerable-global-poor-before-rich-children-who-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/vaccinate-vulnerable-global-poor-before-rich-children-who-says"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:59:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus urges developed world to donate Covid vaccines to Covax programme

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The WHO has urged wealthy countries to reconsider plans to vaccinate children against Covid-19 and instead to donate doses to poorer nations, while warning that the pandemic’s second year looks set to be more deadly.
The World Health Organization’s director-general, Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, voiced outrage that a number of rich countries were now vacc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in Geneva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edwin Poots elected DUP leader to succeed Arlene Foster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/edwin-poots-elected-dup-leader-to-succeed-arlene-foster</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/edwin-poots-elected-dup-leader-to-succeed-arlene-foster"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:54:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland agriculture minister and young Earth creationist says someone else will be first minister
Edwin Poots has been elected leader of the Democratic Unionist party (DUP) on the promise of remoulding Northern Ireland’s biggest party and ratcheting up opposition to the Irish Sea border.
On Friday the Stormont agriculture minister narrowly beat Sir Jeffrey Donaldson, a DUP MP, in a two-horse race to succeed Arlene Foster.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll Ireland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palestinians flee as Israel bombards territory from air, sea and land]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/gazans-flee-as-israel-bombards-territory-from-air-sea-and-land</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/gazans-flee-as-israel-bombards-territory-from-air-sea-and-land"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:47:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Escalation triggers violent protests in West Bank and further clashes between Arabs and Jews in Israel
People in Gaza fled their homes carrying crying children and valued possessions as Israeli forces pounded the territory from air, sea and land on Friday.
The escalating conflict triggered violent protests in the occupied West Bank, where seven Palestinians were killed by Israeli army fire, and further violence between Arabs and Jews in Israel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem, Harriet Sherwood and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California woman may have washed $26m lottery fortune down the drain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/california-lottery-ticket-winner-laundry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/14/california-lottery-ticket-winner-laundry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:31:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Norwalk woman believes winning ticket was lost in laundry
Thursday was last day to redeem prize from November draw

The winner of a $26m California lottery prize may have literally washed the chance of a fortune down the drain.
 Related: Shelter releases 1,000 feral cats on to Chicago streets to combat rat crisis 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on intercommunal violence in Israel: a dangerous development with deep roots | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/the-guardian-view-on-intercommunal-violence-in-israel-a-dangerous-development-with-deep-roots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/the-guardian-view-on-intercommunal-violence-in-israel-a-dangerous-development-with-deep-roots"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Political rhetoric has cultivated hatred. Both Palestinian and Jewish citizens are paying the price

The horror unfolding in the Middle East is both old and new. There is a terrible familiarity to the destruction the Israeli state is raining down upon Gaza, and the lethal missiles fired from the Strip by Palestinian militants. Three wars and numerous battles have taught everyone what to expect: indifference to civilian lives on both sides. Already 119 Palestinians are dead, including 27 children, while eigh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dalian Atkinson died an hour after being shot by stun gun, court hears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/dalian-atkinson-died-within-hour-of-being-shot-by-stun-gun-court-hears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/dalian-atkinson-died-within-hour-of-being-shot-by-stun-gun-court-hears"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:29:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GP tells jury of former footballer’s medical history at murder trial of police officer Benjamin Monk
The former footballer Dalian Atkinson was pronounced dead barely an hour after he was shot with a stun gun and kicked in the head by a police officer, a jury heard on Friday.
PC Benjamin Monk denies the murder or manslaughter of Atkinson, 48, on 15 August 2016.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on taking back the buses: a route to recovery | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/the-guardian-view-on-taking-back-the-buses-a-route-to-recovery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/the-guardian-view-on-taking-back-the-buses-a-route-to-recovery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With plans to reassert public, democratic control over bus networks, mayors and ministers are correcting an old unfairness
In 2024, Greater Manchester will reassert public, democratic control over its buses. The new, shortened timetable set out by mayor Andy Burnham following his re-election will make the combined authority, made up of Manchester and nine surrounding councils, the first area in the country to seize hold of powers passed into law in 2017. Private bus operators will, for the first time in dec…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weird dreams train us for the unexpected, says new theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/14/weird-dreams-train-us-for-the-unexpected-says-new-theory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/14/weird-dreams-train-us-for-the-unexpected-says-new-theory"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI inspires hypothesis that sleeping human brain might try to break its overfamiliarity with daily data 
It’s a common enough scenario: you walk into your local supermarket to buy some milk, but by the time you get to the till, the milk bottle has turned into a talking fish. Then you remember you’ve got your GCSE maths exam in the morning, but you haven’t attended a maths lesson for nearly three decades.
Dreams can be bafflingly bizarre, but according to a new theory of why we dream, that’s the whole point.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Development for Beginners – Learn Basic HTML and CSS to Build Your First Web Page]]></title>
        <id>609e8c2162ab9107fe5aa77d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-development-for-beginners-basic-html-and-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:13:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how websites are built and designed? Do you want to learn the art of web development but you're not that tech savvy – yet? Well, then this tutorial is for you. It's an introduction to Web Development for beginners so you can learn the basics even if]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SFO launches inquiry into Gupta firms, including Greensill finance links]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/sfo-launches-inquiry-into-greensill-financing-of-gupta-firms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/sfo-launches-inquiry-into-greensill-financing-of-gupta-firms"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:52:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move to investigate suspected fraud and money laundering prompts collapse of Liberty Steel rescue deal putting 3,000 UK jobs at risk
The Serious Fraud Office has launched an investigation into the financing of Sanjeev Gupta’s metals empire, including its links to Greensill Capital, in a move that immediately caused the collapse of a rescue deal for Liberty Steel and raised fears over thousands of British jobs.
The UK’s anti-corruption agency said it suspected fraud, fraudulent trading and money laundering r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coroner in Ana Uglow inquest will write to schools to raise sepsis awareness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/ana-uglow-bristol-grammar-school-student-death-trip-new-york-coroner-raise-sepsis-awareness</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/ana-uglow-bristol-grammar-school-student-death-trip-new-york-coroner-raise-sepsis-awareness"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:44:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No ‘gross failings’ by teachers found in Bristol Grammar School pupil’s death during school trip to New York
A coroner is to write to all schools to raise awareness of sepsis after a teenager died with the condition during a school history trip to New York.
Ana Uglow, 17, a pupil at Bristol Grammar School, collapsed in a hotel room and was pronounced dead at Mount Sinai West hospital just before Christmas in 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘From a standing fart’: readers on their favourite Grauniad mistakes | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/from-a-standing-fart-readers-on-their-favourite-grauniad-mistakes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/from-a-standing-fart-readers-on-their-favourite-grauniad-mistakes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:44:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers list some of the paper’s most memorable gaffes and typos over the years as the Guardian celebrates its bicentenary
The necessary speed of the production of the paper is part of the reason for Guardian misprints (Typo negative: the best and worst of Grauniad mistakes over 200 years, 12 May), but that does not fully explain why the Grauniad got its name as a happy hunting ground for misprint seekers.
I was told when I joined the paper in 1965 that the Manchester negotiators had blundered when they enc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consumer groups welcome move to ensure finance firms put customers first]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/groups-welcome-plan-to-make-financial-firms-put-customers-first</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/groups-welcome-plan-to-make-financial-firms-put-customers-first"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:39:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mortgages, pensions, investments and loans must have duty to customer, says UK’s financial watchdog
New plans from the City regulator to compel financial firms to act in the best interest of customers have been welcomed by consumer groups.
A new “consumer duty” outlined by the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) will apply to a range of products, including mortgages, credit, pensions and investments, and require firms to consistently focus on the outcomes for their customers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shane Hickey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third of global food production at risk from climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/third-of-global-food-production-at-risk-from-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/third-of-global-food-production-at-risk-from-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:28:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Food-growing areas will see drastic changes to rainfall and temperatures if global heating continues at current rate
A third of global food production will be at risk by the end of the century if greenhouse gas emissions continue to rise at their current rate, new research suggests.
Many of the world’s most important food-growing areas will see temperatures increase and rainfall patterns alter drastically if temperatures rise by about 3.7C, the forecast increase if emissions stay high.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A funfair ride to the end of the world: Heather Phillipson: Rupture No 1 review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/heather-phillipson-rupture-no-1-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/heather-phillipson-rupture-no-1-review"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:19:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tate Britain, London
Resistance is futile in the sumptuous colours of Phillipson’s entertaining apocalypse, filled with colossal metal creatures, agitated animal eyes and a giant celestial peach
Animal cries, a howling wind, the distant calls of a flock of swans and a gurgling of buffalo at the water hole fill the length of the Duveen Galleries at Tate Britain. Heather Phillipson is at it again in her delayed 2021 Duveen commission, opening, along with the rest of the gallery, on Monday. A funfair ride to t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Searle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why China investment in Inter brings urgent need to scrutinise owners | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/14/china-investment-inter-scrutinise-owners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/14/china-investment-inter-scrutinise-owners"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:12:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the Italian parliament debates whether Italy should formally recognise that China is guilty of genocide on its Uyghur citizens, the Chinese state is a part-owner of the Scudetto champions
You might think Liverpool have had an underwhelming Premier League title defence. The mid-season collapse. The failed attempt to join a Super League. The strangely maudlin video address from the club’s owner, delivered in the style of a baffled senior executive apologising for an involuntary bladder malfunction at the c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Once this violence in Israel and Gaza ends, there can be no return to 'normal' | Jonathan Freedland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/violence-israel-gaza-bloodshed-palestinians</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/violence-israel-gaza-bloodshed-palestinians"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:07:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cycle of bloodshed will repeat, so long as the status quo remains comfortable for everyone except ordinary Palestinians
If Groundhog Day were a horror movie, it would look like this. The deadly violence shaking the Middle East – Israeli airstrikes on Gaza, Hamas rocket attacks on Israel – seems to play out the same way, again and again, as if on some macabre repeat cycle. We saw it in 2009 and we saw it again in 2014. Each element is familiar: the lopsided death toll, Palestinian deaths outnumbering Isr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Freedland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Zoom could help older people avoid dementia, study reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/using-zoom-could-help-older-people-avoid-dementia-study-reveals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/using-zoom-could-help-older-people-avoid-dementia-study-reveals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:02:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who communicate online alongside traditional methods show less of a decline in episodic memory
Defiant in the face of Covid isolation, older people across the country ventured online, often for the first time, and mastered technology: reading bedtime stories to grandchildren over Zoom and holding book clubs on Microsoft Teams.
Now a UK study has shown that their determination to access and enjoy the internet’s social possibilities could have had another advantage: protecting them against dementia.
 Co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Hill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can be proud of the Home Office I lead | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/we-can-be-proud-of-the-home-office-i-lead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/we-can-be-proud-of-the-home-office-i-lead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Permanent secretary Matthew Rycroft responds to an article about his government department
Your characterisation of the Home Office (Cruel, paranoid, failing: inside the Home Office, 13 May) does not match my experience during the year I have led it. 
I have found a group of people committed to public service, determined to have a positive impact and focused on doing the right thing. Everyone at the Home Office acknowledges the wrongs and injustices of the past. We feel these every day and are determined to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Labour MP admits he wanted sexual relationship with aide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/ex-labour-mp-mike-hill-admits-he-wanted-sexual-relationship-with-aide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/ex-labour-mp-mike-hill-admits-he-wanted-sexual-relationship-with-aide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T15:55:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Hill is questioned at tribunal over text messages he sent to parliamentary staff member
A married former Labour MP has admitted having wanted a sexual relationship with a parliamentary staff member and getting into her bed after she had rejected his sexual advances.
Mike Hill, who represented Hartlepool until March, texted the woman, known only as Ms A, saying he was in love with her, “craved” her body, and describing himself as “emotionally fucked”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Latitude to Lady Gaga: what to see as music venues and festivals reopen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/from-latitude-to-lady-gaga-what-to-see-as-music-venues-and-festivals-reopen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/from-latitude-to-lady-gaga-what-to-see-as-music-venues-and-festivals-reopen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T15:39:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As live music returns, we pick the best artists launching post-lockdown tours and festival dates – with the Eagles, Beck and Bloodstock leading the charge 

More events to enjoy: Art | Classical 

The latest entrants in the shouty sprechgesang vocals/post-post punk music field – also home to Black Midi and Black Country, New Road – Brighton-based Squid take the spiky, Krautrock-y, occasionally jazz-influenced sound of their acclaimed debut album, Bright Green Field, on the road. 
Tour begins Silver Building…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Petridis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iranian asylum seeker cleared of Channel smuggling charges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/iranian-asylum-seeker-cleared-of-channel-smuggling-charges</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/iranian-asylum-seeker-cleared-of-channel-smuggling-charges"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T15:25:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Man who took turn steering boat ‘because he didn’t want to die’ freed, with case opening way for others to appeal their sentences

An asylum seeker jailed on smuggling charges for helping to steer a boat filled with migrants from France to England has had his conviction overturned at a retrial after spending 17 months in jail.
Lawyers and campaigners say the verdict could lead to other migrants currently in jail on smuggling charges being freed, allowing the Home Office policy of prosecuting asylum seekers …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Grant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crying about hamburgers is dead-end on climate crisis, Republicans warned]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/republicans-climate-crisis-trump-peter-meijer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/republicans-climate-crisis-trump-peter-meijer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T15:17:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congressman Peter Meijer, 33, warns that false claims of a burger ban or blaming immigrants risk losing the young generation
Lies that hamburgers will be banned, conspiracy-laden claims of government tyranny, blame for environmental degradation foisted upon immigrants – the Republican response to Joe Biden’s climate agenda suggests the base instincts of Donald Trump still strongly animate the party.
 Related: Asia is home to 99 of world’s 100 most vulnerable cities 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eight things you may not know about the Faroe Islands]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/14/eight-things-you-may-not-know-about-the-faroe-islands</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/14/eight-things-you-may-not-know-about-the-faroe-islands"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the green list and with direct flights from Edinburgh starting in July, the dramatic archipelago is again on the tourist radar
The Faroese language is close to Icelandic, with its own alphabet of 29 letters including the slightly confusing ð (edd), which is almost always silent but occurs in many words. Watch out for words beginning with “hv”, which sounds more like “kv”, and “sk” which is more like “sh”. Oh, and there are three genders and four cases, so for English speakers the grammar can be challengi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Ecott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The therapy has never waned’: Guardian readers on their long relationships with us | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:55:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don Borland on how the paper helped him recover from TB, plus letters from Peter Bird, Elizabeth Jurd, Elizabeth Monger, Graham Head, John Boyle, Andrew Dean, Chas Ball, Tony Meacock, Janet Hulme and Robert Daws
In 1953, at the age of 16, I caught tuberculosis. I was in a sanatorium for 18 months. Antibiotics were new and bed rest and lots of fresh air were de rigueur. So I passed the summer of 1953 in a two-bed cubicle in the company of a 17-year-old mate, open to the lawn and trees before us, the stable d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A special day’: how a Glasgow community halted immigration raid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/a-special-day-how-glasgow-community-halted-immigration-raid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/a-special-day-how-glasgow-community-halted-immigration-raid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:51:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activists and local people tell how they forced the release of two men detained in an enforcement van
It was just after 9am on Thursday and he was finishing breakfast when the callout came. Kenmure Street’s “Van Man” – the activist who spent nearly eight hours squeezed underneath an immigration enforcement van to prevent the detention of two men on Glasgow’s southside – was on his bike in minutes.
“It’s not often you can catch raids in the act like this, but the southside has a lot of folks pulling together…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Angela Rayner came out on top after spat with Starmer over reshuffle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/angela-rayner-comes-out-on-top-after-spat-with-keir-starmer-labour-reshuffle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/angela-rayner-comes-out-on-top-after-spat-with-keir-starmer-labour-reshuffle"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:44:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour deputy leader has shown she has a significant power base and is not shy of using it
Joe Biden and his vice-president, Kamala Harris, have a standing weekly date for a private one-to-one lunch, just as Biden did with Barack Obama.
Breaking bread is one way of keeping a political relationship on track. No wonder, perhaps, that Keir Starmer and Angela Rayner have decided to give it a go as they attempt to rebuild their relationship.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart and Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Austrian chancellor’s future in doubt over ‘Ibizagate’ lying claim]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/austria-chancellor-sebastian-kurz-political-future-in-doubt-over-lying-allegation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/austria-chancellor-sebastian-kurz-political-future-in-doubt-over-lying-allegation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:41:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-corruption prosecutor alleges Sebastian Kurz deliberately misled MPs investigating scandal
The political future of Austria’s high-flying chancellor, Sebastian Kurz, is in question after it emerged that he is being investigated for lying to a parliamentary committee during the “Ibizagate” affair.
In a 58-page criminal investigation cited by Austrian media, the country’s anti-corruption prosecutor alleges Kurz deliberately misled MPs trying to shed light on the entanglement of political and commercial in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we know about the Indian Covid variant so far | Julian Tang]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/indian-covid-variant-vaccines-strain-data</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/indian-covid-variant-vaccines-strain-data"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:41:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The good news is, we think existing vaccines will protect us against this rapidly spreading strain. But we need more data

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The new variant of the Covid-19 virus first detected in India comes in three forms: B.1.617.1 (abbreviated as variant 1), B.1.617.2 (variant 2) and B.1.617.3 (variant 3). Each of these has a slightly different genetic makeup. The one that is surging in England is variant 2.
There is some good news and bad news about this var…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wales to launch pilot universal basic income scheme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/wales-to-launch-universal-basic-income-pilot-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/wales-to-launch-universal-basic-income-pilot-scheme"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:38:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners hail ‘huge moment’ as first minister commits to trials of payments to cover living costs
A pilot universal basic income (UBI) scheme is to be launched in Wales, the first minister, Mark Drakeford, has revealed.
The new minister for social justice, Jane Hutt, a close ally of Drakeford’s, will be asked to work on the pilot.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cornwall ‘beach school’ aims to offer hope for vulnerable children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/wave-project-cornwall-beach-school-vulnerable-children-risk-excluded</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/wave-project-cornwall-beach-school-vulnerable-children-risk-excluded"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wave Project charity plans purpose-built facility for Cornish children at risk of being permanently excluded
It will not look or feel much like a conventional school. Built around a central garden, the main classroom will be the great outdoors: the surf, the dunes, the rock pools. The only uniforms will be wetsuits and, on chilly days, students will love hopping into the hot tub.
Plans for what is being billed as the world’s first purpose-built “beach school” will be presented to the public this weekend on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hostile UK border regime traumatises visitors from EU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/hostile-uk-border-regime-traumatises-visitors-from-eu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/hostile-uk-border-regime-traumatises-visitors-from-eu"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:22:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Italian woman visiting family was locked up in detention centre as they waited at the airport, Guardian told

EU citizens arriving in UK being locked up and expelled

Britain’s hostile regime for potential EU migrants is traumatising visitors caught in its web and provoking further worries for European families receiving visits from relatives, according to accounts provided to the Guardian.
The slightest suspicion that someone may be entering Britain to work is often enough for them to be locked up, held at…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Tremlett in Madrid and Lisa O'Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line &#8230;
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It&#8217;s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about &#8230;
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My husband wants a threesome. I don’t. What can I do?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/my-husband-wants-a-threesome-i-dont-annalisa-barbieri</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/my-husband-wants-a-threesome-i-dont-annalisa-barbieri"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m guessing it’s with a partner who suits him, rather than you, says Annalisa Barbieri. Remember what you want matters, too
I’ve been married for 11 years and we have two happy boys; it has been amazing. But my husband has now told me he wants a threesome. I am really trying to understand what it is that he is seeking; after a week of long conversations, I believe what he actually wants is more experiences. He says he doesn’t want to leave me and the boys, and still loves us a lot.
He was 22 when we got ma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annalisa Barbieri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK tourists can enter Portugal from Monday as Covid restrictions end]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/uk-tourists-can-enter-portugal-from-monday-as-covid-restriction-ends</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/uk-tourists-can-enter-portugal-from-monday-as-covid-restriction-ends"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:50:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit Portugal says anyone entering the country will have to have an RT-PCR test 72 hours before departure

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Portugal is to reopen to British visitors with negative PCR test results on Monday, despite the government extending a nationwide state of emergency until the end of the month as the country continues to recover from a third wave of the coronavirus pandemic.
The announcement came a week after the UK government added Portugal to the “green …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid, Mia Alberti in Faro, and Lorenzo Tondo in Palermo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you been affected by UK high street banks shutting down?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-uk-high-street-banks-shutting-down</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/14/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-uk-high-street-banks-shutting-down"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:31:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bank branches are closing down at an alarming rate in the UK. We would like to know how people who are reliant on these branches have been affected
Banks are being closed down at an alarming rate. More than a third of the UK’s bank branches have shut for good in less than five years, while hundreds of those that remain have reduced their opening hours.
We would like to find out how this affects people from across the community. Perhaps you dislike using online banking or are unable to use a computer? Or per…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-pandemic I embraced personal space. Now I want to keep friends close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/pre-pandemic-i-embraced-personal-space-now-i-want-to-keep-friends-close</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/pre-pandemic-i-embraced-personal-space-now-i-want-to-keep-friends-close"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:22:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown brought relief at being able to skip unwanted hugs ... until I craved connection

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Pre-pandemic, I didn’t really distinguish between a hug from a loved one and a bodily restraint. My reluctance to be embraced was well known to friends and family, and immediately obvious to anyone who tried.
“You stood as far away as a person can stand from another person, while in physical contact with them,” a boyfriend once said of our first date.
 Con…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elle Hunt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s county court judgment actually made me feel sorry for him | Zoe Williams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/boris-johnsons-county-court-judgment-actually-made-me-feel-sorry-for-him</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/boris-johnsons-county-court-judgment-actually-made-me-feel-sorry-for-him"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:07:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister’s alleged £535 debt could have affected every aspect of his financial life. I discovered that the hard way a long time ago
It was a piece of singular brilliance from Private Eye to do a speculative search on county court judgments (CCJs) and see if the prime minister’s name turned up. Imagine the delight in the office when there it was, as recent as last October, with “10 Downing Street” as the address, for an unpaid amount – to an unknown creditor – of £535. It was too good (and we all k…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sightings and social media spark British whale-watching boom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/sightings-and-social-media-spark-british-whale-watching-boom</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/sightings-and-social-media-spark-british-whale-watching-boom"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:02:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marine life charities and wildlife tour operators observe growing interest in and empathy for whales
When a sick baby minke whale lost its way up the Thames earlier this week, hundreds of people gathered to watch the rescue efforts at Richmond and Teddington over the course of two days.
It was the furthest upriver a whale had ever ventured, a feat so out of the ordinary that the curiosity among the crowds flocking to the weir and those following the whale’s misguided journey on social media was matched by t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lorelei Mathias: ‘Having an ADHD brain is like having a room full of hecklers in your head’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/14/lorelei-mathias-funniest-thing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/14/lorelei-mathias-funniest-thing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The comedy writer, producer and director on the things that make her laugh the most

A very early Paul Foot gig where he entered and exited the stage by climbing in and out of a window. It was surreal, awkward and belly laugh-inducing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A pint and a madras in a hurricane: is this my first trip to the pub or an endurance event? | Romesh Ranganathan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/pint-madras-hurricane-pub-endurance-event-romesh-ranganathan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/pint-madras-hurricane-pub-endurance-event-romesh-ranganathan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We couldn’t hear each other because of the 40mph winds and spent most of the night trying to pin down flyaway poppadoms
I have made my first visit to a pub since Lockdown 3: The Lockening was announced. A lot of people I know have been talking longingly about the taste of that first proper pint, and I would have been, too, had I not succumbed to buying my own worktop draught beer pump in order to replicate the authentic boozer experience at home.
I have really enjoyed my home pub, although it does feel a li…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Romesh Ranganathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hankering for a hug? Here’s a guide to post-lockdown greetings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/hankering-for-a-hug-heres-a-guide-to-post-lockdown-greetings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/hankering-for-a-hug-heres-a-guide-to-post-lockdown-greetings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:59:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re not ready to hug your neighbour, how about a safer elbow rub, air kiss or cruise tap?

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Are you hankering for a hug, or horrified at the prospect of physical closeness? From Monday, people in England will officially be allowed to touch each other again. After a year of fist bumps, elbow rubs and hails across garden walls, it feels like a symbolic step back towards normality.
Yet with the spread of new variants, increasing coronavirus ca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rights group fear for migrant activist ‘disappeared’ in Qatar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/rights-group-fear-for-migrant-activist-detained-qatar</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/14/rights-group-fear-for-migrant-activist-detained-qatar"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:54:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Malcolm Bidali, a Kenyan who blogged about migrant workers’ plight, detained by Qatari security services
A Kenyan security guard in Qatar who has written about the plight of migrant workers has been “forcibly disappeared”, human rights group say.
Malcolm Bidali was detained by the Qatari security services over a week ago and is being held in an undisclosed location, according to a coalition of rights groups, which include Amnesty International and Human Rights Watch.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pete Pattisson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Would-be dog owners told to think twice before buying flat-faced breeds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/would-be-dog-owners-told-to-think-twice-before-buying-flat-faced-breeds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/would-be-dog-owners-told-to-think-twice-before-buying-flat-faced-breeds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:31:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Brachycephalic breeds prone to health issues and may fuel crime, experts say as registrations soar
Experts have urged would-be dog owners to reconsider buying squashed-faced animals such as French bulldogs, warning they are prone to life-limiting health conditions, and that buying such breeds could fuel criminal activity.
The pandemic has triggered a boom in dog ownership with Kennel Club figures revealing there has been a 12% rise in puppy registrations in the past year alone.
 Continue reading.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis  Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK insists Cop26 must be held in person if possible]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/uk-will-vaccinate-and-test-to-ensure-cop26-is-in-person-event</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/uk-will-vaccinate-and-test-to-ensure-cop26-is-in-person-event"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:22:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alok Sharma is working with health experts and Scottish government on best way for climate summit to go ahead

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The UK government is considering how to use Covid-19 vaccines and testing to try to ensure vital UN climate talks this year go ahead in person, rather than as an online event.
Alok Sharma, a former UK business secretary and now president-designate of Cop26, the climate summit to be held in Glasgow this November, said: “I have always bee…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chess: American 12-year-old closes in on world record for youngest grandmaster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/chess-american-12-year-old-closes-in-on-world-record-for-youngest-grandmaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/14/chess-american-12-year-old-closes-in-on-world-record-for-youngest-grandmaster"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abhimanyu Mishra poised to break Sergey Karjakin’s mark of 12 years seven months despite going six months without playing in a tournament due to Covid-19
One of the most enduring chess records, Sergey Karjakin as the youngest grandmaster ever at 12 years and seven months, looks set to fall in the next few weeks. Abhimanyu Mishra, from New Jersey, US, is already the youngest ever international master, at 10, and has just achieved two of the three required GM norms for the higher title.
 Related: Garry Kaspar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonard Barden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unite leadership candidate reiterates apology for Patel deportation remark]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/unite-leadership-candidate-howard-beckett-reiterates-apology-for-patel-deportation-remark</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/unite-leadership-candidate-howard-beckett-reiterates-apology-for-patel-deportation-remark"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Howard Beckett, who is also a member of Labour’s national executive committee, has been suspended from the party
Howard Beckett has reiterated his apology for saying Priti Patel should be deported after he was suspended from the Labour party, with the nominee to lead the Unite union saying some people had read a tweet he sent too literally.
Beckett, who is also a member of Labour’s national executive committee, was suspended on Thursday after sending a tweet in response to an attempt to deport two asylum se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cameron's clever defence: that he can't do a proper job after leaving office either | Marina Hyde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/cameron-job-office-greensill-scandal-spellchecker</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/cameron-job-office-greensill-scandal-spellchecker"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:17:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[His plea over the Greensill scandal seems to be that he’s a standup guy made to look like a chancer by a spellchecker

Hauled before two select committees to answer for his Greensill lobbying role, David Cameron yesterday claimed his text to the Treasury mentioning a “rate cut” might in fact have meant to say “VAT cut”. As the former prime minister put it: “I think I’m a victim of spellcheck here.” A what now? Still, you’ll have nothing but respect for this excuse, which is basically: “I fear that I, a stan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Hyde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour MP Wes Streeting diagnosed with kidney cancer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/labour-mp-wes-streeting-diagnosed-with-kidney-cancer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/14/labour-mp-wes-streeting-diagnosed-with-kidney-cancer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MP for Ilford North, 38, says news came as ‘enormous shock’ but that he should make full recovery
Labour’s shadow child poverty secretary, Wes Streeting, is to step back from frontline politics for a period to have treatment for kidney cancer, he has announced.
The Ilford North MP, 38, whom Keir Starmer moved into the shadow cabinet role days ago as part of the party’s frontbench reshuffle, said the prognosis was good because the cancer had been detected early, but that the diagnosis was “an enormous shock”…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young Ugandans are being brutally oppressed. They must be allowed a voice | Bobi Wine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/ugandans-oppressed-museveni-government-bobi-wine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/14/ugandans-oppressed-museveni-government-bobi-wine"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T12:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All forms of political opposition here are met with crackdowns from President Museveni’s government


Bobi Wine is leader of the National Unity Platform

Uganda is experiencing its worst wave of political oppression in decades. Hundreds, possibly thousands, of supporters of opposition parties to President General Yoweri Museveni have been abducted, detained and tortured in recent months. Like many, I bear the scars of the baton, have felt the sting of teargas and endured unlawful detention. But I know that …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bobi Wine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A football protest and a lightning strike: Friday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/14/football-protest-lightning-strike-friday-best-photos-around-world-guardian-picture-editors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/14/football-protest-lightning-strike-friday-best-photos-around-world-guardian-picture-editors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T11:50:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scentsational! The 15 best flowers to plant now for a beautifully aromatic garden]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/scentsational-the-15-best-flowers-to-plant-now-for-a-beautifully-aromatic-garden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/scentsational-the-15-best-flowers-to-plant-now-for-a-beautifully-aromatic-garden"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T11:29:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can fill your garden with the familiar scent of roses – as well as plants that smell of almond, candyfloss and even chocolate
Gardens should be a treat for the nose as well as a feast for the eyes. Choose the right plants and your plot can offer up wafts of perfume all year round, thanks to aromatic foliage and scented flowers. Here are 15 of the best to plant this month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jane Perrone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digested week: the one with a reason to thank David Cameron | Lucy Mangan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/digested-week-the-one-with-a-reason-to-thank-david-cameron-friends</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/digested-week-the-one-with-a-reason-to-thank-david-cameron-friends"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T11:02:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Friends will be there for you, unless you’re a former PM calling and texting them with increasing desperation
I do not own a passport, because I do not like to travel and my professional life for the last 18 years has required me only to make my way upstairs to my study, which involves standing on much Lego and Transformer parts but no border crossings.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘She has a skill you can’t buy’: the making of Chelsea’s Emma Hayes | Suzanne Wrack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/the-making-of-chelsea-manager-emma-hayes-champions-league-final</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/14/the-making-of-chelsea-manager-emma-hayes-champions-league-final"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T11:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager left England with a one-way ticket and $1,000 to pursue her dream. On Sunday she takes charge in a Champions League final
“When did I recognise that she was any good in her business?” says Sid Hayes, the 80-year-old father of Chelsea’s manager, Emma Hayes. “I’m going to tell you a story about the London Olympics.”
As Hayes sat next to her dad at Wembley for the Olympic women’s football final, she was to all intents and purposes unemployed. “There was the ceremony on the pitch where the three teams […]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suzanne Wrack</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Chase’s Anne Hegerty: ‘As a child I thought: one day I’ll be famous, then they’ll be sorry’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/14/the-chase-anne-hegerty-fame-feminism-aspergers-im-a-celebrity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/14/the-chase-anne-hegerty-fame-feminism-aspergers-im-a-celebrity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T11:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little more than a decade ago, she was out of work and in debt. Now, ‘the Governess’ is one of Britain’s most famous quizzers. She talks about fame, feminism, Asperger’s and I’m a Celebrity
Rock bottom, for Anne Hegerty, came some time in 2008. Her work – as a freelance copy editor and proofreader – had dried up. “I had become completely undependable,” she says. “Publishing books, you need people to hit the deadline. I wasn’t doing that, so understandably people weren’t giving me work any more.”
She had b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Wollaston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WhatsApp to force users to accept changes to terms of service]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/14/whatsapp-to-force-users-to-accept-changes-to-terms-of-service</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/14/whatsapp-to-force-users-to-accept-changes-to-terms-of-service"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:56:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial changes aim to allow small firms to upload catalogues and let users buy without leaving the app

WhatsApp’s new terms of service: what you need to know

On Saturday, WhatsApp will finally begin to force users to accept its controversial new terms of service, almost half a year after it first announced plans to do so.
Despite an immediate backlash from users, millions of sign-ups to rival messaging firms, and even questions asked in the House of Commons, WhatsApp has pushed ahead with the new r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nine-year-old killed by lightning ‘saved three others’ donating organs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/nine-year-old-killed-by-lightning-saved-three-others-donating-organs-jordan-banks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/nine-year-old-killed-by-lightning-saved-three-others-donating-organs-jordan-banks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:45:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Father of Blackpool’s Jordan Banks pays tribute to ‘little best mate’ who always wanted to help others

The father of Jordan Banks, the nine-year-old boy who died after being struck by lightning, has said his son has saved the lives of three other children by donating his organs.
Paying tribute to his son in a Facebook post, Matt Banks said: “Jordan was and is the most amazing little person he had the biggest heart and would do anything for anyone … Even now his kindness has meant that three other children …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comical, cartoonish, wonky-nostrilled brilliance – Jean Dubuffet: Brutal Beauty review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/comical-cartoonish-wonky-nostrilled-brilliance-jean-dubuffet-brutal-beauty-review-barbican-art-brut</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/comical-cartoonish-wonky-nostrilled-brilliance-jean-dubuffet-brutal-beauty-review-barbican-art-brut"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:39:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barbican, London
With his galumphing caricatures, spurting paint and quivering doodles, the art brut master caught the hectic rhythm of the postwar world – and his street scenes make you want to jump right in
Grinning and bald, Jean Dubuffet leans comically over one of his little sculptures, a frangible little figure that looks like almost nothing at all. Here he is again, in one of the many photos of the artist that punctuate the Barbican’s exhibition, sitting in his studio surrounded by his painters’ para…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Searle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Beavers are just being beavers’: friction grows between Canadians and animals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/canada-beaver-population-problems</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/14/canada-beaver-population-problems"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:15:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beavers cause internet outages, steal posts and even put 30 sq km of a town underwater – but experts say the animals have a profound effect on ecosystems
At first, the theft of wooden fence posts seemed like a crime of opportunity – amid soaring lumber costs, stacks of wood have gone missing from construction sites across North America.
But officers in the Canadian prairie community of Porcupine Plain, Saskatchewan, soon identified the culprit: local beavers had stolen the posts to build their dam.
 Continu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what are your experiences of access on the street as a disabled person?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/tell-us-what-are-your-experiences-of-access-on-the-street-as-a-disabled-person</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/14/tell-us-what-are-your-experiences-of-access-on-the-street-as-a-disabled-person"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:59:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pavements and streets in the UK have become more crowded since the coronavirus restrictions lifted. Has this made them more difficult for you to navigate them?
Since the easing of lockdown last month, pavements and streets across the UK have filled up with people enjoying outside drinking and dining.
We’d like to find out whether reduced access to some streets has had any impact for some disabled people, with wheelchair users and those with visual impairments finding it especially difficult to navigate bloc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shoephoria! The history of footwear – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/14/shoephoria-the-history-footwear-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/14/shoephoria-the-history-footwear-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shoephoria! at the Fashion Museum in Bath showcases 350 pairs of boots and shoes to illustrate their evolution over the last 300 years, demonstrating the creativity and style of shoemakers and wearers

Shoephoria! exhibition to open at Fashion Museum in Bath
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week two]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first of the six stories was reprinted in the Guardian last Friday (7 May). The second is below, with the other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heart singer Ann Wilson: ‘Success was a Faustian bargain we made’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/heart-singer-ann-wilson-success-was-a-faustian-bargain-we-made</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/14/heart-singer-ann-wilson-success-was-a-faustian-bargain-we-made"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the trailblazing band approach their 50th anniversary, Wilson recalls the misery of fame, Heart’s underrated male members and finally realising her creative ambitions as a solo artist

Ann Wilson vividly remembers Heart’s big break. In October 1975, the fledgling group, then based in Vancouver, were offered their biggest show to date, opening for Rod Stewart at a Montreal arena. Heart happened to be available – in fact, they had just been fired from a Calgary club gig – and were eager to drum up support …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annie Zaleski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience: I’m allergic to water]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/experience-im-allergic-to-water</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/14/experience-im-allergic-to-water"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I shower, I feel a tingling. Then it progresses to a gnawing, itching feeling, as if there was something chewing on the inside of my skin
I loved swimming when I was a child. I would go to the pool every week and could be in there for hours. But when I was about 12, I noticed a change. After being in water, I felt itchy. Initially, it was just one of those things you don’t think about, but it got worse throughout my teens, to the point where it was more like a nettle rash, along with itching and burnin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Warwick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japan’s senior cheer-dancing squad – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/japans-senior-cheer-dancing-squad-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/japans-senior-cheer-dancing-squad-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T08:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Japan Pom Pom started with five people 26 years ago and now has 17 active members, all older than 55, who passed auditions to join
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>All pictures by Kim Kyung-Hoon/Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blackstock Road: the world on my doorstep – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/blackstock-road-the-world-on-my-doorstep-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/blackstock-road-the-world-on-my-doorstep-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T06:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Timothy Spurr has been a lifelong resident of Finsbury Park, north London. His work Blackstock Road focuses on food and the environments in which it is served, and examines the stories of independent family businesses of the multi-ethnic community in the area, celebrating the fruits of London’s diversity
Many years later, while sitting at my parents’ home during the first national lockdown of the coronavirus pandemic, I would remember the late afternoons in school uniform, returning to Blacksto…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timothy Spurr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Bristol does things differently’: Green party emerges as city’s rising force]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/bristol-does-things-differently-green-party-emerges-as-citys-rising-force</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/14/bristol-does-things-differently-green-party-emerges-as-citys-rising-force"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T05:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Success in the local council elections has raised the party’s hopes of a parliamentary seat
Four days on from one of the most eye-catching results in England’s local council elections, Yassin Mohamud, the new Green member for the Bristol inner city ward of Lawrence Hill, still has to stop every few minutes to accept the congratulations of residents, neighbours, shopkeepers and taxi drivers when he walks down to the shops.
“It’s very exciting,” said Mohamud. “I can’t wait to get on with the job. This area ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Israel and Palestine on the brink of another war?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, discusses what has prompted the worst unrest in Israel and Palestine since 2014
Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, talks to Rachel Humphreys about the violence that has broken out between Israel and Palestine. In recent weeks there has been a sharp escalation in anger over Israel’s half-century occupation, its ever-deepening military grip over Palestinian life and a wave of evictions and demolitions. In Jerusalem, hundreds of Palesti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Oliver Holmes, produced by Ned Carter Miles and Axel Kacoutié, executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and&#160;released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a&#160;basic grid inspector 
&#8230;
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340573</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2021-design-systems-survey-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T22:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friends at Sparkbox are doing a survey on design systems, as they do each year. Go ahead and fill it out if you please. Here are the results from last year. In both 2019 and 2020, the vibe was &#8230;
The post 2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create an Email Newsletter [2021 Tutorial] – Design, Layout, Send]]></title>
        <id>609414f32cd0545b5e943526</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-an-email-newsletter-design-layout-send/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T21:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you manage a large community, chances are you need a way to communicate updates to your members quickly and efficiently. An email newsletter can be a very effective way to do so. In this article, I am going to provide some tips and suggestions for maximizing the impact and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eid al-Fitr celebrations around the world – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/13/eid-al-fitr-celebrations-around-the-world-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/13/eid-al-fitr-celebrations-around-the-world-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T20:05:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around the world, Eid al-Fitr celebrations have been taking place in another unprecedented year. With the uneven distribution of Covid-19 vaccines, Muslims in countries like the US and UK have been able to gather en masse for the first time in over a year and celebrate the end of Ramadan. Meanwhile, across Asia, some ceremonies have been more muted and somber, as families continue to lose members to the virus. 
Adding to the complex emotions amid this year’s celebration, Muslim communities have been demonst…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Software Testing? The 10 Most Common Types of Tests Developers Use in Projects]]></title>
        <id>609952396008950828b3ea8d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/types-of-software-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T19:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development and testing go hand in hand. And in the era of agile software development, with quick releases of small iterations, you should do testing more and more frequently.  In order to perform effective testing, you need to know about the different types of testing and when you should]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Tutorial – How to Work with Multiple Checkboxes]]></title>
        <id>609bcc6a62ab9107fe5a9f08</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-work-with-multiple-checkboxes-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T18:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handling multiple checkboxes in React is completely different from how you use regular HTML checkboxes. So in this article, we'll see how to work with multiple checkboxes in React. You will learn: How to use a checkbox as a Controlled Input in ReactHow to use the array map and reduce]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Lawyer to Engineer at Google – How to Switch Careers and Learn New Skills]]></title>
        <id>609ccb0d62ab9107fe5aa0ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/from-lawyer-to-google-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T16:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was a corporate lawyer for 12 years. I never thought I'd be working at Google as a software engineer, but now I am. And I'm going to share with you ten important lessons I learned during this career transition. I finished law school in Bangalore, India, a year before]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340036</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/advanced-css-animation-using-cubic-bezier/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with complex CSS animations, there is a tendency to create expansive @keyframes with lots of declarations. There are a couple of tricks though that I want to talk about that might help make things easier, while staying in &#8230;
The post Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340118</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svgator-3-0-reshapes-the-way-you-create-and-animate-svg-with-extensive-new-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building animations can get complicated, particularly compelling animations where you aren&#8217;t just rolling a ball across the screen, but building a scene where many things are moving and changing in concert. When compelling animation is the goal, a timeline GUI &#8230;
The post SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar pushback: how US power firms try to make people pay for going green]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/13/solar-power-us-utility-companies-kansas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/13/solar-power-us-utility-companies-kansas"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T11:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In states like Kansas, energy companies want to impose charges on people who produce their own power with rooftop arrays
Kevin Good is the president of a small solar power company in Kansas – a state that tends to be so sunny you’d think he’d have it made.
“I got into solar at maybe the worst point to do so in the last 50 years,” said Good, who runs Good Energy Solutions in Lawrence, a town of about 100,000.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haines Eason for the New Territory and Emily Holden for Floodlight</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['They saw me as mad and needing to be medicated’ | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T10:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, journalist Iman Amrani speaks to Chris, who after being diagnosed with schizophrenia spent a long time in the mental health system. They discuss medication, frustration at the system, and the importance of being listened to and heard. Dr Rufus May, a clinical psychologist, speaks about how he worked with Chris and other patients to show compassion and empathy, and how this can help people with mental health issues navigate society

Watch other episodes of Modern Mascul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Mat Heywood, Kyri Evangelou, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making a splash: the best – and funniest – Guardian headlines over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/13/guardian-200-making-a-splash-the-best-and-funniest-headlines-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/13/guardian-200-making-a-splash-the-best-and-funniest-headlines-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T06:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Witty, pithy, pretty and hitty, sometimes the headline is better than the story it sits upon

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

It’s late. It always is. Just 10 minutes until the front page has to be sent for printing. And above the main story, the splash, hangs a big white space, awaiting inspiration.
The story: Donald Trump’s fractious state visit to the UK in 2019. The words are on the page, but the most impor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is the UK slashing its international aid budget? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s government has blamed the Covid crisis for its decision to cut its international aid budget, but is there more to it?
When David Cameron rose to become Conservative party leader, he set about identifying totemic policies that would show his party was changing. As well as promoting new thinking on the environment, he made an effort to highlight his commitment to overseas aid. When he was prime minister, his government signed a target of spending 0.7% of national income on foreign aid into law…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Patrick Wintour; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build and Deploy a Portfolio with Vue.js Axios, the GitHub REST API, and Netlify]]></title>
        <id>5fde208ae6787e09839407c3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-portfolio-with-vuejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T20:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this free book, we will build two simple projects and deploy them on Netlify. We will use Vue.js as our front-end framework, and use different technologies to build our projects.  If you follow this tutorial to the end, you will build a simplified version of Twitter and a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use the Kivy Python Library to Create Games and Mobile Apps]]></title>
        <id>609c215862ab9107fe5a9fa9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-the-kivy-python-library-to-create-games-and-mobile-apps/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T18:49:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kivy is a free and open source Python framework for developing mobile apps and games with a natural user interface. We just released a 5-hour Kivy course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. In this Kivy course, you will learn to create games and applications with Python for every platform]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339960</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-disabled-buttons-more-inclusive/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T14:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about disabled buttons. Specifically, let’s get into why we use them and how we can do better than the traditional disabled attribute in HTML (e.g. &#60;button disabled&#62; ) to mark a button as disabled.
There are lots of &#8230;
The post Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandrina Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Israel: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Israel and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Israel and Hamas, Palestinian militants and Israeli jets have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Israel and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Palestine: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Palestine and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Hamas and Israel, Israeli jets and Palestinian militants have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Palestine and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres.&nbsp;
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yem…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can Labour survive Britain’s political realignment? - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/12/can-labour-survive-britains-political-realignment-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/12/can-labour-survive-britains-political-realignment-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T02:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After another set of disappointing election results, columnist John Harris asks if Labour can ever reconnect with voters in its former heartlands, where support is increasingly swinging to the Conservatives
Last week’s local elections were the first serious electoral test for the Labour leader, Keir Starmer, whose first year in the job has been dominated by Covid-19. It did not go well. On Friday morning the news came through from Hartlepool that Labour had been beaten into second place by the Conservatives…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with John Harris; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard, Archie Bland and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Selenium and Python to Scrape Websites More Effectively]]></title>
        <id>6096aafe2cd0545b5e944430</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-web-scraping-with-selenium/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're scraping data from the web with Python, Selenium will often come up as an helpful tool to use. It was originally designed for automated testing, but its scraping capabilities are impressive, too. This is because Selenium can do things that other libraries or frameworks often can't when collecting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340359</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-pie-timer-re-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitty reflected on an ancient blog post here on CSS-Tricks on how to make an animated pie timer. The old technique is still clever. The new technique is equally clever and much easier. I particularly like the steps() animation function&#8230;
The post CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I could build this during the weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340186</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/joaoqalves/i-could-build-this-during-the-weekend-aa093c5e"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many times have you heard that (or even uttered it under your own breath)? I know I&#8217;ve heard it in conversations. I also know I&#8217;ve wondered the same thing about a product or two — hey, the idea here &#8230;
The post I could build this during the weekend appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Gen CSS: @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339138</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/next-gen-css-container/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is experimenting with @container, a property within the CSS Working Group Containment Level 3 spec being championed by Miriam Suzanne of Oddbird, and a group of engineers across the web platform. @container brings us the ability to &#8230;
The post Next Gen CSS: @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Una Kravets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340106</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/distributed-persistent-rendering-dpr/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:33:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like Jamstack, Netlify is coining this term.
If your reaction is: great, a new thing I need to know about and learn, know that while Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) does involve some new things, this is actually a push &#8230;
The post Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves&nbsp;
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other vi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours &mdash; but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topframe]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/topframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is extremely fun. Jeff Lindsay has created Topframe, and writes:
Anybody that knows how to mess around with HTML can now mess around with their desktop computing experience.&#160;Topframe&#160;is an open source tool that lets you 
&#8230;
The post Topframe appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340208</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/migrating-from-parcel-to-snowpack-build-tool-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I find build tooling endlessly interesting, especially right now as we&#8217;re in a juicy next-gen transitional period with players like Vite, wmr, Snowpack, and esbuild. Hugh Haworth has a good run-down of the new players, and we&#8217;ve chatted on &#8230;
The post Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339203</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/variable-aspect-ratio-card-with-conic-gradients-meeting-along-the-diagonal/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently came across an interesting problem. I had to implement a grid of cards with a variable (user-set) aspect ratio that was stored in a --ratio custom property. Boxes with a certain aspect ratio are a classic problem in &#8230;
The post Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Tudor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rukmini Iyer’s recipe for baked ricotta with new-season asparagus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:11:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A one-dish wonder full of the joys of spring, The Roasting Tin author’s vibrant, verdant traybake is ready to shop on Ocado.com
This is a lovely seasonal traybake, starring a whole baked ricotta at the centre. Drizzled with olive oil, sea salt and herbs, the warm ricotta works beautifully with the crisp, lemony roast potatoes, the garlic, peas and asparagus. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rukmini Iyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day seven: arts and entertainment

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From de-stressing to vitamin C: the route to radiance for oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/from-de-stressing-to-vitamin-c-the-route-to-radiance-for-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/from-de-stressing-to-vitamin-c-the-route-to-radiance-for-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:31:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a fine line between a dewy glow and shiny skin. Here’s how to achieve the right amount of sheen
An abundance of sebum, the skin’s naturally occurring protective oil, is a good thing. Without it, hair would have no shine and skin no moisture. But overproduction of sebum leads to shiny, oily skin and, often, blemishes.
On the face, sebum is emitted from sebaceous glands, predominantly in the T-zone, the forehead, nose and chin. You can’t change how your skin operates, but you can manage it. Here’s how…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beatrice Aidin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums&nbsp;


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From using unexpected tools to practical prepping advice: how to nail DIY with TikTok]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:35:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tackling a new DIY project can be intimidating – especially if you’ve never tried it before. Tom Druker overcame his fears with help from short videos
Like most of us, I’ve spent much of the past year staring at walls. I moved house shortly before the first lockdown and managed to channel at least some existential anxiety into painting the house. But after that, I hit a wall. So to speak.
I was not raised in a DIY-competent environment. My dad is less DIY and more GSI (get someone in), so while I understand…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Druker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early &mdash; when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Mistakes To Avoid In Your Technical Interviews]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the technical interview process leaves something to be desired; it’s often riddled with anxiety and stress. In this article, we’ll take a look at seven of the most common mistakes candidates make in their technical interviews and explore ways you can avoid them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Emma Bostian)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>