<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-24T00:41:10.857Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-24T00:41:10.857Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.8.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People in England ‘face three-year waits for dentist appointments’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/24/people-in-england-face-three-year-waits-for-dentist-appointments</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/24/people-in-england-face-three-year-waits-for-dentist-appointments"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:32:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damning report shows surgeries have ‘thousands’ of people on waiting lists
People are being told to wait until 2024 for dentist appointments while others are being removed from their practice lists for not making appointments sooner, according to a damning report into the state of dentistry.
Dental surgeries have reported that they have thousands of people on their waiting lists, while patients are unable to access care after ringing round numerous dental surgeries, a watchdog has warned.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Mickelson wins US PGA Championship in triumph for the ages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/24/phil-mickelson-wins-us-pga-championship-in-triumph-for-the-ages</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/24/phil-mickelson-wins-us-pga-championship-in-triumph-for-the-ages"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:28:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifty-year-old becomes oldest major winner of all time 
Mickelson wins by two shots from Brooks Koepka

In front of howling, euphoric fans in this opulent corner of South Carolina, Phil Mickelson strode into the record books. At 50 years of age, Mickelson became the oldest major winner of all time. It was fitting that galleries, who pulled vehemently for Mickelson, were back in full force to witness the making of history. They mobbed the champion as he played his final hole.
Nothing in golf’s modern era will surpass Tiger Woods’s 2019 Masters triumph but Mickelson has now run his old nemesis close. A second success at the US PGA Championship means Mickelson, whose career has regularly looked to be dwindling towards obscurity, has six major titles to his name. That total is only one shy of Arnold Palmer and Bobby Jones. Seve Ballesteros “only” won five. That Mickelson claimed the Wanamaker Trophy, eight years after taking delivery of major number five at Muirfield, belied his advancing years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray at Kiawah Island</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson to marry fiancee Carrie Symonds in July 2022, report says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/24/boris-johnson-to-marry-fiancee-carrie-symonds-in-july-report-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/24/boris-johnson-to-marry-fiancee-carrie-symonds-in-july-report-says"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:08:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Couple have been engaged since late 2019 but had put their marriage plans on hold due to the coronavirus pandemic

Boris Johnson is reportedly to marry his fiancee, Carrie Symonds, in July 2022 after sending save-the-date cards to family and friends, according to the Sun.
They have been engaged since late 2019 but, like many couples, had put their marriage plans on hold due to the coronavirus pandemic with numbers able to attend ceremonies curtailed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decades review – it’s curtain up to terror and rage from Simon Armitage and Maxine Peake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/24/decades-review-its-curtain-up-to-terror-and-rage-from-simon-armitage-and-maxine-peake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/24/decades-review-its-curtain-up-to-terror-and-rage-from-simon-armitage-and-maxine-peake"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Playhouse
The poet and actor are among six writers whose short monologues span the theatre’s 50 years – from the Yorkshire Ripper to a post-lockdown future 
As Leeds Playhouse welcomes back audiences, it is looking backwards as well as forwards. The theatre’s post-lockdown reopening coincides with its 50th anniversary, marked by a collection of new monologues. Involving writers and directors with close connections to the Playhouse, and featuring stories set in Leeds and the surrounding area, Decades reaffirms the theatre’s place within its community. Some of these monologues are more firmly rooted in their historical moment than others, and each takes inspiration from one of the six decades of the Playhouse’s life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Catherine Love</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Launch of survey into Black British identity hailed as UK first]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/launch-of-survey-into-black-british-identity-hailed-as-uk-first</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/launch-of-survey-into-black-british-identity-hailed-as-uk-first"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Survey to run over summer and focus on issues such as education, business, health and media
A major national survey is launching to explore the evolution of Black British identities as part of a wider research project that has been described as the first of its kind.
The Black British Voices Project (BBVP) will give black people in the UK an opportunity to “define themselves in an autonomous way” for the first time, according to the researchers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin Community affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO and global faith leaders call for fair access to Covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/who-and-global-faith-leaders-call-for-fair-access-to-covid-vaccines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/who-and-global-faith-leaders-call-for-fair-access-to-covid-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Declaration warns that the world is at a turning point in saving poorer countries from devastation

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Global faith leaders and senior health and humanitarian figures are calling on countries to ensure the equitable distribution of Covid vaccines, warning that the world is “at a turning point”.
The signatories of an international declaration include Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, director-general of the World Health Organization; Henrietta Fore, executive director of Unicef, the UN’s children’s agency; Peter Maurer, president of the International Committee of the Red Cross; Filippo Grandi, United Nations high commissioner for refugees; Justin Welby, the archbishop of Canterbury and leader of the global Anglican church; Sheikh Ahmed al-Tayeb, the grand imam of al-Azhar; and Christian and Jewish leaders.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black British Voices Project: ‘Being black and British is an abundance of joy’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/black-british-voice-project-being-black-and-british-is-an-abundance-of-joy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/24/black-british-voice-project-being-black-and-british-is-an-abundance-of-joy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major survey will explore evolution of black British identity
A major national survey, launched by Cambridge University, I-Cubed Ltd and the Voice Newspaper, will explore the evolution of black British identity, from the generations who lived through the 1970s and 1980s to the students leading the Black Lives Matter movement today.
At the launch of the Black British Voices Project, the Guardian asked three people, from different generations, what it means to them to be black British.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Premier League: 10 talking points from the weekend’s action]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/24/premier-league-10-talking-points-from-the-weekends-action</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/24/premier-league-10-talking-points-from-the-weekends-action"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Klopp’s underperformers pull their socks up, fearsome Fornals proves his worth and Foxes could mount a title challenge
A season that looked at once stage like a bona fide catastrophe for Liverpool has not only ended on a high but with a handful of their more maligned performers getting them over the line. Alisson put an error-riddled season behind him with last week’s glorious header. Trent Alexander-Arnold returned to the form that marks him out as a captain-in-waiting. Thiago Alcântara, whose integration to the side coincided with its calamitous downturn in form, swaggered majestically through the run-in. And Sadio Mané finished a campaign to forget with the goals that set the stage for next season. Which is not to say all is suddenly rosy at Anfield – the squad is getting no younger and one of Europe’s best midfielders has bid the club goodbye – but any talk of crumbling dynasties has been proved wildly premature. It says much about Jürgen Klopp that the most miserable year of his Liverpool tenure concluded with him grinning manically as he soaked up the acclaim of rapturous fans. Alex Hess
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK businesses can unlock growth with green exports, says CBI]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/24/businesses-unlock-uk-growth-green-exports-cbi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/24/businesses-unlock-uk-growth-green-exports-cbi"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lobby group publishes ‘vision’ for decarbonising economy and creating 240,000 jobs

British businesses have the opportunity to create 240,000 low-carbon jobs and boost green exports by billions of pounds to radically transform the UK economy over the next decade, the CBI has said.
The UK’s foremost business lobby group said businesses across the country stood to gain from an “early mover advantage” by leading a campaign to decarbonise the global economy to avoid a climate meltdown.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington and Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[European roundup: Lille win at Angers to seal first Ligue 1 title in 10 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/23/european-roundup-lille-win-at-angers-to-seal-first-ligue-1-title-in-10-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/23/european-roundup-lille-win-at-angers-to-seal-first-ligue-1-title-in-10-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T22:04:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PSG finish Ligue 1 runners-up; Monaco are third
Juventus overtake Napoli for Champions League spot

Lille held their nerve to claim a first Ligue 1 title in 10 years with top goalscorer Burak Yilmaz on target in a 2-1 win at Angers which clinched the championship.
Christophe Galtier’s men knew victory on the road would ensure Paris Saint-Germain’s result away to Brest was insignificant and the leaders produced a professional display to secure a 24th league win, with Jonathan David’s 10th-minute opener a key settler for the away side.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunak under pressure to back Biden’s global corporation tax plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/sunak-under-pressure-to-back-bidens-global-corporation-tax-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/sunak-under-pressure-to-back-bidens-global-corporation-tax-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T21:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour expected to trigger Commons vote to force UK government to support proposal
Rishi Sunak is facing growing pressure to support US proposals for a global minimum rate of corporation tax in the run-up to the UK hosting a pivotal meeting between G7 leaders in Cornwall next month.
Labour is expected to trigger a Commons vote on Monday designed to force the UK government to back the plan put forward by the US president, Joe Biden, which is being negotiated between more than 130 nations with the hope of securing an agreement this autumn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man arrested after racist gesture to Rio Ferdinand at Wolves]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/23/man-arrested-after-racist-gesture-to-rio-ferdinand-at-wolves</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/23/man-arrested-after-racist-gesture-to-rio-ferdinand-at-wolves"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T21:03:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ferdinand was at Manchester United game as TV pundit
Wolves have apologised to former England defender

Wolves have apologised to Rio Ferdinand after a supporter was arrested having made a racist gesture towards the former Manchester United and England defender at Molineux.
Ferdinand was at the stadium working as a pundit as Wolves were beaten 2-1 by United in the Premier League on Sunday afternoon.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BLM activist Sasha Johnson in critical condition after gunshot to the head]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/blm-activist-sasha-johnson-in-critical-condition-after-gunshot-to-the-head</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/blm-activist-sasha-johnson-in-critical-condition-after-gunshot-to-the-head"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T21:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting in Southwark, London came after numerous death threats, says her Taking the Initiative party
The Black Lives Matter activist Sasha Johnson is in a critical condition after sustaining a gunshot wound to her head in an incident in south London, her affiliated group, Taking the Initiative party, has announced on social media.
In a statement on the group’s Facebook page, the party said that the incident happened in the early hours of Sunday and followed “numerous death threats”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dina Asher-Smith beats Sha’Carri Richardson to 100m glory in Gateshead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/dina-asher-smith-beats-shacarri-richardson-to-100m-glory-in-gateshead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/dina-asher-smith-beats-shacarri-richardson-to-100m-glory-in-gateshead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T20:52:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British sprinter sets down marker for Tokyo Olympics
Laura Muir powers to victory in women’s 1500m

On a night billed as a dress-rehearsal for the women’s 100m Olympic final in Tokyo, Dina Asher-Smith proved a compelling starring act. In brutal and biting conditions more akin to winter than Whitsun, she powered home to leave a string of top-quality sprinters flailing in her slipstream.
Asher-Smith had promised that she was stronger than ever after working hard during the pandemic, and she proved as good as her word as she came through in 11.35sec. To the casual observer, that time may have seemed nothing special – it is nearly half a second outside her British record. But given it was into driving rain and a -3.1 m/s headwind, it was quietly spectacular.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester give their all to the very end but the richest clubs prevail | Jon ath]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/23/leicester-give-their-all-to-the-very-end-but-the-richest-clubs-prevail</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/23/leicester-give-their-all-to-the-very-end-but-the-richest-clubs-prevail"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T20:20:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brendan Rodgers’ side were unlucky to miss out on top four after a season racked by injuries, while Chelsea imploded but held on to fourth and Liverpool stormed to third
As you were, then. At the end of this most unpredictable and turbulent of seasons, a time of pandemic and insurrection, the top four places in the Premier League ended in the hands of its four biggest and richest clubs.
Eight restless months after we started, English football’s new order – it turned out – looked largely like the old.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Activists to honor George Floyd with series of events in Minneapolis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/george-floyd-minneapolis-anniversary-events</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/george-floyd-minneapolis-anniversary-events"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T20:09:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Program will start with march led by the Rev Al Sharpton and Benjamin Crump to mark a year since Floyd’s murder

One year on, how George Floyd’s murder has changed the world

Activists in the city of Minneapolis were set to begin several days of events on Sunday to commemorate the life of George Floyd and mark the first anniversary of his murder.
The program organized by the George Floyd Memorial Foundation, a non-profit organization founded by Floyd’s younger sister Bridgett Floyd, will start with a march led by civil rights leader the Rev Al Sharpton and civil rights attorney Benjamin Crump on Sunday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At least 15 die in lava flows after volcano erupts in Democratic Republic of Congo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/at-least-15-die-in-lava-flows-after-volcano-erupts-in-democratic-republic-of-congo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/at-least-15-die-in-lava-flows-after-volcano-erupts-in-democratic-republic-of-congo"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T20:05:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 500 homes have been destroyed by the lava that has poured into villages, officials and survivors say
At least 15 people died when torrents of lava poured into villages after dark in the eastern Democratic Republic of Congo, destroying more than 500 homes, officials and survivors said on Sunday.
The eruption of Mount Nyiragongo on Saturday night sent about 5,000 people fleeing from the city of Goma across the nearby border into Rwanda, while another 25,000 others sought refuge to the north-west in Sake, the UN children’s agency said on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chi Modu, the celebrated hip-hop photographer, dies aged 54]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/23/chi-modu-the-celebrated-hip-hop-photographer-dies-aged-54</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/23/chi-modu-the-celebrated-hip-hop-photographer-dies-aged-54"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T19:02:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Details surrounding his death, which was announced on Saturday, have not been divulged
Chi Modu, the photographer behind some of hip-hop’s most celebrated photographs, has died aged 54.
The news was announced on Saturday via Modu’s official Instagram. “Our hearts are broken … we continue the fight,” read the post. The details surrounding his death have not been divulged. “The family request privacy at this time,” the post concluded.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan Deputy fashion editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US-Iran nuclear pact revival at risk after delays to new inspection deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/us-iran-nuclear-pact-revival-at-risk-after-delays-to-new-inspection-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/us-iran-nuclear-pact-revival-at-risk-after-delays-to-new-inspection-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T19:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UN watchdog and Iran so far unable to agree terms for one-month extension of monitoring of nuclear sites 
The future of talks to bring the US back into the Iran nuclear deal is under threat after the UN nuclear watchdog was unable to reach an expected agreement on how to continue to inspect Iran’s nuclear sites.
The UN’s International Atomic Energy Agency was forced to postpone a planned press conference on Sunday that was due to set out details of a one-month extension of the current light-touch inspection regime amid conflicting signals from Iran over whether it would sign up to it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on the rich getting richer during Covid-19 – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/23/ben-jennings-billionaires-covid-coronavirus-wealth-rich-list-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/23/ben-jennings-billionaires-covid-coronavirus-wealth-rich-list-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T19:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chance of England Covid restrictions ending on 21 June ‘looking good’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/chance-of-uk-covid-restrictions-ending-on-21-june-looking-good</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/chance-of-uk-covid-restrictions-ending-on-21-june-looking-good"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T18:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jenny Harries from UK Health Security Agency is upbeat but other scientists warn over latest variant 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 
The prospects for ending all coronavirus lockdown restrictions in England on 21 June are “looking good” as long as people are careful, said Jenny Harries, chief executive of the UK Health Security Agency, while other scientists said the latest variant could spread widely even with high vaccination coverage and the public were urged to get second shots.
Harries was speaking as the government revealed that more than a million people had downloaded the NHS app, which now enables people to prove their vaccination status if they want to travel – suggesting many are hoping for a foreign holiday soon. More than 22.6 million people in the UK have had two doses of a coronavirus vaccine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley Health editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italy in shock as 14 people die in cable car accident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/at-least-eight-dead-in-italian-cable-car-accident</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/at-least-eight-dead-in-italian-cable-car-accident"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T18:25:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Casualties reported after cable car with 15 passengers collapsed near Lake Maggiore in northern Italy
Italy was in shock on Sunday after a cable car crashed to the ground in a northern Italian beauty spot, killing 14 people including a nine-year-old child.
The cable car is believed to have been carrying 15 people on the 20-minute ride between the resort town of Stresa and the Mottarone mountain in the Piedmont region when it plummeted into the woods near Lake Maggiore shortly after midday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida in Rome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blinken pledges US will deal with ‘grave humanitarian situation in Gaza’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/us-antony-blinken-israel-gaza-biden-administration</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/us-antony-blinken-israel-gaza-biden-administration"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:54:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US secretary of state also reaffirms Biden administration supports a two-state solution 
The US secretary of state, Antony Blinken, has pledged the Biden administration will deal with “the grave humanitarian situation in Gaza” and will seek “equal measures of security” for Israelis and Palestinians as a ceasefire after 11 days of conflict held throughout the weekend.
More than 240 people in Gaza, including at least 66 children, and a dozen in Israel were killed during the violence, marking the first major diplomatic crisis for the Biden administration.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police step in as ‘free Palestine’ chanters approach pro-Israel rally in London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/police-step-in-after-free-palestine-marchers-approach-pro-israel-group</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/police-step-in-after-free-palestine-marchers-approach-pro-israel-group"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:47:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Small group of men tried to enter protest area in Kensington waving Palestinian flags
Police officers stepped in after a small group of people chanting “free Palestine” approached a gathering of pro-Israel protesters in London.
The large crowd, which gathered in Kensington High Street on Sunday afternoon, waved Israeli flags and banners and chanted loudly, while speeches were made. Footage circulating on social media appeared to show the English Defence League founder Tommy Robinson, whose real name is Stephen Yaxley-Lennon, among the attenders.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ron Hill obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/ron-hill-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/ron-hill-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:44:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British long distance runner who won gold medals and broke records in the marathon during the 1960s and 70s
Ron Hill, who has died aged 82, was an exceptional and versatile British long distance runner who won gold in the marathon at the 1969 European Championships and the 1970 Commonwealth Games. He broke four world records in various events and ran in 115 marathons. Even today his best marathon time, 2hr 9min 28sec, ranks as one of the quickest by any Briton.
Running in the amateur era, Hill combined his athletics career with a job as a textile scientist, and revealed considerable entrepreneurial skills when he set up a multimillion-pound own-label sportswear company called Ron Hill Sports, which continues to this day as Ronhill.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Neil Shuttleworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We are changing the narrative’: meet the new faces of Australian fashion week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/24/we-are-changing-the-narrative-meet-the-new-faces-of-australian-fashion-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/24/we-are-changing-the-narrative-meet-the-new-faces-of-australian-fashion-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a year of radical upheaval, the country’s premier fashion event will look very different in 2021
Australian fashion week was ready for a change in late 2019. Before a global pandemic irrevocably changed the fashion industry, live events and just about everything else, the week’s organisers had already announced a significant shift: the public would be able to buy tickets to what was previously a trade-only event.
Last year’s shows did not go on, but IMG, the global events company that runs Australian fashion week, is optimistic about the 2021 edition. Barring public health emergencies, the event will begin on 31 May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alyx Gorman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on recycling plastics: keep it in the UK | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/the-guardian-view-on-recycling-plastics-keep-it-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/the-guardian-view-on-recycling-plastics-keep-it-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turkey is the latest country to reject the role of world’s dustbin. With their environment bill, ministers have a chance to end this vandalism
The international plastics recycling market is broken. It is doubtful whether it ever worked. For most of the last decade, China was the world’s largest importer of recyclable materials, some of which were used in manufacturing. But it banned these imports as part of a “beautiful China” policy aimed at improving the environment.
Malaysia was the next country to fight back against being treated as the “dumping ground of the world” – as its environment minister, Yeo Bee Yin, put it in 2019. More than 200 facilities were closed, and thousands of tonnes of waste returned, amid growing evidence of the involvement of organised crime in the global waste business. Now Turkey has rejected the role of international rubbish bin: after a Greenpeace investigation found plastics dumped in rivers, on beaches and in illegal waste mountains, it announced that most plastic waste imports (which included 209,642 tonnes from the UK in 2020) will be banned in six weeks’ time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jo Cox’s sister selected as Labour candidate for Batley and Spen byelection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/jo-cox-sister-labour-candidate-batley-and-spen-byelection-kim-leadbeater</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/jo-cox-sister-labour-candidate-batley-and-spen-byelection-kim-leadbeater"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:26:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kim Leadbeater will try to hold on to West Yorkshire constituency where MP was murdered
Jo Cox’s younger sister has been selected to contest a byelection in Batley and Spen, the constituency where the MP was murdered five years ago.
Kim Leadbeater, 44, a personal trainer and campaigner, declared herself “the candidate the Tories fear”. She will try to hold the seat for Labour later this summer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on community leisure centres: not a luxury | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/the-guardian-view-on-community-leisure-centres-not-a-luxury</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/the-guardian-view-on-community-leisure-centres-not-a-luxury"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:25:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Access to local hubs plays a vital role in maintaining health and tackling inequalities. They must not be allowed to close 
One of the many discoveries of the last 14 months has been how Covid-19 seeks out underlying vulnerabilities. These are as plural and complex as the people they afflict. But one vulnerability the government has, rightly, pinpointed as something to be addressed is obesity. In 2019, the year leading into the pandemic, figures for England showed over a million hospital admissions for causes directly related to obesity, with 67% of men and 60% of women overweight or obese. Months of lockdown are not likely to have improved this. Boris Johnson, recognising that his weight may have contributed to his hospitalisation with Covid-19, has been banging the drum on the need to achieve a healthy weight; and the government is promoting “weight management services”.
It is a pity, then, that the means so far made available to local communities do not support the laudable end. Earlier this month, the former Paralympian Lady Grey-Thompson told Mr Johnson that more than 50% of public leisure facilities are at risk of closing in the next six months. The next day, the District Councils’ Network (DCN), which represents 180 district councils providing leisure services in England, noted that one in three councils expected to close leisure centres for good in the next three months, and over half in the next year. Of those able to remain open, 80% expected to decrease services. The government will point to its recent grant of £100m for leisure centres and a £18,000 restart sum for individual gyms – but the DCN survey was conducted after the awarding of this grant. A funding gap of £325m remains.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands rally at ‘obscene’ motorcade for Jair Bolsonaro]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/thousands-rally-jair-bolsonaro-obscene-motorcade-covid-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/thousands-rally-jair-bolsonaro-obscene-motorcade-covid-deaths"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:13:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 450,000 Covid deaths, president parades through Rio in effort to reenergnise far right 
The Brazilian president, Jair Bolsonaro, has led a raucous column of motorcycle enthusiasts through the streets of Rio in an attempt to reenergise his flagging far-right movement as public anger grows over his handling of the country’s Covid outbreak.
Thousands of flag-waving Bolsonaristas gathered outside the Olympic Park in west Rio on Sunday morning for the two-wheeled show of support before roaring east towards the southern beach districts and city centre, with Bolsonaro near the front.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips in Rio de Janeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fewer than one in 60 rape cases lead to charge in England and Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/23/fewer-than-one-in-60-cases-lead-to-charge-in-england-and-wales</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/23/fewer-than-one-in-60-cases-lead-to-charge-in-england-and-wales"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T17:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figures will put pressure on government to deliver overhaul of rape treatment by criminal justice system
Fewer than one in 60 rape cases recorded by the police last year resulted in a suspect being charged, analysis of Home Office figures seen by the Guardian reveals.
While there were 52,210 rapes recorded by police in England and Wales in 2020, only 843 resulted in a charge or a summons – a rate of 1.6%.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caelainn Barr and Alexandra Topping</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UAE offers to play role in Israel-Palestine peace talks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/uae-offers-to-play-role-in-israel-palestine-peace-talks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/uae-offers-to-play-role-in-israel-palestine-peace-talks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:51:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crown prince says emirates willing to back Cairo’s efforts to shore up Friday’s truce between two sides
The UAE is willing to play a role in peace efforts between Israel and the Palestinians, joining an Egyptian push to bolster a ceasefire in Gaza and de-escalate tensions between the two sides, the Gulf powerbroker’s leadership has said.
Crown Prince Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed said the Emirates, which signed a peace deal with Israel last year, was willing to mediate between both sides and to support Cairo’s efforts to shore up a truce that brought 11 days of fighting to a close on Friday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backlash against the BBC and Martin Bashir is hypocritical | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/backlash-against-the-bbc-and-martin-bashir-is-hypocritical</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/backlash-against-the-bbc-and-martin-bashir-is-hypocritical"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:43:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to criticism of the corporation after Lord Dyson’s report on the 1995 Panorama interview with Diana, Princess of Wales
Marina Hyde provides a superbly balanced, rational exposition of the “paranoia” arising from the Dyson report (They won’t remind us, but the tabloids hurt Diana just as much as Panorama did, 21 May). She examines the groups and individuals bingeing on criticisms of the BBC and Martin Bashir. She calls them out for the self-serving hypocrites they are when they denounce those involved in the securing and broadcasting of the interview with Diana, Princess of Wales. At that time, the prime emotion emanating from most of them was envy that Bashir and the BBC had “scooped” such a prize. Hyde persuasively draws attention to the guilt we all share, some with greater awareness and acceptance than others. 
But in all of this discussion and polemics, let us remember that the sentiments expressed by Diana in that interview were relevant and understandable. She had, since the early days of her marriage, been subjected to duplicity and betrayal by those closest to her. Let us not forget the contribution to her alleged paranoia made by the Prince of Wales and his current wife (then Camilla Parker Bowles). Diana’s isolation and marginalisation had become unsustainable – she needed to both complain and explain. The BBC and Bashir provided the platform. They should not be pilloried by individuals (certainly not by those such as our exceedingly mendacious prime minister), nor indeed by those in the media whose record in this affair is dubious.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Office and the EU settlement scheme | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/home-office-and-the-eu-settlement-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/home-office-and-the-eu-settlement-scheme"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:42:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Foster, the minister for future borders and immigration, says the government has made the system as straightforward as possible. Meanwhile, Dr Jolanta Opacka, writes of the shock she felt on receiving the letter on immigration status that was sent to long-term UK citizens
Rafael Behr’s article (EU citizens made Britain their home – now they face a hostile environment, 18 May) may mislead readers and discourage eligible EU citizens from applying to the EU settlement scheme. I’m delighted that since the EUSS launched in March 2019, more than 5.4m applications have been received. This demonstrates how the government has made the system as straightforward and user-friendly as possible.
It also reflects our investment to raise awareness and support people. We have made £22m available to help vulnerable applicants, spent nearly £8m on public awareness campaigns and have dedicated staff at the EU settlement resolution centre providing support seven days a week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ocean Rebellion co-founder alleges police tried to intimidate him]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/23/ocean-rebellion-rob-higgs-alleges-police-intimidate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/23/ocean-rebellion-rob-higgs-alleges-police-intimidate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:21:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rob Higgs alleges plainclothes officers turned up unannounced at his premises

The co-founder of the eco activist group Ocean Rebellion has filed a complaint to police alleging that officers have tried to intimidate him before next month’s G7 summit in Cornwall.
Rob Higgs, an artist and campaigner, has alleged that at least a dozen plainclothes officers turned up unannounced at his Cornish studios, his home and his boat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belarus accused of ‘hijacking’ Ryanair flight diverted to arrest blogger]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/belarus-diverts-ryanair-plane-to-arrest-blogger-says-opposition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/belarus-diverts-ryanair-plane-to-arrest-blogger-says-opposition"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:14:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roman Protasevich is wanted for organising last year’s protests against Alexander Lukashenko
Belarus has been accused of hijacking a European jetliner and engaging in an act of state terrorism when it forced a Ryanair flight to perform an emergency landing in Minsk after a bomb threat and arrested an opposition blogger critical of authoritarian president Alexander Lukashenko.
Roman Protasevich, a former editor of the influential Telegram channels Nexta and Nexta Live, was detained by police after his flight was diverted to Minsk national airport. Minsk confirmed that Lukashenko ordered his military to scramble a Mig-29 fighter to escort the plane.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Max Verstappen wins Monaco Grand Prix to take world championship lead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/max-verstappen-wins-monaco-grand-prix-to-take-world-championship-lead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/max-verstappen-wins-monaco-grand-prix-to-take-world-championship-lead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:08:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lewis Hamilton finishes seventh and loses lead in title race
Carlos Sainz races home in second, Lando Norris third

Max Verstappen’s win at the Monaco Grand Prix is unlikely to have stirred the soul of Formula One fans. Yet from a broader perspective the Dutchman’s victory from the front to the flag is the absolute tonic the title fight required.
Mercedes and Lewis Hamilton, for once foundering, let slip what for so long has been an impregnable grip on both world championships.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards in Monte Carlo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardline Tories could try to ‘destroy’ BBC for political motives, say opposition parties]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/hardline-tories-could-try-to-destroy-bbc-for-political-motives-say-opposition-parties</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/hardline-tories-could-try-to-destroy-bbc-for-political-motives-say-opposition-parties"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:03:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Opposition MPs increasingly alarmed at government response to fallout from Diana interview
Opposition parties have expressed concern that hardline anti-BBC Conservatives could use the fallout from the discredited interview with Diana, Princess of Wales to try to “destroy” the corporation for political motives.
The warning came as Priti Patel, the home secretary, gave the clearest indication yet that ministers are considering sweeping changes to how the BBC is run, calling next year’s review of the BBC charter “a very, very significant moment” for its governance structures.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC Radio Newcastle presenter Lisa Shaw dies aged 44]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/bbc-radio-newcastle-presenter-lisa-shaw-dies-aged-44</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/bbc-radio-newcastle-presenter-lisa-shaw-dies-aged-44"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:02:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tributes paid to much-loved, award-winning presenter who has died after a short illness 
Tributes have been paid to a Sony Gold award-winning BBC radio presenter who has died aged 44 after a short illness.
Lisa Shaw was a broadcasting institution in the north-east of England, having moved through the region’s commercial radio stations before finding a home at Radio Newcastle in 2015.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small farms have a huge role to play in our sustainable future | Charles, Prince of Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/small-farms-huge-role-sustainable-future-prince-charles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/small-farms-huge-role-sustainable-future-prince-charles"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Small-scale agriculture needs the tools and confidence to deal with the rapid changes society has to make

Charles, Prince of Wales is the heir apparent to the British throne

Family farmers form the backbone of our rural communities. Their hard work puts high-quality food on our tables, which is produced to some of the highest standards in the world, and their careful stewardship knits together the environmental and social fabric of our beautiful and iconic landscapes. They are a remarkable breed; adaptable, resilient and incredibly hardworking. And they are no stranger to innovation through adversity. Their very diversity brings great strengths to our environment, to our rural communities and to disease management. All this must be taken into account as agriculture starts this massive transition, especially as more than 110,000 smaller family farms have already been lost since 1990.
To me, it is essential the contribution of the small-scale family farmer is properly recognised – they must be a key part in any fair, inclusive, equitable and just transition to a sustainable future. To do this, we must ensure that Britain’s family farmers have the tools and the confidence to meet the rapid transition to regenerative farming systems that our planet demands.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles, Prince of Wales</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince Charles: small-scale family farms must be at heart of sustainable future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/23/prince-charles-small-scale-family-farms-must-be-at-heart-of-sustainable-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/23/prince-charles-small-scale-family-farms-must-be-at-heart-of-sustainable-future"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T15:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: ‘Rapid transition to regenerative farming’ needed, says prince, as data reveals 100,000 UK farms lost since 1990

The Prince of Wales has called for small family farmers in the UK and across the world to come together in a cooperative movement using sustainable farming methods, and for their plight to be at the centre of environmental action.
Small farmers, in the UK and EU, are facing their biggest upheavals in more than a generation, with the loss of farm subsidies and new post-Brexit trade deals in the UK, and sweeping reforms to the EU’s common agricultural policy to be announced this week in Brussels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The reputation game: how authors try to control their image from beyond the grave]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/23/the-reputation-game-how-authors-try-to-control-their-image-from-beyond-the-grave</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/23/the-reputation-game-how-authors-try-to-control-their-image-from-beyond-the-grave"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T14:36:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The row over a new biography of Philip Roth has exposed the way agents and estates restrict access and manage archives to maintain a writer’s posthumous good name
Writers and critics are raising questions over the role that agents and estates play in managing archives and limiting access to biographical material.
Fresh worries have been fuelled by the continuing fiasco over the publication of Philip Roth: The Biography, with accusations that access to the famed US author’s archival material is being unfairly constrained.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of child migrants crammed into warehouses in Ceuta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/hundreds-of-child-migrants-in-ceuta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/hundreds-of-child-migrants-in-ceuta"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T14:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spanish enclave in north Africa identifies 438 unaccompanied children and teenagers
Hundreds of children and teenagers are crammed into warehouses or sleeping rough in city parks in the Spanish north African enclave of Ceuta as their fate remains up in the air days after thousands of migrants arrived in the city.
More than 8,000 migrants last week crossed into the seven-square mile territory – many of them swimming or piling into flimsy inflatable rafts to skirt the breakwater that marks the border with Morocco – amid reports that Moroccan officials had relaxed controls over the border last week . At least two people died attempting the crossing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashifa Kassam in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nul points again: how exactly can the UK win Eurovision?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/23/nul-points-how-can-uk-win-eurovision-analysis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/23/nul-points-how-can-uk-win-eurovision-analysis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T14:07:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: James Newman began like a Daniel Bedingfield B-side and went downhill from there

For those who see Eurovision as a proxy war, avenging geopolitical resentments under the cover of glitter and tight trousers, the odds were always stacked against the UK winning this year’s contest.
Pretty much every country may have had a reason to begrudge the UK. Perhaps EU nations have not forgiven us for Brexit. The Russians still cannot believe we did not swallow that story about their secret agents visiting Salisbury Cathedral. The Australians, they might be sore about the trade deal row.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ron Hill, former British marathon runner, dies aged 82]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/ron-hill-former-british-marathon-runner-dies-aged-82</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/ron-hill-former-british-marathon-runner-dies-aged-82"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:38:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hill won Commonwealth gold and Boston Marathon in 1970
Accrington-born athlete ran every day for a record 52 years

Every day between 1964 and 2017 the renowned British athlete Ron Hill ran at least a mile, setting a world record streak of 52 years and 39 days that still stands – even after snapping his sternum in a car accident in 1993.
Yet that was one of many achievements in a glorious career. For Hill, who has died at the age of 82, was also an Olympian, inventor, innovator and undoubtedly one of the country’s greatest marathon runners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid rates in Sefton and Bolton tell a tale of two demographics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/covid-rates-in-sefton-and-bolton-tell-a-tale-of-two-demographics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/covid-rates-in-sefton-and-bolton-tell-a-tale-of-two-demographics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wealthy area of Merseyside has low case rates while town 35 miles away has UK’s highest case numbers

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

At a government press conference last Wednesday, England’s deputy chief medical officer singled out one part of the north-west for praise. Sefton, said Dr Jenny Harries, had “done a brilliant job” dealing with rising cases of the variant first identified in India.
That day, eight people in the Merseyside local authority tested positive for Covid. Two weeks earlier, on 5 May, there had been 36 reported cases. The data was going in the right direction, said Harries.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor, Nicola Davis and Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy 80th birthday to Bob Dylan, rock’s most prescient, timeless voice | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/bob-dylan-80th-birthday-rock</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/bob-dylan-80th-birthday-rock"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As he has aged and changed, so have his songs, but the essentials remain: honesty, wisdom and hope in the face of despair

When I first properly listened to Bob Dylan, I was 10 years old. Each Saturday, Radio 1 aired a series titled 25 Years of Rock, based on news and music spanning the years 1955 to 1979. And that week, in among archive clips of Lyndon Johnson, Harold Wilson, the Vietnam war and whatever else had happened in 1965, there was the sudden whip-crack of a snare drum followed by six minutes of music unlike anything I had ever heard: a great cascading noise, led by a voice that, as the US composer Michael Pisaro later wrote, somehow managed to be simultaneously “compassionate, tragic … vengeful, gleeful, ironic, weary, spectral, [and] haranguing”.
I soon found out that what I had experienced was Dylan’s watershed single Like a Rolling Stone, whose lyric is ostensibly addressed to some unnamed wealthy socialite as she is suddenly cut off from money and privilege. But as a matter of instinct, what I still hear in that song is a message from someone in the midst of early adulthood about how to live at that time of life. The best way to be when young, Dylan seems to insist, is restless, light on baggage, and scornful of any conventions or rules – reconciled, as Like a Rolling Stone famously puts it, to having no direction home.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey pesto! The definitive A-Z of the world’s most versatile ingredient]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/23/pesto-the-definitive-a-z-of-the-worlds-most-versatile-ingredient</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/23/pesto-the-definitive-a-z-of-the-worlds-most-versatile-ingredient"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The midweek-meal saviour is possibly the most customisable food ever. From salads to sauces and stews, here’s how to get the best from the Italian classic

In the 30 years since its UK supermarket debut, pesto has captured Britain’s heart, becoming a go-to saviour of the midweek meal. And not just in the classic pesto alla genovese form. From chilli-spiked to truffled incarnations, pesto has come a long way since 1991.
“Start with the premise that it contains herbs, nuts, cheese and oil,” says George Leigh, chef at the Birmingham pizzeria Otto. “Then pick the herb or cheese and adjust everything else to match.” That attitude will appal purists, but, as this A-Z of pesto reveals, once-hard rules about pesto are increasingly being ignored for the sake of flavour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tony Naylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: what do the terms ‘working class’ and ‘middle class’ actually mean?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/23/readers-reply-what-do-the-terms-working-class-and-middle-class-actually-mean</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/23/readers-reply-what-do-the-terms-working-class-and-middle-class-actually-mean"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
What do the terms “working class” and “middle class” actually mean? Is it just the type of work you do or does your housing situation or education play a part? And what about the kind of coffee you drink? Michael “Flat cap” Moorfield, Wrexham
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing the circus back to life – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/bringing-the-circus-back-to-life-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/bringing-the-circus-back-to-life-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The photojournalist Tom Pilston documents Giffords Circus as they prepare to return to touring for the first time since the pandemic struck in the UK, with their show The Hooley

Giffords are tour from 19 May to 26 September 2021

To watch Giffords Circus at Fennells Farm in Gloucestershire come back to life after suffering the double catastrophe of the premature death of its founder and inspiration, Nell Gifford, followed by the havoc wrought by Covid-19, is a wonderful thing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Pilston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s first fashion editor: ‘Highbrows no longer ignore high fashion’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/may/23/fashion-guardian-first-fashion-editor-alison-adburgham-jess-cartner-morley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/may/23/fashion-guardian-first-fashion-editor-alison-adburgham-jess-cartner-morley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T13:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jess Cartner-Morley, associate editor (Fashion), looks through the archives of Alison Adburgham, one of the pioneers of press style journalism

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

“Now comes the Paris week, with the fighting on the stairways, the multilingual shrieking in the salons; a week of over-heating, under-eating, little sleeping; a week of vitiation and dehydration, ineffectively compensated by indifferent champagne.”
In other words, fashion week has barely changed in 61 years. “For the fashion critic, the sturm und drang of the Paris Openings follow on from the openings in Rome, Florence and London,” Alison Adburgham wrote in 1960. “Already she has an overdraft of fatigue from travelling, typing and long-distance telephoning, from parties and interminable talking … And yet she survives. She brings herself sufficiently alive to turn a confusion of impressions into a fusion of trends, from which she can distill the essential essence of the coming season.” The namedropping of glamorous destinations, while simultaneously giving the impression that covering the shows is war-zone-level challenging, the dash of performative ennui, and the obligatory twist of champagne: this is what being a fashion editor was and is, then and now. Alison, I couldn’t have put it better myself.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Cartner-Morley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid pandemic might unlock doors to golden age for the arts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/commentisfree/2021/may/23/covid-pandemic-might-unlock-doors-to-golden-age-for-the-arts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/commentisfree/2021/may/23/covid-pandemic-might-unlock-doors-to-golden-age-for-the-arts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T12:56:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technological revolutions tend to be the catalyst for artistic revolutions

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

For Britain’s theatres it has been a case of history repeating itself. The playhouses were often closed in the 16th and 17th centuries as a result of the bubonic plague and last year they closed because the prime minister, in his guise as master of the revels, decided that Covid-19 meant watching a play in the flesh was too risky.
Like other sectors of the economy, the theatre adapted, with people able to watch performances on TV or on their mobiles. No question, though, it has been a tough period, as it was in 1593, when the theatres in London were closed for 14 months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alexander Whitley: Overflow review – watch out for the bodyscanners!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/23/alexander-whitley-overflow-review-watch-out-for-the-bodyscanners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/23/alexander-whitley-overflow-review-watch-out-for-the-bodyscanners"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T12:07:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sadler’s Wells, London
There’s little optimism in Whitley’s subtle blast at digital overload but there are some excellent hypnotic effects

“What is it about?” is a question often asked of contemporary dance shows – both before and after seeing them. Sometimes the answer is “nothing”, or “whatever you want it to be”. Sometimes the choreographer has a concrete idea, as in Alexander Whitley’s Overflow, which tackles the dominance of digital technology, big data and the information overload of modern life.
Or at least, if you look very closely it does. Whitley’s thematic ideas are sometimes as under the radar as a social media megacorp quietly sucking up your personal details. What’s dominant here is a hypnotic light installation by the Dutch artists Children of the Light, an LED strip that continually transforms, from glowing amber lightsaber to flaming javelin to shooting stars. It rotates above the stage, distracting our attention from the humans below, who frequently fade into the darkness and thick haze. It could be a proxy for all the screens, the flashing lights that keep us clicking and scrolling, dazzled by tech, losing sight of what’s real.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lyndsey Winship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Group think: why art loves a crowd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/23/group-think-why-art-loves-a-crowd-olivia-laing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/23/group-think-why-art-loves-a-crowd-olivia-laing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T12:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flâneurs to rallies, protests to parties, human beings are drawn to congregate. With social gatherings a possibility once again, Olivia Laing considers the crowd in art and literature
When I was very lonely in New York, one of the things that most comforted me was to wander up Broadway or along the East River, alone but in the company of thousands of strangers. Anonymised by the multitude, I felt the burden of my sorrow slide off me. It was a relief to be part of a whole, no longer agonisingly singular but a drop in what Walt Whitman once called “the rolling ocean the crowd”.
Until last year, the crowd was the trademark of the city. All through the day and night, people shoaled together, hurrying through streets, dawdling in parks, jostling at protests, concerts and football matches, like so many bees in a hive. Pre-pandemic, any film that wanted to kindle an atmosphere of eeriness needed only to show one of the world’s great cities empty of people to instantly convey disaster. From I Am Legend to 28 Days Later, the depopulated city is axiomatic of catastrophe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olivia Laing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Hockney: The Arrival of Spring, Normandy 2020 review – pixels at dawn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/david-hockney-the-arrival-of-spring-normandy-2020-review-pixels-at-dawn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/david-hockney-the-arrival-of-spring-normandy-2020-review-pixels-at-dawn"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T12:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Academy, London
Stick-figure trees, synthetic blossoms, felt-pen colours – the power of Hockney’s daily iPad sketches of spring in Normandy is stunted by technology
Springtime with Hockney – what a glorious prospect! Just think of all those darling buds and greening hedgerows, dew on fresh grass, cherry blossom bursting into pink and white froth beneath brilliant blue skies: an ideal antidote to the winter’s lockdown. The subject matter of the artist’s new show is as simple as a child’s primer, and ought to spell out unqualified joy. But something stymies the pleasure of these images: namely, the method of their making.
In late 2019, at the age of 82, David Hockney moved to a timbered house in rural Normandy to observe the arrival of spring. He had already depicted the season’s wild beauty in his native Yorkshire with the magnificent charcoal drawings of 2014. Now he uses an iPad and stylus to make daily paintings of his French surroundings. The compositions are basic and stock: central tree, low horizon, distant hill, big bright sky; though the scene is occasionally viewed through an open door.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coming back better: New York City is reopening – but will it be fairer?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/new-york-city-reopening-pandemic-equitable-housing-police-mayor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/new-york-city-reopening-pandemic-equitable-housing-police-mayor"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T12:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, the city became the Covid capital of the world. Now, as cases have dropped and home sales increased, some think it’s the perfect time for progressive changes
Of any city in the US, perhaps none has been so marked by the pandemic as New York.
Early last year, the city became the Covid capital of the world, seeing 18,679 deaths in three months. Many from the city’s wealthiest zip codes moved to more spacious places, while those in low-income zip codes bore the brunt of the virus’s health and economic impacts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Aratani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moulting cicadas and a cat gas mask: the weekend’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/23/lost-volcano-boy-and-moulting-cicadas-the-weekends-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/23/lost-volcano-boy-and-moulting-cicadas-the-weekends-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T11:44:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Plimmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Live at Worthy Farm review – beautiful music marred by technical meltdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/23/live-at-worthy-farm-review-glastonburys-dodgy-pyramid-scheme-has-stunning-music</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/23/live-at-worthy-farm-review-glastonburys-dodgy-pyramid-scheme-has-stunning-music"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T11:04:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Access problems mean this could be remembered as a failure – but the filmed performances, from Coldplay’s twinkling spectacular to Kano’s dynamic theatre, are superb

Read: Technical fault blights Glastonbury streamed event

The worried messages start appearing on social media just before the Glastonbury livestream’s scheduled start time. Passwords given to punters, who have paid £20 for access, are registering on the website as invalid. It becomes increasingly apparent that those who can actually watch it are in the minority: most of the audience are locked out.
The company in charge of the stream – which has since apologised – seem to be the tech equivalent of the cheerful but useless Glastonbury steward who looks at your ticket, and confidently directs you to an entrance gate 26 miles away from the one you’re supposed to go to, a journey you undertake to the faint but distinctive sound of a band you really wanted to see, playing a very long way away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Petridis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I had to find them’: kidnapped filmmaker Mellissa Fung on her mission to find the Boko Haram girls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/i-had-to-find-them-kidnapped-filmmaker-on-her-personal-mission-to-find-the-boko-haram-girls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/i-had-to-find-them-kidnapped-filmmaker-on-her-personal-mission-to-find-the-boko-haram-girls"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T11:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being abducted on assignment in Afghanistan, journalist Mellissa Fung shares an intense bond with the teenage girls who were held captive by Boko Haram
The journalist and filmmaker Mellissa Fung is showing me her wound – or to be precise, the scar where her wound once was. It’s from the struggle with one of the Afghan rebels who, 12 years ago, kidnapped Fung near Kabul and held her in a pit in the ground for a month, a place she refers to simply, and rather chillingly as, “the hole”.
“In combat training they teach you not to fight back, but I played ice hockey as a kid so I couldn’t help it,” Fung says. “The guy had a knife so I learned my lesson.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leah McLaren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shops are open again – but when did high street fashion become so drab? | Rachel Connolly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/shops-open-high-street-fashion-drab-chains</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/shops-open-high-street-fashion-drab-chains"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T11:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With chains having become so risk-averse, it’s little wonder fashionistas are turning to secondhand shopping instead 
One of the strangest things about living in a time of supposedly limitless consumer options is the lack of genuine choice. There is a lot of stuff, and it is very easy to access, but much of it is essentially the same thing sold by multiple different retailers – or a close copy of something that was popular within the last few decades, years, or even months. A consumer landscape of blandness and endless repetition is sold to us as a world of infinite possibility; and I am never more aware of this than when I visit high-street clothes shops.
This is not new. Thanks to the constant, freakishly rapid copying of designer brands, the cross-pollination of trends between risk-averse, competing outlets and the tendency for umbrella companies to open sister shops that have an almost indistinguishable ethos to the original outlet, the world of high-street fashion has been derivative and uninspiring for years. But returning to shops recently, for the first time since the pandemic started, the sheer blandness of everything seemed more noticeable than it did before.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Connolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turkey’s leaders accused of ‘playing political games’ over Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/turkeys-leaders-accused-of-playing-political-games-over-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/turkeys-leaders-accused-of-playing-political-games-over-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T10:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anger has grown as politicians have seemingly prioritised political and economic issues over public health

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

On a boiling hot day in Istanbul last July, hundreds of thousands of people gathered outside the Hagia Sophia to celebrate President Recep Tayyip Erdoğan’s declaration that the historic building the modern state’s secular founders had made a museum would be turned back into a mosque.
The decision was widely perceived outside the country as a turning point in Turkey’s relationship with the west. In retrospect, the crowds in Sultanahmet Square represented another cultural shift – a change in how Turkey’s government dealt with the coronavirus pandemic after months of closed borders, and weekend and evening curfews.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan Turkey correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One year on: the BLM event that divided a Gloucestershire town]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/one-year-on-the-blm-event-that-divided-a-gloucestershire-town</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/one-year-on-the-blm-event-that-divided-a-gloucestershire-town"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:45:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When two young women decided to organise a celebration of BAME culture in Lydney, in the Forest of Dean, they hoped it would be welcomed. But the reality was rather different
Growing up, Khady Gueye was one of just a handful of black pupils at her school in the Forest of Dean in Gloucestershire. By the time she was a teenager, she was desperate to fit in and conform. And so when her nickname became “Nigs” – short for the N-word – Gueye didn’t challenge it.
Here, in the rural west of England, where she had been fed racist stereotypes of black people her whole life, she didn’t want to be labelled “the angry black girl” or the self-pitying minority who “couldn’t take a joke” or what was considered a “bit of light banter”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nosheen Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spy who got the cold shoulder: how the west abandoned its star defector]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/spy-who-got-the-cold-shoulder-how-the-west-abandoned-its-star-defector</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/spy-who-got-the-cold-shoulder-how-the-west-abandoned-its-star-defector"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michal Goleniewski exposed Soviet agents in the UK, but the CIA airbrushed him from history, says author
On a cold winter’s day, eight months before the Berlin Wall went up in 1961, the west’s most valuable double agent went on the run in East Berlin. Warned that his colleagues in both the Polish intelligence service and the KGB were on to him, Michal Goleniewski spent days crisscrossing the city, desperately trying to evade their surveillance for long enough to reach the US consulate – and defect to the west.
The day he managed it proved to be one of the most important of the cold war, a new book published later this month will argue. Drawing on previously unpublished documents, it reveals that Goleniewski exposed 1,693 Soviet bloc agents, including some of the most infamous spies of the period.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Ferguson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anger as Starmer intervenes to back closures at popular Primrose Hill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/anger-as-starmer-intervenes-to-back-closures-at-popular-primrose-hill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/anger-as-starmer-intervenes-to-back-closures-at-popular-primrose-hill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners say Labour leader should not follow Tory agenda over night curfews at north London park
One might expect that the leader of the opposition would have more to do than involve himself in a local council dispute over park gates. But to the shock of some locals, Sir Keir Starmer, MP for Holborn and St Pancras, has personally pushed for the erection of nine-foot tall aluminium barriers across Primrose Hill in north London.
Effectively, this means locking off London’s only permanently open royal park from the public on weekend evenings and maintaining its exclusivity for wealthy residents.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nosheen Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greek plan for mandatory neutering to tackle strays hits opposition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/greek-plan-for-mandatory-neutering-to-tackle-strays-hits-opposition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/greek-plan-for-mandatory-neutering-to-tackle-strays-hits-opposition"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:05:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed compulsory sterilisation seeks to improve animal welfare but raises concerns about pure breeds
Greece’s perennial problem of stray cats and dogs has been brought into sharp focus by outrage from vets and breeders over proposed legislation that seeks to make animal neutering mandatory.
The country has one of the largest stray feline and canine populations in the world, with the problem becoming ever more acute during the country’s prolonged debt crisis. Animal rights activists estimate that Athens alone may have as many as 2 million street cats and dogs. Management of strays falls to local municipalities.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should we stay or should we go? The return of free will has left us dithering | Gaby Hinsliff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/should-we-stay-or-should-we-go-the-return-of-free-will-has-left-us-dithering</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/should-we-stay-or-should-we-go-the-return-of-free-will-has-left-us-dithering"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After more than a year of obeying the rules, we’ve suddenly been allowed to make decisions again. It’s terrifying
It’s raining again. Streaming down the windows, sluicing through the streets, turning pub gardens into a soggy mockery of those still too nervous to come inside.
The idea of hot sand between the toes has never felt so achingly appealing, so it isn’t hard, on one level, to understand the planeload of hopeful Brits who took off for Mallorca from Manchester last week even though the island isn’t yet on the official “green list” approved for holidays.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaby Hinsliff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dream-like states: Ming Smith’s black and white photos – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/23/ming-smith-evidence-nicola-vassell-gallery-new-york</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/23/ming-smith-evidence-nicola-vassell-gallery-new-york"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T09:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ming Smith: Evidence will be the inaugural exhibit at the Nicola Vassell Gallery, and will include some of her most recognizable images – and others that have never been seen before. Smith was one of the few women in Kamoinge, a collective of Black photographers established in New York in 1963
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Irresponsible’ Australia trade deal will bring ruin for UK farmers, critics warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/irresponsible-australia-trade-deal-will-bring-ruin-for-uk-farmers-critics-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/23/irresponsible-australia-trade-deal-will-bring-ruin-for-uk-farmers-critics-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish National party says tariff-free imports of hormone-treated beef ‘would represent a bitter betrayal of rural communities’
The UK government was facing a backlash on Saturday over its plans for a trade deal with Australia, which have led to anger from farmers and environmentalists and calls for the Scottish secretary to resign.
Farming unions said that proposals for a zero-tariff and zero-quota trade deal would drive farmers out of business, while green groups said allowing Australian hormone-treated beef would breach the Conservatives’ manifesto commitments.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper and Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charter review is ‘significant moment’ for BBC, says Priti Patel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/charter-review-is-significant-moment-for-bbc-says-priti-patel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/23/charter-review-is-significant-moment-for-bbc-says-priti-patel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:42:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home secretary hints at big changes next year and refuses to rule out an external editorial board

Next year’s review of the BBC charter will be “a very, very significant moment” for the corporation’s governance structures, Priti Patel has said, giving the clearest indication yet that ministers are considering potentially sweeping changes to how it is run.
One option could involve imposing an outside editorial board on the BBC following a damning report about its handling of a 1995 interview with Diana, Princess of Wales, the home secretary said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker  Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the river to the sea, Jews and Arabs must forge a shared future | Kenan Malik]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/river-to-sea-jews-and-arabs-must-forge-shared-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/river-to-sea-jews-and-arabs-must-forge-shared-future"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:30:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Each side in this bitter conflict needs to recognise the other’s fears and aspirations
‘From the river to the sea, Palestine will be free,” runs a Palestinian slogan. Originally a call for a secular state in historic Palestine between the river Jordan and the Mediterranean, it soon became a sectarian slogan, deeply inflected by antisemitism. In the hands of Hamas, it is a call for the driving out of all Jews from the region; at best, a demand for ethnic cleansing, at worst for genocide.
The founding charter of Likud, Israel’s leading centre-right party, and the party of the prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, echoes the same words but from the opposite perspective: “Between the Sea and the Jordan there will only be Israeli sovereignty”. It has continually blocked any workable two-state solution.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenan Malik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turning shut-down shops into homes? It’ll be the developers who enjoy the bargains | Rowan Moore]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/turning-shut-down-shops-into-homes-developers-enjoy-the-bargains</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/23/turning-shut-down-shops-into-homes-developers-enjoy-the-bargains"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By relaxing rules on planning permission, the Tories are doing nothing for tenants or our high streets
Landowners of Britain, rejoice! Your government has not forgotten you. Magnanimous and generous as it is, it has dedicated the vast public resources at its disposal to a noble cause, that of increasing the value of the property you own. Planning is relaxed, taxation reduced and subsidies introduced, all with the effect of increasing the already high prices of land and buildings in this country.
The government doesn’t put it like this. Its departments and ministers say that “we can help the high street to adapt and thrive for the future” or that its policies “will help support the creation of much-needed homes” or that first-time buyers will have a better chance to get on the property ladder. But the most certain effect is that often substantial windfalls arrive in the balance sheets of those who already own.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rowan Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mad man to bad man: Jared Harris on his winning TV streak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/23/mad-man-to-bad-man-jared-harris-the-beast-must-die-the-crown-chernobyl-the-terror</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/23/mad-man-to-bad-man-jared-harris-the-beast-must-die-the-crown-chernobyl-the-terror"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The son of hellraiser Richard Harris has come into his own as one of the most sought-after actors of his generation. Now the star of Chernobyl and The Crown has a juicy role as a ‘creep’ in a new British thriller
In The Beast Must Die, a TV series adapted from a dusty 1930s thriller by Nicholas Blake (AKA the poet Cecil Day-Lewis), Jared Harris plays a man who may, or may not, have knocked down a child while driving his sports car too fast around the Isle of Wight. A nouveau riche horror show in chinos and deck shoes, his character appears to have not a single redeeming feature: if you heard his booming, entitled voice at an airport check-in, you’d pray all the way to the gate not to find him in the seat next to yours. But on screen, it’s a different story. Harris is the greatest televisio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Cooke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s cold and wet, but Scarborough is a beacon of normality for families]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/its-cold-and-wet-but-scarborough-is-a-beacon-of-normality-for-families</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/its-cold-and-wet-but-scarborough-is-a-beacon-of-normality-for-families"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T08:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The weather couldn’t dampen spirits as the Yorkshire resort’s hoteliers and guests celebrated the return of domestic travel
The sky was overcast, a chill wind blew in from the sea, and everyone was wearing coats. But for four-year-old Caitlin and two-year-old Jim, there was little to complain about – they were on a beach and they were building sandcastles.
For their parents, Lindsay and Jim Roger, a week’s holiday in the North Yorkshire seaside town of Scarborough was a blessed relief. Lindsay is a nurse who has been working on Covid wards, while Jim works in construction. As key workers with young children, lockdown has been difficult but they were “really pleased” to be able to travel again. “It’s just nice to get out and nice to see the sea,” Jim said. “It makes such a change from the house and the garden.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have a fear of returning to the office?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/23/do-you-have-a-fear-of-returning-to-the-office-and-will-workplace-life-ever-be-the-same</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/23/do-you-have-a-fear-of-returning-to-the-office-and-will-workplace-life-ever-be-the-same"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T07:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If they want us back, will we go? And how can managers make workplaces more enticing? Emma Beddington wonders if office life will ever be the same again
My husband is standing in the kitchen, asking me if his shirt is stained. He looks different: clean-shaven, sharper. I like it. “I think it’s just the light,” I say. “It’s fine.” He changes anyway, then comes in again, looking preoccupied. “I don’t know whether these trousers work,” he says. “What would you usually wear?” I ask. “My Japanese jeans,” he replies. “But I’ve been wearing them every day for about six months.” “No, not those,” I agree. “Have you found an Oyster card?”
He’s heading back to the office. It’s not even his own, but a client’s – his regular co-working space was another casualty of Covid. He went into an office on an almost daily basis for 20-plus years, but now doing so has the intimidating aura of a polar expedition. Will he get blisters wearing proper shoes? Can he locate a respectable notebook? Will he know what to say when he gets there?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Beddington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Civil war, ruin, raging poverty... but Assad is guaranteed to win Syria’s fake election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/civil-war-ruin-raging-poverty-but-assad-is-guaranteed-to-win-syrias-fake-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/civil-war-ruin-raging-poverty-but-assad-is-guaranteed-to-win-syrias-fake-election"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T07:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sham election this week is designed to give the president a veneer of legitimacy at home and abroad
The last time Syria held presidential elections, in 2014, there was no question over whether President Bashar al-Assad would win – but with opposition forces in control of the country’s cities, as well as the suburbs of Damascus, his future was still far from certain.
Seven years later, after the regime’s Russian and Iranian allies intervened and turned the tide of the war, most of Syria is now back under Assad’s grip. On Wednesday, his citizens will return to the polling booths for a sham democratic display designed to give the president a veneer of legitimacy both at home and abroad.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iran says it will end UN watchdog’s access to nuclear sites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/iran-says-it-will-end-un-watchdogs-access-to-nuclear-sites</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/iran-says-it-will-end-un-watchdogs-access-to-nuclear-sites"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T06:22:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A deal allowing the International Atomic Energy Agency to inspect images of nuclear facilities won’t be renewed
Iran’s parliament speaker has said that a three-month monitoring deal between Tehran and the UN nuclear watchdog has expired, escalating tensions amid diplomatic efforts in Vienna to save Tehran’s atomic accord with world powers.
Iran’s parliament speaker Mohammad Bagher Qalibaf’s comments, aired by state TV, further underscored the narrowing window for the US and others to reach terms with Iran.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: elegy for a lost New York community]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/the-big-picture-elegy-for-a-lost-new-york-community</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/23/the-big-picture-elegy-for-a-lost-new-york-community"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T06:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Al J Thompson reflects on the decline of Spring Valley, a vibrant African-Caribbean suburb eroded by gentrification

Spring Valley is a suburb of New York, 22 miles north of Manhattan. In 1996 it became home to the photographer Al J Thompson, who moved from Jamaica at the age of 16 to join his mother who had settled there. At the time, Spring Valley had, in Thompson’s memory, a thriving and vibrant African-Caribbean community, centred around Spring Valley Memorial Park, where there would be jerk chicken cook-outs and long games of cricket at weekends, and kids his age would play football until it was dark.
Back then, there were big plans to develop the land around the park with new social housing projects, building on the community that lived there, tackling some of the social problems that existed. In the years that followed, however, the social housing did not get built, the land around the park was sold to developers for private condominiums, and the familiar patterns of gentrification followed. The mom-and-pop stores on Main Street were taken over by chains, the kids who dreamed of opening music studios never raised the money. Families like Thompson’s – two-thirds of Spring Valley’s community had been black – were priced out and moved even further towards the city’s margins. By the time he returned to Spring Valley in 2017, African-Caribbean numbers had halved, there were no cricket matches or cook-outs, and the old faces he saw in the park had a more hopeless look.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump’s revenge: tilting of supreme court to the right poised to bear fruit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/23/us-supreme-court-trump-judicial-appointments</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/23/us-supreme-court-trump-judicial-appointments"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cases on voting rights, abortion and gun control will be a test of the ex-president’s laser-like focus on reshaping the judiciary
Donald Trump’s presidency was capricious and chaotic, but there was one issue on which he focused with laser-like discipline: tilting the judiciary to the right.
Now America is about to reap that harvest. In the next year the supreme court is set to consider healthcare, voting, LGBTQ rights, guns and, most explosively, abortion. The cases provide a vivid demonstration of how, after being rejected at the ballot box, conservative partisans could push their agenda through the courts instead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I allowed myself to feel guilty for a very long time’: the teenage cashier who took George Floyd’s $20 bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/christopher-martin-george-floyd-minneapolis-cup-foods</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/23/christopher-martin-george-floyd-minneapolis-cup-foods"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T06:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year ago, Christopher Martin took an allegedly counterfeit bill. The police were called, and shortly after, Floyd would be dead
Christopher Martin lived above a bricked grocery store in south Minneapolis, with a maroon awning and bold red signage that reads Cup Foods. So when a cashier’s position came up last year, he took it without thinking.
He quickly learned the regulars’ orders by heart, their specific tobacco preferences, their favored snacks. The job was more than just a paycheck. “A family, community base,” he remembered. “A lot of jokes and laughs.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughlandand Amudalat Ajasa in Minneapolis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Casa Madeira, London: ‘I love the Portuguese repertoire’ – restaurant review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/23/jay-rayner-restaurant-review-casa-madeira-london-i-love-the-portuguese-repertoire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/23/jay-rayner-restaurant-review-casa-madeira-london-i-love-the-portuguese-repertoire"/>
        <updated>2021-05-23T05:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the place to be for smoky grilled flavours and of course the dreamy custard tarts
Casa Madeira, 46b Albert Embankment, London SE1 7TL (020 7735 0592). Starters £4-£9.50, mains £7.50-£20.50, pastel de nata £1.50, wines from £14.99
Sometimes restaurants call to me. Sometimes I just don’t listen. Casa Madeira is one of those restaurants. I have driven past it hundreds of times. It is on my route home from the centre of London: south over Lambeth Bridge, right along Albert Embankment, and there it is tucked into the railway arches under the line from Waterloo. The pavement here, in the shadow of the MI6 building, edges a wide terrace given over to outside dining. Over the years I have glanced at the tables beneath the umbrellas as I have passed, at clusters of people leaning in over their plates, and thought that it looked like fun. I’ve thought I should go there. Then I haven’t gone there.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Rayner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Painting the memories evoked by motorways – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/22/painting-the-memories-evoked-by-motorways-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/22/painting-the-memories-evoked-by-motorways-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Jen Orpin’s father had a stroke in September 2015, the Manchester-based artist became very familiar with the journey to Surrey to visit him in hospital: M56, M6, M42, M40, M25. After he died, driving down these motorways evoked visceral feelings, which she has captured in a series of paintings. “I’ve had so many conversations with people recently,” she says, “about childhood memories and nostalgic feelings attached to a special bit of road or a bridge they used to go under, passing a tower or service station, all telling them they were close to home or a loved one.” 

Silent Cursors. Punctuated Journeys: Jen Orpin is at the Modernist, Manchester, until 26 June
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palestinians return to devastated homes as UN calls for Gaza dialogue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-return-to-damaged-homes-as-un-calls-for-gaza-dialogue</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-return-to-damaged-homes-as-un-calls-for-gaza-dialogue"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World leaders welcome ceasefire but Hamas and Israel’s Benjamin Netanyahu remain belligerent 
Tens of thousands of displaced Palestinians in Gaza have begun returning to their homes to inspect the devastation from 11 days of Israeli airstrikes in its war with Hamas.
Gaza City, on the Mediterranean coast, had been warped by the attacks, with holes in the skyline where high-rise buildings had collapsed, their remains sprawling into the street. Cars mounted pavements to avoid craters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Gaza City, Peter Beaumont and Bethan McKernan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How centuries of racist images came down in one year – a visual guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/22/racist-statues-monuments-removed-us-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/22/racist-statues-monuments-removed-us-world"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Black Lives Matter protests after George Floyd’s death forced leaders to re-examine the images in our everyday lives – in the US and beyond
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alvin Chang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The JavaScript Array Handbook – JS Array Methods Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>6098ce302cd0545b5e944d0b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-javascript-array-handbook/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In programming, an array is a collection of elements or items. Arrays store data as elements and retrieve them back when you need them.  The array data structure is widely used in all programming languages that support it. In this handbook, I'll teach you all about arrays in JavaScript. You'll]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richest nations agree to end support for coal production overseas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 countries reaffirm commitment to limit global heating to 1.5C after nearly two days of wrangling
The world’s richest nations have agreed to end their financial support for coal development overseas, in a major step towards phasing out the dirtiest fossil fuel.
After nearly two days of wrangling at a meeting of the G7 environment and energy ministers, hosted virtually by the UK on Thursday and Friday, all reaffirmed their commitment to limiting global heating to 1.5C, and committed to phasing out coal and fully decarbonising their energy sectors in the 2030s.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May gales help Britain set record for wind power generation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/may-gales-help-britain-set-record-for-wind-power-generation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/may-gales-help-britain-set-record-for-wind-power-generation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:15:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In early hours of Friday, windfarm turbines provided nearly two-thirds of Britain’s electricity
Powerful gusts of wind sweeping across Britain have helped the country reach a new all-time high for electricity generated from wind turbines.
A new record was set in the early hours of Friday for the share of wind power in the generation mix, with wind providing nearly two-thirds of Britain’s electricity, according to provisional data from National Grid.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG) From Scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK citizens: have you experienced any issues at EU border control?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:31:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from UK citizens who have encountered issues when travelling to other countries in Europe

Following reports that some EU citizens have been sent to immigration removal centres and held in airport detention rooms, we would like to hear from UK citizens about any issues they have faced at border control when travelling to Europe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life inside Gaza during 11 days of bombardment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian journalist Hazem Balousha describes living in, and reporting from, Gaza, under heavy bombardment until a ceasefire began on Friday, while historian Rashid Khalidi discusses the history of the Palestinian struggle for statehood
Anushka Asthana talks to Hazem Balousha, a Guardian correspondent who lives in Gaza. He describes living in, and reporting from, the strip, which was under heavy bombardment from last Monday until the agreement of a ceasefire, beginning early on Friday morning. The latest conflict started after Israel attempted to evict Palestinian residents from the Sheikh Jarrah neighbourhood in east Jerusalem and Israeli police stormed the Jerusalem compound which is home to al-Aqsa mosque after days of worsening clashes. Hamas issued an ultimatum for Israel to withdraw forces and as soon as that passed started firing rockets from Gaza into Israel. Hazem discusses the impact the bombardment has had on him, his family and other Gaza residents, and examines what would need to change for life to improve for them all.
Anushka also talks to Rashid Khalidi, a Palestinian American professor of modern Arab studies at Columbia university in New York and the author of the Hundred Years’ War on Palestine about the history of the Palestinian struggle for statehood.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hazem Balousha and Rashid Khalidi, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn CSS!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340933</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/learn/css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:51:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ooo look at this mighty SEO flex from Google: Learn CSS! Well deserved — this is great content. Twenty-three chapters taking you through all the fundamentals of CSS with extra content, like relevant podcasts, interactive examples, and even quizzes to …
The post Learn CSS! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular 11 Tutorial: Code a Project from Scratch]]></title>
        <id>60a6b3ab906c5207e3a7f5fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/angular-11-tutorial-code-a-project-from-scratch/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angular is one of the most popular web frameworks. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create an Angular 11 project from scratch. It uses a public API to create a game database website. You will gain a great foundation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Modern C++ by Building an Audio Plugin]]></title>
        <id>60a694ab906c5207e3a7f544</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-modern-cpp-by-building-an-audio-plugin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of C++ courses teach you how to build toy projects with no real-world application. But it can often be more helpful to write programs people would actually use. We just released a 5-hour C++ course that will teach you how to write modern C++ code by building an]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Started with Version Control Using Git]]></title>
        <id>60a4b5c7906c5207e3a7e2bb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/get-started-with-version-control-and-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, you'll learn what version control is and how you can contribute to open-source projects using Git.  We'll get through the fundamentals of Git and I'll give you the knowledge that is indispensable for any web developer. What is Git?Git is a version control software which lets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn JavaScript - A Free 7-hour Interactive Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60a36742906c5207e3a7da6e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-javascript-interactive-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last four months, I have recorded what is probably the most interactive JavaScript course that has ever been created. The reason I have done this is because I often see new coders fall into the same pitfalls again and again when trying to learn JavaScript, with the most]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340715</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/can-we-create-a-resize-hack-with-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you follow new developments in CSS, you’ve likely heard of the impending arrival of container queries. We’re going to look at the basics here, but if you’d like another look, check out Una’s “Next Gen CSS: @container” article. …
The post Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jhey Tompkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fit-content and fit-content()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340897</id>
        <link href="https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2021/04/fitcontent_and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s some hardcore deep-dive CSS nerdery from PPK. If you can wrap your mind around min-content (the smallest an element can be based on the content it contains) and max-content (the largest the content of an element can push it) …
The post fit-content and fit-content() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis behind drastic drop in Arctic wildlife populations – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Native shorebirds and caribou among species at risk as survival strategies are upended
A drastic drop in caribou and shorebird populations is a reflection of the dire changes unfolding on the Arctic tundra, according to a new report from the Arctic Council. 
The terrestrial Arctic spans approximately 2.7m sq miles (7m sq km), marked by extreme cold, drought, strong winds and seasonal darkness. Species living in this environment have adapted to thrive in the harsh conditions. But the climate crisis has upended such survival strategies, according to the State of the Arctic Terrestrial Biodiversity report, published by the council’s Conservation of Arctic Flora and Fauna (Caff) working group.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Dickie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you attended a large-scale test event in England?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from the people who attended these events about their experiences
In April, the government launched their scheme to pilot large-scale events in England to test their safety before restrictions are eased on mass gatherings.
The majority of rules on social contact are set to be removed by 21 June, but this is dependent on cases, deaths and hospital admissions continuing to fall.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your favourite memories from the Glastonbury festival]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:25:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the festival gearing up for the Live at Worthy Farm live stream this weekend, we want to hear your most cherished moments from past years
One year off, we could handle. After all, Glastonbury often has a fallow year to let the land, and the workers, have a bit of a rest. But two cancellations of the festival in a row is really quite depressing, leaving us and thousands of ticket holders dolefully marking out June 2022 in the diaries for the next possible trip.
But as well as September’s planned one-day concert Equinox, there’s something to tide us over: Live at Worthy Farm, a five-hour livestreamed concert happening on Saturday, beginning 7pm in the UK – Coldplay, Damon Albarn, Haim, George Ezra, Michael Kiwanuka, Wolf Alice, Idles, Jorja Smith, Kano, Róisín Murphy and Honey Dijon are performing, plus there’s spoken word from PJ Harvey, Jarvis Cocker, Kae Tempest, George the Poet, Kurupt FM, Little Amal and Michael Eavis himself.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rio de Janeiro’s deadliest police raid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T02:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Latin American correspondent Tom Phillips visits Jacarezinho, one of Rio’s biggest favelas, the day after police carried out the deadliest raid in the city’s history
Anushka Asthana talks to Tom Phillips about the police raid in Jacarezinho favela, in the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro. On 6 May police stormed the favela, targeting one of the city’s largest drug gangs, known as Red Command. Twenty-seven men were shot dead by police and one police officer was killed. Police, politicians and some parts of the media called the operation a “surgical” success. Human rights activists, community leaders and residents of the favela have described it as a massacre and are now calling for justice.
Tom tells Anushka about visiting the favela and meeting the residents the day after the attack. Rio’s favelas have suffered countless horrors since the drug conflict began to intensify in the mid-1980s and cocaine and war-grade weapons began flooding communities such as Jacarezinho. Since then, thousands of people – the majority young black men – have lost their lives to the relentless, corruption-fuelled skirmishes between police, drug traffickers and, increasingly, paramilitary gangs with ties to the state.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Tom Phillips, produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340731</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Public Beta of the Notion API dropped! Woot! Here’s their guide. I’ve been a Notion user and fan for a long time, for both personal and professional team use. They even sponsored a few videos around here a …
The post Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Selectors to Style Your Web Page]]></title>
        <id>60a341f5906c5207e3a7da61</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-css-selectors-to-style-webpage/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS selectors are one of the most important parts of CSS. They give you the ability to target HTML elements on your web page that you want to style. Without CSS selectors, you wouldn't be able to style your page to look how you want. Thankfully CSS selectors have been]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Web3? The Decentralized Internet of the Future Explained]]></title>
        <id>60a42386906c5207e3a7dfe2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet is going through a paradigm shift. Learn the differences between Web2 and Web3, and why many developers and companies are shifting their approach in building apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Optimize for Change in Software Development]]></title>
        <id>60a469ec906c5207e3a7e1b9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-optimize-for-change-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine that you work at Magic Money Corp, which runs on just three lines of JavaScript: let input = { step1: 'collect underpants' } doStuff(input)  profit(input) // $$$!!! Now imagine that something's wrong with doStuff and you need to take it down for maintenance. What happens if you temporarily comment out the second]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340692</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svg-loader-a-different-way-to-work-with-external-svg/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVGs are awesome: they are small, look sharp on any scale, and can be customized without creating a separate file. However, there is something I feel is missing in web standards today: a way to include them as an external …
The post svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shubham Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple versus Epic: how the Fortnite app led to a legal showdown - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Apple takes on games developer and Fortnite creator Epic, UK technology editor Alex Hern describes a battle of the tech titans that could reshape the app industry
The video game Fortnite has become a cultural phenomenon in recent years with up to 100 million users a month logging in to play the free online game. They parachute down on to an island with 99 other players and the last one standing is the winner. 
But for users of iPhones and iPads, the wildly popular game has been unavailable ever since it was ejected from the App store. It followed an attempt by Epic, the maker of Fortnite, to offer its own payment service for players, with a 20% cut in cost if they decided to bypass Apple’s in-app purchases. Epic’s founder, Tim Sweeney, has long been vocally critical of Apple’s requirement that the company pay 30% of its iPhone revenues as fees for selling in-game currency.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Alex Hern; produced by Sami Kent and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break into Ethereum, Crypto, and Web3 as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60a53182906c5207e3a7e588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/breaking-into-ethereum-crypto-web3-as-a-developer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I've been talking about my move into the Web3, Ethereum, and crypto space since making the switch from a traditional web, mobile, and cloud background. Since making that move, a shocking number of people have reached out to me who are also thinking about doing the same.  It's really]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinned Audio WordPress Theme]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/pinned-audio-wordpress-theme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m afraid I have to start this with a whole backstory, as the journey here is the point, not so much the theme.
A fella wrote to me a while back outlining a situation he was in. His company has …
The post Pinned Audio WordPress Theme appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance Development Pricing Guide – Should Freelancers Bill by the Hour?]]></title>
        <id>60a3780f906c5207e3a7db5f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-different-ways-to-charge-for-a-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you offer your services as a freelance developer, you have a major say in how you price your project.  But how do you go about charging for a website project? "Well, I just bill by the hour and send an invoice every week or month." ...I hear you say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Neon Text With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340420</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-neon-text-with-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neon text can add a nice, futuristic touch to any website. I’ve always loved the magic of neon signs, and wanted to recreate them using CSS. I thought I’d share some tips on how to do it! In this article, …
The post How to Create Neon Text With CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia O'Dwyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>