<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-22T00:29:55.107Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-22T00:29:55.107Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obama backs Manchin’s voting rights compromise proposal – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/21/joe-biden-climate-change-coronavirus-covid-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/21/joe-biden-climate-change-coronavirus-covid-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T00:09:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-president urges Republicans to join Democrats to pass legislation
Biden misses target of 80m vaccines to be sent around the world
How the rogue Trump DoJ trashed legal and political norms

 1.00am BST 
That’s all for today, thanks for following along. Some key links and developments: 
 12.41am BST 
New York City’s contentious mayoral primary campaign is coming to a close, with voters heading to the polls tomorrow to choose the Democratic nominee, who is expected to become the next mayor in the November general election. 
The former presidential candidate Andrew Yang was initially a frontrunner in the race to be New York’s next mayor, but recent polls have shown that he has slipped. 
 Related: Early frontrunner Andrew Yang slips in New York mayoral poll  
 Related: New York City’s tumultuous mayor’s race closes as voters struggle to choose 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin (now) and Amanda Holpuch (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raiders’ Carl Nassib becomes first active NFL player to come out as gay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/nfl-raiders-carl-nassib-comes-out-as-gay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/nfl-raiders-carl-nassib-comes-out-as-gay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T00:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Defensive end makes announcement in Instagram video: ‘I finally feel comfortable enough to get it off my chest’
Carl Nassib has become the first active NFL player to come out as gay, making the announcement in a video posted to Instagram on Monday. 
“I’m at my house here in West Chester, Pennsylvania,” said Nassib, a defensive end for the Las Vegas Raiders. “I just wanted to take a quick moment to say that I’m gay. I’ve been meaning to do this for a while now but finally feel comfortable enough to get it off my chest. I really have the best life, I’ve got the best family, friends and job a guy can ask for.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Mother Load review – moving audio play gives birth to all the feelings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/22/the-mother-load-review-audio-drama-lynne-radley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/22/the-mother-load-review-audio-drama-lynne-radley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T23:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Available online
Lynda Radley’s drama about three women who meet in an antenatal class captures the love and fear, the comedy and terror of motherhood in all its contradictory reality
Lynda Radley’s audio play about first-time motherhood starts with a bunch of stereotypes around parenting and gradually, movingly, strips everything away. We open in an antenatal class with three very different women: architect and anxious mother-to-be Cat (Wendy Seager); twentysomething wellness enthusiast Rowan (Anna Russell-Martin); and the highly strung Mobina (Nalini Chetty) who has been to every antenatal class in the book. As the babies arrive one by one, meticulous birthing plans are swept aside and the messy reality of early motherhood is ushered in with conviction, warmth and, thankfully, plenty of humour.
The play, presented by Edinburgh’s Royal Lyceum and Pitlochry Festival theatre for the Sound Stage series, is split into three parts. Each mum narrates her own section, sharing her private thoughts and fears. Radley captures the strangely competitive atmosphere that can emerge in antenatal classes, which Cat describes brilliantly as: “like The Hunger Games with haemorrhoids.” As Cat whispers to her unborn baby, the intensely private relationship between a mother and her “bean” is conjured into life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miriam Gillinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drinking coffee may cut risk of chronic liver disease, study suggests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/22/drinking-coffee-may-cut-risk-of-chronic-liver-disease-study-suggests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/22/drinking-coffee-may-cut-risk-of-chronic-liver-disease-study-suggests"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T23:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK analysis shows people who drank coffee had 49% reduced risk of dying from the condition
From espresso to instant, coffee is part of the daily routine for millions. Now research suggests the brew could be linked to a lower chance of developing or dying from chronic liver disease.
Chronic liver disease is a major health problem around the world. According to the British Liver Trust, liver disease is the third leading cause of premature death in the UK, with deaths having risen 400% since 1970.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Met police makes second arrest after BBC’s Nick Watt confronted on street]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/22/met-police-makes-second-arrest-after-bbcs-nick-watt-confronted-on-street</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/22/met-police-makes-second-arrest-after-bbcs-nick-watt-confronted-on-street"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T23:01:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Man, 62, held in south London police station after footage shared online showed reporter being harassed
Police have arrested a second man on suspicion of harassing the BBC journalist Nick Watt after footage emerged online last week of the political editor being confronted and chased by a group of protesters.
The Metropolitan police said a 62-year-old man was being held in custody in a south London police station on suspicion of an offence under section 4a of the Public Order Act, which covers using threatening, abusive or insulting words or behaviour towards another person with the intention to cause them harassment, alarm or distress.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaamil Ahmed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK aid cut behind $284m fall in global  humanitarian spending]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/22/uk-aid-cut-behind-284m-fall-in-global-humanitarian-spending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/22/uk-aid-cut-behind-284m-fall-in-global-humanitarian-spending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T23:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Estimated UK cut of $900m offsets increases by others nations, according to annual Global Humanitarian Assistance Report 
International humanitarian spending by public donors dropped by $284m (£204m) between 2019 and 2020, and UK the government cut its humanitarian funding by the most of any major western country, according to a new report from the independent Development Initiatives has found.
Its annual Global Humanitarian Assistance Report is regarded as one of the best sources for objective statistics on aid trends and humanitarian needs, and the report highlights the extraordinary pressure now being placed on UN-coordinated humanitarian appeals.The total UK cut – put at $900m – offsets increases by others. Humanitarian assistance can be both multilateral or bilateral, but does not cover all overseas aid designed to provide long-term resilience. The UK has cut its large aid budget due to an unprecedented cut in the size of the economy and priority given to dealing with the impact of Covid in the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN warns of worst ‘cascade of human rights setbacks in our lifetimes’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/un-warns-of-worst-cascade-of-human-rights-setbacks-in-our-lifetimes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/un-warns-of-worst-cascade-of-human-rights-setbacks-in-our-lifetimes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T22:29:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rights chief calls for concerted global action, citing recent violations in China, Russia and Ethiopia
The UN rights chief has called for concerted action to recover from the worst global deterioration of rights she had seen, highlighting the situation in China, Russia and Ethiopia among others.
“To recover from the most wide-reaching and severe cascade of human rights setbacks in our lifetimes, we need a life-changing vision, and concerted action,” Michelle Bachelet told the opening of the UN Human Rights Council’s 47th session.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Geneva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mexico border city rocked as weekend of gang violence leaves 19 dead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/mexico-reynosa-gang-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/mexico-reynosa-gang-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T22:06:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President: 15 victims were innocent bystanders in Reynosa
Other four were suspected gunmen who fired indiscriminately

Fear has invaded the Mexican border city of Reynosa after a weekend of violence in which 19 people were killed, including taxis drivers, workers and a nursing student, and security forces responded with operations that left four suspects dead.
This city across the border from McAllen, Texas, is a key trafficking point, and has long been accustomed to cartel violence. President Andrés Manuel López Obrador said on Monday that evidence indicated that 15 of the victims were innocent bystanders. The other four dead were suspected gunmen from a group that drove into the northern border city of Reynosa and opened fire indiscriminately.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Ciudad Victoria</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Exit Vim – Vim Save and Quit Command Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60c81f774dc1a607ed7b2f66</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-exit-vim/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:52:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've been using Vim since the first year I started coding. For all the IDEs/editors that I have used, the Vim plugin is always the very first plugin that I install. I know that Vim can be challenging to work in for people who are not familiar with it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-hit industries will need extra £50m after furlough ends, says Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/covid-hit-industries-will-need-extra-50m-after-furlough-ends-says-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/covid-hit-industries-will-need-extra-50m-after-furlough-ends-says-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak urged to delay end of furlough scheme until restrictions on gatherings can be lifted fully

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The industries most affected by the UK’s delayed reopening will need to find almost £50m to cover wages once the government’s furlough scheme is cut back on 1 July, according to analysis by the Labour party.
Hospitality firms and cultural and arts businesses, which still have large numbers of workers on furlough, will need to cover the higher cost of keeping workers on the scheme even though they have no choice but to limit the number of customers they serve over the next month or are forced to remain shut.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rick and Morty series five review – proof that Elon Musk must be stopped!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/21/rick-and-morty-series-five-review-proof-that-elon-musk-must-be-stopped</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/21/rick-and-morty-series-five-review-proof-that-elon-musk-must-be-stopped"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you are plotting to monkey around with the space-time continuum, at least let it result in a show as funny, clever and brilliant as Rick and Morty
Nerdy Morty is steering his flying saucer back to Earth, escaping the ectoplasmic thing that was menacing him and his mad uncle at the end of season four. Suddenly, the steering wheel comes off. Flames lick his craft and the noise – my God, the noise – of beeping alarm systems portends what rocket scientists call “nothing good”.
Do flying saucers even have steering wheels, you ask? Spare me your plodding literalism, I reply. Morty, convinced he and his comatose, sociopathicscience whiz of an uncle Rick are going to die on re-entry, makes his last phone call. What nonsense, you object: I can’t get mobile coverage in the kitchen, let alone outer space. Again, ditch the scepticism, you plum.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent body should run Windrush compensation scheme, Labour says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/independent-body-should-run-windrush-compensation-scheme-labour-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/independent-body-should-run-windrush-compensation-scheme-labour-says"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Systemic mismanagement’ by Home Office has led to complaints over delays and low offers to claimants
Labour has called on the government to remove the handling of the much-criticised Windrush compensation scheme from the Home Office so it can be run by a neutral, independent body, after two years of complaints from claimants about delays and low compensation offers.
In a letter to the home secretary, Priti Patel, the shadow home secretary, Nick Thomas-Symonds, said there had been “systemic mismanagement” of the “unacceptably slow” scheme, and recommended that placing it under an independent body would “help restore faith in the process and get compensation quickly to people who have been so appallingly treated”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s Mount and Chilwell isolating after Scotland’s Gilmour tests positive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/england-mount-and-chilwell-isolating-after-interacting-with-gilmour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/england-mount-and-chilwell-isolating-after-interacting-with-gilmour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland’s Gilmour, also of Chelsea, tests positive for Covid
Kyle Walker and Harry Maguire set to face Czech Republic

Gareth Southgate’s plans for England’s final Euro 2020 group phase tie against the Czech Republic at Wembley on Tuesday night were thrown into turmoil after two of his expected starters – Ben Chilwell and Mason Mount – were forced to self-isolate.
The Football Association took the measure as a precaution after the pair were deemed to have been in close contact with the Scotland midfielder Billy Gilmour, who returned a positive Covid test on Monday morning. The contact is believed to have taken place in the Wembley tunnel after last Friday’s 0-0 draw. All three play their club football at Chelsea.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python List Methods – append( ) vs extend( ) in Python Explained with Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>60bce157acb62507dd1d9f11</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-list-methods-append-vs-extend/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:25:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're working with Python lists, you often need to combine data from multiple lists. So how do you do that? In this tutorial, we'll see the different ways you can combine data from multiple lists. We'll also learn how the list methods append() and extend() work through simple examples.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342887</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/new-responsive/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una is calling it the new responsive. A nod to the era we were most certainly in, the era of responsive design. Where responsive design was fluid grids, flexible media, and media queries, the new responsive is those things …
The post Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Romelu Lukaku seals Belgium win to leave Finland on the brink of exit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/finland-belgium-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/finland-belgium-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:14:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glory comes in many forms, some of them very strange indeed – and so too does disappointment. The Finland coach Markku Kanerva had described this as the biggest game in his nation’s history and for 75 minutes, it looked as though they were on their way to the knockouts. It had not exactly been desperate defiance – there was too little riding on it for Belgium for that – but still, progress through the group at their first tournament would have been a remarkable achievement.
 Related: England’s Mount and Chilwell isolating after interacting with Gilmour 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denmark roar past Russia to set up Euro 2020 last-16 clash with Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/russia-denmark-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/russia-denmark-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:03:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Few teams have ever deserved to make progress as much as Denmark did on a thrilling night in Copenhagen. Players who, just nine days ago, were traumatised to see Christian Eriksen suffer cardiac arrest in the middle of their first match produced a momentous performance on the same pitch, emerging as glorious victors over Russia to set up a last 16 showdown with Wales.
Mikkel Damsgaard and Yusuf Poulsen ignited celebrations before Artem Dzyuba put them on pause by converting a penalty and news filtered through that the group’s other match, between Belgium and Finland, was not going the way the Danes needed. But that changed as Group B reached a dramatic climax and Denmark confirmed second spot thanks to magnificent goals by Andreas Christensen and Joakim Mæhle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Doyle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Redux by Making a Counter Application]]></title>
        <id>60cccd6e4dc1a607ed7b4f81</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-redux-by-making-a-counter-application/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Redux is a state management library for front end applications. Developers commonly use it with React through the react-redux package, but it can also stand alone – so you can use it in any front end framework or library, including Vanilla JavaScript.  Redux can really be intimidating at first. It might]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tory MPs accused of adding fuel to ‘culture war’ in education report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/21/tory-mps-accused-of-adding-fuel-to-culture-war-in-education-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/21/tory-mps-accused-of-adding-fuel-to-culture-war-in-education-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative-dominated committee warns schools could be breaking the law by promoting terms like ‘white privilege’
White working-class pupils have been let down by decades of neglect in the English education system, according to a controversial MPs’ report which warns that schools could be breaking the law by promoting “divisive” terminology like “white privilege”.
MPs on the Conservative-dominated Commons education committee examined why poor white children underperform compared to other disadvantaged groups, and rejected the government’s view that poverty is solely to blame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[George confident Saracens’ Lions contingent can make immediate impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jamie-george-confident-saracens-british-and-irish-lions-contingent-can-make-immediate-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jamie-george-confident-saracens-british-and-irish-lions-contingent-can-make-immediate-impact"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five players joined up with squad after club’s promotion
George likely to feature in warm-up match against Japan

Jamie George believes Saracens’ British & Irish Lions contingent will make an immediate impact after bolstering the ranks in Jersey thanks to a specially tailored fitness regime at their club, with the England hooker set to be put straight into the squad to face Japan at Murrayfield.
George arrived at the Lions pre-tour camp in Jersey on Monday, along with clubmates Owen Farrell, Maro Itoje, Mako Vunipola and Elliot Daly, 24 hours after cementing Saracens’ return to the Premiership. Finn Russell also arrived on Monday while Kyle Sinckler and Tom Curry joined up on Sunday, leaving Exeter’s quartet as the only players still absent.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US Covid deaths dip below 300 a day for first time since March last year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/21/us-covid-deaths-dip</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/21/us-covid-deaths-dip"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T20:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Approaching milestone of 150 million Americans vaccinated but Biden falls short of target to send 80m doses abroad

US politics – live coverage

US deaths from Covid-19 have dipped below 300 a day for the first time since March last year during the first wave of the pandemic.
Data from federal sources also showed the drive to put shots in arms at home approaching an encouraging milestone: 150 million Americans fully vaccinated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda Holpuch and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morrisons shouldn’t capitulate in another depressing takeover saga]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/21/morrisons-shouldnt-capitulate-in-another-depressing-takeover-saga</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/21/morrisons-shouldnt-capitulate-in-another-depressing-takeover-saga"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T20:10:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Latest private equity’s raid on the stock market looks like buyout in which staff and shoppers will be an after-thought
The stock market is brutal and moves quickly to the main question. If 230p-a-share is not enough to persuade the directors of Morrisons to roll over and accept private equity’s money, what is?
The working assumption is that the “killing ground”, in the investment banker’s charming lingo, lies around the 260p mark – enough to allow the board to claim a stupendous uplift on last week’s 178p, and not too much to jeopardise Clayton, Dubilier & Rice’s debt-heavy financial model. Morrisons’ closing share on Monday of 240p fits the script: the market expects a deal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Armani’s menswear confirms in-person future of Milan fashion week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/21/armani-menswear-confirms-in-person-future-of-milan-fashion-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/21/armani-menswear-confirms-in-person-future-of-milan-fashion-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:33:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Italian designer says fashion cannot survive in exclusively virtual form
Such is Giorgio Armani’s eagerness for getting back to holding physical fashion shows that not even a nasty fall resulting in a fractured shoulder and 17 stitches 20 days ago could stop him from holding his first show in 16 months on Monday evening in Milan.
Addressing the rumours that he had recently been in hospital, the 86-year-old designer explained to waiting press after taking his bow at his spring/summer 2022 menswear show that he fell down the stairs while leaving the cinema but wanted to reassure everyone that he was fine and still raring to go.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scarlett Conlon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artist considers suing Royal Academy in ‘transphobia’ row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/21/artist-jess-de-wahls-considers-suing-royal-academy-in-transphobia-row</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/21/artist-jess-de-wahls-considers-suing-royal-academy-in-transphobia-row"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:28:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jess de Wahls’ work no longer available in RA gift shop after views she expressed were deemed transphobic 
An artist whose work will no longer be available in the Royal Academy’s gift shop after views she expressed in a blogpost were deemed transphobic has said she is considering legal action against the institution.
The RA confirmed Jess de Wahls’ embroidery work would no longer be stocked after a 2019 post – in which she outlined her views on gender identity politics – was determined to be transphobic by the RA.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lanre Bakare Arts and culture correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative MPs put pressure on government to scrap planning reforms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/conservative-mps-put-pressure-on-government-to-scrap-planning-reforms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/conservative-mps-put-pressure-on-government-to-scrap-planning-reforms"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:27:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour has called new bill a ‘developers’ charter’, while Tories fear it cost them the Chesham and Amersham byelection
Communities should not have new housing shoved down their throats with no right to object, Conservative MPs have urged as they upped pressure on the government to scrap some of its controversial planning reforms.
They went public with their concerns after the Tories lost the Chesham and Amersham byelection last week, a defeat partly blamed on how planning changes and HS2 would affect green belt areas such as the Buckinghamshire seat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italy’s PM says Euro 2020 final should be moved to Rome due to UK Covid rates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/italys-pm-says-euro-2020-final-should-be-moved-in-rome-due-to-uk-covid-rates</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/italys-pm-says-euro-2020-final-should-be-moved-in-rome-due-to-uk-covid-rates"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:03:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Mario Draghi’s remarks, head of Italian football federation says they are not seeking to move match
Italy’s prime minister Mario Draghi has said he wants the final of the European football championships to be held in Rome rather than in London, because of Britain’s rising number of coronavirus infections.
Asked during a news conference in Berlin if he was in favour of the move, Draghi said: “Yes … I will try to stop the final being held in a country where infections are rising quickly.” 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Tondo in Palermo and Philip Oltermann in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Burnham calls on Nicola Sturgeon to justify travel ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/burnham-calls-on-nicola-sturgeon-to-justify-travel-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/burnham-calls-on-nicola-sturgeon-to-justify-travel-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greater Manchester mayor says move ‘totally disproportionate’ given case rate in Bolton is lower than Dundee

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Andy Burnham has called on Nicola Sturgeon to justify the “totally disproportionate” travel ban between the north-west of England and Scotland in an open letter.
The mayor of Greater Manchester intervened after Sturgeon extended the ban on non-essential travel – it was already in place for Bolton and Blackburn with Darwen – to Manchester and Salford on Friday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin and Severin Carrell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legacy of toxic leaded petrol lingers in air in London, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/legacy-of-toxic-leaded-petrol-lingers-in-air-in-london-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/legacy-of-toxic-leaded-petrol-lingers-in-air-in-london-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most cities likely to be affected by the pollutant, which is particularly harmful to children’s brains
Toxic lead from petrol that was banned 20 years ago still lingers in the air in London, a study has shown, with researchers saying the legacy of leaded fuels is likely to hang over most cities.
While levels are much lower than at their peak in the 1980s, they remain far above natural background levels. Lead is extremely poisonous and there is no safe amount of exposure. It is of particular concern for children, as it damages their developing brains and ability to learn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Future Cargo review – sci-fi show reflects these strange times back to us]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/21/future-cargo-review-lowry-salford-requardt-rosenberg</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/21/future-cargo-review-lowry-salford-requardt-rosenberg"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lowry, Salford
Three androgynous, silver-clad dancers loop and glide through a retrofuturist sealed set in Requardt and Rosenberg’s spaced-out touring production
Shows that are distributed physically and not digitally remain something of a rarity these days, but Frauke Requardt and David Rosenberg’s Future Cargo, performed inside a 40ft haulage truck that houses its set and tech, is designed for road transport. Inspired by sci-fi, this touring production is not so much futuristic as endearingly retro and analogue, with an opening voiceover about UFO sightings and alien landings that sets a 50s B-movie mood. True, there is some 21st-century tech involved: the audience, seated outside, tune in to a binaural soundtrack through headphones, and I imagine the lighting, which flushes the inside with shades of teal, fuchsia and lilac, uses up-to-date software. But the main theatrical trick is just a mechanical travelator that lets the three dancers glide along the length of the truck before they run round the back to start the loop again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sanjoy Roy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebecca Hendin on Dido Harding’s bid to head the NHS – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/21/rebecca-hendin-on-dido-hardings-bid-to-head-the-nhs-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/21/rebecca-hendin-on-dido-hardings-bid-to-head-the-nhs-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Hendin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microbes and solar power ‘could produce 10 times more food than plants’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/microbes-and-solar-power-could-produce-10-times-more-food-than-plants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/microbes-and-solar-power-could-produce-10-times-more-food-than-plants"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T19:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The system would also have very little impact on the environment, in contrast to livestock farming, scientists say
Combining solar power and microbes could produce 10 times more protein than crops such as soya beans, according to a new study.
The system would also have very little impact on the environment, the researchers said, in stark contrast to livestock farming which results in huge amounts of climate-heating gases as well as water pollution.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venice may be put on endangered list if cruise ships not banned, says Unesco]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/venice-may-be-put-on-endangered-list-if-cruise-ships-not-banned-says-unesco</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/venice-may-be-put-on-endangered-list-if-cruise-ships-not-banned-says-unesco"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UN heritage agency says the historic centre is in danger if ships are not diverted to another port
The UN art heritage agency has said it would examine a proposal to put Venice on its endangered list if the lagoon city does not issue a permanent ban on cruise ships docking there, according to the Italian news agency Ansa.
Unesco said on Monday it will discuss the issue at its plenary session on July 16-31. If approved, the agency could demand urgent action by the Italian government by next February.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Tondo in Palermo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Private members’ club Soho House plans to float on NYSE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/private-members-club-soho-house-plans-float-nyse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/private-members-club-soho-house-plans-float-nyse"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:53:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Owner of 28 clubs worldwide has told its 100,000 members they will be offered  chance to purchase shares
Soho House is to float on the New York Stock Exchange at a potential valuation of $3bn (£2.2bn), as the private members’ club seeks to take advantage of a post-pandemic global business recovery.
The company – which owns 28 Soho Houses worldwide and a clutch of other businesses including Soho Works, Soho Home, The Ned and Scorpios Beach Club – has contacted its more than 100,000 members worldwide offering them the chance to purchase shares.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unesco says Liverpool waterfront should lose heritage status]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/unesco-says-liverpool-waterfront-should-lose-heritage-status-over-skyscrapers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/unesco-says-liverpool-waterfront-should-lose-heritage-status-over-skyscrapers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:53:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Committee report says city should be removed from world heritage list after ignoring advice on skyscrapers
Unesco has recommended Liverpool waterfront be removed from the list of world heritage sites after the city ignored its advice over the development of skyscrapers.
The United Nations heritage organisation will vote at its 44th annual conference next month as to whether to delist the historic port, which was granted Unesco world heritage status in 2004.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sanjeev Gupta’s Jaguar Land Rover supplier asks for time to talk to buyers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/sanjeev-gupta-jaguar-land-rover-supplier-asks-for-time-to-talk-to-buyers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/21/sanjeev-gupta-jaguar-land-rover-supplier-asks-for-time-to-talk-to-buyers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:53:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liberty Aluminium Technologies, part of GFG metals empire, could reportedly collapse within days
Part of Sanjeev Gupta’s metal empire that faces the threat of administration has asked its bankers to give it time to try to negotiate with four potential buyers.
It is understood that Liberty Aluminium Technologies, a supplier of cast parts to Jaguar Land Rover, could be forced into administration within days if its main bank, Close Brothers, does not agree to give it more time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police name suspected killer of Gracie Spinks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/police-name-suspected-killer-of-gracie-spinks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/police-name-suspected-killer-of-gracie-spinks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:34:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Sellers, 35, whose body was found nearby, was a former colleague said to have been infatuated with Spinks
The suspected killer of Gracie Spinks found dead in an apparent murder-suicide has been named by police as Michael Sellers.
Spinks was found on Friday morning with serious injuries in the paddocks where she kept her horse near Duckmanton in Derbyshire and died at the scene. Police confirmed she was killed by a man she knew who was found dead in a field less than a mile away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray Midlands correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dom’s blog of last resort (a bloke has to scrape a living somehow) | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/doms-blog-of-last-resort-a-bloke-has-to-scrape-a-living-somehow-dominic-cummings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/doms-blog-of-last-resort-a-bloke-has-to-scrape-a-living-somehow-dominic-cummings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:33:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where between 50 to 100 people have paid £10 a pop for the pleasure of asking me questions
An experiment. My seven-hour session in front of the joint inquiry of the science and technology and health and social care committees didn’t go entirely as planned. Quite the reverse in fact, as the more I tried to pin most of the blame on Matt Hancock, the more people started to feel sorry for the hopeless halfwit. So I then tried releasing some WhatsApp messages in which Boris Johnson – it takes one to know one – described the health secretary as “completely fucking useless” but no one paid much attention to that either.
So here we are. In the blog of last resort, where between 50 to 100 people have paid £10 a pop for the pleasure of asking me questions on any topic and I get to demonstrate why I’m the narcissistic sociopath everyone had always imagined. It’s not quite how I imagined spending a Monday afternoon, but beggars can’t be choosers and a bloke has to scrape a living somehow.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chernobyl and The Feed among dramas driving UK TV exports to Europe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/21/chernobyl-and-the-feed-among-dramas-driving-uk-tv-exports-to-europe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/21/chernobyl-and-the-feed-among-dramas-driving-uk-tv-exports-to-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:29:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figures for 2019/20 show sales to Europe rose 4%, with an appetite for archive shows as well as new
For British television and film, Europe is the second biggest market after the US – with Chernobyl, His Dark Materials and The Feed featuring among popular recent UK shows on the continent.
Chernobyl, the Emmy award-winning historical drama, was a Sky Studios production bought by OCS City for a French audience, Sky Atlantic for the Germans and Italians and HBO for the Poles, Spaniards and Swedes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeffrey Donaldson seeks leadership of DUP after Poots resignation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/jeffrey-donaldson-seeks-leadership-of-dup-after-poots-resignation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/jeffrey-donaldson-seeks-leadership-of-dup-after-poots-resignation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:16:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MP is seen as a moderate and bases appeal on opposing post-Brexit customs checks in Northern Ireland
Sir Jeffrey Donaldson has declared his candidacy to lead the Democratic Unionist party (DUP) and said he will seek to unite Northern Ireland’s unionists in a campaign against the Irish Sea border.
The Lagan Valley MP made the announcement on Monday, confirming his status as the favourite to replace Edwin Poots, a short-lived leader who resigned last week after an internal revolt.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll Ireland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Portfolio Website with React]]></title>
        <id>60d0d0ff6e1a1407b6b0a506</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-portfolio-website-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:15:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today you're going to create one of the most important apps you can build for yourself: your developer portfolio. Every React developer or web developer in general needs to be able to show off what they can do to any potential client or employer. That's exactly what we're going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christoph Baumgartner strike sinks Ukraine and puts Austria in last 16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/ukraine-austria-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/ukraine-austria-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T18:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Austria made fools of anyone who had doubted their honesty. In the buildup to this game they had batted away the obligatory references to 1982, when their notorious “Disgrace of Gijón” with West Germany served both causes perfectly in navigating the World Cup group stage. A similar agreement would have required them and Ukraine to be on the same page but, in the event, for long periods it seemed jarring that they should even be sharing a pitch.
Andriy Shevchenko’s side would have finished second in Group C with a point and, given they had looked one of the tournament’s more enterprising propositions in previous outings, they could have been expected to assert themselves. They did not turn up, though, and a performance devoid of spirit and initiative means they must twiddle their thumbs while the ranking of third-place contenders whittles down. The odds on their progression are poor and they have this wasted opportunity to blame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Figma? A Design Crash Course [2021 Tutorial]]]></title>
        <id>60cda7104dc1a607ed7b5588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/figma-crash-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:52:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figma is a powerful design tool that helps you to create anything: websites, applications, logos, and much more. By learning to use Figma, you'll take your first steps into User Interface Design and and User Experience Design. These skills are essential for building a great portfolio for yourself and potentially]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jon Rahm driven to US Open glory by Harrington and Faldo messages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jon-rahm-us-open-glory-harrington-faldo-messages-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jon-rahm-us-open-glory-harrington-faldo-messages-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:48:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spaniard inspired by former champions’ tales of bouncing back from disaster to win first major two weeks after Covid infection
Two weeks ago, Jon Rahm was playing the golf of his life at the Memorial at Muirfield Village, equalling the tournament’s 54-hole record at 18 under par and opening a six-stroke lead over the field, only to be informed on live television while coming off the 18th green that he would have to withdraw after testing positive for the coronavirus.
The guidelines of the PGA Tour and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention – the US public health agency – require 10 days of self-isolation after a positive test, limiting Rahm’s ability to practise before the US Open. Only because he was able to return two negative tests within 24 hours was he permitted to cut his quarantine short and arrive at Torrey Pines Golf Course for the season’s third major before Tuesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bryan Armen Graham at Torrey Pines</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on France’s far-right: an advance thwarted | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/the-guardian-view-on-frances-far-right-an-advance-thwarted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/the-guardian-view-on-frances-far-right-an-advance-thwarted"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:46:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marine Le Pen’s far-right Rassemblement National failed to break through, but the biggest loser in regional elections was Emmanuel Macron
Wherever you look, it is said, nationalism in Europe is rising. In Spain and Italy, the far right is making gains. On Monday the nationalist Sweden Democrats plunged the country into a political crisis by driving through a no-confidence vote in the centre-left prime minister. Yet the first round results of regional elections on Sunday in France, a major test of public opinion before presidential polls next year, dashed Marine Le Pen’s hopes of turning the vote into a launchpad for her run at the top job.
Ms Le Pen’s far-right Rassemblement National did much worse than expected. Her party managed only a fifth of the vote nationally and topped the list in only one region, rather than the expected six. Unfortunately, Emmanuel Macron’s La République en Marche – her probable opponent in next year’s race to the Elysée Palace – did even worse, with only 11% of the national vote. The winners were the traditional parties, especially the centre-right Les Républicains – which won 27% of the national vote.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on second homes: put main homes first | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/the-guardian-view-on-second-homes-put-main-homes-first</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/the-guardian-view-on-second-homes-put-main-homes-first"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:46:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Housing inequalities are growing while more properties are converted to holiday use 
For a while last year it looked as though the widening of inequalities of all kinds, which has been one of the hallmarks of the pandemic, might not extend to housing. Demand for short-term and holiday lets on platforms such as Airbnb collapsed. While this was alarming for landlords, it looked as though more property could become available for long-term residential use. In London, rents fell fast. For once, perhaps, the scales could be tipping away from the UK’s two million landlords and towards the 13 million people who rent from them.
Since this was not the kind of levelling up that ministers had in mind, the chancellor, Rishi Sunak, intervened. A stamp duty holiday was introduced and then extended, to pump up prices. A new version of help to buy was launched. Meanwhile, wealthy people saw their savings grow, as opportunities to spend money (restaurants, parties, foreign holidays) shrank: an additional £192bn was put aside in the year following the first lockdown.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raisi sets out hardline stance in first remarks since winning Iran election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/raisi-sets-out-hardline-stance-in-first-remarks-since-winning-iran-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/raisi-sets-out-hardline-stance-in-first-remarks-since-winning-iran-election"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:40:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New president offers blunt preview of Iran’s global relations but vows to salvage nuclear deal with the west
Iran’s president-elect staked out a hardline position in his first remarks since his landslide election victory, rejecting the possibility of meeting Joe Biden or discussing Tehran’s ballistic missile programme and support of regional militias.
The comments by Ebrahim Raisi on Monday offered a blunt preview of how Iran might deal with the wider world in the next four years as it enters a new stage in negotiations to resurrect its tattered 2015 nuclear deal with global powers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infected blood scandal: Ex-pupil tells inquiry he did not know he was in a trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/infected-blood-scandal-ex-pupil-tells-inquiry-he-did-not-know-he-was-in-a-trial</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/infected-blood-scandal-ex-pupil-tells-inquiry-he-did-not-know-he-was-in-a-trial"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:26:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Webster, who went to Treloar College, was part of a cohort of 89 children, less than a quarter of whom are still alive
A man who was one of scores of pupils infected with contaminated blood products at a specialist boarding school has told a public inquiry neither he nor his parents were told that he was taking part in medical trials.
Out of 89 haemophiliac children who attended Treloar College in Hampshire in the 1970s and 1980s, less than a quarter of former pupils are still alive, the public inquiry into the contaminated blood scandal heard on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[West tightens Belarus sanctions to make Lukashenko regime ‘run dry’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-widens-belarus-sanctions-to-make-lukashenko-regime-run-dry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-widens-belarus-sanctions-to-make-lukashenko-regime-run-dry"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:20:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sanctions extended as punishment for forced landing of Ryanair flight and detention of journalist

Western countries have extended sanctions against Belarus, with a pledge to make Alexander Lukashenko’s regime “run dry”, following last month’s forced landing of a Ryanair flight to arrest a dissident.
In a coordinated move against Lukashenko, the UK, US, EU and Canada announced travel bans and asset freezes on senior Belarusian officials and entities that bankroll the regime as a punishment for the arrest of the activist and journalist Raman Pratasevich and his girlfriend, Sofia Sapega, who were detained after being hauled off a flight from Athens to Vilnius.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jennifer Rankin in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU warns anyone judged to be delaying Libya elections will risk sanctions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-warns-anyone-judged-to-be-delaying-libya-elections-will-risk-sanctions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-warns-anyone-judged-to-be-delaying-libya-elections-will-risk-sanctions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T17:12:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Message comes ahead of major UN meeting of foreign ministers in Berlin on Wednesday
The EU has warned that anyone judged to be delaying elections in Libya beyond the planned date of 24 December will be at risk of sanctions, ahead of an important meeting of foreign ministers intended to tighten the screw on those obstructing either elections or the withdrawal of foreign forces from the country.
The meeting in Berlin will set our proposals for a coordinated and sequential withdrawal of foreign forces, principally Russian and Turkish, and again call for elections at the end of the year. Previous deadlines for the withdrawal of foreign forces have been ignored.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Civil servants to stop investigating complaints against Scottish ministers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/scottish-civil-servants-to-stop-investigating-complaints-against-government-ministers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/scottish-civil-servants-to-stop-investigating-complaints-against-government-ministers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:53:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reforms come after controversy surrounding sexual harassment claims against Alex Salmond
Scottish civil servants will be stripped of their role investigating complaints against government ministers after the controversy surrounding sexual harassment claims against Alex Salmond.
Nicola Sturgeon, Salmond’s successor as first minister, said on Monday her government had accepted it needed sweeping reforms to its handling of ministerial misconduct allegations and its ethics policies, after three independent reports criticised its policies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell Scotland editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There are solutions to the housing crisis, but none of them are Tory | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/government-planning-reforms-tories-lose-chesham-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/government-planning-reforms-tories-lose-chesham-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:50:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson wants to ‘build, build, build’ but he needs property prices to keep rising. And it’s first-time buyers who are hit
Enjoy the schadenfreude as angry Tories lacerate their party for losing the Chesham and Amersham byelection. The defeated candidate, Peter Fleet, bitterly lashes out at “the appalling state of our local roads” – though Tory Buckinghamshire is a low-spend, low-tax county and his Tory government halved all council funding.
Enjoy the contradictions as Fleet says local Tories “want to hear more about traditional Conservative values” that “restore fiscal discipline”, fearing “a return to a bloated public sector” which stifles private enterprise and “demands ever higher taxes”. Telegraph letter-writers pile in with every favourite gripe explaining the defeat: “the expensive vanity project that is HS2”, “over-the-top Covid laws” and “inaction over illegal cross-Channel migration”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working from home has benefits – for employers | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/21/working-from-home-has-its-benefits-for-employers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/21/working-from-home-has-its-benefits-for-employers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:40:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Risks and maintenance costs are transferred to workers, writes Terry Kelly, while Janet Poliakoff believes it reduces carbon emissions and Caroline Mozley is glad there is still a choice
Your report that HSBC is planning to cut its global office footprint by 40% as a result of requiring its staff to work from home is somewhat misleading (Morgan Stanley boss tells US staff to be back in office in September, 15 June). In reality, what HSBC and a host of other companies are planning to do is cut the cost of their office footprint by transferring the square footage they pay for in town and city centres to the homes of their staff. So the total office space such companies use is not reduced, it is simply transferred, along with the cost, to the staff who are required to work from home.
The implication, of course, is that HSBC et al will enjoy enormous cost savings in terms of rents, building maintenance and, not least of all, business rates, by moving commercial premises to residential settings. Quite apart from issues of planning (ie, residential premises being used for commercial purposes), there is the question of whether someone who uses their home officially for business purposes should be paying towards the shortfall in business rates that local authorities will lose out on as businesses vacate their city/town centre premises – not to mention the knock-on effect on service industries that depend on office workers for their livelihood. Also, who pays for cleaning the home/office space that employees use on behalf of their employer? Presumably the employee.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greater Manchester clean air zone could launch in May 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/greater-manchester-clean-air-zone-could-launch-in-may-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/greater-manchester-clean-air-zone-could-launch-in-may-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:40:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mayor unveils plans to charge high-polluting vehicles, but campaigners angered by private car exemption
Greater Manchester has approved plans for a clean air zone (CAZ) scheme under which high-polluting commercial and passenger vehicles will be charged to drive through the city.
High-polluting heavy goods vehicles, buses and coaches will be charged £60 a day; vans, £10; and taxi and private hire vehicles, £7.50 to drive within the zone. Failure to pay will result in a £120 fine in addition to the daily charge. Private cars will be exempt. The scheme is expected to be rubber-stamped at a meeting of the Greater Manchester Combined Authority (GMCA) next week and is expected to launch on 30 May 2022.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Technical Guide to IPFS – the Decentralized Storage of Web3]]></title>
        <id>60a55b37906c5207e3a7ea78</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/technical-guide-to-ipfs-decentralized-storage-of-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But where do you store your application's content? Storing the content on the blockchain would be expensive and inefficient. Your blockchain application needs decentralized storage!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the CSS Position Property Works – Explained with Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>6063b9e19618b008528a9d9a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/css-position-property-explained/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:36:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we're gonna learn everything you need to know about the CSS position property along with examples. Let's get started 🎖️ Table of contents What is CSS Position Property?What is the Static Position in CSS?What are the Relative and Absolute Positions in CSS?What is the Fixed Position in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sadly, children’s services are not a political priority | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/21/sadly-childrens-services-are-not-a-political-priority</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/21/sadly-childrens-services-are-not-a-political-priority"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:36:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lucy Peake on the value of kinship care and Steven Walker on politicians’ indifference to the plight of children. Plus letters by June O’Sullivan and Megan Jarvie
If the English children’s services system is a “tower of Jenga held together by Sellotape” (Children’s services in England shaky as Jenga tower, says review lead, 17 June), then kinship carers and the children they care for are the blocks that have already toppled off the sides.
For too long, kinship care has been marginalised by policymakers and treated as the poor relation to adoption. Yet evidence tells us that well-supported kinship care offers continuity, stability and the preservation of important family bonds, the very same basic obligation to children that the independent review of children’s social care report outlines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The problem isn’t remote working – it’s clinging to office-based practices | Alexia Cambon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/remote-working-office-based-practices-offices-employers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/remote-working-office-based-practices-offices-employers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:33:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do we need to go to offices?  Work 9 to 5? At this unique moment in history, employers can rethink everything
There have been few moments in the history of work as pivotal as the one we find ourselves in now. It took a pandemic to normalise remote working, and, despite the fears of many CEOs, most organisations saw no demonstrable loss of productivity. Now, the global workforce is demanding its right to retain the autonomy it gained through increased flexibility as societies open up again. Pre-pandemic, it was not uncommon for an employer to ask staff to justify their need to work from home. Post-pandemic, employees may ask employers to justify the need to come into the office.
Yet many organisations are still resisting this more flexible future. They argue that employees’ wellbeing is compromised by remote working, and that unless they are brought back into the office, many more will suffer from “Zoom fatigue”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexia Cambon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Lieder festival finale review – a beautifully voiced inquiry into gender]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/21/leeds-lieder-festival-finale-review-carolyn-sampson-roderick-williams-hannah-kendall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/21/leeds-lieder-festival-finale-review-carolyn-sampson-roderick-williams-hannah-kendall"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:11:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall 
Carolyn Sampson and Roderick Williams tackled songs usually allotted to their opposite sexes, while Shakespearean shapeshifter Rosalind poetically inspired a Hannah Kendall premiere
Leeds Lieder festival packed a great deal – masterclasses and lectures as well as song recitals – into its four days, with all the events streamed online as well as given before live audiences in Leeds Town Hall. Its finale was a recital by the soprano Carolyn Sampson and baritone Roderick Williams, accompanied by the festival’s artistic director Joseph Middleton, that explored the question of gender in song.
It was a cleverly devised, beautifully polished programme, with the two singers taking on songs usually allotted to the opposite sex – Sampson began with two numbers from Schubert’s Die Schöne Mullerin, and Williams with two from Schumann’s Frauenliebe und -leben, for instance – and also inviting the audience to comment on the switches, as well as to nominate the songs they included in a final group; settings by Britten, Schubert, Debussy and Butterworth were among the choices.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Clements</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bafta-winning TV firm accused of mishandling sexual assault complaint]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/21/bafta-winning-tv-firm-accused-of-mishandling-sexual-assault-complaint-left-bank-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/21/bafta-winning-tv-firm-accused-of-mishandling-sexual-assault-complaint-left-bank-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T16:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Two women allege Left Bank Pictures acted to protect accused colleague and minimise severity of his behaviour
Two female former staffers at the multi-Bafta-winning independent production company behind Netflix’s The Crown have accused it of badly mishandling a complaint about a male senior executive who sexually and physically assaulted them following a work event.
Holly Bourdillon and Laura Johnston were freelancers for Left Bank Pictures, which is part-owned by Sony. They were hired to work on the post-production edit of the hit Netflix show White Lines in December 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clamping koala: how a new sex guide prompted complaints – and delight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/clamping-koala-how-a-new-sex-guide-prompted-complaints-and-delight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/clamping-koala-how-a-new-sex-guide-prompted-complaints-and-delight"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:58:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you are pregnant, have back pain or bad knees, Norway’s public broadcaster has advice on the best position to try. But not everyone is happy
Name: Clamping koala.
Age: Newly coined.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jos Buttler frustrated to miss England Tests but has ‘no perfect answers’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jos-buttler-frustrated-miss-england-tests-t20-sri-lanka</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/jos-buttler-frustrated-miss-england-tests-t20-sri-lanka"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:43:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[T20 vice-captain has been rested for five Tests this year
England begin T20 series against Sri Lanka on Wednesday

Jos Buttler has said there are no perfect answers to the scheduling overkill that has led to him missing five of England’s eight Test matches this year in order to rest and with Twenty20 cricket seemingly prioritised.
A centrally contracted player for England in all three formats, Buttler’s itinerary thus far in 2021 sums up much of the wider frustration with the team’s rotation policy, having left the Test series in India for a scheduled break with the side 1-0 up and following back-to-back victories in Sri Lanka. Joe Root’s side have lost four of their five Tests since – the 3-1 defeat by India was followed by a 1-0 series loss at home to New Zealand – while Buttler has featured in all eight of the white-ball team’s fixtures and played in the Indian Premier League before its cancellation at the start of May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Gorilla Glue Girl’ launches haircare products]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/21/gorilla-glue-girl-launches-haircare-products</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/21/gorilla-glue-girl-launches-haircare-products"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:11:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tessica Brown, who went viral in February, has announced a new range including merchandise and a hairspray called Forever Hold
Tessica Brown, AKA “Gorilla Glue Girl”, the woman who went viral in February for accidentally gluing her hair to her head, has launched her own range of haircare products.
Brown’s Forever Hair range will feature a hairspray named Forever Hold, a play on her online infamy. The collection will include a growth-stimulating oil and a range of merchandise including a T-shirt that features a screen grab of her famous video and the logo “Bonded For Life”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social care to royal yacht: battle looms over UK spending priorities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/social-care-royal-yacht-battle-looms-uk-spending-priorities</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/21/social-care-royal-yacht-battle-looms-uk-spending-priorities"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:10:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The economic damage from Covid will make Boris Johnson and Rishi Sunak’s decisions even harder

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Battles within government over spending priorities are looming, with the task made harder because of the economic damage from Covid. Here are some of the main fiscal decisions ahead for Boris Johnson and his chancellor, Rishi Sunak:
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker  and Damian Carrington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monday’s best photographs: summer solstice and International Yoga Day]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/21/mondays-best-photographs-summer-solstice-and-international-yoga-day</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/21/mondays-best-photographs-summer-solstice-and-international-yoga-day"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:49:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I made it as if this was the end of my life’: Scorsese on Raging Bull at 40]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/21/raging-bull-at-40-scorsese-de-niro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/21/raging-bull-at-40-scorsese-de-niro"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:34:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At a Tribeca film festival event, the director and his star Robert De Niro discussed the legacy of the greatest boxing movie ever made
In Martin Scorsese’s 1980 magnum opus, Raging Bull, the self-destructive boxer Jake LaMotta goes from the greatest to a washed-up parody of himself, clinging to his memories of the good ol’ days. For the director and star Robert De Niro, looking back on the film from the present day could have been tempting fate, a couple of ageing men reminiscing about their younger years via a movie illustrating the hazards of just that.
At this year’s closing night for De Niro’s own Tribeca film festival, during an hour-long pre-recorded conversation that preceded the evening’s screening, there was a slight hint of the rueful in the way he and dear pal “Marty” discussed the experience with emcee Leonardo DiCaprio. “Our way of making movies went down,” Scorsese proclaimed, citing the massive financial failure of the pricy Heaven’s Gate that same year as a sign that the party was over for creative talents in search of studio carte blanche. “The kind of thing we were doing was too much trouble for, ah, what they would reap from it.” De Niro clarified: “Money.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Bramesco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342448</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-css-charts-with-interesting-shapes-glyphs-and-emoji/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:32:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s forego the usual circles and bars we typically see used in charts for more eccentric shapes. With online presentations more and more common today, a quick way to spruce up your web slides and make them stand out is …
The post How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image To Text Conversion With React And Tesseract.js (OCR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have to process data manually because it is served through images or scanned documents? An image-to-text conversion makes it possible to extract text from images to automate the processing of texts on images, videos, and scanned documents. In this article, we look at how to convert an image to text with React and Tesseract.js(OCR), preprocess images, and deal with the limitations of Tesseract (OCR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ayobami Ogundiran)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artists call for ‘white-run’ UK Chinese gallery to be defunded in racism row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/artists-call-for-white-run-uk-chinese-gallery-to-be-defunded-in-racism-row</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/artists-call-for-white-run-uk-chinese-gallery-to-be-defunded-in-racism-row"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centre for Chinese Contemporary Art in Manchester has ‘entrenched acceptance of racist attitudes’, claim artists
Artists recruited to transform one of the UK’s leading Chinese arts centres have called for support to be withdrawn from the organisation, claiming it has an “entrenched acceptance of racist attitudes”.
Seven artists of Chinese heritage have called for the Centre for Chinese Contemporary Art (CFCCA) in Manchester to be defunded because of a “current and [historical] culture of institutional racism”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nazia Parveen Community affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Labour/Lib Dems alliance could defeat the Tories in seat after seat | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/labour-lib-dems-alliance-defeat-tories-seat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/labour-lib-dems-alliance-defeat-tories-seat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:50:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Lib Dems are a nuisance party. They should disband, or step aside in winnable seats in return for a government role
Anyone who predicts the outcome of general elections from byelections should stick to the horses. This applies especially to periodic Liberal Democrat upsets such as last week’s at Chesham and Amersham in Buckinghamshire, where they overturned a blue majority. This was nothing to do with choosing a government, rather it was passing judgment on Johnson’s “algorithmic” deregulation of rural planning in the south-east. It was about “taking back control”, community politics not party politics.
The Lib Dems stand for nothing radical or recognisable, just a vaguely left-of-centre outlook on life. Local issues aside, they appeal to those who vaguely agree with Labour, but cannot quite vote that way. As across Europe, the effect is to split the left-of-centre vote and thus empower the right. Over the weekend, the Lib Dem leader, Ed Davey, appeared to rule out any formal progressive pact. “We don’t need stitch-ups and deals,” he said. “I’m very sceptical about all that.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’m working through 1001 Albums You Must Hear Before You Die’: readers’ WFH playlists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/im-working-through-1001-albums-you-must-hear-before-you-die-readers-wfh-playlists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/im-working-through-1001-albums-you-must-hear-before-you-die-readers-wfh-playlists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:49:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some of you went classic rock; others Iranian ambient. And yet others took on epic challenges that will take  years to complete … here’s what you’ve been listening to while working under lockdown
If I need to concentrate on something really thorny, I go for Bach every time. It seems to allow my brain to work at a high level and I do almost all my best work to Bach. András Schiff or Angela Hewitt playing keyboard works, and Hilary Hahn on violin. Beethoven’s late quartets and Schubert lieder are good for deep thought. If I’m just doing low-level stuff, then Radio Paradise is my go-to – it’s a commercial-free internet station, which I like because it mixes a lot of stuff I know from my younger days with music that I’m less familiar with. Edward Collier, software developer, Cheltenham
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Princess Latifa: Instagram image appears to show Dubai ruler’s daughter in Spain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/princess-latifa-instagram-image-appears-to-show-dubai-rulers-daughter-in-spain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/princess-latifa-instagram-image-appears-to-show-dubai-rulers-daughter-in-spain"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:41:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Princess, who was seized after fleeing the sheikhdom in 2018, has appeared in several social media posts recently
A Dubai princess who was seized at gunpoint in 2018 after fleeing the Gulf sheikhdom has been pictured in an Instagram post that appears to show her as being in Spain as part of what was described as a “European holiday”.
It is the first time that Princess Latifa has been pictured outside Dubai since her escape via a yacht was dramatically cut short by a commando raid three years ago, although the picture only shows her inside Madrid’s main airport.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dido Harding’s pledge to cut overseas NHS staff is a kick in the teeth | Gaby Hinsliff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/dido-harding-overseas-nhs-staff-nhs-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/21/dido-harding-overseas-nhs-staff-nhs-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T13:40:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In her public campaign for the NHS England top job, Harding is using 170,000 crucial, exhausted workers as political pawns 
When Boris Johnson was fighting for breath in intensive care, two nurses in particular earned his seemingly undying gratitude.
Jenny McGee was originally from New Zealand, and Luis Pitarma from Portugal. Both risked their lives to work on Britain’s Covid frontline, and the prime minister later marvelled at the dedication with which they watched over him “every second of the night”. But words are cheap; it’s action that counts. Which brings us to the Tory peer Dido Harding, fresh from presiding over the chaos of track and trace, and her audacious application to follow that by taking over the running of the NHS in England. Crucially, her pitch for the job reportedly includes a pledge to stop relying on overseas-born doctors and nurses and train British-born replacements instead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaby Hinsliff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[York Minster faces deficit of £2.3m after Covid closures in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/york-minster-faces-deficit-of-23m-after-covid-closures-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/york-minster-faces-deficit-of-23m-after-covid-closures-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:41:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cathedral’s annual income from visitors and worshippers fell by 74% from 2019 figures

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

York Minster is facing up to the catastrophic impact of the pandemic on its finances after recording a £2.3m deficit last year.
Income at the cathedral plummeted from a surplus of £332,000 in 2019 due to low visitor numbers caused by the pandemic, according to the minster’s recently published accounts for the year to 31 December 2020.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City make Harry Kane bid worth at least £100m to Tottenham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/manchester-city-harry-kane-bid-worth-at-least-100m-to-tottenham-reject</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/21/manchester-city-harry-kane-bid-worth-at-least-100m-to-tottenham-reject"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spurs will reject Premier League champions’ offer for striker
City open to discussing a players-plus-money deal

Manchester City have made an opening bid for Harry Kane which would guarantee Tottenham at least £100m for the England striker.
City are open to discussing a players-plus-money deal but Spurs have no intention of accepting their offer for the 27-year-old, who has told the club he wants a transfer. The first bid does not have a swap option but names to be included in any future negotiations are understood to be Raheem Sterling, Aymeric Laporte and Gabriel Jesus among others.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Romano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Undead on arrival: should zombies run or lurch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/should-zombies-run-or-lurch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/should-zombies-run-or-lurch"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From 28 Days Later to Army of the Dead, fast zombies are everywhere – but aren’t they supposed to be slow and unsteady?
In the Guide’s weekly Solved! column, we look into a crucial pop-culture question you’ve been burning to know the answer to – and settle it
You used to know where you were with zombies. Normally it was 10ft ahead of them, watching them lurch pathetically towards you. This afforded plenty of time to find a baseball bat, something sharp, maybe even a chainsaw. If The Walking Dead, which wraps up after 11 seasons this autumn, has taught us anything, it’s that zombies only really become a problem if there’s a horde of them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James McMahon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomasina Miers’ recipe for kritharaki, broad beans and tomato with baked feta | The simple fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/21/thomasina-miers-recipe-for-kritharaki-broad-beans-and-tomato-with-baked-feta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/21/thomasina-miers-recipe-for-kritharaki-broad-beans-and-tomato-with-baked-feta"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fragrant Greek salad of small, orzo-like pasta, baked feta and tomatoes, all liberally laced with fresh herbs
My local deli sells lovely, organic products from Greece, including kritharaki (a type of orzo) and a wild oregano that is woody, floral and intensely evocative of holidays in that sunshine and piercing, blue sea. It was there that I once had a barrel-aged feta so soft and creamy that I was barely able to contain myself. I had no idea feta could be such a silky, delicate-tasting collection of soft curds. Here, I bake it to try to emulate that texture, and it works beautifully in this sun-soaked salad.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomasina Miers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We didn’t want it named after another person’: how residents of Cecil Rhodes House feel about its new name]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/we-didnt-want-it-named-after-a-person-how-residents-of-cecil-rhodes-house-feel-about-its-new-name</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/we-didnt-want-it-named-after-a-person-how-residents-of-cecil-rhodes-house-feel-about-its-new-name"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the 1980s, there was an attempt to rename the block after Robert Mugabe, but now it will simply be Park View House. It reflects changes being made across the country
Some time in the next few weeks, a team of council maintenance staff will be dispatched to a nine-storey block of flats behind St Pancras station in central London. They will unscrew the panels that bear the name Cecil Rhodes House, and affix newly made replacement signs, making it clear that the building should now be known as Park View House.
As the Rhodes Must Fall campaign in Oxford drags on into a fifth year, with 150 dons announcing this month that they refuse to teach at Oriel College because of its decision not to remove a statue of the former Cape Colony prime minister, Britain’s other Rhodes controversy has been dealt with relatively swiftly.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU prepares to cut amount of British TV and film shown post-Brexit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-prepares-cut-amount-british-tv-film-shown-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/eu-prepares-cut-amount-british-tv-film-shown-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T11:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: number of UK productions seen as ‘disproportionate’ and threat to Europe’s cultural diversity
The EU is preparing to act against the “disproportionate” amount of British television and film content shown in Europe in the wake of Brexit, in a blow to the UK entertainment industry and the country’s “soft power” abroad.
The UK is Europe’s biggest producer of film and TV programming, buoyed up by £1.4bn from the sale of international rights, but its dominance has been described as a threat to Europe’s “cultural diversity” in an internal EU document seen by the Guardian.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tour de France 2021: stage-by-stage guide | William Fotheringham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/tour-de-france-2021-stage-by-stage-guide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/tour-de-france-2021-stage-by-stage-guide"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T11:10:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s race begins in France’s cycling heartland before heading to the mountains and a climax in the Pyrenees

The Tour opens with a loop through France’s cycling heartland, home to heroes of the past such as the five-times winner Bernard Hinault, and present-day aspirants such as Warren Barguil. A hilly route travels south to Quimper then returns north to finish close to the start, up a steep two-mile climb tailor made for France’s biggest current star, Julian Alaphilippe, who will be under intense pressure to deliver the stage win and yellow jersey. With more brief ascents approaching the finish crashes are inevitable as the field fights for position before the closing hill.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Words by William Fotheringham. Graphics by Finbarr Sheehy and Harvey Symons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Les Hijabeuses: the female footballers tackling France’s on-pitch hijab ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/21/les-hijabeuses-the-female-footballers-tackling-frances-on-pitch-hijab-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/21/les-hijabeuses-the-female-footballers-tackling-frances-on-pitch-hijab-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T11:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Young players excluded from matches because of their religious dress find a way to play on and encourage other hijab-wearing women into the sport
Founé Diawara was 15 years old when she was first told she could not wear her hijab in a football match.
It was an important game. She had recently got into the team of a club in Meaux, the town north-east of Paris where she grew up, and they were playing a local rival. Diawara had been wearing her hijab during training, but as she was about to walk on to the pitch, the referee said she must remove it if she wanted to play.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stanley Tucci: the flirty hero of foodie TV you need in your life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/21/stanley-tucci-the-flirty-hero-of-foodie-tv-you-need-in-your-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/21/stanley-tucci-the-flirty-hero-of-foodie-tv-you-need-in-your-life"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T10:59:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor charms the pants off everyone he meets in his new culinary travelogue that will whet your appetite for a trip abroad when it’s finally allowed
You may not realise this at the moment, but your heart has been crying out for a series like Stanley Tucci: Searching for Italy. If you saw last night’s first episode, tucked away on CNN International, you will already be aware of this. If you didn’t, stop what you’re doing and seek it out. It’s less a TV show and more an hour of full-body relaxation. By the time the episode ended, I felt as if my entire brain had been taken out and massaged in olive oil.
Although the title suggests a different series, in which a beloved actor receives a concussion then forlornly attempts to navigate Google Maps, this is actually a culinary travelogue. Tucci visits a different Italian region in every episode and contentedly samples its food. It is a formula you will have seen thousands of times before, albeit with a couple of key differences.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: has the pandemic changed your attitude towards commuting?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2021/jun/21/tell-us-has-the-pandemic-changed-your-attitude-towards-commuting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2021/jun/21/tell-us-has-the-pandemic-changed-your-attitude-towards-commuting"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T10:48:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re keen to hear whether the pandemic has made people feel differently about commuting, using public transport to get to work and living far away from their workplace
We’re interested to hear whether people’s attitudes towards commuting have changed during the pandemic, and whether this has inspired people to make changes in their daily routine in order to reduce their commute.
 What are your views about commuting long distances now? How do you feel about walking or cycling to work, and how comfortable are you with using public transport? In any case, if your views on commuting are not the same as they used to be, we’d like to hear about it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Roddy’s recipe for roast aubergine with tomato and basil | A kitchen in Rome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/21/rachel-roddy-recipe-roast-aubergine-tomato-and-basil</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/21/rachel-roddy-recipe-roast-aubergine-tomato-and-basil"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T10:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Thick, striped rounds of aubergine baked with loads of olive oil and salt until tender and velvety, then topped with finely diced macerated tomato’
Years ago, I did a workshop in a church hall that smelled of milky tea and damp carpet. One of the various exercises was to write a short story, a page long, about something dramatic that had happened to us or someone we knew. Having written our page, we were told to read the story back, then cross it out with a single line. The next stage was to write the same story, only this time to take up half a page. Again, we were told to read it, then strike a line through it. The last part was to write the same story in a single sentence, read it twice, then underline two words.
Almost without exception, and regardless of where the story had started and how dramatic or bad it was, the sentences were tender and funny. The two words (“busy orange” are the ones I remember best) were all moving and hilarious, which was no doubt also due to the fact that we had been incubating in a strip-lit room that smelled of milky tea and damp carpet. After a break to drink the tea we had been smelling all morning and to eat chocolate bourbons and ginger nuts, we came back to discuss the exercise. It was all about the stories we are tied to, and how we tell them and can change them; at the time, it felt as if we were hitting on the meaning of life. Some things have stayed with me, and nothing more so than the smell and taste of milky tea and a busy orange.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Roddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tokyo 2020 will allow up to 10,000 domestic fans into Olympic venues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/tokyo-2020-will-allow-up-to-10000-fans-into-olympic-venues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/21/tokyo-2020-will-allow-up-to-10000-fans-into-olympic-venues"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:52:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Olympic organisers cap fans at 50% of venue capacity
Spectators could still be cut if infection situation worsens

Thousands of Japanese spectators will be allowed to attend events at the Olympic Games this summer, organisers said on Monday, despite warnings from health experts that crowds risk fuelling a surge in coronavirus cases.
The president of the Tokyo 2020 organising committee, Seiko Hashimoto, said attendance would be capped at up to 50% of a venue’s capacity or a maximum of 10,000 people.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry in Tokyo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Government postpones ‘do or die’ meeting on social care in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/21/government-postpones-do-or-die-meeting-social-care-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/21/government-postpones-do-or-die-meeting-social-care-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:09:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talks between Boris Johnson, Rishi Sunak and Matt Hancock called off as calls grow for plan to tackle crisis
A “do or die” meeting on social care involving Boris Johnson, Rishi Sunak and Matt Hancock has been postponed, it is understood, as the government came under renewed pressure over delays in setting out a policy for the sector.
The discussion between the prime minister, the chancellor and the health secretary, billed as a chance to set out broad policy objectives for social care, had been scheduled for Tuesday. It is not known why it was postponed, or when the meeting will take place.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crippled by Covid: the vintage British cinemas under threat – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/gallery/2021/jun/21/crippled-by-covid-the-british-cinemas-under-threat-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/gallery/2021/jun/21/crippled-by-covid-the-british-cinemas-under-threat-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:08:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic has laid waste to independent cinemas across the UK, with releases delayed and audiences vanishing. Now lockdown is over, here are 11 classic venues that are worth your support
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘He saved my life – and he’s drop-dead gorgeous’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/how-we-met-he-saved-my-life-and-hes-drop-dead-gorgeous</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/how-we-met-he-saved-my-life-and-hes-drop-dead-gorgeous"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patrick, 59, and Richard, 50, met at a dinner party that Patrick had tried to skip. Years later, when Patrick’s kidneys began to fail, Richard donated one of his
In 1995, Patrick was a professor at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, teaching behavioural sciences. One night in March, he was invited to a friend’s house for a dinner party. “I didn’t realise it was a matchmaking thing. I was tired and nearly pulled out, but the host was very insistent,” he says.
It was there that he met Richard, a Hong Kong local who was teaching at a further education college. After dinner, they found themselves outside, talking. “I thought he was handsome and he seemed very thoughtful. He had this very melancholy book in his hand,” remembers Patrick. They swapped numbers at the end of the night.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Betty Boo on how she made Doin’ the Do]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/betty-boo-how-we-made-doin-the-do-slang-cunnilingus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/21/betty-boo-how-we-made-doin-the-do-slang-cunnilingus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T09:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Much later, someone told me it was actually slang for cunnilingus’
When I was 17, I was in a female rap trio called the She Rockers. We saw LL Cool J and Public Enemy play Hammersmith Odeon when the 1987 Def Jam tour came to London. Afterwards, we saw Public Enemy in McDonald’s. We went “Oi!” and told them we were rappers, so they filmed us doing a freestyle rap, right there in McDonald’s.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Dave Simpson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A woman, a refugee, and a Jew’: pioneering reporter Hella Pick on breaking down walls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/jun/21/hella-pick-foreign-correspondent-before-my-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/jun/21/hella-pick-foreign-correspondent-before-my-time"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T08:32:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A former Guardian foreign correspondent tells a successor about defying prejudice and gaining global acclaim for her work
On Hella Pick’s first day as the Guardian’s Washington correspondent in 1963, she opened her office door to discover her predecessor had cleared the bookshelves of reference volumes, emptied out the archive of old article cuttings and carted off all the bureau’s address books.
There is no real modern equivalent for how devastating this was. The closest a journalist might come now would be having the internet permanently cut off.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Graham-Harrison</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The rogue department: how the Trump DoJ trashed legal and political norms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/21/trump-doj-bill-bar-attorney-general-justice-department</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/21/trump-doj-bill-bar-attorney-general-justice-department"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T08:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New investigations will examine the scale of wrongdoing – and experts say there could be more revelations of abuse to come
Donald Trump never did much to hide his dangerous belief that the US justice department and the attorneys general who helmed it should serve as his own personal lawyers and follow his political orders, regardless of norms and the law.
Former senior DoJ officials say the former president aggressively prodded his attorneys general to go after his enemies, protect his friends and his interests, and these moves succeeded with alarming results until Trump’s last few months in office.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Stone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do what you love – and take it easy: eight ways to get back lost fitness and motivation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/do-what-you-love-and-take-it-easy-eight-ways-to-get-back-lost-fitness-and-motivation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/21/do-what-you-love-and-take-it-easy-eight-ways-to-get-back-lost-fitness-and-motivation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic has left many of us feeling tired, out of sorts and beaten. But it is possible to get your exercise rhythm back. Here’s how
Many of us have been working at home for more than a year now, without the “ambient” exercise we used to get during the 9 to 5 – walking to and from the station, say, or up and down the office stairs. And so we’ve made a conscious effort to get our feet moving and our hearts pounding.
Even in the gloomy months of January and February, it was surprisingly easy to stay motivated. Endless mournful laps of the neighbourhood park, brisk jogs past shuttered high streets and empty window displays; they gave you a legitimate excuse to get out of the house. But now that pubs and bars have reopened and we can finally see our friends, many of us have found that our fitness and enthusiasm have plunged off a cliff.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Buds A-Series review: Google’s cheaper but good earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AirPods rivals have top sound, battery and translation features but cost significantly less
Google’s latest AirPods competitors, the Pixel Buds A-Series, get a big price cut and a slightly more comfortable design.
The new Bluetooth earbuds take a cue from Google’s cheaper but great A-Series phones, cutting a few features to cost £100 (US$99) – a full £80 cheaper than their predecessors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Documenting violence against migrants in South Africa | a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/documenting-violence-against-migrants-in-south-africa-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/documenting-violence-against-migrants-in-south-africa-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 12 years have passed since xenophobic violence swept unexpectedly through South Africa’s townships, leaving more than 60 people dead, hundreds injured and tens of thousands displaced from their homes. Photojournalists James Oatway and Alon Skuy document the unrest in a new book, [BR]OTHER
In May 2008, a series of xenophobic attacks accompanied by widespread looting and vandalism left at least 62 people dead, 1,700 injured and 100,000 displaced in South Africa. The violence began in Alexandra in Johannesburg after a local community meeting at which migrants were blamed for crime and for “stealing” jobs. Within days the attacks had spread around the country, with Ramaphosa settlement on the East Rand becoming one of the areas that witnessed inhumanity on an unthinkable level.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Oatway and Alon Skuy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hungary’s LGBT protests and Juneteenth Day: human rights this fortnight – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/jun/21/human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/jun/21/human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A roundup of the coverage on struggles for human rights and freedoms from China to Colombia
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Johnson, compiled by Eric Hilaire</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s going to come as a big shock’: UFO experts await Pentagon report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/its-going-to-come-as-a-big-shock-ufo-experts-await-pentagon-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/21/its-going-to-come-as-a-big-shock-ufo-experts-await-pentagon-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK ufologists are worlds apart on the importance of a hotly anticipated US intelligence release
Nearly 75 years after Roswell, the possibility that we are not alone in the universe is once again the talk of mainstream politics.
The impending release of a Pentagon report on the activities of the Advanced Aerospace Threat Identification Program (AATIP) has sparked a wave of interest and recent pronouncements from the programme’s former director, Luis Elizondo , have raised the eyebrows of ufologists worldwide.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New EU rules would permit use of most polymers without checks, experts warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/new-eu-rules-would-permit-use-of-most-polymers-without-checks-experts-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/21/new-eu-rules-would-permit-use-of-most-polymers-without-checks-experts-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposals would allow common plastics to be used despite valid concerns about possible harms, scientists say
New rules on chemicals to be debated by the EU this week would allow most polymers to be used without further checks, according to a group of scientists.
Only about 6% out of about 200,000 polymers would require extensive safety checks under proposals being discussed as part of Europe’s Reach chemicals regulations.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘People are feeling pent-up’: Swansea struggles with rise in violence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/people-are-feeling-pent-up-swansea-struggles-with-rise-in-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/21/people-are-feeling-pent-up-swansea-struggles-with-rise-in-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents and politicians say lockdown, deprivation and social division played a part in recent riot
A month on, Adam Romain is still clearly deeply traumatised by the outburst of violence that took place on the doorstep of his Swansea home.
Rioters set fire to cars outside his terrace house, and when he attempted to stop them, hurled bricks through his windows. Delivery driver Romain turned on a head-cam and captured the screams of his partner and children as glass smashed and the flames danced outside. He dialled 999 and told the operator: “They’ve targeted my house. They are throwing bricks at my house. I have two children inside, please come.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Karim’s story: Egypt’s crackdown on human rights workers – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/21/karim-ennarah-egypt-crackdown-human-rights-workers-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/21/karim-ennarah-egypt-crackdown-human-rights-workers-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T02:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten years since the Arab spring rocked Egypt and removed its president, the country is still detaining human rights workers and locking up political prisoners
Karim Ennarah, a human rights worker for the Egyptian Initiative for Personal Rights, was at a beach resort in South Sinai when he was arrested and accused of joining a terrorist group and “spreading false news”. He was detained in a prison in Cairo and became one of thousands of political prisoners in the country. 
Ennarah tells Anushka Asthana that his arrest was only the beginning of his separation from his British wife. Jess Kelly describes to Anushka the moment that she found out her husband had been arrested by the security services as she rode her bike along a London street, and the great difficulties she herself has faced to be reunited with him.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana; produced by Courtney Yusuf and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN blasts world leaders for failing to seal £72bn-a-year deal on climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/un-blasts-world-leaders-for-failing-to-seal-72bn-a-year-deal-on-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/20/un-blasts-world-leaders-for-failing-to-seal-72bn-a-year-deal-on-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T09:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Financial aid ‘critical’ to help developing countries limit fossil fuels – and make Cop26 a success, says UN
The head of climate change at the UN has warned that world leaders are still “far away” from securing a deal to limit the disastrous effects of global heating, with less than five months to go before a key summit in Glasgow.
Time is now running out, said Patricia Espinosa, who was formerly foreign minister of Mexico but now leads the UN on climate policy. She told the Observer that although advances had been made at the G7 meeting in Cornwall last weekend, progress had not been made on honouring past commitments to find $100bn (£72.5bn) a year to help developing countries invest in green technologies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm &amp; Robin McKie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: sun’s out, bums out! Isle of Wight festival,1969]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/the-big-picture-isle-of-wight-festival-1969-david-hurn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/20/the-big-picture-isle-of-wight-festival-1969-david-hurn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T06:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Hurn’s photograph captures the last hurrah of a decade of freedom
A hundred and fifty thousand people camped out at the 1969 Isle of Wight festival to see Bob Dylan return to a live stage for the first time in three years. The photographer David Hurn, then 35, got a few pictures of Dylan’s set, but he was more interested in turning his camera on the crowd than the performers. That year’s festival, at the end of August, came a couple of weeks after Woodstock and was perhaps the closest Britain’s festivalgoers ever came to the authentic spirit of the summer of love.
Hurn, who grew up in Wales, had been on the frontline of much of the 1960s; as well as documenting indelible images of early Beatlemania, he had shot the film posters for Sean Connery’s James Bond in From Russia With Love and Jane Fonda’s Barbarella. The 1969 festival, which came a month after the moon landing and the death of Brian Jones, felt like a last hurrah for the decade. Hurn slept near the beach without a tent with the other festivalgoers and when hundreds of people plunged bare-arsed into the sea on the Sunday morning he felt he ought to join in and get naked himself. No other photographer was around to capture this scene, which, for all the cheerful nudity, is made by the presence of the boat at anchor, making the festivalgoers appear like a recently discovered, and distinctly hedonistic, island tribe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Head of Independent Sage to launch international climate change group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/20/head-of-independent-sage-to-launch-international-climate-change-group"/>
        <updated>2021-06-20T05:01:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir David King hopes to emulate success of British Covid advisory body by issuing monthly reports on environmental crisis
Several of the world’s leading scientists plan to launch an independent expert group this week to advise, warn and criticise global policymakers about the climate and nature crises.
The new body has been inspired by Independent Sage – the cluster of British scientists who have held UK ministers and civil servants to account for their lack of transparency and mishandling of the Covid pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Watts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A tour of Black London – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/19/a-tour-of-black-london-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/19/a-tour-of-black-london-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-19T18:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nelson Mandela, Mary Seacole and Thierry Henry are some of the highlights of the tour of Black London from a new book by Avril Nanton and Jody Burton which celebrates Black history, culture and art in the capital. Andy Hall photographed a selection of the statues, murals and plaques

From Tudor courts to BLM, a new book brings London’s black history to life
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341511</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-the-outline-property-as-a-collapsable-border/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T20:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outline property in CSS draws a line around the outside of an element. This is quite similar to the border property, the main exception being that outline isn’t a part of the box model. It is often used for …
The post Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carter Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TCP vs UDP – Which Protocol is Faster?]]></title>
        <id>60b46dbd11ffb70827ef9dea</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/tcp-vs-udp-which-is-faster/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is TCP?TCP is an acronym for Transmission Control Protocol. It is a transport layer protocol that allows packets to be sent from one location to another.  TCP is a connection-oriented protocol, which means it establishes the connection before any communication between the network’s computer units. Because we]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Specialisation Courses for Advanced ML Practitioners]]></title>
        <id>60cc5a904dc1a607ed7b4c54</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-specialisation-courses-for-advanced-ml-practitioners/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, you don’t need to go to a university or a college to pursue a career in machine learning or any data-driven domain. But you do need a plan and a roadmap to guide your studies. Once you have charted your own learning roadmap with a goal in mind,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Sorting Algorithms]]></title>
        <id>60cca3294dc1a607ed7b4c76</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/understanding-sorting-algorithms/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:56:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every programming language uses sorting algorithms. While programming languages have easy-to-use sorting methods, it can be helpful to understand how they work. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you some of the most popular sorting algorithms! Haris Iftikhar developed this course. Haris]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342326</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied the fonts of the top 1000 websites. Here’s what I learned. — Michael Li brings the data. San-serif has total dominance. “[…] it is rare to go below 10px or above 24px.” And poor <h5> always being the 
…
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why brutal protests have been sweeping across Colombia – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T11:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the Amazon to the Caribbean coast, several weeks of protests have swept Colombia – dozens have died as demonstrators have faced sometimes deadly retaliation from police. 
The catalyst was a proposed tax hike, since withdrawn, in response to the coronavirus crisis. Demands expanded to calls to end inequality, economic disparity and police violence in Colombia – in almost two months, demonstrations have caused food and goods shortages.
Protest leaders have temporarily suspended in-person demonstrations due to a rise in Covid cases, but Joe Parkin Daniels, reporting for the Guardian, explains why this widespread discontent is unlikely to end


 ‘This is a revolution’: the faces of Colombia’s protests
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels, Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why England’s footballers are so determined to keep taking the knee - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/18/why-englands-footballers-are-so-determined-to-keep-taking-the-knee-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/18/why-englands-footballers-are-so-determined-to-keep-taking-the-knee-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T02:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England’s footballers will take the knee before their match against Scotland at Wembley tonight in an anti-racism protest that has divided supporters. Liam Rosenior and Paul MacInnes reflect on how football became enmeshed in the culture wars
When England’s footballers took to the pitch for their first match of Euro 2020 last Sunday they felt the weight of expectation as one of the tournament’s hotly tipped sides. But after a loudly bellowed national anthem, the team dropped to one knee on the Wembley turf for the anti-racism act that has become a mainstay of English football for the past year. Some of their own supporters loudly booed before the majority drowned them out in applause. 
Liam Rosenior, a former professional footballer currently on the coaching staff at Derby County, tells Anushka Asthana of his sadness but not surprise at the booing. He takes apart the argument that the players are making an overtly political statement and chastises politicians who he believes have sought to use the issue to inflame existing tensions. The Guardian’s sports reporter Paul MacInnes delves into the history of the gesture itself, which gained traction in the US on the back of the long-running anti-racism protest made by NFL quarterback Colin Kaepernick. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Liam Rosenior and Paul MacInnes;  produced by Joshua Kelly, Courtney Yusuf and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341948</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/perfect-tooltips-with-css-clipping-and-masking/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clipping and masking have been around for a while now in CSS and even have pretty decent browser support. I recently worked on a project that needed to use a clipping technique for tooltips showing above links in text.
Those …
The post Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Hoebregts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342257</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/start-serving-optimized-images-in-vue/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have become extremely important to the effectiveness of websites. They speak a 1000 words, attract attention, and stimulate emotions.
However, web performance is also a growing problem for most websites. And images are at the heart of many web …
The post Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ImageEngine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: were you affected by the 2011 England riots?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is 10 years since the riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester. We would like to hear from those who witnessed them
This year marks the tenth anniversary of the 2011 riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester which followed protests after the police shooting of Mark Duggan. We would like to hear from those affected – including witnesses, former police officers, and people who participated. How did the riots affect you? What is your perspective now?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small businesses: have you given up the office permanently?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/17/smes-have-you-ditched-the-office-permanently</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/17/smes-have-you-ditched-the-office-permanently"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from small businesses who have given up on office-working since the pandemic – or are thinking about it – in favour of working from home
After the pandemic hit, the proportion of people working from home in the UK more than doubled.
We’d like to hear from small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) who have shifted to remote-working from home and are now planning to ditch the office for good.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is the truth out there? The US government prepares its landmark report on UFOs - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/17/is-the-truth-out-there-the-us-government-prepares-its-landmark-report-on-ufos-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/17/is-the-truth-out-there-the-us-government-prepares-its-landmark-report-on-ufos-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T02:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A hotly anticipated US government report on decades of mysterious sightings of UFOs is due for release this month. The Guardian’s Adam Gabbatt and former Ministry of Defence employee Nick Pope investigate
In December 2020, just before Donald Trump left the White House, the CIA was given six months to release all of the evidence it had gathered in the last 14 years about UFOs. So later this month a highly anticipated report will be released. 
Guardian reporter Adam Gabbatt tells Anushka Asthana that in recent years a series of government videos showing unidentified objects have been released, including footage from a navy F-18 fighter jet which showed an oblong object flying through the sky near San Diego in 2004. The wave of recent videos and the imminent release of the government report has ignited excitement around unidentified flying objects not seen for years. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Adam Gabbatt and Nick Pope; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inline Styles as Classes (lol)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342358</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inline-styles-as-classes-lol/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re abhorred by using inline styles, just move that style to the class attribute! And then make sure you have CSS in place that, ya know, does what it says on the box. 
I've revolutionized CSS. pic.twitter.com/1AWCldyCwP
— Sam 

…
The post Inline Styles as Classes (lol) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful and Useless Code Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/useful-and-usless-code-comments/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Nielsen: 
If somebody says a comment isn’t adding any value, I would ask: to whom?
Personally, I’ve never liked the advice that writing obvious comments is bad practice—probably because I write obvious comments all the time.
Jim showed …
The post Useful and Useless Code Comments appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342353</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-i-used-the-waapi-to-build-an-animation-library/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Animations API lets us construct animations and control their playback with JavaScript. The API opens the browser’s animation engine to developers and was designed to underlie implementations of both CSS animations and transitions, leaving the door open to …
The post How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okiki Ojo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care home workers: share your thoughts on mandatory Covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from care home staff on their thoughts about vaccines among reports ministers will make them mandatory
Ministers are planning to announce that Covid vaccinations are to become mandatory for care home staff in England, with them considering extending the move to all NHS staff.
We would like to hear from care home workers on their thoughts about mandatory vaccines and what their experiences have been like.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detect Unused Classes in… HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342198</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/detect-unused-classes-in-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T23:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, when “unused” comes up in conversation regarding CSS, it’s about removing chunks of CSS that are not used in your site or, at least, the styles not currently in use on a specific page. The minimal amount of CSS …
The post Detect Unused Classes in… HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Media Queries in Times of @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342519</id>
        <link href="https://mxb.dev/blog/media-queries-in-times-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T19:51:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Böck took me up on my challenge to look through a codebase and see how many of the @media queries could ultimately become @container queries.
I took the bait and had a look at some of my projects – 
…
The post Media Queries in Times of @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just How Niche is Headless WordPress?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342248</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/just-how-niche-is-headless-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T14:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wonder where headless WordPress will land. And by “headless” I mean only using the WordPress admin and building out the user-facing site through the WordPress REST API rather than the traditional WordPress theme structure.
Is it… big? The future …
The post Just How Niche is Headless WordPress? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342294</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-tables-with-sticky-header-and-footers-got-a-bit-easier/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It wasn’t long ago when I looked at sticky headers and footers in HTML <table>s in the blog post A table with both a sticky header and a sticky first column. In it, I never used position: sticky on …
The post Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342229</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-tricks-chronicle-xxxx/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a little link roundup of some off-site stuff I’ve done recently. As I’m wont to do from time to time. 
DevJourney Podcast
#151 Chris Coyier from ceramics to CSS-Tricks and CodePen‘
Chris took us from playing on 
…
The post CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342070</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/securing-your-website-with-subresource-integrity/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you load a file from an external server, you’re trusting that the content you request is what you expect it to be. Since you don’t manage the server yourself, you’re relying on the security of yet another third party …
The post Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khari McMillian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>