<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-31T01:25:32.183Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-31T01:25:32.183Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.9.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tribunal claims for ageism at work soar since Covid lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/31/ageism-work-tribunal-claims-soar-covid-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/31/ageism-work-tribunal-claims-soar-covid-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Age discrimination cases in England and Wales increase by 176% in last three months of 2020

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The number of age discrimination claims taken to employment tribunals has increased dramatically in England and Wales since Covid lockdown, according to analysis of Ministry of Justice data.
Claims increased by 74% over the last year, with a 176% rise between October and December 2020 compared with the same period the year before.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Hill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uganda police killings reconstructed using mobile phone footage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/31/uganda-police-killings-reconstructed-using-mobile-phone-footage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/31/uganda-police-killings-reconstructed-using-mobile-phone-footage"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interviews with more than 30 witnesses also used in investigation by BBC Africa Eye into deaths in Kampala 
A single truck carrying eight police officers was responsible for a mass shooting in the centre of the Ugandan capital, Kampala, in November last year in which at least four people died and many more were injured, an investigation by BBC Africa Eye has found.
The shootings were part of a crackdown on protests in Kampala following the arrest of opposition leader Robert Kyagulanyi, a singer turned politician known as Bobi Wine, who was campaigning as a candidate for presidential elections held two months later.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke Africa correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TV stars and fans to appear as holograms at Bafta awards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/31/tv-stars-fans-holograms-bafta-awards</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/31/tv-stars-fans-holograms-bafta-awards"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public can sign up for the chance to line the red carpet and meet their favourite actors 
TV stars and fans will follow in the virtual footsteps of Tupac Shakur, Michael Jackson and Whitney Houston by appearing in hologram form at the Bafta television awards, it has been announced.
Nominees for this year’s British Academy Television Awards who cannot attend the 6 June ceremony because of Covid restrictions can be beamed on to the red carpet. The technology will be offered to TV stars who may be restricted to production filming bubbles as well as fans who had hoped to line the red carpet.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edinburgh international children’s festival review – a riot of colour and emotion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/31/edinburgh-international-childrens-festival-review-a-riot-of-colour-and-emotion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/31/edinburgh-international-childrens-festival-review-a-riot-of-colour-and-emotion"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Available online
Animation and street dancing power Mixed Up, a film about validating feelings, while The Super Special Disability Roadshow gives voice to a young audience
There’s a video for delegates to the Edinburgh international children’s festival showing a primary-school class responding to Katy Wilson’s film Mixed Up (5 and 6 June). The film itself is a delight. Choreographed by Ashley Jack, it’s a sequence of street dances performed by Gabriele Bruzzese and Ursula Manandhar. They switch between loneliness, joy and introspection as swiftly as the soundtrack moves from hip-hop to disco.
Meanwhile, artist Ursula Cheng plays with swirls of turquoise and orange paint to create patterns recalling a Damien Hirst spin painting. She also superimposes pulsating animations that have the appealing simplicity of Keith Haring’s squiggles. Adding to the sensory collage is Bigg Taj with his dextrous beatboxing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 1: Italy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/31/euro-2020-team-guides-part-1-italy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/31/euro-2020-team-guides-part-1-italy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roberto Mancini has got Italy believing again but they need one of their strikers to have the month of their lives to go far
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
Roberto Mancini has been busy putting together the biggest numbers in Italy since Pythagoras, who travelled to the country in 530BC to teach his theorem. Mancini took over shortly after Gian Piero Ventura failed to qualify for the 2018 World Cup and at the time of writing, has the highest win rate of any Italy manager (70%). “Back in May 2018, I was confident we could be back, because nobody believed in us,” Mancini said. He was right. The Azzurri have so far won 21 games out of 30 under his tenure, including 10 wins in 10 qualifying group matches. Moreover, Italy extended their unbeaten run to 25, five games shy of a famous record set by Vittorio Pozzo in the 1930s.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Bianchin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyprus election: far-right party linked to Greek neo-Nazis doubles vote share]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/far-right-cyprus-election-parliament</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/far-right-cyprus-election-parliament"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T21:59:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Popular Front takes 6.8% of vote amid government corruption scandals and ‘xenophobic climate’
A far-right party with links to Greece’s defunct neo-Nazi Golden Dawn has doubled its support in Cyprus after widespread disaffection over corruption scandals dominated elections for a new parliament on Sunday.
The National Popular Front (Elam) garnered 6.8% of the vote, narrowly replacing the Movement of Social Democrats (Edek) as the fourth biggest political force in the island’s Greek Cypriot party system for the first time in 45 years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Nicosia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea eye Romelu Lukaku as Tuchel targets Premier League title challenge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/30/chelsea-eye-romelu-lukaku-as-tuchel-targets-premier-league-title-challenge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/30/chelsea-eye-romelu-lukaku-as-tuchel-targets-premier-league-title-challenge"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T21:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Tuchel keen to add to his attacking options
‘Two or three signings could be very good – we don’t need seven’

Thomas Tuchel is planning a move for Romelu Lukaku as he considers how to build a dynasty at Chelsea and mould a side capable of challenging for the Premier League title next season after winning the Champions League on Saturday night.
Chelsea became European champions for the second time after their 1-0 victory over Manchester City at the Estadio do Dragão and Tuchel, who is close to signing a new two-year deal, is already hungry for more success. The manager, who met the club’s owner, Roman Abramovich, in person for the first time on Saturday, is targeting a maximum of three signings this summer and is keen to increase his options in attack, with Internazionale’s Lukaku prominent in his thoughts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg in Porto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden promises to press Putin on human rights at Geneva summit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/joe-biden-vladimir-putin-human-rights-geneva-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/joe-biden-vladimir-putin-human-rights-geneva-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T21:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US and Russian presidents to meet in Geneva in June
Biden marks Memorial Day with speech in Delaware

Joe Biden said on Sunday he will press Vladimir Putin to respect human rights when the two leaders meet in June.
In a speech marking the Memorial Day holiday, Biden said: “I’m meeting with President Putin in a couple weeks in Geneva, making it clear we will not stand by and let him abuse those rights.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The $3bn bargain: how China dominates Pacific mining, logging and fishing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/31/the-3bn-bargain-how-china-dominates-pacific-mining-logging-and-fishing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/31/the-3bn-bargain-how-china-dominates-pacific-mining-logging-and-fishing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T20:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China received more than half of all seafood, wood, and minerals exported from the region in 2019. Experts warn this is creating ‘enormous challenges for sustainable development’

Read more of our Pacific Plunder series here

One country dominates the Pacific’s resources extraction.
Guardian analysis of trade data has revealed that China received more than half the total tonnes of seafood, wood and minerals exported from the region in 2019, a haul worth $3.3bn that has been described by experts as “staggering in magnitude”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Nicholas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pacific Plunder: this is who profits from the mass extraction of the region’s natural resources – interactive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/may/31/pacific-plunder-this-is-who-profits-from-the-mass-extraction-of-the-regions-natural-resources-interactive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/ng-interactive/2021/may/31/pacific-plunder-this-is-who-profits-from-the-mass-extraction-of-the-regions-natural-resources-interactive"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T20:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Across the region, mining, logging and fishing have formed the basis of economies and development, but have sometimes come at catastrophic cost

Read more of our Pacific Plunder series here
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Nicholas, Andy Ball, Nick Evershed, Ben Doherty and Kate Lyons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC Covid distancing sensor devices beset by noise and fire safety issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/30/bbc-withdraws-covid-protection-devices-over-safety-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/30/bbc-withdraws-covid-protection-devices-over-safety-concerns"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:44:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Staff claim body-worn proximity devices have been withdrawn after one started smoking

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

When the BBC bought thousands of proximity sensors in January, the hope was that they would protect staff by aiding compliance with Covid-19 social distancing rules in newsrooms. Instead, it has had to deal with fears that the body-worn electronic devices could set themselves on fire – and complaints that they were so noisy, they disrupted recordings.
The Bluetooth technology was introduced in January to ensure that employees who had to go into the office and work as part of a team stayed 2 metres apart. The idea was that any employees in the office, usually journalists working on key news programmes, would wear them around their neck or in their pocket. If colleagues got too close to one another, an alarm would warn them to back away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amy Cokayne doubles up as Harlequins beat Saracens for first Premier 15s title]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/amy-cokayne-doubles-up-as-harlequins-beat-saracens-for-first-premier-15s-title</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/amy-cokayne-doubles-up-as-harlequins-beat-saracens-for-first-premier-15s-title"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Saracens 17 - 24 Harlequins 
Lagi Tuima notches five penalties to dethrone holders

Harlequins clinched their first Premier 15s title to erase memories of two defeats against a Saracens side that had beaten them in the last two finals. It was Harlequins’ first domestic title and came after they had raced into a 16-point lead.
The match started the match on shaky ground for the champions with Zoe Harrison kicking the ball straight out of play. The fly-half was in trouble again as Quins’ captain Rachael Burford charged down her kick which led to the first points of the match as Lagi Tuima slotted a penalty in front of the posts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Rendell at Kingsholm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robson-Kanu left out of Wales squad for Euro 2020 but Colwill called up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/30/robson-kanu-left-out-of-wales-squad-for-euro-2020-but-colwill-called-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/30/robson-kanu-left-out-of-wales-squad-for-euro-2020-but-colwill-called-up"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:20:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hero of 2016 campaign left out of 26-man Wales squad
Cardiff teenage midfielder Ruben Colwill a surprise inclusion

Hal Robson-Kanu will not repeat his heroics at the European Championship this summer after being left out of the 26-man Wales squad for this summer’s tournament, with Cardiff City’s teenage midfielder Rubin Colwill a wildcard inclusion, alongside the captain Gareth Bale, Aaron Ramsey, and Joe Allen. Wales ramp up their preparations with a friendly against world champions France in Nice on Wednesday before hosting Albania in Cardiff on Saturday.
Robson-Kanu scored a sensational goal to help Wales beat Belgium and reach the semi-finals at Euro 2016 but his international career appears to be over after he was omitted by interim manager Robert Page, who will lead the team in the continued absence of Ryan Giggs. Robson-Kanu, who received his last call-up against Mexico in March, was sent home from the last international camp after breaching a curfew at the team hotel and was not part of the Wales training camp in Portugal last week, for which Page named a 28-man squad.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU Commission calls on UK to ditch ideology over Northern Ireland protocol]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/eu-commission-uk-northern-ireland-protocol-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/eu-commission-uk-northern-ireland-protocol-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:07:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maroš Šefčovič says he is trying to iron out disruption to businesses caused by the protocol

A senior European Commission figure has defended the Northern Ireland protocol, calling on the UK government to ditch ideology in favour of pragmatism in order to transform problems arising from the Brexit deal.
Maroš Šefčovič said he was looking at “solutions” to iron out disruption to businesses caused by the protocol, a key part of the Brexit agreement designed to protect the bloc’s single market at its frontier with the UK on the island of Ireland, without a return to a hard border.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Democrats say Republican voting bill marks ‘dark day for democracy’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/texas-republicans-sb7-restrictive-voting-law</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/texas-republicans-sb7-restrictive-voting-law"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bill rushed to floor of state senate in middle of the night
Castro: restrictions ‘clearly aimed at people of colour’
‘Un-American and wrong’: Biden blasts Texas voting bill

Texas Democrats called Sunday “one of the darkest days” for American democracy, after Republicans pushed one of the most restrictive voting measures in the US to the cusp of law, rushing the bill through the state Senate in the middle of the night.
 Related: Republicans who embraced Trump’s big lie run to become election officials 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicola Jennings on Boris Johnson and Carrie Symonds’ wedding – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/30/nicola-jennings-on-boris-johnson-and-carrie-symonds-wedding-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/30/nicola-jennings-on-boris-johnson-and-carrie-symonds-wedding-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tim Southee: ‘New Zealand, world Test champions? It would be special’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/tim-southee-new-zealand-world-test-champions-it-would-be-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/tim-southee-new-zealand-world-test-champions-it-would-be-special"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The New Zealand seamer on playing at Lord’s, his side’s stellar bowling attack and the chance to become a world champion
It was in the art deco city of Napier that Tim Southee announced himself, the 19-year-old farmer’s son crackling on his Test debut against England in 2008 with a five-wicket haul and a blaze of sixes. Some 13 years and 77 caps later he pitches up at Lord’s for the fourth time in his Test career as the leader of what is arguably New Zealand’s finest attack.
A natural purveyor of right-arm swing from a 6ft 4in frame, yet doing so predominantly with the less conducive Kookaburra ball, Southee has been one of the pillars of understated excellence that has driven Kane Williamson’s side to next month’s World Test Championship final against India in Southampton.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate Now Conquers: Kanneh-Mason/Chineke!/Edusei review – fine sounds of celebration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/30/fate-now-conquers-kanneh-masonchinekeedusei-review-fine-sounds-of-celebration</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/30/fate-now-conquers-kanneh-masonchinekeedusei-review-fine-sounds-of-celebration"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T18:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Festival Hall, London
Chineke! Orchestra had the deserved honour of welcoming audiences back to the venue, with work inspired by BLM protests and a swashbuckling finale
It had been 439 days, we were told, since the Royal Festival Hall last opened its doors to a public audience. Whatever the disappointments of such a long period of closure, the mood as the players of Chineke! Orchestra took to the stage was celebratory. That this ensemble was chosen to be first back shows how far it has come in its six-year existence. There were cheers as Chineke!’s founder Chi-chi Nwanoku was presented with Making Music’s Sir Charles Groves prize, and more of them at the mention of that organisation’s campaign for amateur choirs to be allowed to rehearse together again.
There is indeed always campaigning to be done in the music world – but at least Chineke!’s work as an amplifier for composers of colour is bearing fruit. This concert began with two works written last year. The first, a UK premiere, was Fate Now Conquers by Carlos Simon, a breezy, motoring overture with the harmonies of the second movement of Beethoven’s Symphony No 7 as its jumping-off point. Desmond Neysmith made something lovely of the cello solo at its centre.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erica Jeal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tributes follow stabbing of north London flower seller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/tributes-follow-stabbing-of-north-london-flower-seller</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/tributes-follow-stabbing-of-north-london-flower-seller"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T18:48:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Eastlake died from a knife wound on Saturday after what witnesses described as an ‘altercation’
Tributes have flooded in for a flower seller who was stabbed to death close to his stall in north London on Saturday afternoon.
Tony Eastlake, 55, died from a knife wound after being attacked in Islington just before 5.30pm, and despite the efforts of emergency services was pronounced dead at the scene. Witnesses reported him being involved in “an altercation” with another man before the assault, the Metropolitan police said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third wave of Covid may be under way in UK, scientists say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/third-wave-of-covid-may-be-under-way-in-uk-scientists-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/third-wave-of-covid-may-be-under-way-in-uk-scientists-say"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T18:48:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With new infections at level last seen in March, experts have cautioned against lifting restrictions too soon

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Scientists have warned ministers that a third wave of coronavirus may have already begun in Britain, casting doubt on plans in England to lift all lockdown restrictions in three weeks’ time.
Experts cautioned that any rise in coronavirus hospital admissions could leave the NHS struggling to cope as it battles to clear the huge backlog in non-Covid cases.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti, Nicola Davis and Ian Sample</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli opposition figures reach deal aimed at ousting Netanyahu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/israel-opposition-netanyahu-lapid-bennett</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/israel-opposition-netanyahu-lapid-bennett"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T18:21:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far-right politician Naftali Bennett says he has agreed to a deal with Yair Lapid to forge a coalition government
The far-right Israeli politician Naftali Bennett and opposition leader Yair Lapid have agreed to forge a coalition government that would oust Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu from his 12 straight years in power.
“It’s my intention to do my utmost in order to form a national unity government along with my friend Yair Lapid, so that, God willing, together we can save the country from a tailspin and return Israel to its course,” said Bennett, a former settler leader and religious nationalist, in a televised address.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bank holiday Monday could be hottest day of year so far in UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/bank-holiday-monday-could-be-hottest-day-of-year-so-far-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/bank-holiday-monday-could-be-hottest-day-of-year-so-far-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:57:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forecasters say temperatures may pass 25C in sunny end to unusually wet and cold May
The UK could have its hottest day of the year so far on bank holiday Monday, with temperatures predicted to soar after rising across the country over the weekend.
Forecasters said the mercury may pass 25C (77F) on Monday, which would be a new record for this year, beating the current high of 24.5C measured in Kew Gardens on 31 March.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two dead and more than 20 injured in Florida banquet hall shooting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/two-dead-more-than-20-hurt--florida-banquet-hall-shooting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/two-dead-more-than-20-hurt--florida-banquet-hall-shooting"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:45:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three people open fire indiscriminately on concert crowd
Police lament ‘despicable act of gun violence’

At least two people were killed and more than 20 injured in Miami early on Sunday as attackers opened fire on concertgoers outside a banquet hall. It was the city’s second deadly mass shooting in little more than 24 hours.
A police spokesman said the shooting happened in the Hialeah area when three people got out of a white SUV and began firing on a line outside the El Mula banquet hall. The attackers, whom witnesses said were wearing ski masks and hoodies, used assault rifles and a handgun, authorities said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Real compromise’ possible on Biden infrastructure plan, key Republican says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/real-compromise-biden-infrastructure-plan-republican-capito</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/real-compromise-biden-infrastructure-plan-republican-capito"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:31:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shelley Moore Capito part of Senate talks group
Buttigieg: GOP offer is funds that would be spent anyway

Negotiations with Joe Biden over a potentially massive infrastructure investment package are inching forward even though disagreements remain over the size and scope of such legislation, Republican senator Shelley Moore Capito said on Sunday.
 Related: Joe Biden seeks Republican buy-in but how long before patience snaps? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neil Finn on the return of Crowded House: ‘I am ultimately very optimistic about the world’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/31/neil-finn-on-the-return-of-crowded-house-i-am-ultimately-very-optimistic-about-the-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/31/neil-finn-on-the-return-of-crowded-house-i-am-ultimately-very-optimistic-about-the-world"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the band release their first record in a decade, the New Zealand songwriter reflects on their influences – from Fleetwood Mac to Donald Trump
Neil Finn, New Zealand music’s jovial elder statesman, is remembering his best friend and bandmate Paul Hester.
He recalls the Crowded House drummer holding Finn’s baby son Liam up to the heavens, recreating a scene from the 70s TV show Roots; how Hester taught Liam’s younger brother, Elroy, to play the drums. But Hester’s gone now – he took his own life in 2005.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Buckley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m one of those irritating people who says they like running and actually means it | Emma Kemp]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/31/im-one-of-those-irritating-people-who-says-they-like-running-and-actually-means-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/31/im-one-of-those-irritating-people-who-says-they-like-running-and-actually-means-it"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running is both pleasure and pain, success and failure, exhilaration and tedium. I will never stop
It is raining, hard. It’s back during the New South Wales floods, and I can hardly see through the saturated sheets of water stinging my face. There isn’t a soul on the streets – no other halfwit is putting themselves through this deluge. But I have already missed two marathon training sessions this week and will not under any circumstances make it a terrible trifecta.
I arrived at my parents’ place for dinner, planning a tempo run before we eat. Inexplicably, my shoes did not arrive with me. So here I am, plodding in an old pair of my mum’s, akin to squelching weights around my ankles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Kemp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on funding universities: the market model isn’t working | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/the-guardian-view-on-funding-universities-the-market-model-isnt-working</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/the-guardian-view-on-funding-universities-the-market-model-isnt-working"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sub-prime state of the student loan book reflects an increasingly dysfunctional system
Around a decade has passed since David Cameron’s coalition government tripled the cap on university tuition fees to £9,000, while drastically reducing direct grants to higher education institutions in England. Conveniently for a government that made cutting the deficit its raison d’etre, this manoeuvre took public spending on higher education off the books, and an accounting assumption was made that the government-backed loans would be repaid. Ten years on, there are clear signs that this funding model, and the marketised campus culture it created, is becoming dysfunctional.
In Whitehall, alarm bells are ringing over the distinctly sub-prime state of the student loan book, which the Office for National Statistics now insists is included in national accounts. Ten years ago, it was assumed that 30% of fee loans would be written off. The current estimate is well over 50%, costing the public purse about £1tn by 2040. Over 80% of students will never repay their loans in full. For students, the job market has not offered the earning opportunities anticipated by the architects of the loans system. Many graduates never come close to the £27,295 threshold at which repayments start.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Catholics question why Boris Johnson was able to marry in church]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/boris-johnson-carrie-symmonds-married-catcholic-church</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/boris-johnson-carrie-symmonds-married-catcholic-church"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:28:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clergy and worshippers raise query as faith’s law does not recognise divorce
Catholics, including members of the congregation at Westminster Cathedral, have questioned why the prime minister was able to be married in a Catholic church following his two previous divorces.
Boris Johnson married Carrie Symonds at the cathedral in a ceremony with 30 friends and family on Saturday, planned in strict secrecy and reportedly carried out by Father Daniel Humphreys, who baptised their son Wilfred last year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on medical records: NHS data grab needs explaining | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/the-guardian-view-on-medical-records-nhs-data-grab-needs-explaining</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/the-guardian-view-on-medical-records-nhs-data-grab-needs-explaining"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In England, ministers’ plans to suck up GP records need to be scrapped and restarted with a proper debate about their use and privacy implications
The government wants to extract the general practice history of every patient in England by 1 July. Haven’t you heard? Ministers are not exactly shouting about this momentous news. NHS Digital, the body proposing the new scheme, has described it as a way to “improve” the collection of patient information that would allow better planning of healthcare services and use of data in medical research. But there are charging guidelines for the use of this data. One might reasonably conclude that the most sensitive medical details of the entire adult English population are being collected and some portion may be provided at “costs” agreed with third parties.
The records being stored contain the most private details of a person’s life. The proposals suggest mass collection of every English patient’s history, including mental health episodes, their smoking and drinking habits, and diagnoses of diseases such as cancer. But it will also include dated instances of domestic violence, abortions, sexual histories and criminal offences. Given the proposed scope of such a database, it is reasonable to ask who will be given this data, and for what purpose.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naomi Osaka fined for media snub and threatened with French Open expulsion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/french-open-womens-singles-naomi-osaka-patricia-tig</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/french-open-womens-singles-naomi-osaka-patricia-tig"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:23:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No 2 seed fined $15,000 by the four grand slam organisers
Osaka defeats Patricia Maria Tig to reach second round

Naomi Osaka has been fined $15,000 (£10,570) for her refusal to “honour her contractual media obligations” following her 6-4, 7-6 (4) victory over Patricia Maria Tig in her first-round match at Roland Garros on Sunday .
In a lengthy and stern statement released shortly after her win, the four grand slam tournaments warned that should Osaka repeatedly violate the rules, she could be “exposing herself” to sanctions including being thrown out of the tournament and a major offence investigation that could lead to future grand slam suspensions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hollywood actor Steven Seagal joins pro-Kremlin party]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/30/hollywood-actor-steven-seagal-joins-pro-kremlin-party</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/30/hollywood-actor-steven-seagal-joins-pro-kremlin-party"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:12:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Martial arts enthusiast and Putin admirer proposes crackdown on businesses that harm the environment
The Hollywood actor Steven Seagal, a long-time admirer of Russian president Vladimir Putin, has joined a pro-Kremlin party, the party said on Sunday.
Seagal received a membership card of an alliance named A Just Russia – Patriots – For Truth on Saturday, a video released by the party showed. It was formed earlier this year, when three leftist parties, all of which support Putin, merged.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dozens of new school buildings in England ‘have combustible insulation’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/dozens-of-new-school-buildings-in-england-have-combustible-insulation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/dozens-of-new-school-buildings-in-england-have-combustible-insulation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: cladding banned from high-rise blocks after Grenfell disaster still allowed on schools
Dozens of schools have been built using combustible insulation since the material was banned on high-rise apartment blocks after the Grenfell Tower disaster, raising fears for children’s safety.
More than 70 schools are likely to have used plastic foam insulation, which burns, since it was banned on residential buildings over 18 metres in height in December 2018, according to industry research.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slade and Vermeulen lead Exeter to 74-3 demolition of hapless Newcastle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/exeter-newcastle-premiership-rugby-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/exeter-newcastle-premiership-rugby-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T16:42:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exeter 74-3 Newcastle
Henry Slade and Jacques Vermeulen score two tries each

One or two other sides are finishing the regular season strongly but they still have to loosen the iron grip of last season’s champions Exeter. Roared on by the first home fans to populate Sandy Park for five months the rampant Chiefs proved far too much for their under-strength visitors and are now just three points behind leaders Bristol with two rounds to play.
The Chiefs also equalled their record tally for a Premiership match, matching the 74 points rattled up against London Welsh six years ago, with man-of-the-match Henry Slade and Jacques Vermeulen collecting two tries apiece. It has not been the greatest of months for Slade, unluckily omitted from the British & Irish Lions squad to tour South Africa, but the gifted centre enjoyed himself here in front of the watching England coach, Eddie Jones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson at Sandy Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The collapse of the last Hillsborough trial shows our legal system is broken | Andy Burnham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/collapse-hillsborough-trial-legal-system-law-bereaved-family-trauma-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/collapse-hillsborough-trial-legal-system-law-bereaved-family-trauma-court"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T16:24:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s time to pass a law to make sure no bereaved family is ever again callously made to relive their trauma in court
Back in 2009, on the evening of the 20th anniversary, I made a promise to the Hillsborough families at Liverpool town hall that I would do everything I could to support them. Twelve years on, we have arrived at the end of the legal line. But there is one more battle left, and it’s the biggest of them all: the root-and-branch reform of English justice.
The families’ 32-year fight for justice furnishes us with all the evidence anyone could need that our legal system is broken. Aside from the brutal, re-traumatising way it treats bereaved families, it has comprehensively failed to provide any real accountability for 96 unlawful deaths and a cover-up. The latter took the form of a false, blame-shifting narrative briefed to newspapers days after the tragedy, was maintained by South Yorkshire police throughout the Taylor inquiry and the first inquest, and was repeated only last week to the BBC by a senior QC involved in the case.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Burnham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The shameful failures that threw care home residents to Covid | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/the-shameful-failures-that-threw-care-home-residents-to-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/the-shameful-failures-that-threw-care-home-residents-to-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:51:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers on the government’s mistakes and neglect that meant elderly patients were discharged to care homes, without a Covid test, at the height of the pandemic
I am no fan of Dominic Cummings but I am pleased that the evidence he gave last week has opened up the conversation regarding discharges to care homes (Dominic Cummings says PM had no plan to protect vulnerable people from Covid, 25 May).
I am a nurse and during the first wave of Covid-19 I was on a ward that was caring for elderly patients. A huge part of my job was arranging what are known as complex discharges. This mainly consisted of discharging people to care homes. I am racked with guilt about this.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Einstein’s theories play their part in our time | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/30/einsteins-theories-play-their-part-in-our-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/30/einsteins-theories-play-their-part-in-our-time"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All scientific observations are likely to be superseded by later scientists, writes Ian Flintoff, while Tony Maynard-Smith says that new discoveries do not prove Einstein ‘wrong’
A word of caution on the latest observations of the universe and earlier theories such as those of Albert Einstein (Astronomers create largest map of the universe’s dark matter, 27 May). All such observations and conclusions are best qualified by the understanding that even our latest technologies (brilliant as these are), enhancing our five senses plus our intelligence and reasoning (evolved as the best we know on our planet), do not, in all likelihood, amount to a full or final perception of the phenomena in question. Human capacities – sensory and rational – with whatever ingenious technological enhancements, should not be assumed to be even close to the truth of many phenomena. We are not, and will never be, omniscient.
The ingenuities and perceptions of time supersede one another, as Einstein superseded Isaac Newton, and no doubt he in turn will be superseded. Meanwhile, new theories might perhaps always best be prefaced with the following warning: with the current state of human understanding, enhanced by human technologies and human reasoning, it looks as if these tentative findings might, for the time being, be discussed further. Perhaps Plato was right: we do not see things as they really are, but merely as we see them.
Ian Flintoff
Oxford
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Egan Bernal seals Giro d’Italia title after final time trial stage in Milan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/cycling-giro-ditalia-egan-bernal-milan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/30/cycling-giro-ditalia-egan-bernal-milan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:21:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colombian beats Italy’s Damiano Caruso by 1m 29sec
Britain’s Simon Yates third, Filippo Ganna wins stage

After the disruption of 2020, the first Grand Tour of the cycling season, the Giro d’Italia, marked a return to something approaching business as usual, with Egan Bernal of Team Ineos taking victory. In spite of a couple of glitches in the final week, Bernal fended off late challenges from Damiano Caruso and Simon Yates, largely thanks to the strength of the team with the biggest budget in cycling.
For Ineos, the race marked a return to the dominant, steamroller style which has now won them 12 Grand Tours in the last 10 years. Through Bernal and one of their strongest team riders, Filippo Ganna, they led the Giro for 16 of the race’s 21 stages and that display of collective strength was concluded in Sunday’s time trial into Milan where Ganna took his second stage win of the race after his victory in the opener in Turin, in spite of a puncture.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>William Fotheringham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work is where your laptop is: meet the globetrotting digital nomads]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/work-is-where-your-laptop-is-meet-the-globetrotting-digital-nomads</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/work-is-where-your-laptop-is-meet-the-globetrotting-digital-nomads"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:02:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worldwide shift to flexible and home working in pandemic has led to rise of new kind of backpacker

Home working drives demand for ‘shoffice’ space in UK gardens

Samantha Scott does not miss her daily commutes in London, particularly “the dread of having to wake up and get on the tube, and heading into work sweaty and flustered. I’m still waking up at 6 or 7am, but I’m able to go for a walk on the beach before I start work.”
When she and her partner Chris Cerra arrive with their luggage in a new city, they can easily be mistaken for tourists. But they are part of a new generation of “digital nomads” who hop from country to country to live and work.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family accuses East Surrey hospital of letting woman ‘waste away’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/family-accuses-east-surrey-hospital-letting-woman-waste-away</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/family-accuses-east-surrey-hospital-letting-woman-waste-away"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coroner ruled that neglect contributed to Linda Doherty’s death from starvation amid blunders in 2017
The family of a woman who starved to death in hospital claim staff “lacked humanity” and let her “waste away” amid an array of medical blunders over her feeding.
The care Linda Doherty received was so poor that, in an unusual move, the coroner who investigated her death ruled that neglect by East Surrey hospital had contributed to it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In brief: Leave the World Behind; The Breakup Monologues; Diving for Pearls – reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/in-brief-leave-the-world-behind-the-breakup-monologues-diving-for-pearls-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/in-brief-leave-the-world-behind-the-breakup-monologues-diving-for-pearls-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hidden pasts in Dubai, locked-down disaster and a frank, enjoyable relationships guide
Rumaan Alam
Bloomsbury, £8.99, pp256
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben East</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partner of Lord Ashcroft’s son questioned over killing of Belize police officer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/jasmin-hartin-partner-of-lord-ashcroft-son-questioned-over-killing-of-belize-police-officer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/jasmin-hartin-partner-of-lord-ashcroft-son-questioned-over-killing-of-belize-police-officer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:55:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jasmin Hartin was arrested near to location of body with ‘what appeared to be blood on her arms’
The partner of the son of Lord Ashcroft, a Conservative party donor and former treasurer, is being questioned in Belize over the killing of a police officer.
Jasmine Hartin was arrested on Friday following the discovery of the body of Supt Henry Jemmott on a pier in the resort town of San Pedro.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Weaver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK companies face pressure over links to Belarus regime]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/uk-companies-face-pressure-over-links-to-belarus-regime</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/uk-companies-face-pressure-over-links-to-belarus-regime"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:54:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rolls-Royce and British American Tobacco among firms that may take action in wake of Ryanair ‘hijacking’

The role of UK companies in allegedly helping to prop up Europe’s so-called “last dictatorship” is coming under unprecedented pressure amid signs that lobbying by Belarusian exiles and others is paying off.
Rolls-Royce and British American Tobacco are among the firms that have responded to lobbying by the Belarusian diaspora and indicated they were willing to take action.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home working drives demand for ‘shoffice’ space in UK gardens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/home-working-drives-demand-shoffice-space-uk-gardens-shed-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/home-working-drives-demand-shoffice-space-uk-gardens-shed-office"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:34:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change to working practices during Covid pandemic has led to booming sales of high-end sheds

Work is where your laptop is: meet the globetrotting digital nomads

Cropping up at the bottom of gardens up and down the UK is the latest trend among the country’s home workers – the “shoffice”, an office in a shed.
After more than a year working from kitchen tables, sofas or spare bedrooms, many Britons are looking to carve out a quiet workspace in the loft or in their garden.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock has Boris Johnson’s backing – for now | Katy Balls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/matt-hancock-boris-johnson-dominic-cummings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/matt-hancock-boris-johnson-dominic-cummings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:22:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To sack the health secretary would be to lend weight to Dominic Cummings’ criticisms of the prime minister

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

When Dominic Cummings gave evidence to MPs last week, few cabinet ministers came away unscathed. But one man suffered the most: Matt Hancock. While the former senior No 10 aide pulled no punches with his former boss, Boris Johnson – declaring him unfit to lead – it was the health secretary who ended up bearing the brunt of Cummings’ attacks.
Among the various missiles Cummings launched were claims that Hancock ought to have been sacked already for “15 to 20 things”, and was guilty of “criminal, disgraceful behaviour that caused serious harm”. The most serious allegation is that Hancock lied about protecting care homes from Covid in March – telling the prime minister residents would be tested before being sent back from hospital when that wasn’t the case. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katy Balls</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s easy to dismiss Black women’s lives’: Texas drags feet on maternal mortality crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/texas-maternal-mortality-crisis-black-women-medicaid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/texas-maternal-mortality-crisis-black-women-medicaid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As state legislature falls short on Medicaid expansion, campaigners vow to keep addressing healthcare disparities
When medical staff prepped Shawn Thierry for an emergency C-section, she knew something was very wrong. After an epidural, excruciating pain ran through her legs. Soon, she could barely breathe.
 Related: The Texas abortion ban is a performance of misogyny. But it might get worse | Moira Donegan 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mary Tuma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mare of Easttown: 20 questions the finale must answer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/mare-of-easttown-20-questions-the-finale-must-answer-kate-winslet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/mare-of-easttown-20-questions-the-finale-must-answer-kate-winslet"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Who’s in the photograph? And just what is in those journals? As the Kate Winslet thriller comes to a close, here are the mysteries we’re desperate to see solved
Warning: this article contains spoilers for episodes one to six of Mare of Easttown.
Mare of Easttown has become a bona fide phenomenon. A thriller revolving around an aloof, small-town detective tracking down the perps of the sexual abuse and murder of girls is pretty much the least original idea there is, but its combination of phenomenal performances (Kate Winslet is one of the best actors working today), surprising comic chops (Jean Smart is hilarious) and breadth of suspects has proved gripping. The show even has Stephen King hooked. Who knew a bunch of bearded men in flannel shirts could be this interesting?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Jane Parkinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Startup Wife by Tahmima Anam review – trouble in Utopia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-trouble-in-utopia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-trouble-in-utopia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A man takes the credit for his brilliant coder wife’s invention in a savage satire of tech startups
It’s easy to recall a time when Tahmima Anam’s new novel, a pacy satire set in a secretive tech “incubator”, might have passed for science fiction. Not any longer. From the all-consuming social media platform that hogs centre stage to the deadly pandemic that looms over its ending, The Startup Wife pulses with up-to-the-minute topicality. Real-world parallels can be found for even its most far-fetched notions. Software that channels the voice of a deceased loved one? Microsoft patented something very similar at the start of this year (note to IT bosses: Anam’s version goes catastrophically awry).
Look beyond the bleeding-edge technology and apocalyptic anxieties, however, and you’ll find a cautionary tale as old as time: a woman invents something, a guy takes the credit. In keeping with the credo of its backdrop (“Change is everything”), Anam is out to disrupt this narrative, embedding her efforts in a quest for love and self-determination, and swiping as she goes at an industry in which innovation has far outpaced regulation, leaving ethics in the dust. The end result may not be entirely persuasive philosophically, but as high-octane entertainment that hits notes poignant as well as savagely witty, it soars.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hephzibah Anderson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most Britons cannot name all parts of the vulva, survey reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/most-britons-cannot-name-parts-vulva-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/most-britons-cannot-name-parts-vulva-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T13:33:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 40% mislabelled clitoris regardless of their gender in study conducted out of concern for female patients

Do you know your urethra from your clitoris? And could you locate either of them on a diagram? According to a survey of patients in hospital waiting rooms, half of Britons could not identify the urethra, while 37% mislabelled the clitoris – regardless of their gender. Meanwhile, just 46% correctly identified that women have three “holes” down below.
Dina El-Hamamsy, a senior obstetrics and gynaecology registrar, now at Addenbrookes hospital in Cambridge, and her colleagues, conducted the survey out of concern that many of their female patients were confused by the nature of their medical problems.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gigs, protests and messing about in boats: the weekend’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/30/gigs-protests-and-messing-about-in-boats-the-weekends-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/30/gigs-protests-and-messing-about-in-boats-the-weekends-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T13:26:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPs warn over plans to share patient data with third parties in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/gps-warn-plans-share-patient-data-third-parties-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/gps-warn-plans-share-patient-data-third-parties-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T13:26:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors say NHS Digital’s proposals could erode the relationship between them and their patients
Doctors have warned that plans to pool medical records on to a database and share them with third parties could erode the relationship between them and patients.
The warning came as the Royal College of GPs wrote to NHS Digital urging it to better communicate with the public about the plans and their options for opting out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Don’t freak out!’ Why keeping calm and carrying on exercising can help back pain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/dont-freak-out-why-keeping-calm-and-carrying-on-exercising-can-help-back-pain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/dont-freak-out-why-keeping-calm-and-carrying-on-exercising-can-help-back-pain"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it hurts to walk, bend or even sit, it’s tempting to lie down until your spine sorts itself out. But moving can be the key to getting better

Turns out pandemics can be atrocious for our backs.  By last October, more than a third of people in the UK had reported increased back pain, according to one study – and that was before an intense winter lockdown, followed by a month-long storm. We’ve been doing online yoga without an instructor’s watchful eye and lunging with Joe Wicks without warming up, but mostly slouching over laptops feeling tense or depressed.
While the onset of back, shoulder or neck pain can feel like the last straw, the good news is that it probably isn’t as bad as you think. “It’s not likely to be serious,” says Chris Mercer, an NHS consultant physiotherapist in Sussex who specialises in back pain. It was not uncommon to keep an old door under the bed, upon which to lie when your back “went”. But the latest evidence indicates that being active is essential for both avoidance and recovery. “Keep moving, keep active and things will settle,” he says.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Fleming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: if the UK built 1m homes, what would happen to house prices?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/readers-reply-if-the-uk-built-1m-homes-what-would-happen-to-house-prices</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/readers-reply-if-the-uk-built-1m-homes-what-would-happen-to-house-prices"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
If the UK built, say, a million homes, what would happen to house prices? Gerald Jimes, south-east London
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police hunt heavily armed former soldier in south-west France]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/police-hunt-heavily-armed-former-soldier-south-western-france</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/police-hunt-heavily-armed-former-soldier-south-western-france"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T12:54:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents in Le Lardin-Saint-Lazare in the Dordogne told to stay indoors during hunt for convict 
French police backed by helicopters are searching for a heavily armed former soldier who had allegedly opened fire on officers responding to a domestic violence dispute in south-western France.
Some 210 officers and four helicopters were involved in the hunt for the man, who has an electronic tag because of a prior domestic violence conviction and who was still at large in the woods of the Dordogne region.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Le Lardin-Saint-Lazare</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BJ Thomas, singer of Raindrops Keep Fallin’ On My Head, dies at 78]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/30/bj-thomas-singer-raindrops-keep-fallin-on-my-head-dies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/30/bj-thomas-singer-raindrops-keep-fallin-on-my-head-dies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T12:41:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grammy-winning singer who enjoyed success on the pop, country and gospel charts announced in March he had lung cancer
BJ Thomas, a Grammy-winning singer who enjoyed success on the pop, country and gospel charts with hits including Raindrops Keep Fallin’ On My Head and Hooked on a Feeling, has died. He was 78.
Thomas, who announced in March that he had lung cancer, died on Saturday at his home in Arlington, Texas, his publicist said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Arlington, Texas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some long Covid sufferers in England waiting months for treatment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/some-long-covid-sufferers-in-england-waiting-months-for-treatment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/some-long-covid-sufferers-in-england-waiting-months-for-treatment"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T12:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs call on Matt Hancock to explain ‘postcode lottery’ despite assertion that clinic network is operational

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

People who remain chronically ill after Covid infections in England have had to wait months for appointments and treatment at specialist clinics set up to handle the surge in patients with long Covid.
MPs called on Matt Hancock, the health secretary, to explain the lengthy waiting times and what they described as a “shameful postcode lottery” which left some patients facing delays of more than four months before being assessed at a specialist centre while others were seen within days.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[London is being scapegoated to boost the Tories’ ‘levelling up’ agenda | Chaminda Jayanetti]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/london-scapegoated-tories-levelling-up-agenda-capital-privilege</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/london-scapegoated-tories-levelling-up-agenda-capital-privilege"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T12:07:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may be electorally useful to portray the capital as an enclave of privilege – but for most people in the city, that’s just not true
It’s fashionable to demonise London as everything from pampered and out of touch to an anti-British “enemy within” that actively keeps the rest of the country down. In this narrative, Labour has been pushed back to the supposedly privileged “metro-liberal” cities – with none more privileged, metropolitan or liberal than the UK capital.
But the notion of London as a city bathing in its own privilege is a ridiculous oversimplification. Tell it, for instance, to the six households from Grenfell Tower who are still stuck in temporary accommodation, four years on from the catastrophic fire, a lethal product of administrative corruption, ignorance and incompetence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chaminda Jayanetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Motherhood: A Manifesto; (M)otherhood; The Motherhood Complex review – calling time on the cult of the perfect parent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/motherhood-a-manifesto-motherhood-the-motherhood-complex-review-calling-time-on-the-cult-of-the-perfect-parent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/30/motherhood-a-manifesto-motherhood-the-motherhood-complex-review-calling-time-on-the-cult-of-the-perfect-parent"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T12:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eliane Glaser, Pragya Agarwal and Melissa Hogenboom offer challenging responses to the contradictions of so many parenting guides
The theme of the indignities of post-feminist motherhood is always fresh. And yet the past year seems to have rendered the wound more raw than ever. Eliane Glaser’s Motherhood: A Manifesto has already generated social media coverage galore for the assertions that “motherhood is the unfinished business of feminism” and “the cult of the perfect mother must end”. Who would disagree with these statements? But these things need saying and loudly, especially when “the pandemic is amplifying bias against working mothers”, to quote a recent typical headline.
And yet what are the solutions on offer that haven’t already been proposed decades ago by, say, Betty Friedan or Simone de Beauvoir, both, happily, quoted here? Glaser homes in on the awkward truths: “Modern motherhood somehow manages to demean women while simultaneously raising the stakes.” “For too long, the injustices of modern motherhood have been concealed by anxiety and guilt.” “… fathers’ participation has flat-lined…” But is there much “manifesto” in Motherhood: A Manifesto (ie instruction rather than insight)? Arguably not. This is more exploration and truth-telling. But when it’s so well written and well argued, who cares?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Viv Groskop</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In big tech’s dystopia, cat videos earn millions while real artists beg for tips | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/big-tech-cat-video-artists-tips-musicians-spotify-donation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/30/big-tech-cat-video-artists-tips-musicians-spotify-donation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T11:39:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instead of paying musicians properly, the likes of Spotify have set up ‘donation’ buttons – thus passing the buck to fans

Just over a year ago, the music streaming giant Spotify announced a new addition to its services: an innovation called Artist Fundraising Pick, which would allow people to send musicians the online equivalent of a tip. The move came just as controversy began to snowball about the often pitiful returns from streaming, something that reached a peak in April this year, when such big-name musicians as Paul McCartney, Kate Bush and Stevie Nicks signed a letter calling on the UK government to finally get to grips with the issue.
At around the same time, there was rising speculation about the Spotify co-founder and CEO Daniel Ek – whose net worth is put at £3.3bn – leading a consortium that wanted to buy Arsenal football club. In the context of that potentially vast deal, what Spotify had launched highlighted the tendency of big business to offer its detractors and complainants mere crumbs, but there it was: an acknowledgment that many musicians needed some extra financial help, coupled with an apparent attempt to shift the onus on to their fans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bees give me a sense of calm: discovering nature in my back garden]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/self-and-wellbeing-bees-give-me-a-sense-of-peace-and-supply-our-summer-soundtrack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/self-and-wellbeing-bees-give-me-a-sense-of-peace-and-supply-our-summer-soundtrack"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T11:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Their busy buzzing supplies the soundtrack to our summer – and by spotting them I’ve found a fresh sense of inner peace
Lockdown started, or reignited, a love of nature in many people. The RSPB reported a 70% increase in visitors to its website during the first lockdown. This came as no surprise to me; stuck at home, without the usual distraction of social engagement, my interest in nature grew. During the winter, I would look up into leafless trees trying to locate a bird whose loud call I could clearly hear. I even bought myself a pair of binoculars so I could acquaint myself with some of the local avian population.
But now I have a new hobby. As the warmer weather slowly arrives, I have been lowering my gaze towards the stirring flower beds and roadside verges, as well as rustling in the undergrowth in the hope of spotting my favourite insects. On a sunny day, there’s nothing better than sitting quietly by a patch of swaying flowers or under a blossoming tree to listen for the tell-tale sign of buzzing. This quintessential sound of summer connects me to the seasons and the natural world, even in the inner city, and fills me with joy. It is also a welcome break from staring at a screen all day. I wait peacefully, in anticipation and excitement of seeing different types of bees.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Benjamin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italy cable car crash detainees released from prison]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/italy-cable-car-crash-detainees-released-from-prison</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/italy-cable-car-crash-detainees-released-from-prison"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T11:12:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Judge places one of the three men under house arrest as investigation into brake tampering continues
An Italian judge has ruled that three men detained over a cable car crash that killed 14 people in northern Italy can leave prison, with one of them being placed under house arrest.
In the crash a week ago, a gondola on the cable connecting the Lake Maggiore resort town of Stresa to a nearby mountain plunged to the ground, killing all aboard apart from a five-year-old Israeli boy who remains in hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Milan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gadgets have stopped working together, and it’s becoming an issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/30/gadgets-have-stopped-working-together-interoperability-apple</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/30/gadgets-have-stopped-working-together-interoperability-apple"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our reliance on technology means ever more devices and apps and ever less interoperability – and the ubiquity of Apple hasn’t helped
In 2001, if you listened to digital music, you did it with a large folder of MP3 files. How you acquired them is probably best left between you and a priest, but you may have ripped them from a CD, downloaded them from a file sharing service, or bought them from one of a few nascent download sites.
Whichever option you picked, you’d play them on your computer with a program built for the task. And if you were lucky enough to have an early standalone MP3 player, it was probably made by another company again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hermitage Museum proposal divides Barcelona authorities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/hermitage-museum-proposal-divides-barcelona-authorities</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/hermitage-museum-proposal-divides-barcelona-authorities"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T10:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[City council rejects scheme to open branch of Russian institution after port authority gave the go-ahead
Barcelona’s frequently agonised debates over how to market itself to tourists have taken another twist, after the city council rejected a scheme to open a branch of St Petersburg’s Hermitage Museum in its port area.
The port authority, which owns the site of the proposed museum, gave the green light but the council has objected on the grounds of location and fears the scheme will provide little value to local residents.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Burgen in Barcelona</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Produce evidence Matt Hancock lied on Covid, Dominic Cummings to be told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/produce-evidence-matt-hancock-lied-on-covid-dominic-cummings-to-be-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/produce-evidence-matt-hancock-lied-on-covid-dominic-cummings-to-be-told"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T10:15:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Select committee chiefs to demand PM’s former aide backs up explosive claims

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Dominic Cummings will be asked by senior MPs this week to produce evidence that Matt Hancock lied repeatedly about policy on Covid-19 before the health secretary’s appearance in front of a parliamentary committee early next month.
Jeremy Hunt and Greg Clark, the chairs of the joint select committee which took seven hours of explosive testimony from Cummings last week, will write to the former adviser to the prime minister in the next few days asking that he produce the evidence within the next fortnight.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm Political Editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California faces another drought as lake beds turn to dust – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/california-drought-water-shortage-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/30/california-drought-water-shortage-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T10:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Water shortages and dry conditions are already affecting the state as the governor has declared an emergency in 41 of 58 counties
Verdant hillsides losing their hue, receding reservoirs with bathtub rings of newly exposed earth, crops withering in the fields.
These are the visions of California’s parched landscape as the state braces for another potentially devastating drought. Water shortages and exceptionally dry conditions are already beginning to hit home.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabrielle Canon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alarm at secret court scheme in UK-Australia trade deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/alarm-at-secret-court-scheme-in-uk-australia-trade-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/30/alarm-at-secret-court-scheme-in-uk-australia-trade-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T09:45:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners concerned by controversial plans for tribunals where firms can seek compensation for effect of government policies 
A free trade deal between the UK and Australia is on course to include a controversial system of secret courts that will allow businesses to seek compensation if their profits are hit by government policies.
In a move that has alarmed trade unions and anti-poverty campaigners, trade minister Greg Hands said UK negotiators were in talks with Australian officials over proposals to include a scheme that will arbitrate on disputes behind closed doors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What will it take to give Britain the all clear by 21 June?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/race-to-give-britain-the-all-clear-by-21-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/race-to-give-britain-the-all-clear-by-21-june"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T09:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explainer: The India variant of coronavirus has raised doubts on the roadmap out of lockdown. What will it take to make it safe?

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

In three weeks, the government says it hopes to remove all legal limits on social contacts as the nation emerges from its Covid lockdown. Nightclubs and music venues could reopen and larger sporting events allowed to resume without crowd restrictions.
That is the hope. The actuality may be very different as fears rise about the spread of the India variant. Some reports suggest this is 67% more transmissible than previous variants, though Professor Mark Woolhouse of Edinburgh University, counsels caution. “Sixty seven percent is an upper likely limit. The lower is around 20% or less. We will soon find out the right figure, however,” he said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie Science Editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trevor Phillips: ‘Battles over history make everything about white people and their guilt’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/trevor-phillips-battles-over-history-make-everything-about-white-people-and-their-guilt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/30/trevor-phillips-battles-over-history-make-everything-about-white-people-and-their-guilt"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T09:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The writer discusses his role on the new Heritage Advisory Board set up to guide the national debate on Britain’s past
Trevor Phillips, the broadcaster and writer chosen to become one of the members of a controversial new Heritage Advisory Board set up by Culture Secretary Oliver Dowden, has revealed the priorities that will guide him as he helps to set a steadying course for the government through Britain’s contested cultural history.
Speaking to the Observer Phillips said: “I am not against things being changed. Things get changed all the time. That’s what happens. But I want people to be honest about their motives.” The broadcaster and writer said he does object though to the cultural “window dressing” of merely changing names and taking down statues. Phillips believes it is distraction from the real work of tackling less fashionable problems, such as the lack of opportunity and economic equality facing many Britons.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vanessa Thorpe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine inequality exposed by dire situation in world’s poorest nations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/vaccine-inequality-exposed-by-dire-situation-in-worlds-poorest-nations</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/vaccine-inequality-exposed-by-dire-situation-in-worlds-poorest-nations"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T09:15:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: the failings of the Covax programme, logistical issues and governments’ own inadequacies are making a bad situation worse

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Only 1% of the 1.3 billion vaccines injected around the world have been administered in Africa – and that comparative percentage has been declining in recent weeks. It is a stark figure that underlines just how serious a problem global vaccine inequity has become. But the answer for the developing world is not as simple as delivering more vaccines.
From Africa to Latin America, Asia and the Caribbean, the same issues have been replicated. On top of finding enough doses, there have been logistical difficulties with delivery, problems over healthcare infrastructure and, in some countries, public hesitancy towards vaccines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marching on: the young loyalist bands of Northern Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/30/marching-on-young-loyalist-bands-northern-ireland-gareth-mcconnell-photography</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/30/marching-on-young-loyalist-bands-northern-ireland-gareth-mcconnell-photography"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T09:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth McConnell’s photographs of working-class Protestant bands offer a new take on the subculture at a time when tensions are once more on the rise
Towards the end of March, the London-based photographer Gareth McConnell returned to Northern Ireland to shoot a series of portraits of young people in his home town, Carrickfergus, and nearby Larne. The portraits were commissioned by Intercomm, a Belfast-based cross-community project, and the subjects, aged between seven and 26, were members of local loyalist marching bands. McConnell’s aim, he says, was “to transcend the cliched depictions of young people from Protestant working-class communities by evoking the more primal instincts that underlie these rituals of belonging”.
The resulting series, To the Beat of the Drum, bears his unmistakable imprint: vivid colours, atmospheric lighting and the creative use of blur and movement. Eschewing digital post-production techniques, McConnell achieves his heightened images when shooting, through the deft manipulation of light, movement and long exposures. The series, which also includes a mesmerising video piece of a young boy beating a drum, will be exhibited in a grid at the Ulster Museum in Belfast next month. The images have no names or captions as “they ground the work in a more documentary style,” says McConnell, “while it’s really more about exploring or suggesting a collective experience”. McConnell’s dreamlike aesthetic is more usually found applied to the creation of otherworldly still lifes and fashion editorials, but, in this instance, it has a more subtly subversive undertow.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean O’Hagan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overconsumption and the environment: should we all stop shopping?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/should-we-all-stop-shopping-how-to-end-overconsumption</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/should-we-all-stop-shopping-how-to-end-overconsumption"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T08:30:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over-consumption is at the root of the planet’s environmental crisis. One solution, proposed by author JB MacKinnon, is that we should simply buy less. But would that really work?
I fear I’m in JB MacKinnon’s bad books. Halfway through our Zoom interview, I tilt my camera to adjust to the setting sun – but from this new angle, an e-commerce box can be spotted over my shoulder. Its barcode glows in the fading light, a totem of 21st-century materialism presiding over our call.
MacKinnon is too polite to say anything, but he can’t be thrilled by my cardboard companion. After all, the Canadian bestselling author and journalist is on a mission to get us to buy a lot less stuff. The Day the World Stops Shopping, his new book, explores what might happen if the world transformed into a society that does not revolve around purchasing, one in which our primary role is not as consumers and our credit cards are not our most commonly deployed tools.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Waters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heatwave deaths set to soar as UK summers become hotter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/30/heatwave-deaths-set-to-soar-as-uk-summers-become-hotter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/30/heatwave-deaths-set-to-soar-as-uk-summers-become-hotter"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T08:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Met Office warning over impact of global heating prompts calls for action to protect elderly and vulnerable
Britain is failing to protect its vulnerable citizens from the threat of intensifying heatwaves, health experts warned last week. Thousands of preventable deaths could be triggered every year because simple measures to keep houses and care homes cool have not been implemented.
As global heating worsens and heatwaves become more frequent, the problem is likely to worsen significantly – unless urgent action is taken, they say. Those most likely to suffer include the very young, the elderly and people suffering from chronic conditions such as asthma.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parents in UK prepare for legal action over A-level results]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/30/parents-in-uk-prepare-for-legal-action-over-a-level-results</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/30/parents-in-uk-prepare-for-legal-action-over-a-level-results"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T08:15:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teachers, unions and academics concerned at potential chaos over cancelled exams as parents prepare to challenge grades
Parents who fear this summer’s teacher-assessed A-levels will be unfair are already contacting lawyers about how to appeal against their children’s grades, the Observer understands.
Ministers abandoned an algorithm designed to deliver marks after last summer’s chaotic results season. However, teachers, unions and academics are concerned that this summer could see serious fallout amid claims of grade inflation and major disparities in the way different schools assess their pupils. With exams cancelled, teachers are assessing grades.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fazackerley and Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Counting the personal cost: when axing bank branches doesn’t add up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/counting-the-personal-cost-when-axing-bank-branches-doesnt-add-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/30/counting-the-personal-cost-when-axing-bank-branches-doesnt-add-up"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T08:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As thousands are taken off the high street, fears grow for the vulnerable left without access to services

Once, high streets offered a choice of three or four banks. Now, 50 branches are closing every month, making what was a reliable cornerstone of every town, a rarer and rarer fixture.
Earlier this year the financial regulator called on banks to reconsider closures, amid fears that vulnerable people could be left without access to services.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shane Hickey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Staycation boom forces tenants out of seaside resort homes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/staycation-boom-forces-tenants-out-of-seaside-resort-homes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/staycation-boom-forces-tenants-out-of-seaside-resort-homes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T07:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Cornwall to Kent, people are driven out of popular destinations where landlords favour short lets for tourists
The lockdown shackles are off. The great half-term getaway began with predictable traffic chaos on Friday night as Britons finally got the chance to escape to the seaside.
But some people living in the resorts are being forced to head in the opposite direction along the clogged-up roads, priced out of their homes by a coastal housing crisis that has been turbocharged by the pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper and Suzanne Bearne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My parents still have no clue what I’m doing’: Lupin star Omar Sy on Hollywood, fame and fighting racism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/omar-sy-star-of-lupin-on-hollywood-racism-and-his-big-break</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/omar-sy-star-of-lupin-on-hollywood-racism-and-his-big-break"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T07:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a decade in Hollywood, French actor Omar Sy returned home to star in Netflix’s much-loved hit, Lupin. He talks about playing the charming thief, growing up with Arsenal’s Nicolas Anelka and his battle with racism
Actors, obliged to exhaustively market their wares, will pose for hours in front of posters of their latest film or TV show. They’ll hop between city premieres, sit on dreary festival panels, tell rehearsed comic stories on night-time talkshows, then get up early to be on breakfast radio. Before meeting Omar Sy, a 43-year-old Frenchman who stars in the massively popular Netflix drama Lupin, I’d never heard of an actor picking up a bucket and brush to spend a day gluing up their own billboard posters on the Paris metro. Sy, who is 6ft 2in, born in a working-class Parisian suburb to West African parents, explains the thinking behind this unusual marketing stunt that took place just before the first series of Lupin debuted earlier this year.
“A lot of people know me in Paris,” begins Sy, who worked as a comedian in France through his 20s before becoming a film star there in his early 30s. “Because people in France have watched me in stuff for years, I’m used to meeting strangers who recognise me and who already have smiles on their faces.” In Lupin, lightly adapted from the classic heist books by Maurice Leblanc, Sy plays a French-Senegalese man called Assane Diop, an anonymous Parisian who is used to being ignored and overlooked in his home town, but who is willing to use that to his advantage while robbing the city’s jet-set blind. “The show is entertainment and we want to have fun with it,” he says, “but at the same time we’re talking about something very serious: that some people in France are simply not seen.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Lamont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chefs lament the demise of food bible that made postwar British life better]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/30/chefs-lament-the-demise-of-food-bible-that-made-postwar-british-life-better</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/30/chefs-lament-the-demise-of-food-bible-that-made-postwar-british-life-better"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T06:45:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anger and sadness as Waitrose closes The Good Food Guide, the gourmet restaurant-goer’s friend for the past 70 years 
In his first job in a pub kitchen as a teenager, someone handed Gareth Ward a copy of The Good Food Guide. “I knew nothing about food or restaurants, but I read it cover to cover like it was a fairystory. It blew me away. It was a world I didn’t even know existed,” he said.
Ward, now the chef-proprietor of Ynishir on the mid-Wales coast, decided he wanted to be No 1 in the guide’s top 50. Last year, Ynishir was No 4. “I was so close, and now it will never happen.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: out and about in carefree times]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/30/the-big-picture-out-and-about-in-carefree-times</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/30/the-big-picture-out-and-about-in-carefree-times"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T06:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taken six months before the first national lockdown, Francesco Gioia’s shot of a stranger outside a London cinema is a bittersweet reminder of a happier era
When Francesco Gioia took this photograph halfway up Shaftesbury Avenue in central London, he wasn’t thinking about the privilege of being able to move freely around the city without fear of infection, or the luxury of popping into a cinema on a whim to catch a movie. The time was September 2019, six months before the UK went into lockdown, and he was more interested in shapes and colours and how people’s clothes might interact with their surroundings in striking ways.
He saw a man walking along the street wearing an eye-catching hat. “So, as I often do, I discreetly went after him and took a couple of shots,” he recalls. “Only later did I realise that, in addition to the complementary colours that you see in the picture – the blues, the whites, and the red of the cinema logo – there was also a small, heart-shaped sweat stain on the back of his shirt, which made the shot more interesting to me, because he looks very elegant otherwise.” (He never glimpsed the man’s face.)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Killian Fox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Bull and Last, London: ‘I love their grub and it’s date night’ – restaurant review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/30/fay-ripley-restaurant-review-bull-and-last-london-i-love-their-grub-and-its-date-night</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/30/fay-ripley-restaurant-review-bull-and-last-london-i-love-their-grub-and-its-date-night"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T05:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supper is so sexy at this fine gastropub on the Highgate Road, you may feel you need to get a room…
The Bull and Last, 168 Highgate Road, London NW5 1QS (020 726 7 3641). Starters £4-£12, mains £10-£34, wines from £26
When Jay Rayner asked me to step in and take care of his beloved column for a week, it felt as if he’d given me the keys to his sports car or entrusted me to breastfeed his firstborn. The jammiest job in the business only requires the answer to one big question: which restaurant brings me joy?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fay Ripley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I can’t find a partner. How can I learn to love my single life?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/dear-mariella-frostrup-i-cant-find-a-partner-how-can-i-learn-to-love-my-single-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/dear-mariella-frostrup-i-cant-find-a-partner-how-can-i-learn-to-love-my-single-life"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T05:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t have to live like swans, mating for life with one partner, says Mariella Frostrup. And be of good heart, someone nice may come along
The dilemma I am a 48-year-old single woman with a full and independent life. I’m close to my family and have a 15-year-old daughter. I have a good group of friends and several hobbies. I’ve had struggles with mental health in the past, but am doing better now than ever.
I’d also love to be in a relationship, but it’s something I’m just not able to find success in. I’ve had relationships, but I’ve spent the majority of my time single. I’ve been online dating for many years, but it seems to bring out the absolute worst in men. It’s such a cliché, but it seems that everyone is married and there are no parties or natural social occasions (including before Covid) that allow for meeting someone in a natural way.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariella Frostrup</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phone intercepts shine more light on Jordanian prince’s alleged coup attempt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/phone-intercepts-jordanian-prince-alleged-coup-attempt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/phone-intercepts-jordanian-prince-alleged-coup-attempt"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T04:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discussions took place before Prince Hamzah was put under house arrest
Aides to the former Jordanian heir Prince Hamzah sought pledges of allegiance on his behalf from tribal leaders and former military officers in the weeks before he was detained, conversations caught on phone intercepts and listening devices suggest.
The recordings are key pieces of evidence in the Jordanian government’s case against two men accused of acting as proxies for Hamzah in a failed attempt to oust his half-brother, King Abdullah, as monarch. Both men – Bassem Awadallah, a former envoy to Saudi Arabia, and Sharif Hassan bin Zaid, a cousin of the king – are expected to stand trial in Amman starting on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov and Michael Safi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kumbh Mela: how a superspreader festival seeded Covid across India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/kumbh-mela-how-a-superspreader-festival-seeded-covid-across-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/kumbh-mela-how-a-superspreader-festival-seeded-covid-across-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T00:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From across India, millions of Hindu pilgrims came to take a ritual dip in the Ganges, then returned home carrying Covid-19. Here are their stories 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

On 12 April, as India registered another 169,000 new Covid-19 cases to overtake Brazil as the second-worst hit country, three million people gathered on the shores of the Ganges.
They were there, in the ancient city of Haridwar in the state of Uttarakhand, to take a ritual dip in the holy river. The bodies, squashed together in a pack of devotion and religious fervour, paid no visible heed to Covid protocols.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen  and Aakash Hassan in Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A printmaker’s paean to moths – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/a-printmakers-paean-to-moths-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/a-printmakers-paean-to-moths-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British printmaker Sarah Gillespie was drawn to moths because they’re “overlooked and underloved”. Then she found out they’re in catastrophic decline: 50-60 species have become extinct in the past 80 years. 
So Gillespie has created a series of mezzotints, on show now at Castle Howard in Yorkshire, to highlight their existential plight. “We have done enormous damage to those we share the Earth with. The work of the artist is to pay attention – to refuse not to notice.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Original Observer photography]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/original-observer-photography</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/original-observer-photography"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Director Barry Jenkins, the plight of Syria’s refugees, and the return of live music – the best photography commissioned by the Observer in May 2021
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josy Forsdike</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Journey – How I Went from Making $1,000 to $100,000 a Year]]></title>
        <id>60acf28e11ffb70827ef6dd9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-developer-journey-how-i-went-from-1000-a-year-to-100000-as-a-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T22:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone, my name is Santosh. In this article, I will tell you how I ramped up my career and ended up making $100,000 a year as a developer.  I'll share what I learned from each job along the way, how you can stand out, tips for negotiating salary,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moments in Goomalling: the Mavis Phillips archives – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/moments-in-goomalling-the-mavis-phillips-archives-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/moments-in-goomalling-the-mavis-phillips-archives-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T20:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mavis Phillips nee Walley was one of Australia’s earliest known Indigenous photographers. She grew up in Goomalling, in rural Western Australia, and started shooting in the 1930s using a simple cardboard camera called the box Brownie. The images in this collection share the happiest times of her life when her family lived and worked on a farm owned by a white family, protected from native welfare. But they were then moved to the Goomalling native eeserve where they were subject to Western Australia’s apartheid-style laws.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farm incomes fall by 20% in a year due to weather, Covid and Brexit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/28/farm-incomes-fall-by-20-in-a-year-due-to-weather-covid-and-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/28/farm-incomes-fall-by-20-in-a-year-due-to-weather-covid-and-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increased hardship for small farmers as close to a billion pounds wiped off UK’s farming economy in 2020
Farm incomes dropped drastically last year, as poor weather combined with the impact of the pandemic and Brexit-related issues wiped close to a billion pounds off the UK’s farming economy and increased hardship for many small farmers.
Total income from farming, calculated annually by the government, fell from nearly £5.2bn in 2019 to just over £4.1bn in 2020, the lowest value in real terms since 2007.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Secure Your Android App – Four Security Best Practices Every Android Dev Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60b08d8811ffb70827ef8c7b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-secure-your-android-app/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've been following the news lately, you may have noticed a worrisome tech trend. The frequency and severity of cybersecurity attacks are exploding.  We've seen news of a sprawling hack involving the SolarWinds management platform. That attack may have compromised the systems of over 18,000 SolarWinds customers.  Then,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Computer Vision with Python]]></title>
        <id>60b0de2211ffb70827ef8d7c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/advanced-computer-vision-with-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T12:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More and more applications are using computer vision these days. We just published a full course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help you learn advanced computer vision using Python. You will learn state of the art computer vision techniques by building five projects with libraries such as]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friends: The Reunion – share your reviews of the TV special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/28/friends-the-reunion-share-your-reviews-of-the-tv-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/28/friends-the-reunion-share-your-reviews-of-the-tv-special"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:03:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week saw the Friends cast reunite for an unscripted tribute to the hit show. Send us your reviews and we’ll publish the best
The cast of Friends has reunited for a retrospective of the hit sitcom, broadcast in the UK on 27 May on Sky One and Now. Friends: The Reunion was recorded on the original soundstage with David Schwimmer, Lisa Kudrow, Matt LeBlanc, Jennifer Aniston, Courteney Cox and Matthew Perry, plus guests including Lady Gaga, Justin Bieber and David Beckham.
Did you enjoy the special? Did it live up to your expectations? And what did you think of the revelation that Ross and Rachel almost had a real-life romance?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you in a platonic marriage or a similar relationship?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T09:13:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from couples who have got married as a celebration of deep friendship rather than romance
Although legislation around marriage has changed over the last 10 years – from the introduction of same sex marriage to civil partnerships being extended to heterosexual couples – what has remained the same is the idea that marriage is for two parties romantically involved in each other. 
However, across Europe and America, the beginnings of a trend seem to be emerging: platonic marriage. This is where two parties get married as a celebration of deep friendship, rather than romance, and where their best friend is their significant other with whom they are building a life (eg. raising children).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Forever chemicals’ found in home fertilizer made from sewage sludge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/28/home-fertilizer-toxic-pfas-forever-chemicals-sewage-sludge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/28/home-fertilizer-toxic-pfas-forever-chemicals-sewage-sludge"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alarming toxic PFAS levels revealed in new report raise concerns that the chemicals are contaminating vegetables
Sewage sludge that wastewater treatment districts across America package and sell as home fertilizer contain alarming levels of toxic PFAS, also known as “forever chemicals”, a new report has revealed.
Sludge, which is lightly treated and marketed as “biosolids”, is used by consumers to fertilize home gardens, and the PFAS levels raise concerns that the chemicals are contaminating vegetables and harming those who eat them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Perkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘They fired at everyone’: peril of Pakistani villagers protesting giant luxury estate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/28/they-fired-at-everyone-peril-of-pakistani-villagers-protesting-giant-luxury-estate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/28/they-fired-at-everyone-peril-of-pakistani-villagers-protesting-giant-luxury-estate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T06:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activists were shot and beaten at demonstration to stop property giant Bahria Town building on indigenous land they say was taken with force
Muhammad Anwar was not aware of any danger when he took the day off work to join his friends at a demonstration on a construction site of a powerful real estate company.
When Anwar, 35, reached the west bank of Langeji river, near Karachi, earlier this month, he saw the bulldozers levelling land next to Bahria Town, a luxury gated development.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shah Meer Baloch in Karachi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A state-sponsored ‘hijacking’ – the arrest of Belarus blogger Raman Pratasevich]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T02:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova examines why Alexander Lukashenko, the president of Belarus, apparently diverted a Ryanair flight in order to arrest 26-year-old blogger Raman Pratasevich. Guardian Moscow correspondent, Andrew Roth, discusses the fallout from the action
Anushka Asthana talks to the Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova about the 26-year-old opposition blogger Raman Pratasevich and his 23-year-old girlfriend, Sofia Sapega. On Sunday their Ryanair flight, which was meant to be flying to Lithuania, was forced to make an emergency landing in Minsk and they were arrested. Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, the Belarusian opposition leader, told the European parliament on Wednesday that Lukashenko was “turning the country into the North Korea of Europe: non-transparent, unpredictable and dangerous”.
Anushka also talks to the Guardian’s Moscow correspondent Andrew Roth about the international reaction to what has been called a ‘state-sponsored hijacking’. The British government has told all UK planes to cease flying over Belarus, while the EU has imposed new economic sanctions. Kremlin officials have offered only muted support over the incident.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hanna Liubakova and Andrew Roth, produced by Marilyn Rust and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve Machine Learning Model Performance by Combining Categorical Features]]></title>
        <id>60af931811ffb70827ef85d3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-machine-learning-model-performance-by-combining-categorical-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're training a machine learning model, you can have some features in your dataset that represent categorical values. Categorical features are types of data that you can divide into groups. There are three common categorical data types: Ordinal – a set of values in ascending or descending order. Example: rating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make a Bouncing Basketball in Unity with Materials and Textures 🏀]]></title>
        <id>60a325c6906c5207e3a7da25</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-a-basketball-in-unity-with-materials-and-textures/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll teach you how to make a basketball using materials and textures in Unity. You can extend this micro-concept to create any kind of ball like a football, tennis ball, or snooker balls.  That said, these techniques aren't just limited to creating round 3D objects like balls.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your stories of holiday disasters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:32:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about your holiday catastrophes and trips that didn’t go to plan
With travel still subject to strict Covid rules, many of us will be opting to stay put this summer. But while we often idolise the idea of a sun-filled getaway, in reality, our holidays can sometimes fail to meet expectations – and sometimes they can be downright disastrous.
With this in mind, we’d love to hear about your holiday catastrophes and the trips that didn’t go according to plan, as a reminder that we might not always be missing out after all. Perhaps your luxurious city break was ruined by terrible weather? Or maybe your backpacking adventure plans were quashed by a bout of food poisoning? Whether your family vacation ended in tears, or your romantic weekend away was blighted by lost luggage and booking mishaps, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The government failed’: Dominic Cummings takes aim at No 10’s Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former aide lashed out at every aspect of the government’s approach and Boris Johnson and Matt Hancock in particular
Dominic Cummings spent an hours-long session in parliament on Wednesday giving evidence to a joint committee on the government’s response to the Covid pandemic. He took aim at Boris Johnson for overseeing a chaotic response and at the health secretary, Matt Hancock, for what he alleged was lying over preparedness and PPE stocks.
Guardian columnist Gaby Hinsliff tells Anushka Asthana that it was the first chance to get a detailed firsthand account of what was going on in the heart of government as the crisis unfolded. But how much should Cummings himself be seen as culpable for the failures?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Gaby Hinsliff; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giphy API Tutorial – How to Generate Animated Text GIFs with ReactJS]]></title>
        <id>60a44b9f906c5207e3a7e098</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/giphy-api-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial you will create an app that generates dynamic animated text using Giphy's API with ReactJS. After that I'll go over some of the other API features Giphy provides that you can use to make other interesting projects. You can find the code for the tutorial here. Video]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Contribute to Open Source  Projects – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60abe7fb11ffb70827ef63a6</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-contribute-to-open-source-projects-beginners-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a developer, you've probably come across the term "open source." If you've ever wondered what it's all about and how to contribute, you are in exactly the right place.  I put aside all my fears about how and what to contribute during Hacktoberfest 2020, and made]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Basic Terraform Syntax in 20 minutes]]></title>
        <id>606f4f5fd5756f080ba96b65</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/terraform-syntax-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll give you a brief overview of the configuration syntax of Terraform.  Terraform's docs provide the most comprehensive look at its syntax. But this article should serve as a condensed quick start introduction that'll give new users a simplified overview. We'll focus on the basic structures without]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a GraphQL API Using Laravel]]></title>
        <id>60abc59d11ffb70827ef6304</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-graphql-api-using-laravel/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll walk you through how to set up your own GraphQL API using PHP and Laravel. Two years ago, I started working professionally as a backend developer. And I was very intimidated by all the technology I didn't yet know. Words like Docker, Kubernetes, and GraphQL seemed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Super Mario Bros, Zelda, and Space Invaders with Kaboom.js]]></title>
        <id>60aced0011ffb70827ef6d96</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-mario-zelda-and-space-invaders-with-kaboom-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video course I show you how to build three popular games using the latest game development library for JavaScript called Kaboom.js. This course is exciting for two reasons: First of all, I am going to be introducing a new technology designed especially for game development in JavaScript.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what are your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T09:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This bank holiday weekend will be the first opportunity for many to visit loved ones who live further away. We’d like to hear about your plans
What were your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend – the first opportunity many of us have had to visit grandparents and loved ones who live further away?
What impact have these new No-Go zones had on your arrangements: are you going to adapt or abandon your visits – or are you going ahead, as planned?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Britain becoming a hostile environment for EU citizens? | Podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T02:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid travel restrictions begin to be lifted, a new, far less welcoming post-Brexit attitude is greeting EU citizens at the UK border 
EU citizens living and working in the UK are being met with suspicion and in some cases refused entry at the UK border for the first time in their lives, after the implementation of new post-Brexit rules and the lifting of Covid travel restrictions. 
Chloe, a pastry chef from Denmark, tells Anushka Asthana that, because she could not produce a return ticket, she was denied entry at Calais to the UK recently and forced to make the long drive back to Denmark. It is becoming a familiar story, with other EU citizens reporting hostility from officials and some being held at immigration detention centres. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rafael Behr; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[proxy-www]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341153</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/justjavac/proxy-www"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T19:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like a good trick. What if… a URL was…  a promise… that fetched said URL?
www.codepen.io.then((response) ={
  console.log(response);
});
That’s what @justjavac did with JavaScript Proxys. A clever trick, that. Don’t @ me about the practicality. Trick…
The post proxy-www appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340626</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wrangling-control-over-pdfs-with-the-adobe-pdf-embed-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T13:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By our last estimate, there are now more PDFs in the world than atoms in the universe (not verified by outside sources) so chances are, from time to time, you’re going to run into a PDF document or two. Browsers …
The post Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raymond Camden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about male incontinence: six common questions answered]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/lets-talk-about-male-incontinence-six-common-questions-answered</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/lets-talk-about-male-incontinence-six-common-questions-answered"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:26:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wetting yourself isn’t something that happens just to older people or women who’ve given birth. A quarter of men over 40 experience some form of leakage, yet many are loath to speak out
Incontinence comes loaded with misconceptions, not least that it’s a women’s or older person’s problem. This could be why so many younger men stay silent when urinary incontinence strikes. Here, we look at what causes a condition that is far more widespread than many think – and how it’s eminently treatable.
How common is male incontinence?
A quarter of men over the age of 40 experience some form of urine leakage according to research by the global health and hygiene company Essity. And, in the US, the National Association for Continence says that incontinence affects as many as 15% of men aged 15-64, which belies the myth that it’s only postpartum or menopausal women who suffer from it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Koch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I’d tell my 25-year-old self about sex – and how it has improved for me with age]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/what-id-tell-my-25-year-old-self-about-sex-and-how-it-has-improved-for-me-with-age</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/what-id-tell-my-25-year-old-self-about-sex-and-how-it-has-improved-for-me-with-age"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On his 55th birthday, New York-based writer and sex therapist Ian Kerner reflects on his sex life and explains why men don’t need to let ageing get in the way of their desire
I know for a fact that tonight I’m going to get lucky: I’m definitely going to have sex. According to a study published in the Archives of Sexual Behavior, the average American has sex 54 times a year, which roughly translates to once a week with a couple of extra times thrown in for special occasions. And today is my birthday. I’m turning 55. And like all my birthdays for the past 20 years I’ve been married, my bonus present is sex. But, special occasion or not, given that I’m pushing up in years this is a good moment to take stock of how my sex life has changed over time – and what I’ve learned as a sex therapist about how other men age through the life-cycle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Kerner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘As a woman, I don’t feel I can own up to loving sex’: the taboos that still need breaking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/as-a-woman-i-dont-feel-i-can-own-up-to-loving-sex-the-taboos-that-still-need-breaking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/as-a-woman-i-dont-feel-i-can-own-up-to-loving-sex-the-taboos-that-still-need-breaking"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:22:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We may be in 2021, but even so there are aspects of life that feel off limits – when really they shouldn’t. That’s why some readers took this opportunity to get things off their chest
From not wanting kids to grown men crying, and women dating younger men to wetting yourself, we asked you to own up to the things that you don’t tend to talk about. And you spilled the beans because, let’s face it, we’re all friends here …
“I’ve recently started talking to my personal trainer about my period. He’s a good looking 25-year-old and I felt myself burning up with embarrassment when he asked why I was lacking in energy one week. I went to lie but then thought, why do women still feel shame about this? He looked a bit uncomfortable but since then I have tried to make a point of talking about my cycle as ultimately it affects my body and my performance, which is completely relevant to his job as my trainer. It still feels ‘wrong’ and almost distasteful to talk about, but I know it shouldn’t.” Sammy, 43
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Compiled by Samantha Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘To lose weight, I hatched a really bad plan’: how men hide their body-image issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/to-lose-weight-i-hatched-a-really-bad-plan-how-men-hide-their-body-image-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/to-lose-weight-i-hatched-a-really-bad-plan-how-men-hide-their-body-image-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:19:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over half of all men suffer from body insecurities, so why is it so hard for us to talk about them the way women do, asks Andrzej Łukowski
When I started secondary school I was a bit on the tubby side.
Other than a general aversion to competitive sports (though I did swim, I had badges an’ all!), I’m not really sure there was any particular reason for this.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrzej Łukowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>