<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-22T00:38:17.761Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-22T00:38:17.761Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden awards first Medal of Honor as president to ‘true American hero’ – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/21/us-politics-joe-biden-democrats-republicans-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/21/us-politics-joe-biden-democrats-republicans-live"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T00:15:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retired colonel Ralph Puckett rewarded for bravery in Korean war
South Korean president Moon Jae-in attendance for ceremony
Biden lowers infrastructure offer to Republicans by $500bn

 1.14am BST 
That’s all from me here on the west coast. This is a bit of what’s been going on in US news and politics today:
 12.46am BST 
Louisianna police say they plan to release all video associated with the death of Ronald Greene tonight. Green died after being pulled over and then stunned, kicked and dragged on the groun…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abené Clayton (now) and Joan E Greve (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Mickelson rolls back years to share US PGA lead with Louis Oosthuizen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/phil-mickelson-rolls-back-years-to-lead-us-pga-after-his-second-round</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/phil-mickelson-rolls-back-years-to-lead-us-pga-after-his-second-round"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T00:04:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifty-year-old hits 69 at Kiawah Island in second round
Oosthuizen also five-under with Koepka one shot back

The first time Phil Mickelson competed in the US PGA Championship, John Major was not yet halfway through his term as Prime Minister and Freddie Mercury’s ‘Living on my Own’ sat atop the UK charts. Paul Azinger, the US PGA champion, collected a cheque for $300,000.
The intervening years – all 28 of them – have witnessed a decorated Mickelson career but nothing that would surpass victory at Kiawah Is…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray at Kiawah Island</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Horses: Wembley can win the cup for O’Brien in Irish 2,000 Guineas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/may/22/talking-horses-racing-tips-irish-2000-guineas-wembley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/may/22/talking-horses-racing-tips-irish-2000-guineas-wembley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aidan O’Brien’s runner has proven form in heavy conditions with the Curragh set to be very testing after heavy rain
The track at the Curragh was unraceable yesterday after torrential rain and if the course passes the planned inspection on Saturday morning the going will be as tough as it gets in Ireland for the 2,000 Guineas.
This will be a completely different test to the one on fast ground when Poetic Flare and Lucky Vega were first and third in the English Guineas at Newmarket this month and the winner h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tony Paley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real Water, a premium bottled water, recalled amid death and liver illnesses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/real-water-alkalized-liver-illness-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/real-water-alkalized-liver-illness-death"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T22:22:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A consent decree order stopped the production and distribution of the product whose packaging touted its healthy detoxifying properties
Federal authorities have ordered a complete recall of the Las Vegas-based bottled water brand Real Water and ordered the company to surrender records in investigations of at least one death and multiple cases of liver illness among people who reported drinking it.
The product is sold as premium alkalized drinking water in distinctive boxy blue bottles touting “E2 Electron E…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jürgen Klopp braced for Anfield ‘final’ at end of tough road for Liverpool | Andy Hunter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/jurgen-klopp-braced-for-anfield-final-at-end-of-tough-road-for-liverpool</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/jurgen-klopp-braced-for-anfield-final-at-end-of-tough-road-for-liverpool"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:30:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The manager believes Champions League qualification would be vindication after injuries hampered his side’s title defence
Jürgen Klopp straight-batted every question relating to what Champions League qualification would represent for Liverpool on the basis it has not been achieved, although by mentioning Basel, Kiev and Madrid alongside preparations for Crystal Palace he gave a clear indication of what it would mean for him. Sunday is another European final in Klopp’s eyes, with vindication the immediate pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Tuchel throws Chelsea’s hat into the ring in Harry Kane fight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/harry-kane-kevin-de-bruyne-would-be-a-dream-to-play-with-tottenham-manchester-city</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/harry-kane-kevin-de-bruyne-would-be-a-dream-to-play-with-tottenham-manchester-city"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea manager: ‘Any coach would like Kane in his team’
Kane praises Man City’s Kevin De Bruyne as ‘striker’s dream’

Thomas Tuchel has signalled Chelsea’s interest in Harry Kane, admitting any manager in the world would jump at the chance to work with the Tottenham striker.
Kane has been open about his desire to leave Tottenham and his representatives have been contacted by Chelsea, Manchester City and Manchester United. The race is likely to be intense and Tuchel, who wants his side to become more ruthle…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg and David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No criminality in video of Rangers players after title win, police say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/no-criminality-in-video-of-rangers-players-after-title-win-police-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/no-criminality-in-video-of-rangers-players-after-title-win-police-say"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:19:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow club starts legal action against ‘individuals’ over alleged sectarian language despite decision
Rangers has said it is taking legal action against “certain individuals” after police found no criminality in a video that appeared to show players using sectarian language during their title celebrations.
The clip circulated online on Saturday after the Glasgow club was awarded the Scottish Premiership trophy for the first time since 2011.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Danny Masterson: That ‘70s Show actor must stand trial on three counts of rape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/danny-masterson-that-70s-show-rape-trial</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/danny-masterson-that-70s-show-rape-trial"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:11:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Judge’s decision followed days of emotional testimony from three women who say the actor raped them in 2001 and 2003
Danny Masterson, the actor best known for his role in That ’70s Show, must stand trial on three counts of rape, a judge said on Friday.
The determination by Charlaine F Olmedo, of the Los Angeles superior county court, came on the fourth day of a preliminary hearing where the prosecution laid out its evidence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester edged out by Montpellier in thrilling Challenge Cup final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/leicester-edged-out-by-montpellier-in-thrilling-final</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/leicester-edged-out-by-montpellier-in-thrilling-final"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:08:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester 17-18 Montpellier
French side win European Challenge Cup at Twickenham

Leicester’s wait for another major title goes on after Johan Goosen’s second-half try for Montpellier inflicted the narrowest of defeats but the Tigers displayed enough defiance in defeat to suggest it may not be too much longer. Leicester gave their more heralded opponents an almighty run for their money with a performance built on forward power that their illustrious predecessors would have been proud of.
They scored classic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher at Twickenham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sha’Carri Richardson may be the most exciting sprint star since Usain Bolt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/athletics-shacarri-richardson-sprinting-star-usain-bolt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/athletics-shacarri-richardson-sprinting-star-usain-bolt"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising US star brings baggage and a back story as she takes on Dina Asher-Smith over 100m this Sunday
Sha’Carri Richardson is the most exciting, compelling, and intriguing sprinter since Usain Bolt. The world just doesn’t know it yet. It’s not only that the 21-year-old has sonic boom speed – last month in Florida she ran 100m in 10.72 sec, the sixth quickest time in history – and mesmerising acceleration. It’s everything else, too. The look. The backstory. The attitude. And, yes, the baggage – although more…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheslin Kolbe: ‘Everyone knows about French flair. That’s what I love’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/cheslin-kolbe-french-flair-toulouse-champions-cup-rugby-union</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/21/cheslin-kolbe-french-flair-toulouse-champions-cup-rugby-union"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T21:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[South Africa’s World Cup winner hails the freedom he has been given at Toulouse as playing a massive part in his success before Champions Cup final
Not since Asterix the Gaul went to Britain to help his first cousin Anticlimax fight the Romans has such a diminutive figure crossed the Channel so well equipped to embarrass the big boys. No subtitles are required when Cheslin Kolbe is in full flight, to the point where even the little legend himself is not entirely sure where his magical footwork is going to t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Chinese provinces hit by earthquakes, with two reported dead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/two-chinese-provinces-hit-by-earthquakes-with-two-reported-dead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/two-chinese-provinces-hit-by-earthquakes-with-two-reported-dead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:57:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 20,000 people evacuated after Qinghai in north-west and Yunnan in south-west struck on same day
A series of strong earthquakes has rattled north-west and south-west China, leaving at least two people dead.
Both Qinghai province in the north-west on the Tibetan plateau and Yunnan province in south-western China are prone to earthquakes. And both tremors were shallow, which generally means they cause more damage.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AFP in Beijing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two bears shot at Whipsnade Zoo after escaping from enclosure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/two-bears-shot-at-whipsnade-zoo-after-escaping-from-enclosure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/two-bears-shot-at-whipsnade-zoo-after-escaping-from-enclosure"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:47:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chief curator says his team had no other option as there was an immediate threat to human life
Two female brown bears have been shot and killed at Whipsnade Zoo in Bedfordshire after they escaped from their enclosure when strong winds toppled a tree.
The zoo’s chief curator, Malcolm Fitzpatrick, said in a statement that the tree fell in such a way that it formed a “bridge” between the brown bears’ pen and the fence of the neighbouring wild boar enclosure.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifa to look at the possibility of staging World Cups every two years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/fifa-to-look-at-the-possibility-of-staging-bi-annual-world-cups</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/fifa-to-look-at-the-possibility-of-staging-bi-annual-world-cups"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Men’s and women’s tournaments could become biennial
Gianni Infantino says study will be made with open mind

Fifa is to explore the possibility of staging the men’s and women’s World Cups every two years after it was raised at the governing body’s annual congress on Friday.
Although a study does not guarantee the changes will be implemented, it will be seen by many as the latest action in a global struggle for control over the football calendar and likely to have a severe impact on regional tournaments such…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Albert Einstein letter with E=mc2 equation in his own hand sells for $1.2m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/albert-einstein-letter-e-mc2-equation-in-his-own-hand-sells-for-12m</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/albert-einstein-letter-e-mc2-equation-in-his-own-hand-sells-for-12m"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:04:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Only two similar examples of world-changing equation known
1946 letter to physicist Ludwik Silberstein auctioned

A handwritten letter by Albert Einstein that contains his famous E=mc2 equation has sold at auction for more than $1.2m, about three times more than it was expected to get, a Boston-based auction house said on Friday.
 Related: Albert Einstein's 'God letter' reflecting on religion auctioned for $3m 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After the deluge: Australia’s outback springs to life as mighty rivers flow again]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/22/after-the-deluge-australias-outback-springs-to-life-as-mighty-rivers-flow-again</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/22/after-the-deluge-australias-outback-springs-to-life-as-mighty-rivers-flow-again"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two months after rains fell in the north, billions of litres of water are finally coursing down the Baaka-Darling system, rejuvenating the Menindee Lakes and farming communities 
In late March parts of Queensland were deluged by rain. Cars were swept from roads and flash floods inundated towns as rivers broke their banks.
Billions of litres of water flowed across flood plains into creeks and from creeks into the rivers that stretch like fingers across the region.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anne Davies  Photographs by Mike Bowers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cricket Australia should have opened sandpaper wound and flushed it out | Geoff Lemon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/cricket-australia-should-have-opened-sandpaper-wound-and-flushed-it-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/cricket-australia-should-have-opened-sandpaper-wound-and-flushed-it-out"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T20:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bancroft’s small comment only became so big because there is still little clarity on Cape Town and the suspicion preceding it
It was telling that it took so little. A few vague words, a verbal half-shuffle that wasn’t evasive enough, and the whole story lit up like bonfire night. As part of a wider-ranging interview with the Guardian, Australian batter Cameron Bancroft called it “self-explanatory” that tampering with a cricket ball benefits bowlers, in the context of him being caught with sandpaper during a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Lemon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump bills Secret Service $40,000 at Mar-a-Lago since leaving office]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/trump-secret-service-mar-a-lago-florida-room</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/trump-secret-service-mar-a-lago-florida-room"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T19:40:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Records obtained by Washington Post show agency paid $396.15 every night since 20 January until at least 30 April

‘Racist, sexist pig’: book details Obama’s thoughts on Trump

Donald Trump has billed the Secret Service more than $40,000 for a room for his own security detail, which has been guarding him at his Mar-a-Lago resort since he left office in January.
 Related: Trump family members got ‘inappropriately close’ to Secret Service agents, book claims 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Oladipo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlético and Real Madrid gear up for one final chapter in wild La Liga story]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/atletico-and-real-madrid-gear-up-for-one-final-chapter-in-wild-la-liga-story</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/21/atletico-and-real-madrid-gear-up-for-one-final-chapter-in-wild-la-liga-story"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T19:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This season has taken countless twists and turns, and now the Madrid rivals are both potentially 90 minutes from glory
All that and it comes to this. After 37 exhausting weeks, a title race full with so many turning points no one knows which way it’s facing any more, and every moment spent on edge, it all rests on a single evening and two locations, 195km apart; 3,330 minutes down, 90 to go. Time enough for anything to happen still, one more wild chapter in a story full of them.
At 6pm local time on Saturda…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on William and Harry’s comments on the Dyson report – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/21/martin-rowson-on-william-and-harrys-comments-on-the-dyson-report-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/21/martin-rowson-on-william-and-harrys-comments-on-the-dyson-report-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T19:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buy a copy of this cartoon at our print shop
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research findings that are probably wrong cited far more than robust ones, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/research-findings-that-are-probably-wrong-cited-far-more-than-robust-ones-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/research-findings-that-are-probably-wrong-cited-far-more-than-robust-ones-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T18:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Academics suspect papers with grabby conclusions are waved through more easily by reviewers
Scientific research findings that are probably wrong gain far more attention than robust results, according to academics who suspect that the bar for publication may be lower for papers with grabbier conclusions.
Studies in top science, psychology and economics journals that fail to hold up when others repeat them are cited, on average, more than 100 times as often in follow-up papers than work that stands the test o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fears of ‘feeding frenzy’ against BBC after Diana interview backlash]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/ex-bbc-trust-chair-fears-feeding-frenzy-over-diana-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/ex-bbc-trust-chair-fears-feeding-frenzy-over-diana-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:50:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-chair of BBC Trust warns criticism could lead to ‘destroying something it would be impossible to recreate’
A former chair of the BBC Trust has warned against the “feeding frenzy” engulfing the corporation as ministers said they would look at how it is governed in the wake of damning findings about its 1995 interview with Diana, Princess of Wales.
As the broadcaster faced further searching questions over its handling of the crisis, Sir Michael Lyons, who chaired its then governing body from 2007 until 201…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker, Mark Sweney and Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infected blood scandal: Hancock pledges payouts if advised by inquiry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/infected-blood-scandal-hancock-pledges-payouts-advised-inquiry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/infected-blood-scandal-hancock-pledges-payouts-advised-inquiry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:48:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary agrees government has ‘moral responsibility’ to address what happened in 1970s and 80s
Matt Hancock has said compensation will be paid to people people infected by contaminated blood products and their relatives if is recommended by the public inquiry into the scandal.
Appearing at the inquiry on Friday, the health secretary agreed the government had a “moral responsibility” to address what had happened.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grenfell costs surpass £500m as council bill revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/grenfell-costs-surpass-500m-as-council-bill-revealed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/grenfell-costs-surpass-500m-as-council-bill-revealed"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:35:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kensington and Chelsea has spent £406m on its response to blaze, which followed £300,000 cost-cutting move
The public costs of the Grenfell Tower fire have exceeded £500m after the Royal Borough of Kensington and Chelsea revealed it had spent £406m on its response and recovery efforts in almost four years since the disaster.
The sum is in addition to the costs to the taxpayer of the ongoing public inquiry, which hit £117m by the end of March this year, most of which was taken up with lawyers’ bills.
 Contin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signs of rise in Covid infections in England amid variant warnings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/signs-of-rise-in-covid-infections-in-england-amid-variant-warnings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/signs-of-rise-in-covid-infections-in-england-amid-variant-warnings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:33:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson still plans to end restrictions in June despite experts’ fears over spread of India and Kent variants

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Covid infection levels are showing early signs of an increase in England, data has revealed, as experts continue to warn the variant of concern first detected in India could grow exponentially in the UK.
On Friday Boris Johnson told broadcasters in Portsmouth he has seen nothing to suggest it will be necessary to “deviate from the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis and Ian Sample</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/21/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/21/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:32:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The conflict in Gaza and Israel, migrants on the border between Morocco and Spain’s north African enclave of Ceuta, a volcano in Iceland, and Covid vaccinations in the Amazon: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the richest getting richer: fix a broken economic system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-richest-getting-richer-fix-a-broken-economic-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-richest-getting-richer-fix-a-broken-economic-system"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:16:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government activism is needed to deal with the baleful and growing levels of inequality in society
The Sunday Times rich list provides a useful social X-ray of Britain. It is a journalistic tool that looks inside high society without damaging its subjects. However, the findings of the latest survey – that the richest have got even richer – have been released when many people have endured a Covid year of hardship, loss and boredom. A preview released on Friday reveals that there are now 24 more billionaires …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on cryptoart: caution is necessary | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-cryptoart-caution-necessary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-cryptoart-caution-necessary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:15:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-fungible tokens are all the rage in the art market, but the environmental impact is huge
NFTs – non-fungible tokens – are being grandly hyped in the art market. There were headlines globally when a digital artwork by Beeple (real name Mike Winkelmann) was sold by Christie’s in March for $69.3m, along with an NFT – effectively a token proving ownership, which is stored on a blockchain. Blockchains, unalterable and unhackable “digital ledgers” that are also used to store the ownership records of cryptocur…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charles Koch funded eviction push while investing in real estate companies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/charles-koch-foundation-eviction-real-estate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/charles-koch-foundation-eviction-real-estate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:59:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between 2017 and 2019, Koch’s foundation contributed almost $7.7m to three conservative US groups leading court battle
Billionaire Charles Koch’s foundation has bankrolled three conservative legal groups leading the court battle to eliminate prohibitions against tenant evictions during the Covid-19 pandemic in America.
At the same time, Koch’s corporate empire has suddenly stepped up its real estate purchases during the pandemic – including making large investments in real estate companies with a potential …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Perez and David Sirota of the Daily Poster</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iran stunned by case of couple who drugged and dismembered son]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/babak-khorramdin-iranian-couple-arrested-for-of-film-maker-son-47</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/babak-khorramdin-iranian-couple-arrested-for-of-film-maker-son-47"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:58:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parents admit murdering film-maker Babak Khorramdin and to killing daughter and son-in-law years before
An Iranian couple have been arrested for drugging, murdering and dismembering their film-maker son, Babak Khorramdin, 47, and also confessed to killing their daughter and son-in-law in the same way years earlier.
The case has stunned Iran, where it has been splashed across the front pages of newspapers with headlines including “Society in shock” and “Occupants of terror house”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Graham-Harrison and Akhtar Mohammad Makoii</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Associated Newspapers pays damages for revealing Sand Van Roy as Luc Besson accuser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/associated-newspapers-pays-damages-for-revealing-sand-van-roy-as-luc-besson-accuser</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/associated-newspapers-pays-damages-for-revealing-sand-van-roy-as-luc-besson-accuser"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MailOnline published actor’s identity as complainant in rape case against French director
Associated Newspapers has paid substantial damages and apologised to actor Sand Van Roy for revealing her identity as a complainant in a rape case against the French film director Luc Besson.
In May 2018, Van Roy filed a complaint with French police alleging that she had been raped by Besson. She expected to remain anonymous, as is her right under French law, but details of her complaint were leaked and reported in the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venice Architecture Biennale 2021 review – a pick’n’mix of conceptual posturing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/venice-architecture-biennale-2021-review-how-will-we-live-together</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/venice-architecture-biennale-2021-review-how-will-we-live-together"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:50:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Refugee camps, ad-hoc mosques and Wetherspoon’s carpets are among the muddle of answers to the well-intentioned curatorial question: ‘How will we live together?’
A robotic arm twitches above a lumpy landscape of compacted earth, pock-marked with little hollows from which pink tufts of fungus emerge. This is an “ecosystem of empathy and coexistence”, a caption tells us, the fungal flora and mechanical limb living together in perfect harmony. Nearby, bubbling tanks of lurid green algae are apparently busy cul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Wainwright</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Palestinians return to devastated homes as UN calls for Gaza dialogue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-return-to-damaged-homes-as-un-calls-for-gaza-dialogue</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-return-to-damaged-homes-as-un-calls-for-gaza-dialogue"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World leaders welcome ceasefire but Hamas and Israel’s Benjamin Netanyahu remain belligerent 
Tens of thousands of displaced Palestinians in Gaza have begun returning to their homes to inspect the devastation from 11 days of Israeli airstrikes in its war with Hamas.
Gaza City, on the Mediterranean coast, had been warped by the intense attacks, with gaping holes in the skyline from where high-rise buildings had collapsed, their remains sprawling into the street. Cars mounted pavements to avoid craters.
 Cont…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Gaza City and Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canadian soldier allegedly fed cannabis cakes to gunners in live fire exercise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/canadian-soldier-cannabis-cakes-live-fire-exercise</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/canadian-soldier-cannabis-cakes-live-fire-exercise"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bombardier Chelsea Cogswell faces 18 charges at a court martial for serving edibles to unsuspecting members of artillery battery
A Canadian soldier is facing court martial after alleging serving cannabis-laced cupcakes to unwitting members of her artillery unit during a live fire exercise.
Bombardier Chelsea Cogswell faces 18 charges for her baking, including administering a noxious substance and behaving in a disgraceful manner.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maggie Perkins obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/21/maggie-perkins-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/21/maggie-perkins-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:21:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My mother, Maggie Perkins, who has died aged 92, worked as a continuity and script editor on hundreds of episodes of classic British TV series in the 1960s and 1970s, including The Avengers, The Saint, Randall & Hopkirk (Deceased) and The Professionals.
She was born in Barnet, Hertfordshire, one of three children of Samuel and Gwendoline Spirito, first generation immigrants from southern Italy. In 1945 their family home was completely destroyed by a doodlebug raid, fortunately while all of its usual occupan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Perkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lawyers ‘appalled’ at woman’s 10-year sentence after murder conviction quashed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/21/lawyers-appalled-at-womans-10-year-sentence-after-conviction-quashed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/21/lawyers-appalled-at-womans-10-year-sentence-after-conviction-quashed"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Farieissia Martin, convicted of murder of Kyle Farrell in 2014, to remain in prison for manslaughter
Lawyers for a woman sentenced to 10 years in prison for manslaughter have said they are “appalled and gobsmacked” that she will remain in prison six months after her murder conviction was quashed.
Farieissia Martin was convicted of murder after stabbing Kyle Farrell, 21, in November 2014. She was jailed for life with a minimum term of 13 years, but the ruling was quashed last year after judges ruled that new…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Topping and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can anyone solve the puzzle of Paul Dano’s Riddler in The Batman?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/21/paul-dano-the-riddler-the-batman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/21/paul-dano-the-riddler-the-batman"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:12:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked artwork has sparked a flurry of speculation over how exactly the supervillain will be portrayed in Matt Reeves’ forthcoming movie
The Riddler has always been a Batman supervillain with a penchant for thorny posers. And yet usually the question marks are set by the caped crusader’s mischievous nemesis himself, as spiky traps for Gotham’s dark knight to fall into. In the case of Matt Reeves’ forthcoming The Batman, it looks as if they might zero in more precisely on the identity of Edward Nygma himself…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Child</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arts figures leap to BBC’s defence over classical music TV output]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/21/arts-figures-leap-to-bbcs-defence-over-classical-music-tv-output</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/21/arts-figures-leap-to-bbcs-defence-over-classical-music-tv-output"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T16:05:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lenny Henry, Lucy Worsley and others sign letter backing outgoing head of music commissioning
• Letter: Jan Younghusband will leave a great legacy for the BBC to build on
Leading figures in the arts have defended the BBC’s classical music programming following accusations that the broadcaster’s attitude towards the genre shows “negativity verging on hostility”.
A letter to the Guardian signed by 18 prominent figures said the accusations took a “wholly inaccurate and unbalanced” view of the record of the BBC…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why ID card plans are likely to pass this time | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/why-id-card-plans-are-likely-to-pass-this-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/why-id-card-plans-are-likely-to-pass-this-time"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:56:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jem Whitely, Mike Cushman, Martin Willey and Eleanor Martindale respond to Simon Jenkins’ article about the government’s plans for voter identity checks
Simon Jenkins is right (Johnson’s voter ID checks are not about electoral fraud, they’re about power, 18 May), but also wrong. This is not mainly about “regulation and surveillance of daily life”, it’s about voter suppression, and for the Tories it’s so much the better if, like so many of their policies, it disproportionately impacts ethnic minorities. Beca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whining and dining: keep kids out of pubs | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/whining-and-dining-keep-kids-out-of-pubs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/whining-and-dining-keep-kids-out-of-pubs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:54:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers defend a London pub’s decision to ban entry on children under 10
Following Grace Dent’s review (14 May) of the Alma in Crystal Palace, London, you published a letter (When pubs leave parents out in the cold, theguardian.com, 17 May) contesting the pub’s seemingly “bizarre” ban on children under the age of 10. I feel compelled to provide a counter point of view.
As a woman who has chosen not to have children, a choice many others know is something we are judged for almost on a daily basis – “you’ll c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From bats to hornbills: Whitley award winners – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/21/from-bats-to-hornbills-whitley-award-winners-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/21/from-bats-to-hornbills-whitley-award-winners-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:50:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Whitley Fund for Nature has announced this year’s winners of its annual awards, which support conservation work across the global south. More details at www.whitleyaward.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeremy Paxman diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/jeremy-paxman-diagnosed-with-parkinsons-disease</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/jeremy-paxman-diagnosed-with-parkinsons-disease"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:40:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University Challenge host reveals he has been receiving treatment for mild symptoms
Jeremy Paxman has revealed that he has been diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease.
The 71-year-old broadcaster and host of BBC Two’s University Challenge said he had been receiving “excellent treatment” and that his symptoms were “currently mild”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The JavaScript Array Handbook – JS Array Methods Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>6098ce302cd0545b5e944d0b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-javascript-array-handbook/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In programming, an array is a collection of elements or items. Arrays store data as elements and retrieve them back when you need them.  The array data structure is widely used in all programming languages that support it. In this handbook, I'll teach you all about arrays in JavaScript. You'll]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew Barney: Redoubt review – mountains carved in the hunter’s sights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/matthew-barney-redoubt-review-intruiging-brew-of-sharpshooters-bears-and-strange-goings-on-in-the-forest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/matthew-barney-redoubt-review-intruiging-brew-of-sharpshooters-bears-and-strange-goings-on-in-the-forest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:17:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hayward Gallery, London 
Wild animals and menacing women with guns stalk Barney’s grizzled ranger in the artists’ feature-length work that retells Ovid’s mythological tale of Diana and Actaeon

Matthew Barney’s Redoubt at the Hayward is a bewildering and intriguing litany of objects and fleeting, capricious images. At its heart is a feature-length film whose themes and images are continued and compounded by several monumentally scaled sculptures and a long series of engraved, etched and otherwise chemically…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Searle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richest nations agree to end support for coal production overseas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 countries reaffirm commitment to limit global heating to 1.5C after nearly two days of wrangling
The world’s richest nations have agreed to end their financial support for coal development overseas, in a major step towards phasing out the dirtiest fossil fuel.
After nearly two days of wrangling at a meeting of the G7 environment and energy ministers, hosted virtually by the UK on Thursday and Friday, all reaffirmed their commitment to limiting global heating to 1.5C, and committed to phasing out coal and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow politicians call on Home Office to halt immigration raids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/glasgow-politicians-call-on-home-office-to-halt-immigration-raids</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/glasgow-politicians-call-on-home-office-to-halt-immigration-raids"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:14:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners demand greater transparency over police operations week after protest foils detention of two men in city
Leading Glasgow politicians have written to the Home Office telling officials to stop unannounced immigration raids, as the Scottish Refugee Council urged Police Scotland to “push back” against further operations.
Their demands came a week after a peaceful protest prevented the detention of two men in the south of the city.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel should take note: the weight of opinion is turning against it | Jonathan Freedland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/israel-opinion-western-attitudes-middle-east</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/israel-opinion-western-attitudes-middle-east"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:10:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks in part to a global focus more intense than on any other conflict, western attitudes to the Middle East may be shifting
It’s not over, because it’s never over. But there is at least the hope of a pause. After less than a fortnight in which nearly 250 people have been killed, both Hamas and Israel agreed late on Thursday to hold their fire, each crafting a victory story to tell the world and themselves.
 Related: The pro-Palestine movement is broad but it can’t be a home to antisemitism | Keith Kahn-H…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Freedland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number of billionaires in UK reached new record during Covid crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/21/number-of-billionaires-in-uk-reached-new-record-during-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/21/number-of-billionaires-in-uk-reached-new-record-during-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:09:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite year of economic turmoil, 24 people became billionaires in UK during pandemic, taking total to 171
Britain created a record number of billionaires during the coronavirus pandemic as wealth surged despite a year of economic turmoil, prompting calls for the government to increase taxes on the ultra-rich.
There are 171 billionaires in the UK, 24 more than a year ago, according to an annual ranking compiled by the Sunday Times. It was the highest number in the 33 years of the newspaper’s rich list, as t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocktail of the week: The Alchemist's Chase the rainbow – recipe | The good mixer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/21/cocktail-of-the-week-the-alchemists-chase-the-rainbow-recipe-gin-pink-grapefruit-prosecco</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/21/cocktail-of-the-week-the-alchemists-chase-the-rainbow-recipe-gin-pink-grapefruit-prosecco"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get the weekend off to a flying start with this pink grapefruit and gin spritz with hints of orange
Serve this super-refreshing cocktail of citrus flavours – think tart pink grapefruit and sweet oranges – in a wine glass filled with lots of ice to keep it chilled right down to the last sip. There’s a bit of sparkle in there, too, from the prosecco and soda water. It makes a lovely, long summer drink.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Holly Tudor, Felix Crosse and Jenny McPhee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings evidence could settle Boris Johnson’s fate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/dominic-cummings-evidence-could-settle-boris-johnsons-fate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/dominic-cummings-evidence-could-settle-boris-johnsons-fate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:55:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Westminster eagerly awaits as former aide prepares to spill beans on key Covid decisions

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

It promises to be the parliamentary event of the year so far – and may yet determine the fate of the prime minister.
On Wednesday next week, Dominic Cummings will give evidence to MPs about Boris Johnson’s role in making key decisions that critics say may have cost many thousands of lives.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yorkshire church to install stone carvings celebrating women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/21/yorkshire-church-to-install-stone-carvings-celebrating-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/21/yorkshire-church-to-install-stone-carvings-celebrating-women"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:46:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medieval St Mary’s in Beverley to install nine historical figures including Mary Wollstonecraft and Mary Seacole
They have graced the exterior of one of the most beautiful medieval churches in England for 500 years. But carvings at St Mary’s in Beverley, in the East Riding of Yorkshire, have become unrecognisable fragments, eroded by centuries of weather.
Now the crumbling stonework is to be replaced by nine carvings celebrating the achievements of women. Eight are historical figures from the fields of math…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s so much tween ‘empowerment’ on TV. I’d rather my kids watched Sharknado | Emma Brockes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/tween-empowerment-tv-kids-sharknado-drama-children-gaslight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/tween-empowerment-tv-kids-sharknado-drama-children-gaslight"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:45:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An early experience with Psycho II taught me that ‘inappropriate’ viewing is not always what it seems
My parents were having a dinner party and I was allowed to stay up, left unattended in front of the TV. This was long before TV-on-demand, when children’s programming aired only on Saturday mornings and for a few hours after school and, as a result, my memory of what I watched is retrievably sharp. This was the era of Why Don’t You? and Danger Mouse and, going back further, prehistoric-looking Bagpuss and K…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Brockes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resplendence of things past: museum of Paris revels in £50m revamp]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/resplendence-of-things-past-museum-of-paris-revels-in-50m-revamp</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/resplendence-of-things-past-museum-of-paris-revels-in-50m-revamp"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:42:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Carnavalet, devoted to the city’s history, has been shaken out of its dusty and confusing former shape
One of the first cities in Europe to award itself a museum devoted to its own history, Paris will soon have one of the continent’s most modern as the Musée Carnavalet reopens this month following a spectacular five-year, €58m (£50m) renovation.
Opened in 1880 at the suggestion of Baron Georges-Eugène Haussmann, who realised 20 years earlier that the mammoth programme of urban renewal he was carrying ou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What changes can government make to the BBC?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/what-changes-can-government-make-to-the-bbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/what-changes-can-government-make-to-the-bbc"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:12:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ofcom’s powers relating to editorial oversight could be beefed up at charter’s midterm review next year 
The BBC operates under a royal charter agreed with the government, the latest of which runs until the end of 2027. At the beginning of next year the government is due to start a midterm review of the charter, a “health check”, specifically focusing on governance and regulatory arrangements. The government will set the terms of reference for the midterm review so it certainly has the power to seek major c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trouble in cyclists’ paradise: Amsterdam accused of favouring pedestrians]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/trouble-cyclists-paradise-amsterdam-accused-favouring-pedestrians</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/trouble-cyclists-paradise-amsterdam-accused-favouring-pedestrians"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dutch cycling union claims city has turned on them by making centre more difficult to navigate
Its reputation is that of an idyll for cyclists, a city freed from the torment of cars. But while Amsterdam remains a model to most of the world, there are signs of trouble in paradise.
A series of developments have led the Amsterdam branch of the Fietsersbond, the Dutch cyclists’ union, to claim the municipality has turned on them, unfairly prioritising pedestrians in the city’s historic centre.
 Continue reading…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My first birth was traumatic: should I have a second baby?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/my-first-birth-traumatic-second-baby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/my-first-birth-traumatic-second-baby"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You need to feel informed and in control, says Annalisa Barbieri. Ask yourself: what support do I have now that I didn’t have the first time round?
My first and only child is three and a half, and I’ve been thinking about having another. This is something I really want, but part of me is scared. When I had my first child, it went badly: physically and emotionally. The birth itself was very traumatic, and three days after she was born I had a panic attack, which spiralled into postnatal depression and PTSD f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annalisa Barbieri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It will not be the last war’: Palestinians and Israelis reflect on Gaza ceasefire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-and-israelis-reflect-gaza-ceasefire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/palestinians-and-israelis-reflect-gaza-ceasefire"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many people fear that with no political solution, violence will return again and again
After four wars in 13 years, or four battles in a single conflict punctuated by intermittent periods of calm, many Israelis and Palestinians on Friday expressed a weary sense of deja vu about the latest Gaza ceasefire between Hamas and Israel.
“Life will return, because this is not the first war, and it will not be the last war,” said a shop owner, Ashraf Abu Mohammad, in Gaza. “The heart is in pain; there have been disas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sufian Taha and Quique Kierszenbaum in Jerusalem, Rachel Obordo and Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Despite the ceasefire, Gaza’s health service is on the brink of collapse | Raja Musleh and Alaa Alkhatib]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/commentisfree/2021/may/21/ceasefire-gaza-health-service-covid-19-hospitals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/commentisfree/2021/may/21/ceasefire-gaza-health-service-covid-19-hospitals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:29:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our hospitals were already under intolerable pressure because of Covid-19. Then came the latest bombardments
Today the streets of Gaza City are full of cheering in response to the news of a ceasefire. But during the 11 days of the aerial bombardment by Israel, the streets told a different story: they were empty, except for ambulances rushing to hospitals and people displaced from their homes by bombings looking for a place to sleep. It was a ghost town with the soundtrack of a nightmare: explosions, sirens …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raja Musleh and Alaa Alkhatib</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Late capitalism’ is written off as a crank’s phrase. But there’s more to it than that | Zoe Williams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/late-capitalism-written-off-cranks-phrase-but-more-to-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/late-capitalism-written-off-cranks-phrase-but-more-to-it"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People may roll their eyes at the concept, but at least it tries to address a problem that won’t go away on its own
“Maybe mental health isn’t the problem,” said Mr Z, listening to a news item about mental health on the radio. “Maybe it’s a crisis in late capitalism.”
“Funny, that’s what Sinéad O’Connor thinks,” I replied.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concerns raised over long Covid impact on north-west England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/21/concerns-raised-over-long-covid-impact-on-north-west-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/21/concerns-raised-over-long-covid-impact-on-north-west-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:02:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report says impact likely to be greater in region owing to employment and economic inequalities 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Towns such as Bolton and Blackburn-with-Darwen are facing a deep health and economic crisis due to a growing number of long Covid cases keeping people out of work and placing a “double hit” of pressure on the NHS, health officials have said.
Research seen by the Guardian suggests more than 140,000 people in north-west England had long Covid – meanin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Halliday and Helen Pidd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mary Beth Barone: ‘Chlamydia would be a beautiful name for a little girl’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/21/mary-beth-barone-funniest-things</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/21/mary-beth-barone-funniest-things"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The comedian, improviser and actor on the things that make her laugh the most

Amy Schumer Live at the Apollo. I was already a fan and it came out when I was a few months into doing open mics. I was just in awe of her writing, performance and confidence. She always makes it look effortless to be that funny.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not saying I’m an emotional wreck, but almost anything can reduce me to tears | Romesh Ranganathan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/emotional-wreck-almost-anything-can-reduce-me-to-tears-romesh-ranganathan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/emotional-wreck-almost-anything-can-reduce-me-to-tears-romesh-ranganathan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T13:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mere sight of Watford Gap services sent me into a flood
A few years ago, I was on my way to Australia to perform at the Melbourne comedy festival, and was feeling a bit nervous about what Australian audiences were going to make of me. On the plane I decided to try to take my mind off it by having a drink and watching the in-flight entertainment. An hour and a half later, I was watching Dev Patel’s character reunite with his family in India in the film Lion and sobbing my eyes out. One of the cabin crew …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Romesh Ranganathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Black fungus’ disease linked to Covid spreads across India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/mucormycosis-black-fungus-disease-linked-covid-spreads-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/mucormycosis-black-fungus-disease-linked-covid-spreads-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:59:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[7,200 mucormycosis cases reported, usually in patients with diabetes or compromised immune systems

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

States across India have begun declaring a “black fungus” epidemic as cases of the fatal rare infection shoot up in patients recovering from Covid-19.
The fungal disease, called mucormycosis, has a 50% mortality rate. It affects patients initially in the nose but the fungus can then spread into the brain, and can often only be treated by major sur…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen in Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meghan, Diana, drugs and therapy: what Harry said in Apple TV series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/meghan-diana-drugs-therapy-what-harry-said-apple-tv-series</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/meghan-diana-drugs-therapy-what-harry-said-apple-tv-series"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duke accused royal family of ‘total silence and total neglect’ as he told of his and his wife’s struggles

Prince Harry says trauma of Diana’s death led him to use alcohol and drugs

The Duke of Sussex has accused the royal family of “total silence and total neglect” as his wife, Meghan, struggled to adjust to palace life, and said the family tried to prevent the couple from leaving.
In a new mental health documentary series with Oprah Winfrey, Prince Harry tells how he turned to drink and drugs to mask the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Officials take police action against leaders of bulldozed mosque in India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/officials-take-police-action-against-leaders-of-bulldozed-mosque-in-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/officials-take-police-action-against-leaders-of-bulldozed-mosque-in-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:29:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demolition of mosque in Uttar Pradesh was ‘violation of rule of law’, says Indian MP 
A local administration accused of illegally tearing down a mosque in the Indian state of Uttar Pradesh has filed a police case against nine local Muslim leaders who challenged the demolition.
On Monday, Masjid Gareeb Nawaz Al Maroof in Barabanki district was bulldozed without notice after it was declared an illegal structure by the local administration, which had contested its presence. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen in Delhi and Mohammad Sartaj Alam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stonehenge research at risk if Sheffield archaeology unit closes, say experts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/stonehenge-research-in-jeopardy-if-sheffield-university-archaeology-unit-closes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/21/stonehenge-research-in-jeopardy-if-sheffield-university-archaeology-unit-closes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:26:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University of Sheffield’s archaeology team argue vital work will be lost if threatened closure goes ahead
Important research on Stonehenge could be put in jeopardy if the threatened closure of one of the UK’s most renowned university archaeology departments goes ahead, leading experts on the prehistoric monument have warned.
Current and former members of the University of Sheffield’s archaeology department are at the forefront of some of the most intriguing work at the Wiltshire site and argue that if it is…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Isis-linked fighters in Nigeria cannot claim reward for Boko Haram leader, says US]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/isis-linked-fighters-in-nigeria-cant-claim-reward-for-boko-haram-leader-says-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/isis-linked-fighters-in-nigeria-cant-claim-reward-for-boko-haram-leader-says-us"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:24:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[State department had offered a $7m reward for Abubakar Shekau, believed killed or badly injured

The US government has told Islamic State-affiliated fighters in Nigeria they are not eligible for a reward after reports that the leader of Boko Haram had died during clashes in a forest in the north-east. 
The US state department had offered $7m (£4.9m) for information about the identity or location of Abubakar Shekau as part of its global counter-terrorism rewards programme aimed at tracking down leading viole…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke Africa correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Novavax volunteers in UK threaten to quit over approval delays]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/21/novavax-volunteers-in-uk-threaten-to-quit-over-approval-delays</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/21/novavax-volunteers-in-uk-threaten-to-quit-over-approval-delays"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:19:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Participants cannot prove they are fully vaccinated on NHS app leaving them unable to travel to Europe

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The Novavax coronavirus trial threatens to descend into chaos as exasperated volunteers say they will drop out because they cannot prove they are fully vaccinated on the NHS app, leaving them unable to travel to Europe.
Among the 15,000 volunteers who took part, many say they are considering quitting or getting alternative jabs – despite the p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[They won’t remind us, but the tabloids hurt Diana just as much as Panorama did | Marina Hyde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/tabloids-hurt-princess-diana-panorama-bbc-scapegoat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/tabloids-hurt-princess-diana-panorama-bbc-scapegoat"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:05:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BBC makes a convenient scapegoat when in reality all of us were part of the ecosystem that destroyed Diana
“It brings indescribable sadness,” ran Prince William’s statement on the damning report into Panorama’s interview with his mother, “to know that the BBC’s failures contributed significantly to her fear, paranoia and isolation that I remember from those final years with her.”
“Paranoia” – what a word to take you back. When Martin Bashir’s Diana interview aired in 1995, the MP (and friend of Prince C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Hyde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All the small things: how Blink 182’s Travis Barker became the most influential person in music]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/21/all-the-small-things-how-blink-182s-travis-barker-became-the-most-influential-person-in-music</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/21/all-the-small-things-how-blink-182s-travis-barker-became-the-most-influential-person-in-music"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Lil Wayne to Willow Smith, the pop-punk drummer is making his mark across the musical landscape – is it more than mere nostalgia?
The most influential person in music right now is Blink-182 drummer Travis Barker. Don’t believe us? This year alone, 25 tracks featuring or produced by Barker have been released. He has worked with the new pop-punk era Willow Smith and TikTok e-boy turned singer Lil Huddy, signed TikTok emo Jxdn, produced Trippie Redd’s Neon Shark album, and drummed on Bebe Rexha’s new sing…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Issy Sampson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asthma in toddlers linked to in-utero exposure to air pollution, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/asthma-in-toddlers-linked-to-in-utero-exposure-to-air-pollution-ufps-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/asthma-in-toddlers-linked-to-in-utero-exposure-to-air-pollution-ufps-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Developing foetuses ‘exquisitely sensitive’ to harm from tiny particles, scientists say
Infants whose mothers were exposed to higher levels of tiny air pollution particles during pregnancy are much more likely to develop asthma, according to research.
The study analysed the impact of ultra-fine particles (UFPs), which are not regulated by governments. These are thought to be even more toxic than the larger particles that are routinely monitored and have also been linked to asthma.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to wear a breezy cotton dress | Jess Cartner-Morley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/21/how-to-wear-breezy-cotton-dress-jess-cartner-morley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/21/how-to-wear-breezy-cotton-dress-jess-cartner-morley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An easy summery day dress and an old favourite pair of sandals are the perfect way to get back into the swing of dressing up
I have barely taken off my coat in front of someone I don’t live with since last summer. Which is a bit bizarre, come to think of it. But life has been so strange in so many ways for so long now that stuff like that happens and we barely notice.
Going for a walk replaced going for a coffee or a drink all winter long, so I had a coat on. Then outdoor dining came back, which was thrilli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Cartner-Morley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance of things past: 10 readers on the lost possessions they will mourn for ever]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/remembrance-of-things-past-10-readers-on-the-lost-possessions-they-will-mourn-for-ever</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/remembrance-of-things-past-10-readers-on-the-lost-possessions-they-will-mourn-for-ever"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:41:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From wedding rings to tattered old teddies, we asked you to tell us about the irreplaceable objects you have mislaid and why they were so important to you
A few days before leaving London to move to Southend last November, I realised I didn’t know where my childhood stuffed toy was. The toy, named Katie, lived on my bed, and had done since my great-nan gave her to me a few weeks before my first birthday. She was tattered, patched and ripped, but just perfect, and meant a lot to me. We searched the entire ho…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers and Rachel Obordo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG) From Scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High winds and the disappeared: Friday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/21/high-winds-disappeared-friday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/21/high-winds-disappeared-friday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:24:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kate Winslet in Mare of Easttown – style icon of the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/21/kate-winslet-in-mare-of-easttown-style-icon-of-the-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/21/kate-winslet-in-mare-of-easttown-style-icon-of-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:11:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pennsylvania detective’s unvarnished realness has hit a fashion nerve with viewers 
The style icon everyone is talking about wears drab flannel shirts with flat shoes and crumpled jeans. She has frown lines and dark roots. She might wear mascara if she’s going out to eat but if she’s going to work she doesn’t bother. As a Pennsylvania detective in Mare of Easttown, the Oscar-winning actor Kate Winslet bucks the trend for high fashion on the small screen that has given us a string of glossy shows such as…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Cartner-Morley Associate editor (fashion)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok: six of the video-sharing app’s greatest hits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/21/tiktok-six-of-the-video-sharing-apps-greatest-hits</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/21/tiktok-six-of-the-video-sharing-apps-greatest-hits"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As co-founder stands down, we look at the lip-syncing, sea shanties and recipe sharing that went viral

Bytedance boss goes at uncertain time for Chinese tech firms

Despite controversy in the US, TikTok has risen to become one of the best-known social media apps in recent years. With 800 million users, the home of the 15-second clip is now a global hub of lip-syncing, choreographed dancing and even recipe sharing, creating some of the most unlikely stars in the digital galaxy along the way. As its co-found…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK weather: May on track to be wettest on record with more rain to come]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-weather-may-on-track-to-be-wettest-on-record-with-more-rain-to-come</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-weather-may-on-track-to-be-wettest-on-record-with-more-rain-to-come"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T10:52:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rainfall totals across UK exceed monthly average with flood warnings in England and Wales
The UK is on track for its wettest May on record, with further heavy rain forecast as lockdown rules start to lift.
According to provisional figures from the Met Office’s national climate information centre, Wales has already recorded 129% (110.6mm) of its average rainfall for the whole of the month, while the UK as a whole has had 88% (61.1mm).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A radical change’: America’s new generation of pro-Palestinian voices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/israel-gaza-conflict-biden-palestine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/21/israel-gaza-conflict-biden-palestine"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T10:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Progressive coalition could become counterweight to pro-Israeli traditions of Democratic party
It just so happened that Joe Biden was due to visit Detroit, home to the biggest Arab American community in the country, at the height of the latest upsurge in Israeli-Palestinian violence.
The sight of the presidential motorcade on Tuesday passing through a protest bedecked with Palestinian flags – and of Biden himself in heated discussion with Rashida Tlaib, the first Palestinian woman to be elected to Congress,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK citizens: have you experienced any issues at EU border control?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:31:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from UK citizens who have encountered issues when travelling to other countries in Europe

Following reports that some EU citizens have been sent to immigration removal centres and held in airport detention rooms, we would like to hear from UK citizens about any issues they have faced at border control when travelling to Europe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Brazil is a global pariah’: Lula on his plot to end reign of ‘psychopath’ Bolsonaro]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/brazil-lula-bolsonaro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/brazil-lula-bolsonaro"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:05:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brazil’s former leftist leader Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva left no doubt he was planning a finale to a dramatic political career
Brazil can be rescued after being turned into a Covid-stricken global outcast by its “psychopath” president Jair Bolsonaro, the politician best placed to defeat him in next year’s presidential election has insisted.
In an interview with the Guardian, Brazil’s former leftist leader Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva – who is widely tipped to challenge Bolsonaro for the presidency after regain…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips in Rio de Janeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will you get douze points? Take our fiendish Eurovision quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/21/will-you-get-douze-points-take-our-fiendish-eurovision-quiz</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/21/will-you-get-douze-points-take-our-fiendish-eurovision-quiz"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Abba to Bucks Fizz, dancing grannies to French diplomacy, our quiz requires some serious song contest chops to get 12 points – or a perfect 20 
Vampires, naked apes and free booze! The wildest Eurovision performances ever

After last year’s hiatus, the Eurovision song contest is finally back on Saturday night at 8pm on BBC One, with all the glitz, glamour and camp delight that entails. To get you in the mood, take our fiendish Eurovision quiz. Can you avoid the dreaded nul points? Let us know how you d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week three]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-three</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/21/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-three"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first two of the six stories were reprinted in the Guardian on 7 and 14 May. The third is below, with the other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU to delay adding UK to travel ‘white list’ due to Covid variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/eu-decision-to-add-uk-to-travel-white-list-to-be-delayed-due-to-covid-variant-fears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/eu-decision-to-add-uk-to-travel-white-list-to-be-delayed-due-to-covid-variant-fears"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T08:05:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising number of British B.1.617.2 cases to push back Brussels decision by two weeks

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A decision in Brussels to add the UK to an EU “white list” of countries from where tourists will be welcome this summer is to be delayed, it is understood, due to concerns over the Covid variant first identified in India.
EU diplomats were expected to use a revised threshold of infection cases to extend the list of countries at a meeting on Friday but sources s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four weeks of protests in Colombia – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/21/four-weeks-of-protests-in-colombia-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/21/four-weeks-of-protests-in-colombia-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A wave of anti-government protests entered their fourth week on Wednesday as unions, student groups and others demand social change amid intermittent talks between the government and strike organisers
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amid the Covid pandemic, Senegal women find renewed hope in fishing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/amid-the-covid-pandemic-senegal-women-find-renewed-hope-in-fishing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/21/amid-the-covid-pandemic-senegal-women-find-renewed-hope-in-fishing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than a thousand women in Bargny, and many more in the other villages dotting Senegal’s sandy coast, process fish – performing a crucial role in one of the country’s largest exports
Since her birth on Senegal’s coast, the ocean has always given Ndeye Yacine Dieng life. Her grandfather was a fisher, and her grandmother and mother processed fish. Like generations of women, she now helps support her family in the small community of Bargny by drying, smoking, salting and fermenting the catch brought home by…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carley Petesch/AP; photography by Léo Corrêa/AP</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Luckily I’m very decisive’: Liverpool’s new mayor plans fresh start for city]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/luckily-im-very-decisive-liverpools-new-mayor-plans-fresh-start-for-city</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/luckily-im-very-decisive-liverpools-new-mayor-plans-fresh-start-for-city"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joanne Anderson is keen to show the change from her predecessor and aims to rebuild trust
Liverpool’s new mayor has pledged to appoint external, independent chairs to oversee aspects of council decision-making and to listen to the opinions of all the city’s residents, not just those of “a selected few”.
Joanne Anderson made history this month when she became the first black woman to be a directly elected as mayor of a major UK city. Aside from the strides in terms of diversity – every previous leader of Liv…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life inside Gaza during 11 days of bombardment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian journalist Hazem Balousha describes living in, and reporting from, Gaza, under heavy bombardment until a ceasefire began on Friday, while historian Rashid Khalidi discusses the history of the Palestinian struggle for statehood
Anushka Asthana talks to Hazem Balousha, a Guardian correspondent who lives in Gaza. He describes living in, and reporting from, the strip, which was under heavy bombardment from last Monday until the agreement of a ceasefire, beginning early on Friday morning. The latest con…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hazem Balousha and Rashid Khalidi, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn CSS!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340933</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/learn/css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:51:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ooo look at this mighty SEO flex from Google: Learn CSS! Well deserved — this is great content. Twenty-three chapters taking you through all the fundamentals of CSS with extra content, like relevant podcasts, interactive examples, and even quizzes to …
The post Learn CSS! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular 11 Tutorial: Code a Project from Scratch]]></title>
        <id>60a6b3ab906c5207e3a7f5fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/angular-11-tutorial-code-a-project-from-scratch/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angular is one of the most popular web frameworks. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create an Angular 11 project from scratch. It uses a public API to create a game database website. You will gain a great foundation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Modern C++ by Building an Audio Plugin]]></title>
        <id>60a694ab906c5207e3a7f544</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-modern-cpp-by-building-an-audio-plugin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of C++ courses teach you how to build toy projects with no real-world application. But it can often be more helpful to write programs people would actually use. We just released a 5-hour C++ course that will teach you how to write modern C++ code by building an]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Started with Version Control Using Git]]></title>
        <id>60a4b5c7906c5207e3a7e2bb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/get-started-with-version-control-and-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, you'll learn what version control is and how you can contribute to open-source projects using Git.  We'll get through the fundamentals of Git and I'll give you the knowledge that is indispensable for any web developer. What is Git?Git is a version control software which lets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn JavaScript - A Free 7-hour Interactive Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60a36742906c5207e3a7da6e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-javascript-interactive-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last four months, I have recorded what is probably the most interactive JavaScript course that has ever been created. The reason I have done this is because I often see new coders fall into the same pitfalls again and again when trying to learn JavaScript, with the most]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340715</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/can-we-create-a-resize-hack-with-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you follow new developments in CSS, you’ve likely heard of the impending arrival of container queries. We’re going to look at the basics here, but if you’d like another look, check out Una’s “Next Gen CSS: @container” article. …
The post Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jhey Tompkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fit-content and fit-content()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340897</id>
        <link href="https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2021/04/fitcontent_and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s some hardcore deep-dive CSS nerdery from PPK. If you can wrap your mind around min-content (the smallest an element can be based on the content it contains) and max-content (the largest the content of an element can push it) …
The post fit-content and fit-content() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis behind drastic drop in Arctic wildlife populations – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Native shorebirds and caribou among species at risk as survival strategies are upended
A drastic drop in caribou and shorebird populations is a reflection of the dire changes unfolding on the Arctic tundra, according to a new report from the Arctic Council. 
The terrestrial Arctic spans approximately 2.7m sq miles (7m sq km), marked by extreme cold, drought, strong winds and seasonal darkness. Species living in this environment have adapted to thrive in the harsh conditions. But the climate crisis has upend…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Dickie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you attended a large-scale test event in England?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from the people who attended these events about their experiences
In April, the government launched their scheme to pilot large-scale events in England to test their safety before restrictions are eased on mass gatherings.
The majority of rules on social contact are set to be removed by 21 June, but this is dependent on cases, deaths and hospital admissions continuing to fall.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your favourite memories from the Glastonbury festival]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:25:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the festival gearing up for the Live at Worthy Farm live stream this weekend, we want to hear your most cherished moments from past years
One year off, we could handle. After all, Glastonbury often has a fallow year to let the land, and the workers, have a bit of a rest. But two cancellations of the festival in a row is really quite depressing, leaving us and thousands of ticket holders dolefully marking out June 2022 in the diaries for the next possible trip.
But as well as September’s planned one-day…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Divine, Pacino, Jagger … and me: 50 years of Albert Watson’s portraits – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/divine-pacino-jagger-photographer-albert-watson-gallery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/divine-pacino-jagger-photographer-albert-watson-gallery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legendary photographer’s new book features inspiring images and insider tips – such as remembering to order in a subject’s favourite coffee
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate disasters ‘caused more internal displacement than war’ in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T04:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Refugee organisation says 30m new displacements last year were due to floods, storms or wildfires
Intense storms and flooding triggered three times more displacements than violent conflicts did last year, as the number of people internally displaced worldwide hit the highest level on record.
There were at least 55 million internally displaced people (IDPs) by the end of last year, according to figures published by the Norwegian Refugee Council’s Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC).
 Continue read…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saeed Kamali Dehghan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rio de Janeiro’s deadliest police raid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T02:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Latin American correspondent Tom Phillips visits Jacarezinho, one of Rio’s biggest favelas, the day after police carried out the deadliest raid in the city’s history
Anushka Asthana talks to Tom Phillips about the police raid in Jacarezinho favela, in the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro. On 6 May police stormed the favela, targeting one of the city’s largest drug gangs, known as Red Command. Twenty-seven men were shot dead by police and one police officer was killed. Police, politicians and some p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Tom Phillips, produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340731</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Public Beta of the Notion API dropped! Woot! Here’s their guide. I’ve been a Notion user and fan for a long time, for both personal and professional team use. They even sponsored a few videos around here a …
The post Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Selectors to Style Your Web Page]]></title>
        <id>60a341f5906c5207e3a7da61</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-css-selectors-to-style-webpage/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS selectors are one of the most important parts of CSS. They give you the ability to target HTML elements on your web page that you want to style. Without CSS selectors, you wouldn't be able to style your page to look how you want. Thankfully CSS selectors have been]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Web3? The Decentralized Internet of the Future Explained]]></title>
        <id>60a42386906c5207e3a7dfe2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet is going through a paradigm shift. Learn the differences between Web2 and Web3, and why many developers and companies are shifting their approach in building apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Optimize for Change in Software Development]]></title>
        <id>60a469ec906c5207e3a7e1b9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-optimize-for-change-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine that you work at Magic Money Corp, which runs on just three lines of JavaScript: let input = { step1: 'collect underpants' } doStuff(input)  profit(input) // $$$!!! Now imagine that something's wrong with doStuff and you need to take it down for maintenance. What happens if you temporarily comment out the second]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate change could make overwinter ‘zombie’ fires more common]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds burn area from fires that survive winter varies depending on warmth of summers
In the boreal forests of the far northern hemisphere, where the climate is warming faster than almost anywhere else, some wildfires are surviving winter snows and picking up again in spring.
Now scientists from the Netherlands and Alaska have figured out how to calculate the scope of those “zombie fires” that smoulder year-round in the peaty soil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340692</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svg-loader-a-different-way-to-work-with-external-svg/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVGs are awesome: they are small, look sharp on any scale, and can be customized without creating a separate file. However, there is something I feel is missing in web standards today: a way to include them as an external …
The post svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shubham Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple versus Epic: how the Fortnite app led to a legal showdown - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Apple takes on games developer and Fortnite creator Epic, UK technology editor Alex Hern describes a battle of the tech titans that could reshape the app industry
The video game Fortnite has become a cultural phenomenon in recent years with up to 100 million users a month logging in to play the free online game. They parachute down on to an island with 99 other players and the last one standing is the winner. 
But for users of iPhones and iPads, the wildly popular game has been unavailable ever since it …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Alex Hern; produced by Sami Kent and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break into Ethereum, Crypto, and Web3 as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60a53182906c5207e3a7e588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/breaking-into-ethereum-crypto-web3-as-a-developer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I've been talking about my move into the Web3, Ethereum, and crypto space since making the switch from a traditional web, mobile, and cloud background. Since making that move, a shocking number of people have reached out to me who are also thinking about doing the same.  It's really]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinned Audio WordPress Theme]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/pinned-audio-wordpress-theme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m afraid I have to start this with a whole backstory, as the journey here is the point, not so much the theme.
A fella wrote to me a while back outlining a situation he was in. His company has …
The post Pinned Audio WordPress Theme appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance Development Pricing Guide – Should Freelancers Bill by the Hour?]]></title>
        <id>60a3780f906c5207e3a7db5f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-different-ways-to-charge-for-a-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you offer your services as a freelance developer, you have a major say in how you price your project.  But how do you go about charging for a website project? "Well, I just bill by the hour and send an invoice every week or month." ...I hear you say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Neon Text With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340420</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-neon-text-with-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neon text can add a nice, futuristic touch to any website. I’ve always loved the magic of neon signs, and wanted to recreate them using CSS. I thought I’d share some tips on how to do it! In this article, …
The post How to Create Neon Text With CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia O'Dwyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>