<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-25T00:34:48.229Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-25T00:34:48.229Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’ve struck a deal’: Biden says agreement reached on infrastructure plan – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/24/biden-covid-delta-variant-infrastructure-deal-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/24/biden-covid-delta-variant-infrastructure-deal-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T00:18:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Republican and Democratic senators have reached deal – president
Speaker: ‘It is imperative that we seek the truth as to what happened’
Giuliani’s New York law license suspended ‘effectively immediately’
Biden urges unvaccinated to get shots as ‘deadlier’ Delta strain spreads

 1.18am BST 
That’s all for today, thanks for following along. Here are some key links and developments from the day:
 1.00am BST 
While Biden has extended the federal eviction restrictions through July, advocates in California are growing increasingly concerned about the state ban on evictions that is due to expire next week. 
State officials have said California has $5.2bn to pay landlords all of what they were owed while giving low-income renters who have fallen into debt a clean slate. But advocates and officials in some of the hardest-hit cities, say they fear the plan will not reach the people in need and note that the process to dole out relief has been very slow.
 Related: California has a $5.2bn plan to pay off unpaid rent accrued during the pandemic 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin in Los Angeles (now) and Adam Gabbatt in New York (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Business, unions and EHRC press government on ethnic pay gap reporting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/25/cbi-tuc-and-ehrc-press-government-on-mandatory-ethnic-pay-gap-reporting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/25/cbi-tuc-and-ehrc-press-government-on-mandatory-ethnic-pay-gap-reporting"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T23:24:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Letter signed by group says good reporting can help to better understand and address pay disparities
The UK’s largest business lobby group has joined the Trades Union Congress (TUC) and the human rights watchdog in calling for mandatory ethnicity pay gap reporting, saying data collection will help tackle racial inequalities at work.
In a letter to the Cabinet Office minister Michael Gove, the Confederation of British Industry (CBI), TUC and Equality and Human Rights Commission, said the move would help draw attention to pay disparities and a lack of minority representation across senior positions, and hopefully spark action by employers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 600m NHS home Covid tests unaccounted for, auditors reveal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/25/almost-600m-nhs-home-covid-tests-unaccounted-for-auditors-reveal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/25/almost-600m-nhs-home-covid-tests-unaccounted-for-auditors-reveal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T23:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Results from only 14% of the 691m tests handed out in England have been registered with test and trace

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Almost 600m lateral flow tests given to the public in England may not yet have been used, according to a report that says the hugely expensive test-and-trace system is still bedevilled by problems.
The National Audit Office said NHS Test and Trace (NSHT&T), which Boris Johnson promised would be world-beating and has a budget exceeding that of the Department for Transport, was struggling with some “fundamental parts” of its role.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[J’Ouvert review – the history of Notting Hill carnival comes to life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/24/jouvert-review-harold-pinter-theatre-notting-hill-carnival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/24/jouvert-review-harold-pinter-theatre-notting-hill-carnival"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T22:59:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harold Pinter theatre, London
In Yasmin Joseph’s play, three girls wind their way through the streets, guided by the spirit of the activist who founded the carnival
J’Ouvert evokes the spirit of carnival from its first, thumping beat: the ground-shaking thunder of music, the sweaty crush of crowds, the feathers and the floats with friends dancing on them.
We land in the thick of the Notting Hill carnival, just a few months after the nearby Grenfell Tower fire of 2017, though the focus of the play is the heritage and politics of this specific street party. Nads (the dominant friend, played by Gabrielle Brooks) and Jade (tough, protective, played with grit by Sapphire Joy) take us through their day, from Nads’ ambition to become dancing queen to Jade’s desire to mobilise and speak out. There are stories of leering, drunken men who exoticise or grope them; encounters with the older Caribbean community; and observations of the wealthy contingent that have gentrified the area. There are sparks in the girls’ friendship, too, when Nisha (Annice Boparai) joins them, though she remains a flat character; a middle-class do-gooder, hoping to share their intimacies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arifa Akbar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A managerial disaster class’ – the verdict from the Euro 2020 countries who are out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/a-managerial-disaster-class-verdict-euro-2020-countries-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/a-managerial-disaster-class-verdict-euro-2020-countries-out"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T22:03:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Turkey to Hungary, the teams who were eliminated have been met by contrasting reviews back home
This week Euro 2020 bade farewell to eight of the 24 countries who had qualified and the eliminated teams were met by quite contrasting headlines back home. As in every tournament there were those who had exceeded expectations and those who had fallen way below them
One of the dark horses of the tournament, Turkey, had a horrible experience and were dumped out after three straight defeats. The press did not hold back. The sports newspaper Fanatik led with the headline “The End” and wrote that the “Turkish wall crumbled”. Another sports newspaper Fotomac kept it simple: “Disgrace” while in his Fanatik column, Mehmet Demirkol wrote: “The zero [points] we watched do not even deserve a zero. We witnessed a managerial disaster class.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England defy rain and Sri Lanka’s fightback with ball to win T20 series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/sam-curran-powers-england-to-rain-hit-t20-series-win-over-sri-lanka</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/sam-curran-powers-england-to-rain-hit-t20-series-win-over-sri-lanka"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:44:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sri Lanka 111-7; England 108-5
England reach revised target to go 2-0 up with one to play

As England eased past Sri Lanka in their opening T20 encounter on Wednesday night they seemed to have an embarrassment of riches, but there was a time as the teams met again 24 hours later that they flirted with just plain embarrassment. Having restricted Sri Lanka to the meagre total of 111 they turned a procession into a problem with the loss of four early wickets, but a partnership of 53 between Sam Billings and Liam Livingstone settled their nerves and, after their target was trimmed to 103 because of a brief rain delay, they won by five wickets to take an unassailable 2-0 lead in the series.
Livingstone has hit more explosive innings than his 26-ball 29 here, but it was tailored perfectly to the situation his team was in. The England captain, Eoin Morgan, complained afterwards that “every time we seemed to take a risk we lost a wicket” but Livingstone played conservatively until, with the die apparently cast, he ramped Dushmantha Chameera for six, his only boundary. “With Sam we tried to hit the fielders and run as hard as we could, and knock the runs off that way,” he said. “The rain actually helped the pitch a lot. It wasn’t easy going early on and it made the ball skid on more.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Burnton at Sophia Gardens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diana review – the princess and her definitively undashing prince]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/diana-review-the-princess-and-her-definitively-undashing-prince</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/diana-review-the-princess-and-her-definitively-undashing-prince"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:35:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Diana would be turning 60, this retelling of her life offered nothing new … apart from perhaps an insight into how bizarrely limited life was for gels like her
There is a moment in Diana, ITV’s feature-length documentary marking what would have been the princess’s 60th birthday, when, after her cousin and boarding school friend Diana McFarlane describes the teenage Diana having pictures of Prince Charles on her bedside table (“a sort of childhood crush really”), the makers cut to contemporaneous footage of the “dashing prince”. He is so definitively undashing that you cannot help but feel a point has, advertently or inadvertently, been made about the limited life view of young gels of Diana’s era and breeding.
That’s about as much insight, deliberate or otherwise, we are given in this offering. And really, why should there be more? We’ve had it all, surely, over the 24 years since she was killed in a car crash in Paris. And before that, during the years when her marriage to Charles was falling apart and they jockeyed for position and control of the narrative in the press, via interviews, leaks, tell-all books, meaningful silences, photo ops and all the messy rest of it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Rashford tells England to ‘put names in history’ by beating Germany]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/marcus-rashford-tells-england-to-put-names-in-history-by-beating-germany</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/marcus-rashford-tells-england-to-put-names-in-history-by-beating-germany"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rashford: ‘There is no point fearing the past’
Jordan Henderson: ‘Our young squad can be a positive thing’

Marcus Rashford has urged England to write their names into history by securing a famous victory over Germany in the last 16 of Euro 2020.
England have endured plenty of heartbreak against their old rivals in tournaments, but there is a belief within the camp that they will not be carrying any mental baggage when they face Joachim Löw’s side. Most of the squad are too young to remember their manager, Gareth Southgate, missing the decisive penalty in the Euro 96 semi-final against Germany and Rashford feels it is vital that they do not show any fear at Wembley on Tuesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lothar Matthäus: ‘We’re favourites if England v Germany goes to penalties’ | Ed Aarons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/lothar-matthaus-england-germany-penalties-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/lothar-matthaus-england-germany-penalties-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The former Germany captain on his reservations about the current side and what it takes to win a major tournament
“We like Wembley and we like to come to England,” Lothar Matthäus says with a smile. “Yes, it’s a motivation for our players. We like motivations.”
It is more than 20 years since the man who won a record 150 Germany caps and became the first outfield player to appear in five World Cup finals hung up his boots but his competitive edge clearly remains. Matthäus – who captained Franz Beckenbauer’s side to their penalty shootout victory against England in the semi-final at Italia 90 but missed the Euro 96 rematch at Wembley after falling out with Jürgen Klinsmann and the manager Berti Vogts – is typically confident about Germany’s chances on Tuesday should it go the distance again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Aarons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami building collapse: one dead as rescue crews say 99 unaccounted for]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/emergency-operation-under-way-after-miami-building-collapse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/emergency-operation-under-way-after-miami-building-collapse"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:16:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Officials say about 55 of building’s 130 apartments affected
Reason for collapse in Surfside not yet known – authorities

A large-scale rescue operation was continuing Thursday evening at the site of a collapsed condominium block in Miami, where authorities said at least one person was killed, 10 injured and dozens more unaccounted for.
Crews reported hearing noises from inside the rubble as they searched for survivors at the Champlain Towers South condo in Surfside, a 12-storey apartment block that came crashing down at about 1.30am. Authorities said they expected the number of deaths to rise, but would not be drawn on the number.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer tells PM to ditch yacht and tackle antisocial behaviour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/keir-starmer-tells-pm-to-ditch-yacht-and-tackle-antisocial-behaviour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/keir-starmer-tells-pm-to-ditch-yacht-and-tackle-antisocial-behaviour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour leader criticises costly ‘national flagship’ plan and pledges to fund crime-fighting instead
Keir Starmer is calling on Boris Johnson to scrap his plans for a “vanity yacht” and instead spend the money on tackling antisocial behaviour.
Pledging to make Labour “the party of law and order”, Starmer highlighted the blight of antisocial behaviour, such as off-road bikes and high-powered cars being raced through residential neighbourhoods.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mo Farah in ‘good shape’ for last-ditch shot at Olympic qualification]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/mo-farah-in-good-shape-for-last-ditch-shot-at-olympic-qualification</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/mo-farah-in-good-shape-for-last-ditch-shot-at-olympic-qualification"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T21:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Farah failed to meet time required this month
British Championships also feature Dina Asher-Smith

The doors of the last chance saloon are about to swing shut for Mo Farah’s Olympic qualification hopes, but there is a growing confidence in UK Athletics circles that he is injury-free and can revert to “Classic Mo” in his final attempt to make the Tokyo Games.
The 38-year-old’s chances of defending his Olympic 10,000m title appeared to be ebbing away when he plodded home 22 seconds outside the qualifying time of 27min 28sec at the British trials on 5 June. However, insiders at Font Romeu, where Farah has been training with the Scottish athlete Andy Butchart, say he has recovered from ankle niggle that affected him that night and are optimistic he will qualify for Tokyo at a hastily arranged 10,000m at the British Athletics Championships in Manchester on Friday
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leave campaigners ‘surprised’ by decay in relations with EU, says David Frost]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/brexit-campaigners-surprised-by-sour-relations-with-eu-says-lord-frost</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/brexit-campaigners-surprised-by-sour-relations-with-eu-says-lord-frost"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T20:40:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit minister says dispute over border checks in Northern Ireland main barrier to better relationship
The deterioration in relations with the EU, partly driven by the Northern Ireland “sausage war”, has come as a surprise to those, who campaigned to leave the bloc five years ago, the government has admitted.
The Brexit minister, David Frost, said they had dreamed of a sovereign Britain, which could set forth on a global mission while maintaining friendly relations with its neighbours.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK eases Covid travel rules for tourist spots despite cabinet rift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/uk-lifts-quarantine-for-arrivals-from-malta-balearics-and-some-caribbean-islands</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/uk-lifts-quarantine-for-arrivals-from-malta-balearics-and-some-caribbean-islands"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T20:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Holiday hopes boosted as quarantine lifted for arrivals from Balearics, Malta and some Caribbean islands

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage


Ministers have sought to rescue the summer holiday season by easing travel restrictions for a number of tourist hotspots, amid a cabinet rift over plans to grant extra freedoms to people who have received both doses of their Covid vaccine.
But Thursday evening’s long-awaited move to scrap self-isolation for Britons returning from certain countries risked being immediately undermined, when some European leaders indicated they would toughen their own border measures to stop the UK’s surge in Delta variant infections in the UK hitting their shores.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti, Daniel Boffey, Nicola Davis and Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden vows to evacuate thousands of interpreters before Afghanistan pullout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/afghanistan-us-evacuate-interpreters-pullout</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/afghanistan-us-evacuate-interpreters-pullout"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T20:04:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Biden: those who helped US ‘are not going to be left behind’
• Operation expected to include up to 50,000 people
Joe Biden has vowed that Afghans who helped the US military “are not going to be left behind” as his administration stepped up planning to evacuate thousands of Afghan interpreters while their applications for US entry are processed.
Planning has accelerated in recent days to relocate the Afghans and their families to other countries before the US military completes its withdrawal from Afghanistan, according to officials.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and angencies in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on a patriotic song and a Brexit sausage battle – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/picture/2021/jun/24/ben-jennings-on-a-patriotic-song-and-a-brexit-sausage-battle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/picture/2021/jun/24/ben-jennings-on-a-patriotic-song-and-a-brexit-sausage-battle"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T19:18:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Good Turn review – everyday questions of love and mortality]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/24/one-good-turn-review-abbey-dublin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/24/one-good-turn-review-abbey-dublin"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T19:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abbey, Dublin, and online
Una McKevitt’s droll domestic drama shows us a day in the life of a family dealing with the ill health of an ageing father
Reopening to live audiences for the first time in 15 months, the Abbey theatre’s warm welcome seems to come with a tongue-in-cheek smile. As audience members are individually escorted to their socially distanced seats, they are presented on stage with what they may have just left at home: a domestic interior, fitted out in realistic detail from kitchen sink to television.
Una McKevitt’s droll new play presents a single day in the life of a cooped-up family whose members are sorely in need of respite from each other. Although written during the pandemic, these characters are not actually in lockdown but tied together by the long-term illness of Frank (Bosco Hogan), who needs 24-hour care. His wife and carer, Brenda (Catherine Byrne), cannot leave the house without someone to keep an eye on him, and is fraying from exhaustion. Having chucked in her job, their adult daughter, Fiona (Liz Fitzgibbon), is back living at home – an unsatisfactory arrangement highlighted by a flying visit from her sister (Aoibhéann McCann).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Meany</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best of the Balearics: four Spanish islands to visit from the green list]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/24/best-balaerics-spanish-islands-to-visit-green-list-mallorca-ibiza-menorca-formentera</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/24/best-balaerics-spanish-islands-to-visit-green-list-mallorca-ibiza-menorca-formentera"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mallorca, Ibiza, Menorca and Formentera don’t just offer dazzling beaches, they’re also a paradise for walkers, cyclists and divers
A lot of us have been dreaming of plunging into the Balearic Islands’ glittering seas over the last year, and with a bit of luck the fantasy may become a reality before too long.
Floating in the Mediterranean isn’t the only thing on our Balearic wishlist though. We are thinking of staying in small hotels in inland villages, eating in restaurants that use the produce found in the surrounding countryside, and drinking wines from local vineyards. Of course, we still want to lie on the beach, but we might also want to explore by bike, paddle around the coast in a kayak or reboot on a yoga retreat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annie Bennett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backlash after Florida governor signs bill against ‘indoctrination’ at colleges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/ron-desantis-florida-governor-bill-indoctrination-colleges</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/ron-desantis-florida-governor-bill-indoctrination-colleges"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:45:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Republican Ron DeSantis claims university campuses are ‘intellectually repressive environments’ 
Florida’s Republican governor, Ron DeSantis, sparked backlash this week when he signed legislation cracking down on so-called educational “indoctrination” at colleges and universities, soon after the state banned critical race theory in its public schools.
“It used to be thought that a university campus was a place where you’d be exposed to a lot of different ideas. Unfortunately now, the norm is really these are more intellectually repressive environments,” DeSantis said during a press conference at a Fort Myers middle school.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Villarreal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When does the Bank’s relaxed stance become complacency? | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/24/when-does-the-banks-relaxed-stance-become-complacency</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/24/when-does-the-banks-relaxed-stance-become-complacency"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:44:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With inflationary pressures all too visible, Threadneedle Street could perhaps be slightly more worried
Inflation is “likely to exceed 3% for a temporary period”, says the Bank of England’s monetary policy committee, which would prefer the emphasis to be put on the word “temporary”. The rate-setters, or most of them, are sticking to their script: once the inevitable strong period for growth and inflation is out of the way, both readings will fall back, so there’s no need to be alarmed.
The benign view has a lot going for it, of course. Inflation plunged last year during lockdowns and the reopening phase was bound to produce a spike of some size. May’s inflation reading was 2.1%, a relative surge from just 0.7% in March. But if the peak proves to be 3%-ish, the “transitory” narrative – central bankers’ favourite word these days – would still be intact.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experts press ministers to publish mass event pilot findings for England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/no-10-says-mass-event-pilot-findings-for-england-will-be-published-shortly</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/no-10-says-mass-event-pilot-findings-for-england-will-be-published-shortly"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists advising the government say they are frustrated at the delay in making the research public

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Scientists advising the government on research into pilot mass events such as concerts and sports matches are frustrated at the delay in making the findings public and have been pressing for them to be released, the Guardian has learned.
Some of the events, which have included the Download music festival, the snooker world championships and a club night in Liverpool, took place as long ago as April and government sources say the results have been encouraging.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears and her battle for freedom: what we know so far – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears has spoken out publicly for the first time against the controversial legal arrangement that has stripped her of independence for 13 years – and handed control of her estate, career and aspects of her personal life to her father, Jamie Spears, who also at times had authority over her medical and mental health treatment. 

The 39-year-old delivered an emotional speech to a Los Angeles court on Wednesday 23 June, saying she has been forced to work against her will, and that the conservatorship has blocked her from getting married and from having her IUD birth control removed so she could try to have another child. She added: 'I just want my life back.'
Her allegations were detailed and disturbing, and will fuel the growing #FreeBritney movement, as Guardian US correspondent Sam Levin explains.

‘Denied a baby’: key claims from Britney Spears testimony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arsenal confident of signing Brighton’s Ben White in deal worth up to £50m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/arsenal-confident-of-signing-brightons-ben-white-in-deal-worth-up-to-50m</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/arsenal-confident-of-signing-brightons-ben-white-in-deal-worth-up-to-50m"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:27:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arsenal offer initial £45m plus add-ons for defender
Club had £40m bid turned down for England player

Arsenal are confident of signing Ben White from Brighton in the next few days after offering a deal worth up to £50m for the England defender. 
Arsenal had an initial £40m bid turned down this month, with Brighton indicating they wanted a guaranteed £50m for the 23-year-old. But the London club, who have agreed personal terms with White, hope their offer of an initial £45m plus £5m in add-ons can persuade Brighton to sell.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Aarons and Fabrizio Romano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fossilised bones found in Israel could belong to mystery extinct humans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/24/fossilised-bones-found-in-israel-could-belong-to-extinct-humans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/24/fossilised-bones-found-in-israel-could-belong-to-extinct-humans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:27:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remains with combination of Neanderthal and early human features date back 100,000 years
Fossilised bones recovered from an ancient sinkhole in Israel may belong to a previously unknown group of extinct humans that lived in the Levant more than 100,000 years ago.
Researchers unearthed the bones alongside stone tools and the remains of horses, fallow deer and wild ox during excavations at the Nesher Ramla prehistoric site near the city of Ramla in central Israel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billionaire Peter Thiel amasses $5bn tax-free nest egg in retirement account]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/billionaire-peter-thiel-5bn-tax-free-savings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/billionaire-peter-thiel-5bn-tax-free-savings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:22:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[•  ProPublica reveals files on other billionaires’ tax-free savings
• Roth IRAs were originally intended for middle-class Americans
Billionaire Peter Thiel, one of the founders of PayPal, has used a retirement account designed to help ordinary Americans save for their golden years to amass a $5bn tax-free nest egg, according to records obtained by ProPublica.
Thiel, a vocal opponent of higher taxes, is one of a number of ultra-rich Americans to use a Roth individual retirement account (IRA) to amass a tax-free fortune.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greek Orthodox church on defensive after acid attack on bishops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/greek-orthodox-church-on-defensive-after-acid-attack-on-bishops</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/greek-orthodox-church-on-defensive-after-acid-attack-on-bishops"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:12:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Questions over how attack could have occurred in Athens building where church’s governing body meets
The Greek Orthodox church has been put on the defensive after a priest was accused of an acid attack that injured 10 people, including seven senior bishops.
Three bishops remained in hospital on Thursday, with one reportedly undergoing plastic surgery, while the suspect was due to appear before a public prosecutor. Two lawyers and a police officer were also injured in Wednesday’s attack. Most had burns on their face and hands. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Grenfell management chief ‘kept board in dark’ over safety issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/former-grenfell-management-chief-kept-board-in-dark-over-safety-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/former-grenfell-management-chief-kept-board-in-dark-over-safety-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:08:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public inquiry into June 2017 disaster hears that Robert Black failed to mention numerous risks and problems following review
The former boss of Grenfell Tower’s management body repeatedly failed to alert residents and councillors overseeing its work to serious fire safety issues and has admitted to “keeping the board in the dark”.
Robert Black, who was chief executive of the Kensington and Chelsea Tenant Management Organisation (KCTMO) at the time of the fire, did not tell boards at the council and the arm’s-length management body about problems with smoke extractors at Grenfell, a deficiency notice issued by London fire brigade on the tower, or problems with fire doors at another block that suffered a fire.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11: Microsoft revamps start menu and adds Android apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/windows-11-microsoft-revamps-start-menu-and-adds-android-apps</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/windows-11-microsoft-revamps-start-menu-and-adds-android-apps"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:52:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New version of PC software unveiled with fresh design, faster performance, longer battery life and more open store
Microsoft has unveiled Windows 11 as it seeks to modernise the world’s most popular desktop software, add Android apps and improve gaming without alienating users.
Announced during a livestream that had some technical issues, Windows 11 will replace Windows 10 and marks the biggest change to the 35-year-old operating system since 2015.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ofsted boss warns ‘militant’ activism in schools is a threat to education]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/24/ofsted-boss-warns-militant-activism-in-schools-is-a-threat-to-education</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/24/ofsted-boss-warns-militant-activism-in-schools-is-a-threat-to-education"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:44:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amanda Spielman says disputes over issues are leading to abuse of children and teachers
The head of the schools watchdog in England has denounced a “militant” new brand of activism in school communities, which she warned was leading to confrontation within and outside the school gates and having a potentially limiting effect on education.
Ofsted’s chief inspector, Amanda Spielman, raised concerns not only about recent parent and community protests, which have led to children having to cross picket lines to get to school, but also a rise in pupil activism on issues such as racism, climate change and recent developments in the Middle East.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Northern Ireland: Boris Johnson isn’t bothered | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/the-guardian-view-on-northern-ireland-boris-johnson-isnt-bothered</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/the-guardian-view-on-northern-ireland-boris-johnson-isnt-bothered"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:29:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Jeffrey Donaldson may try to steer unionist opinion away from scrapping the protocol. But the UK government does not care
The past eight weeks have rocked Northern Ireland’s Democratic Unionist party to its core, perhaps terminally. So it is not surprising that most of the DUP has reacted to the unopposed election of Sir Jeffrey Donaldson as the party’s third leader since Easter with something like exhausted relief. Sir Jeffrey will be confirmed as leader on Saturday, but he is already benefiting from a general sense that the recent period of fevered inner-party turmoil, in which Arlene Foster and Edwin Poots were each removed in short order as DUP leaders, could not be permitted to continue.
Feelings remain very high, however, and it is possible that Sir Jeffrey’s expected move against Northern Ireland’s first minister, Paul Givan, a Poots nominee, may rekindle the DUP civil war. It may therefore prove less bothersome if Mr Givan, installed only last week in a manoeuvre that backfired spectacularly on Mr Poots, stays on for a while, until Sir Jeffrey can join the Northern Ireland assembly and take over. That depends on how Mr Givan and his more fundamentalist wing of the party created by Ian Paisley in 1971 respond. A bitter radio interview by Mr Poots this week suggests wounds are deep.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Hong Kong’s Apple Daily: gone but not forgotten | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/the-guardian-view-on-hong-kongs-apple-daily-gone-but-not-forgotten</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/the-guardian-view-on-hong-kongs-apple-daily-gone-but-not-forgotten"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:29:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outspoken tabloid’s closure is a chilling moment. But as Beijing silences dissent, the spirit of resistance endures
Apple Daily is dead. At midnight on Wednesday, Hong Kong’s biggest pro-democracy news outlet closed, forced out of business after authorities froze the assets of the 26-year-old tabloid and arrested executives and journalists. Through its outspoken support for protests, it had come to stand for resistance itself: for the freedom to know what is happening, to challenge authorities, and to imagine and demand another Hong Kong.
Beijing is determined to crush that resistance. Each day it turns the screws further. Many have fallen silent already, but Apple Daily was defiant. Its owner, Jimmy Lai, already jailed over a protest, could face life in prison due to further charges under the draconian national security law. The editor-in-chief and chief executive of its parent company have been charged with conspiracy to collude with “external elements” after 500 officers raided its headquarters last week. Authorities say that the case relates to articles calling for sanctions on the Hong Kong and Chinese governments, some published before the imposition of the security law, which is not supposed to be retroactive. This vindictive action marks the criminalisation of journalism. On Wednesday, the company announced it was closing overnight, citing employee safety and staffing levels after officers arrested its lead opinion writer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rudy Giuliani barred from practicing law in New York over election lies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/rudy-giuliani-law-license-new-york-suspended</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/rudy-giuliani-law-license-new-york-suspended"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:16:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Court: Trump lawyer made  ‘false and misleading’ statements
• License suspended pending possible disciplinary action
Rudy Giuliani is suspended from practicing law in New York state following disciplinary proceedings over his misleading statements to courts and the public following the 2020 US presidential election.
The New York supreme court issued its decision on Thursday, saying that it had found “uncontroverted evidence” that Giuliani made “demonstrably false and misleading statements to courts, lawmakers and the public at large”, on behalf of his client, then-president Donald Trump, and created a “narrative that due to widespread voter fraud, victory in the 2020 United States presidential election was stolen from his client”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Betancourt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ineos Grenadiers put faith in numbers at Tour de France as Pogacar threat looms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/ineos-grenadiers-faith-in-numbers-tour-de-france-as-pogacar-threat-looms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/ineos-grenadiers-faith-in-numbers-tour-de-france-as-pogacar-threat-looms"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:08:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ineos rider Richie Porte acknowledges threat of 2020 winner
British team have strong lineup but uncertainty over leader

Although 184 riders will roll away from the Tour de France start line in Brest on Saturday, there are in fact fewer than a dozen contenders for victory in Paris on 18 July. The problem for most, though, is they do not ride for Ineos Grenadiers. 
After a poor Tour in 2020, the British team again look like holding all the cards, with four riders – Geraint Thomas, Richard Carapaz, Tao Geoghegan Hart and Richie Porte – all capable of playing a leadership role. The problem for Ineos Grenadiers, however, is that they have not hired the most exciting young rider in the sport.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Whittle in Brest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[£2,104.18: tourists charged by date for rides on Brighton Palace Pier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/210418-tourists-charged-by-the-date-for-rides-on-brighton-palace-pier</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/210418-tourists-charged-by-the-date-for-rides-on-brighton-palace-pier"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:06:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worldpay apologises for error affecting debit card users on 18 April at seaside attraction in England
One of England’s most popular tourist attractions has apologised after hundreds of visitors to Brighton Palace Pier were overcharged for fairground rides to the tune of thousands of pounds.
The pier – which is largely cashless – blamed the fiasco on the processing company Worldpay, which it said had used the date of the transaction instead of the actual amount in each case.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn and Nigel Bunyan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Common React Mistakes You Might Be Making – And How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>60d3ee396e1a1407b6b0b6ef</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/common-react-mistakes-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go over the most common mistakes you might be making in your React code right now, plus how to fix them. If you want to create amazing React applications, it's essential to avoid many common errors along the way. In this article, we'll not only cover how to fix]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain imposes one-year ban on shooting of at-risk turtle dove]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/24/spain-imposes-one-year-ban-on-shooting-of-at-risk-turtle-dove</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/24/spain-imposes-one-year-ban-on-shooting-of-at-risk-turtle-dove"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:57:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Population of threatened bird in western Europe could increase by 5% if hunting stopped
Nearly 1 million migrating turtle doves will be spared after Spanish authorities agreed a one-year ban on the shooting of the bird.
The turtle dove is a globally threatened species and is Britain’s most endangered breeding bird, with populations having halved in just five years and possibly fewer than 2,000 pairs left.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big events are making a nonsense of Covid rules  | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/big-events-are-making-a-nonsense-of-covid-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/big-events-are-making-a-nonsense-of-covid-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:51:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 summit had to have played a role in Cornwall’s case spike, writes Nick Jemmett. Plus letters by Brian Hatton, Richard Burtle, Jane McAdoo and Simon Routh 
Your article on the spike in Covid cases in places that were most used by G7 personnel during the summit in Cornwall (No 10 says G7 summit not to blame for rise in Cornwall’s Covid cases, 22 June) missed a major impact source: the 1,000-plus police officers housed on a cruise ship in Falmouth. They – like the other 4,000 or so police brought into the county – came from all over England and, unsurprisingly, a number of them were self-isolating on the ship after testing positive.
During the summit, off-duty officers were visible out in the town, in bars and other venues, and whereas it is assumed they adhered to Covid rules, it’s unlikely that all were Covid-free. Also, a large number of journalists were in the town. Falmouth has had one of the biggest spikes of Covid cases in Cornwall in June, and while half-term visitors and university students are a factor, the G7 must be seen as a major player in the outbreak. It’s disappointing, since Cornwall had hitherto made a huge effort in keeping Covid infection rates to among the lowest in the country. 
Nick Jemmett
Falmouth, Cornwall
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenTelemetry to Understand Software Performance]]></title>
        <id>60d4b5e96e1a1407b6b0bac4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opentelemetry/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want good performance in your application, you need to collect data to figure out where to make improvements. That's where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemetry offers a single set of APIs and libraries that standardize how you collect and transfer telemetry data. OpenTelemetry provides a specification for instrumentation so]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Channel 4 could thrive as a social enterprise | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/24/channel-4-could-thrive-as-a-social-enterprise</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/24/channel-4-could-thrive-as-a-social-enterprise"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:50:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Holbrook suggests an alternative to privatisation, while Peter Grimsdale points out that if the Tories sold off the broadcaster they would be trashing a bit of their own heritage
Following the news that the culture secretary is expected to launch a consultation into the future of Channel 4 (C4 privatisation would lead to regional cuts, broadcaster warns, 22 June), we urge the government to allow it to convert into a social enterprise. This would enable the broadcaster to maintain its independence and continue to commission programmes that serve a diverse audience, and use its profits to support independent production companies.
The UK is home to 100,000 social enterprises – businesses set up to trade for a social and environmental purpose, which reinvest the majority of their profits to further these aims. They contribute £60bn to the economy, employ 2 million people, and offer a path away from the binary choice of state ownership or privatisation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Louis Vuitton’s Virgil Abloh showcases men in dresses and skirts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/24/louis-vuittons-virgil-abloh-showcases-men-in-dresses-and-skirts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/24/louis-vuittons-virgil-abloh-showcases-men-in-dresses-and-skirts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:46:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Designer calls for an end to male and female dressing in favour of ‘human’ approach
Virgil Abloh makes the case for dresses and skirts for men in the latest Louis Vuitton collection.
The poetic film for its spring summer collection, Amen Break, features a starry cast including Saul Williams, Goldie and the Wu-Tang Clan’s GZA, plus models in pleated skirts, white dresses, miniskirts, tiered puff dresses and long dress-like coats that are cinched at the waist.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan Deputy fashion editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canada discovers 751 unmarked graves at former residential school]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/canada-school-graves-discovery-saskatchewan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/canada-school-graves-discovery-saskatchewan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:36:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Graves found at site of Marieval Indian school in Saskatchewan
Growing calls for Catholic church to confront historical role 

A First Nation in Canada’s Saskatchewan province is treating a now-defunct residential school as a “crime scene” following the discovery of 751 unmarked graves just weeks after a similar discovery in British Columbia prompted a fresh reckoning over the country’s colonial past.
Chief Cadmus Delorme of the Cowessess First Nation said that the graves were found on the site of the Marieval Indian residential school, also known as Grayson, after a search with ground-penetrating radar was launched on 2 June.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Africans ‘dangerously exposed’ by lack of Covid jabs, says WHO]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/africans-dangerously-exposed-by-lack-of-covid-jabs-says-who</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/africans-dangerously-exposed-by-lack-of-covid-jabs-says-who"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:26:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Third wave could be Africa’s worst yet, official says, with health systems in some parts close to overwhelmed

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The World Health Organization has made a new appeal for vaccines for Africa, saying a “fast-surging” third wave of Covid-19 is outpacing efforts to protect populations, “leaving more and more dangerously exposed”.
“The third wave is picking up speed, spreading faster, hitting harder. This is incredibly worrying. With rapidly rising case numbers and increasing reports of serious illness, the latest surge threatens to be Africa’s worst yet,” Dr Matshidiso Moeti, the WHO regional director for Africa, said on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke in Johannesburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winston Marshall quits Mumford & Sons after Andy Ngo controversy, citing free speech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/winston-marshall-quits-mumford-sons-citing-free-speech-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/winston-marshall-quits-mumford-sons-citing-free-speech-concerns"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:16:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guitarist and banjoist prompted backlash in March after supporting Unmasked, Andy Ngo’s book criticising the anti-fascist protest movement, antifa
Winston Marshall, guitarist-banjoist with chart-topping group Mumford & Sons, has quit the band following controversy around his support for Unmasked, a book decrying the leftist protest movement antifa.
In March, Marshall had tweeted to the book’s author, conservative journalist Andy Ngo: “Congratulations. Finally had the time to read your important book. You’re a brave man.” Following an online backlash, he apologised, and announced he would take time away from the group. “Over the past few days I have come to better understand the pain caused by the book I endorsed,” he said, adding that he would “examine my blindspots”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rodon, Bale and the dream of more famous Wales fridge magnet moments | Elis James]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/wales-denmark-euro-2020-last-16-elis-james-joe-rodon-gareth-bale</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/24/wales-denmark-euro-2020-last-16-elis-james-joe-rodon-gareth-bale"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The achievement of reaching the last 16 must not be played down – this is a team who continue to find a way
I have lots of fridge magnets commemorating Euro 2016, which renew my vigour as I replace my son’s Petit Filous because he’s thrown the first one I got him against the wall. “You have lived your dream,” I think, staring at Ashley Williams acknowledging the Welsh fans in Lille, “and no one comes round because of Covid anyway, so why does it matter that we have historic yoghurt splashes on the ceiling?”
I had fallen in love with the current group of Welsh players long before the tournament began, but they are constantly creating more fridge magnet moments. Aaron Ramsey’s Italian adventure in Turin meant I’d forgotten he sticks his tongue out at moments of high excitement, if you’ve ever wondered what a gifted international footballer crossed with a picture of a Westie on a tin of shortbread would look like.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elis James</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyclist fatalities on British roads rose by 40% in 2020, says DfT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/cyclists-killed-on-british-roads-rose-by-40-in-2020-official-figures-show</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/cyclists-killed-on-british-roads-rose-by-40-in-2020-official-figures-show"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:58:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AA says increase revealed in official figures is ‘staggering’, as cycling groups blame dangerous driving
The number of cyclists killed on British roads increased by 40% in 2020, official statistics show, with cycling groups saying an increase in dangerous driving could have cancelled out the safety dividend from fewer cars on the roads amid lockdown.
In total, 140 cyclists were killed on the roads over the 12 months, up from 100 the year before, an increase the AA called “staggering”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colbert on Republicans blocking voting rights bill: ‘A lot of stupid explanations’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/24/stephen-colbert-republican-opposition-to-voting-rights-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/24/stephen-colbert-republican-opposition-to-voting-rights-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:53:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hosts discuss the GOP’s refusal to back Biden’s landmark voting rights measure and Trump’s dwindling inner circle
Stephen Colbert discussed the failure of the Biden administration landmark voting rights bill to pass a procedural vote on Tuesday, as the For the People Act was left stranded in a 50-50 stalemate along party lines. “Republicans instead supported the ‘For Some of the People – We Can’t Say It Out Loud But You Know Which Ones We Mean Act,’” Colbert joked.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Horton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EE reintroduces roaming charges for UK users in Europe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/ee-reintroduces-roaming-charges-for-uk-users-in-europe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/ee-reintroduces-roaming-charges-for-uk-users-in-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:49:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mobile phone operator is the first to bring back the charge since the start of Brexit trade deal
The BT-owned mobile operator EE is to start charging UK customers to use their phones in Europe, having previously said it had no plans to reintroduce roaming costs after the Brexit trade deal struck at Christmas.
New EE customers or those upgrading after mid-July will have to pay £2 a day when they use their phones in 47 European countries from January. EE is the first UK operator to officially reintroduce roaming charges, although O2 has said it will impose an extra “fair use” charge if customers use more than 25GB of data in a month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five years on, we finally know what Brexit means: a worse deal for everyone | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/five-years-brexit-calamity-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/five-years-brexit-calamity-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:32:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On trade, finance, migration, food standards and more, the UK suffers fresh ignominy on a daily basis
Five years ago today, in the early hours, Britain discovered what it had done – and what had been done to it by the liars, charlatans and rogues who mis-sold Brexit as “taking back control”. The wound is as fresh as ever. Breaking apart political parties and reversing erstwhile red or blue wall seats is a minor matter, but Brexit’s explosive division of the country by social class, geography and a deep sense of personal identity is a lasting injury.
Few have changed their mind: though polls put remain (or return) ahead by a nose, no one wants to be put through that hell again. Brexit is done for the foreseeable future, though a government thriving on national disunity strives to keep it alive with infantile culture wars and “anti-woke” phoney patriotism. Polls give the Conservatives a 14-point lead, as they head into next week’s Batley and Spen byelection. No surprise, for what party in power could dream of a better boast than this: the vaccines are genuinely bestowing the gift of staying alive on every single citizen. And Britain is out ahead of other European countries: pollsters tell me voters sincerely (though unjustly) believe that had we remained in the EU, we couldn’t have had our own programme. Despite EU vaccinators catching up, and the UK having more people dead and more debt than they do, Covid is still a convenient cover.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stars and fans rally behind Britney Spears after shocking claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/stars-and-fans-rally-behind-britney-spears-after-shocking-testimony</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/stars-and-fans-rally-behind-britney-spears-after-shocking-testimony"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:23:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Justin Timberlake and Rose McGowan among those calling for end to singer’s conservatorship
There was tentative anticipation surrounding Britney Spears’ address to an LA court during a hearing on Wednesday on the future of the conservatorship that has governed her life for 13 years.
Would she affirm the theories of the #FreeBritney movement, which alleges she is being held against her will? Or would it be a disappointing procedural affair of little substance?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Snapes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinosaurs lived in the Arctic, research suggests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/24/dinosaur-fossils-eggs-arctic-research</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/24/dinosaur-fossils-eggs-arctic-research"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:13:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of tiny fossils indicates dinosaurs raised young in freezing region – and may have been warm-blooded
It had long stretches of winter darkness, freezing temperatures and often scarce resources, but an array of tiny fossils suggests dinosaurs not only roamed the Arctic, but hatched and raised their young there too.
While dinosaur fossils have previously been found in the Arctic, it was unclear whether they lived there year-round or were seasonal visitors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science Correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One woman dead and 430 affected by Scotland cervical cancer screening error]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/24/one-woman-dead-and-430-affected-by-scotland-cervical-cancer-screening-error</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/24/one-woman-dead-and-430-affected-by-scotland-cervical-cancer-screening-error"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:01:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish public health minister says women were wrongly told they did not need to be screened for cervical cancer
A woman in Scotland has died from cervical cancer after more than 400 women were wrongly told they did not need to be screened.
Maree Todd, the Scottish public health minister, said a “serious adverse event” in a cervical cancer screening programme meant at least 430 women were not tested. Of those, a small number later developed cervical cancer, and one had since died.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell Scotland editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After 16 years of Merkel, EU summit could mark end of an era]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/after-16-years-of-angela-merkel-eu-summit-could-mark-end-of-an-era</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/after-16-years-of-angela-merkel-eu-summit-could-mark-end-of-an-era"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Outgoing German chancellor attended her first summit in 2005 with likes of Tony Blair and Jacques Chirac
When Angela Merkel attended her first EU summit in December 2005, her fellow leaders included Tony Blair and Jacques Chirac. It was a different world from the one that exists now as she attends what could be her last.
Europe’s divisions over the Iraq war were still raw. Blair was running the European Council, as the British held the EU’s rotating presidency. During the summit, the UK brokered a deal on the EU budget that cut the British rebate to pay for enlargement into central and eastern Europe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jennifer Rankin in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen meets Boris Johnson in person again with weary resignation | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/the-queen-meets-boris-johnson-in-person-again-with-weary-resignation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/the-queen-meets-boris-johnson-in-person-again-with-weary-resignation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:45:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why could they not carry on having their weekly meetings on Zoom, the monarch wondered
There was a knock on the door. “Come in,” said the Queen, her heart sinking. It was the moment she had been dreading. Why on earth couldn’t she have carried on her weekly meetings with the prime minister on Zoom?
Not having to deal with Boris Johnson face to face had been one of the few upsides of the coronavirus lockdown. She couldn’t stand the way he put his feet up on the furniture and generally acted as if he owned the place. There was only so much entitlement a Queen could take.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘They thought we were terrorists’: meet Joe Rush, the master of mutoid art and king of Glastonbury]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/joe-rush-i-am-a-mutoid-mutoid-waste-company-glastonbury-g7-mount-recyclemore</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/joe-rush-i-am-a-mutoid-mutoid-waste-company-glastonbury-g7-mount-recyclemore"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:39:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The punky master of outsider art was once a pariah, thrown out of Britain for his anarchist ways. Now, he’s a national treasure. Joe Rush relives 40 years of sticking it to the ‘straight world’
“They thought we were terrorists,” says Joe Rush, remembering the day not long after the fall of the Berlin Wall when he and a fellow anarchist took over a patch of no man’s land at the heart of the German capital. They filled it with military hardware: tanks and artillery and the like – along with a MiG-21 fighter jet that they pointed directly at the nearby Reichstag.
“The authorities were furious,” he says. And no wonder. The police feared that, just as the cold war was ending, another military face-off had begun. “They thought we were going to fire missiles into the Reichstag,” says Rush. “So we pointed the MiG into the ground to make it clear we weren’t.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amnesty: ‘catalogue of violations’ by Israeli police against Palestinians]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/amnesty-catalogue-of-violations-by-israeli-police-against-palestinians</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/amnesty-catalogue-of-violations-by-israeli-police-against-palestinians"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:36:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Palestinians face repression from Israel and Palestinian Authority, human rights watchdog says
The latest flare-up of violence in the Gaza Strip has been accompanied by a “catalogue of violations” committed by Israeli police against Palestinians in Israel and occupied East Jerusalem, according to research from Amnesty International.
Arab citizens of Israel have been subjected to unlawful force from officers during peaceful demonstrations, sweeping mass arrests, torture and other ill-treatment in detention, and police have failed to protect Palestinians from premeditated attacks by rightwing Jewish extremists, the human rights watchdog said on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HS2 asks government to help it deal with rising number of protests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/hs2-asks-government-help-rising-number-protests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/hs2-asks-government-help-rising-number-protests"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:33:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boss of high-speed rail line says it is struggling to counter direct action that has cost £75m to date
HS2 has sought support from across government to counter a growing number of protests, as the boss of the high-speed rail project said it was struggling to deal with direct action that had cost it £75m to date.
Mark Thurston, the chief executive of HS2, said “violent and disruptive” protests were spreading north and he had urged ministers to use “all the agencies of government” to help it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 9: Community]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342818</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/chapter-9-community/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April of 2009, Yahoo! shut down GeoCities. Practically overnight, the once beloved service had its signup page replaced with a vague message announcing its closure.
We have decided to discontinue the process of allowing new customers to sign up 
…
The post Chapter 9: Community appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Hoffmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lewis Hamilton fears allowing 140,000 fans at F1 British GP is ‘premature’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/british-grand-prix-to-take-place-in-front-of-140000-crowd-at-silverstone</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/british-grand-prix-to-take-place-in-front-of-140000-crowd-at-silverstone"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:26:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[F1 champion concerned over Silverstone’s return to full capacity
Race takes place day before end of England’s Covid restrictions

Lewis Hamilton has expressed grave concern at the announcement that the British Grand Prix will host more than 140,000 spectators this year. The Formula One world champion believes the decision to allow a full-capacity crowd at Silverstone may be premature given the recent rise in Covid cases across the UK, fears British racing fans may be being used as test cases and has questioned the confusing messages coming from the government.
Silverstone confirmed on Thursday that it had got the green light for approximately 141,000 fans to watch the British GP, paving the way for the biggest UK crowd since the start of the pandemic. The grand prix takes place just one day before the mooted end of coronavirus restrictions in England on 19 July, and Silverstone officials will be allowed to sell out for the entire 16-18 July weekend.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards at Spielberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The advertising industry sold us the perfect woman – do we finally understand the price we paid?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/the-advertising-industry-sold-us-the-perfect-woman-do-we-finally-understand-the-price-we-paid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/the-advertising-industry-sold-us-the-perfect-woman-do-we-finally-understand-the-price-we-paid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For decades, marketing left women feeling they must live up to punishing ideals. Now, finally, some brands are offering a glimmer of hope
When Billie Eilish appeared on the cover of Vogue’s June edition sporting a corset and a magnificent set of platinum blond curls, staring into camera and daring anyone to object, it felt properly shocking. Many on social media berated her, vigorously and unforgivingly, for “selling out”. Eilish was unfazed. She is, she said, an adult. She has every right to dress as she prefers. And at that moment, she preferred a corset.
She was, in effect, claiming her womanhood, her adulthood, her right to present herself in any way that makes her feel good. She was growing up, not giving in.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jane Cunningham and Philippa Roberts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Murdoch seeks to remove editorial independence rules at the Times]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/jun/24/rupert-murdoch-seeks-to-remove-editorial-independence-rules-at-the-times</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/jun/24/rupert-murdoch-seeks-to-remove-editorial-independence-rules-at-the-times"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:17:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[News UK asks government to scrap legal curbs at Times and Sunday Times, paving way for full-blown merger
Rupert Murdoch has asked the government to abolish the legal restraints on him interfering in the editorial independence of the Times and the Sunday Times that were put in place when he first bought the newspapers.
At the moment the two newspapers are required to have largely separate editorial teams, while Murdoch nominally has to answer to a group of independent directors on key editorial matters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britain acknowledges surprise at speed of Russian reaction to warship]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/british-warships-might-enter-crimean-waters-again-says-minister</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/british-warships-might-enter-crimean-waters-again-says-minister"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:06:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kremlin summons UK ambassador as Boris Johnson says HMS Defender’s deployment ‘wholly appropriate’
British officials acknowledged they were taken by surprise by the speed of the Russian reaction to HMS Defender’s 36-minute passage through Crimean waters on Wednesday as the British ambassador to Moscow was summoned to the Kremlin.
Although a Russian response to the Royal Navy warship’s passage within the 12-mile territorial limit was anticipated, the UK Ministry of Defence did not expect the Kremlin to speedily declare that warning shots had been fired.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh in London and Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dalian Atkinson: jury discharged after failing to reach verdict on second PC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/dalian-atkinson-jury-discharged-failing-reach-verdict-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/dalian-atkinson-jury-discharged-failing-reach-verdict-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:03:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PC Mary Ellen Bettley-Smith was accused of assaulting the former footballer with a baton
A jury has been discharged following its failure to reach a verdict on allegations that a police officer assaulted the former footballer Dalian Atkinson with a baton after he was felled by a stun gun on the night he died.
The case against Mary Ellen Bettley-Smith, a West Mercia probationary constable, ended with a hung jury a day after PC Benjamin Monk was convicted of manslaughter and told he would face an inevitable prison term.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rise Of Design Thinking As A Problem Solving Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the dynamic and unpredictable environments in which we work, even the most carefully crafted solutions can have a short shelf life. When we accept that our work is impermanent and our problem-solving abilities are limited, our goal can shift from delivering full solutions to developing tools that empower our users to adaptively design for themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Josh Singer)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top insurers join Prince Charles to fight climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/top-insurers-join-prince-charles-to-fight-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/top-insurers-join-prince-charles-to-fight-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taskforce led by Lloyd’s of London plans to expand coverage of greener projects and help countries facing extreme risk
Chief executives from the UK’s largest insurers have joined forces with the Prince of Wales to launch a sector-wide taskforce aimed at tackling the climate crisis.
The Sustainable Market Initiative Insurance Taskforce – comprising bosses from 17 firms including Legal & General, Allianz, Hiscox and Axa – has pledged to support the transition to a less carbon-intensive economy by expanding insurance coverage for projects such as offshore windfarms, and partnering with governments to provide better disaster protection cover in countries facing serious risks like extreme weather caused by global heating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Something had gone horribly wrong’: me, Mick Jagger and the lost autobiography]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/something-had-gone-horribly-wrong-me-mick-jagger-and-the-lost-autobiography</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/something-had-gone-horribly-wrong-me-mick-jagger-and-the-lost-autobiography"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:13:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ghostwriter Barry Coleman says he was given two ‘awful’ weeks to finish an entire book with the Rolling Stone – then the singer pulled the plug in case it was too dull 
Barry Coleman still remembers the day in 1983 when he was called by his editor at the publisher Weidenfeld & Nicolson and told: “We’ve got a problem. Can you come in … tomorrow?”
“The urgency was a bit disorienting,” he recalls. “Something had clearly gone horribly wrong.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Simpson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: has your garden been improved in the last year?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/tell-us-has-your-garden-been-improved-in-the-last-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/tell-us-has-your-garden-been-improved-in-the-last-year"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:08:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to see your garden upgrades: everything from garden bars, to hot tubs, to amazing plants 
Has something amazing happened to your garden in the past year? As part of our How to Live Now series, we’re keen to hear about (and see photos of) everything from your garden bars, to hot tubs, to amazing plants – anything that has given your garden an upgrade lately.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When a child is born: the film lifting the lid on surrogacy, race and disability]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/24/when-a-child-is-born-the-film-lifting-the-lid-on-surrogacy-race-and-disability</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/24/when-a-child-is-born-the-film-lifting-the-lid-on-surrogacy-race-and-disability"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writer-director Jeremy Hersh and his newcomer star Jasmine Batchelor hope their new film, The Surrogate, will provoke awkward questions
There are two films called The Surrogate. The first is a made-for-TV movie about an obsessive fan who cons her way into a writer’s life by carrying their baby.
“I’ve seen that movie,” says the director Jeremy Hersh, pulling a face. “I hope no one settles on that looking for this. It’s basically anti-women. The implication is that surrogates are crazy and calculating and out to steal some poor woman’s husband.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cath Clarke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selling off Channel 4 is a terrible idea. Here’s a better one | Phil Redmond]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/selling-off-channel-4-terrible-idea-merge-with-bbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/selling-off-channel-4-terrible-idea-merge-with-bbc"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, it’s time for a change – so why not merge the channel with the BBC to turbo-charge public service broadcasting?
So, here we go again. Another review of public service broadcasting and another round of soul searching about whether to privatise Channel 4. It’s a bit like reviewing supermarkets and deciding to spin out the flowers.
 Related: Channel 4 privatisation proposal: ‘This could prove irreversible’  
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phil Redmond</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experiences of staying in a Covid quarantine hotel in the UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/26/have-you-spent-time-in-a-covid-quarantine-hotel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/26/have-you-spent-time-in-a-covid-quarantine-hotel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T12:48:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from travellers who have had to stay in a quarantine hotel in the UK 
Quarantine rules for travellers to the UK have been in place since January. One of the measures saw the introduction of quarantine hotels for people arriving to the country.
We’d like understand what it’s like to spend time in a ‘Covid hotel’ in the UK. How are you finding the conditions in the hotel you’re staying at? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beach acrobatics and an opera festival: Thursday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/24/beach-acrobatics-and-an-opera-festival-thursdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/24/beach-acrobatics-and-an-opera-festival-thursdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T12:36:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Johnson warns Lions: ‘People are looking for reasons to send you off’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/martin-johnson-lions-muck-in-enjoy-it-its-history-very-quick-south-africa-rugby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/24/martin-johnson-lions-muck-in-enjoy-it-its-history-very-quick-south-africa-rugby"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T12:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Lions captain, who won in South Africa in 1997, wants series to be decided by players, not red cards for high tackles
Can it really be 20 years since Martin Johnson last led a British & Irish Lions side into battle? Listening to him even now is to be reminded that great Lions never entirely hang up their body armour. “The main things don’t change, do they?” says the last Lions captain to win a Test series in South Africa, in 1997.
“You’ve got a team of people who have to come together, find a common purpose and use that as motivation to overcome adversity. Everyone talks about the honour of it. The reality is that it’s a tough thing to do.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s how a progressive alliance would actually work | Neal Lawson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/how-progressive-alliance-tory-britain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/how-progressive-alliance-tory-britain"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T12:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have two years to create a coherent approach that appeals to non-Tory voters, who are the majority in Britain today
After the crushing 2019 general election defeat, the historic byelection loss in Hartlepool for Labour and the spectacular win for the Liberal Democrats in Chesham and Amersham, the idea of a “progressive alliance” is firmly in the political ether. But what is a progressive alliance, and how can it best work?
We start with the “why” of an alliance. The driving reason is political. The critical alliance is not one of parties or voters, but minds and then actions. The societal challenges we face; of climate, culture, care, technology, ageing and inequality simply can no longer be met by any single party. If we want a red, green and liberal future we need to meld the politics of these essential strands into a coherent and consistent political project, with urgency because the march of national populism wants to strip democracy of its power to deliver the hope of this good society.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Neal Lawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oil and gas donors gave over £400k to Tories before North Sea decision]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/oil-gas-donors-gave-over-400k-tories-before-north-sea-decision</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/24/oil-gas-donors-gave-over-400k-tories-before-north-sea-decision"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:47:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: payments in past year came as government decided on licences for new fossil fuel sites
Individuals and companies linked to the oil and gas industries have donated more than £400,000 to the Conservative party in the past year, while the government mulled controversial new licences to explore the North Sea for fossil fuel production sites, it can be revealed.
Disclosures from last July to the end of March, the latest date for which data is available, show at least £419,000 was given to the Conservatives by donors with a strong interest in oil and gas, including in the North Sea, research by the environmental investigations group DeSmog and the Guardian has found.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anton Du Beke waltzes in to become Strictly Come Dancing judge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/anton-du-beke-waltzes-in-to-become-strictly-come-dancing-judge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/24/anton-du-beke-waltzes-in-to-become-strictly-come-dancing-judge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:38:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Previous incumbent Bruno Tonioli had to pull out because of Covid-related travel restrictions
Anton Du Beke has been confirmed as a judge for the new series of Strictly Come Dancing, replacing Bruno Tonioli.
Tonioli, who has been a fixture on the show since 2004, is being replaced as he cannot fly over from the US, where he is based as a judge on Dancing with the Stars, because of Covid travel restrictions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Julian Opie review – we need so much more from art than this empty irony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/24/julian-opie-review-pitzhanger-manor-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/24/julian-opie-review-pitzhanger-manor-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:27:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pitzhanger Manor, London
Staged in Sir John Soane’s Ealing mansion, Opie’s brand of dot-eyed simplicity – epitomised here by a sterile model town showpiece – is stuck in the 90s

A Julian Opie woman is striding towards the facade of Sir John Soane’s mansion in Ealing. This animated, larger-than-life figure in the forecourt is a flat sculpture for the digital age, flickering in white lines on a black screen mounted on a plinth. If you don’t know what I mean by a Julian Opie woman, she’s a line drawing in profile of someone in the street, stylish and contemporary. Other women in the show look at phones or tote bags in similarly simplified delineations.
I couldn’t help wondering what happens when she reaches the house. Will she bump her head? Or will the structure crumble into ruins under the impact of the 21st century? For Opie’s exhibition at Soane’s Pitzhanger Manor is not so much an encounter between new and old as a car crash in which a high-end motor smashes into a centuries-old yew tree.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cut-down conifer becomes Sheffield attraction after neighbour dispute]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/cut-down-fir-tree-becomes-sheffield-attraction-after-neighbour-dispute</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/24/cut-down-fir-tree-becomes-sheffield-attraction-after-neighbour-dispute"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:08:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Row over roosting birds making noise and mess in drive of bungalow results in tree surgeon job
A tree cleaved in half has become an attraction in a residential part of South Yorkshire after a dispute between neighbours.
Bharat Mistry said he and his family were “gutted” when their next-door neighbours asked tree surgeons to cut down half the branches of a 5 metre conifer tree that had stood in his garden in the Sheffield suburb of Waterthorpe for 25 years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Your body just stops’: long Covid sufferers face new ordeals as sick pay runs out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/your-body-just-stops-long-covid-sufferers-face-new-ordeals-as-sick-pay-runs-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/your-body-just-stops-long-covid-sufferers-face-new-ordeals-as-sick-pay-runs-out"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nurses, teachers and shopworkers who have lost their health and their jobs talk about their struggle for support

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage


Working seven days a week as a nurse and a fitness instructor, while bringing up two young daughters, Rebecca Logan led an extremely active life – until she contracted Covid-19 while working in the emergency department of a hospital in Northern Ireland.
Over a year after first falling ill, the 40-year-old is still suffering from long Covid. For Logan, that means she can only walk for five minutes before needing to rest, and there is a constant ringing in her ears. Her husband has had to pick up the slack at home, alongside his job as a school principal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Doors’ greatest songs – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/the-doors-greatest-songs-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/24/the-doors-greatest-songs-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:02:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the 50th anniversary of singer Jim Morrison’s death, we rank the LA band’s best tracks, from the summer of love anthem Light My Fire to the apocalyptic The End
Jim Morrison frequently drew on his romantic dalliances for lyrical inspiration. Take Morrison Hotel’s raucous rocker Queen of the Highway, a song about his soon-to-be-wife, Pamela Courson, that frames their relationship as loving, if somewhat ill-fated: “He was a monster / Black dressed in leather / She was a princess / Queen of the Highway.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annie Zaleski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[June design news: ice cream, guitar straps and Lego]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/june-design-news-ice-cream-guitar-straps-and-lego</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/june-design-news-ice-cream-guitar-straps-and-lego"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T10:48:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inclusive design, abstract expressionist ceramics and the recycled lifejackets helping refugees start afresh 

Using design to shape the world so that it’s accessible and welcoming is a great achievement. This month’s design news celebrates projects that aim to do just that, from artist Annie Nicholson’s mental health support and ice cream project Fandangoe Whip to the biannual Index Prize shortlist which has a real focus on inclusive products. Special mention goes to social enterprise Love Welcomes, an organisation which brings craft skills, legal and business advice to women living in refugee camps. The Edge from U2 has designed a guitar strap for sale as part of their range.
To receive more stories about art, architecture, design and sustainable living, sign up to the monthly Design Newsletter here
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulva decor: is Cara Delevingne’s vagina tunnel the start of something big?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/vulva-decor-is-cara-delevingnes-vagina-tunnel-the-start-of-something-big</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/vulva-decor-is-cara-delevingnes-vagina-tunnel-the-start-of-something-big"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T10:11:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The model and actor has a new household installation - a pink tunnel where she goes to think. Vulval art and design has an ancient history, but it’s becoming more popular than ever
Should you swap all your doors for a vagina tunnel? This is the pressing question raised by a video tour from the model and actor Cara Delevingne, who takes Architectural Digest around her LA home, and I believe the answer has to be “yes”. In her living room, a secret door in the mirrored panelling reveals a soft pink opening. Crawl right in, take the dog with you (Delevingne does). “I come in here to think, I come in here to create, I feel inspired in the vagina tunnel,” says Delevingne.
Delevingne, and her architect, Nicolò Bini, were inspired, she says repeatedly, by Alice in Wonderland, but this is more like a vulval version of the Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe – the Chronicles of Labia, if you like. You climb out through a washing machine at the other end – “rebirthed and cleansed!” cries our host. The vagina’s rebirth powers are strong: Delevingne’s terrier goes in, and comes out a husky. The theme continues through the rest of the house: there is a floral display in her bedroom (“This lovely bouquet of vagina flowers”) and a “pussy palace”, a tactile pink suedette-lined secret room complete with swing and mirrored ceiling.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emine Saner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Someone old, someone new, someone borrowed, someone blue – take the Thursday quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T10:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia plus a few jokes every Thursday – how will you fare?
Thursday lunchtime? Check. Fifteen questions? Check. General knowledge and topical news trivia with a few jokes and some weird facts along the way? Check. It must be the Thursday quiz! It’s just for fun and there are no prizes, but there are bonus points on offer if you can make the quizmaster laugh in the comments below. Let us know how you get on.
The Thursday quiz, No 9
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Now I can look busy while doing nothing’: what Guardian readers learned from their summer jobs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/24/now-i-can-look-busy-while-doing-nothing-what-guardian-readers-learned-from-their-summer-jobs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/24/now-i-can-look-busy-while-doing-nothing-what-guardian-readers-learned-from-their-summer-jobs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T10:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you’re scrubbing dishes in a restaurant or picking up stones on a golf course, there’s nothing as educational as holiday work
Rhianna Lindsay-Nieto, product manager, London
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mystery of the wheelie suitcase: how gender stereotypes held back the history of invention]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/mystery-of-wheelie-suitcase-how-gender-stereotypes-held-back-history-of-invention</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/mystery-of-wheelie-suitcase-how-gender-stereotypes-held-back-history-of-invention"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why have some brilliant innovations – from rolling luggage to electric cars – taken so long to come to market? Macho culture has a lot to answer for
In 1972 an American luggage executive unscrewed four castors from a wardrobe and fixed them to a suitcase. Then he put a strap on his contraption and trotted it gleefully around his house.
This was how Bernard Sadow invented the world’s first rolling suitcase. It happened roughly 5,000 years after the invention of the wheel and barely one year after Nasa managed to put two men on the surface of the moon using the largest rocket ever built. We had driven an electric rover with wheels on a foreign heavenly body and even invented the hamster wheel. So why did it take us so long to put wheels on suitcases? This has become something of a classic mystery of innovation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katrine Marçal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Child victims of sexual abuse ‘often accused of lying to police’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/child-victims-of-sexual-abuse-often-accused-of-lying-to-police</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/child-victims-of-sexual-abuse-often-accused-of-lying-to-police"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Officers also mismanaged cases in a way that could lead to reprisals for victims, survivors tell England and Wales inquiry
Child sex abuse victims and survivors are often accused of lying when trying to report the abuse to police, according to a report by the independent inquiry into child sexual abuse in England and Wales.
The inquiry’s team spoke to 56 victims and survivors of child sexual abuse between the ages of 11 and 21, and only “a small number” stated that they were satisfied with the police process.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uruguay accused of squandering early Covid success amid deadly surge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/uruguay-covid-coronavirus-surge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/uruguay-covid-coronavirus-surge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Country has highest death rate in Latin America after centre-right government abandoned social restrictions
Enrique Soto, a senior cardiologist in Uruguay knew that, at the age of 65, he was at higher risk of Covid-19. His 40-year-old son Marcos had warned him as much but Soto replied he could not abandon his patients.
When Soto died at the beginning of Uruguay’s devastating recent second wave of infections his death became emblematic of the disaster that has unfolded in recent months in the small South American country.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quique Kirszenbaum and Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rainbow stadiums: German football lights up for solidarity – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/gallery/2021/jun/24/rainbow-stadiums-german-grounds-show-solidarity-in-pictures-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/gallery/2021/jun/24/rainbow-stadiums-german-grounds-show-solidarity-in-pictures-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T08:11:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following Uefa’s decision to block a planned LGBTQ+ rainbow stadium protest at Munich’s Allianz Arena, football stadiums elsewhere in Germany pledged to light up in rainbow colours instead during the Euro 2020 match against Hungary
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s happened at the BBC and the Met police shows the perils of groupthink | Martin Kettle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/bbc-met-police-perils-groupthink</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/24/bbc-met-police-perils-groupthink"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T08:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When facing scrutiny the institutions reacted in a rigid, defensive manner. It’s a common theme across Britain
Doris Lessing always asked awkward questions. She posed them in her novels on subjects such as sex, politics and illusion. She posed them in her journalism about nuclear weapons and migration. And she posed them in her table talk, as I know from occasional meetings in the 1990s in a West Hampstead cafe that also appeared in some of her fiction.
At one such lunch, Lessing – whose life and work take up the entire new issue of Critical Quarterly magazine – recounted the story, which she later wrote about in her autobiography, of one of the most enduringly awkward questions that even she ever asked. In 1952 she joined a group of leftwing British writers, including my father, on a cold war visit to Stalin’s Soviet Union. During the visit, she grew frustrated by the endless official Marxist rhetoric from her hosts. So she and my father devised a question they hoped would produce a more honest and human discussion.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Kettle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magic Johnson: the NBA superstar who smashed HIV stigma – then built a huge fortune]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/24/magic-johnson-the-nba-superstar-who-smashed-hiv-stigma-then-built-a-huge-fortune</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/24/magic-johnson-the-nba-superstar-who-smashed-hiv-stigma-then-built-a-huge-fortune"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T05:22:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He stunned basketball fans and transformed HIV awareness by announcing his diagnosis in 1991. Thirty years on, he discusses his relationship with Anthony Fauci, the meaning of money and why he’s still optimistic
On 7 November 1991, a press conference in Inglewood, California, brought America to a standstill. Against a black-draped backdrop, dressed in a black suit, white shirt and multicoloured tie, Earvin “Magic” Johnson, spoke calmly into a single microphone and told the world that he had been diagnosed with HIV.
Cameras flashed and reporters clamoured to ask questions, but Johnson, National Basketball Association (NBA) superstar and one of the world’s most revered athletes, appeared unfazed as he announced his immediate retirement. Had he grappled with his own mortality? When had he found out? How had he acquired the virus? What would he do next?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The revolt against liberalism: what’s driving Poland and Hungary’s nativist turn?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/revolt-against-liberalism-eastern-europe-poland-hungary-nativist-politics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/revolt-against-liberalism-eastern-europe-poland-hungary-nativist-politics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T05:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the hardline conservatives ruling Poland and Hungary, the transition from communism to liberal democracy was a mirage. They fervently believe a more decisive break with the past is needed to achieve national liberation
In the summer of 1992, a 29-year-old Hungarian with political ambitions made his first visit to the US. For six weeks he toured the country with a coterie of young Europeans, all expenses paid by the German Marshall Fund, a thinktank devoted to transatlantic cooperation.
America had long fascinated Viktor Orbán, but he seemed disengaged and unaffected as the group walked around downtown Los Angeles, which was still reeling from the Rodney King riots two months earlier. One Dutch journalist on the trip recalled that the eastern Europeans in the group preferred to spend their daily stipends on “a Walkman and other electronics” rather than on food or fancy hotels. The free market and cutting-edge technologies certainly appealed more to Orbán than American debates and struggles over equality, justice or the rights of people of colour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Mulder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The longest of Covids: the man infected for 10 months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/the-longest-of-covids-the-man-infected-for-10-months</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/24/the-longest-of-covids-the-man-infected-for-10-months"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T05:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dave Smith, 72, from Bristol, tells of an experience including 42 positive tests and seven hospital admissions

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Like thousands of people, Dave Smith became infected with coronavirus at the start of the first wave in the UK in 2020. But while most people, including those who suffer “long Covid”, eliminate the live virus from their bodies within a couple of weeks, Smith experienced a very different sort of long-term problem: a persistent infection lasting more than 290 days, or almost 10 months. This has been the longest recorded active Covid-19 infection to date.
During that period, Smith, 72, from Bristol, recorded 42 positive PCR tests and was admitted to hospital seven times. He said: “Whenever I went bad, I went really bad – down to death’s door. My wife started to arrange a funeral five times.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How meme stars of the early internet are striking it rich with NFTs - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of non-fungible tokens has given rise to massive windfalls for those behind early virals. Sirin Kale and Alex Hern explain all
On 28 May 2016 the photographer Jeff McCurry was taking pictures of a 17-year-old western lowland gorilla called Harambe in Cincinnati zoo when a child entered the enclosure. The zookeepers reacted by shooting the gorilla dead. The child was unhurt. What was a local story suddenly became a global phenomenon due to the combination of social media and McCurry’s picture. Harambe’s image was everywhere. But, despite his photo being shared billions of times, McCurry did not see much of a financial benefit. Now advances in technology have given the world non-fungible tokens (NFTs) – and McCurry has a way of finally cashing in on his famous image.
The Guardian’s technology editor, Alex Hern, tells Rachel Humphreys that this year’s craze for NFTs follows in the wake of speculation on cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin. Now similar technology means unique images, film clips, animations and even poems are being bought and sold online for increasingly large sums.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Alex Hern; produced by Alex Atack, Ned Carter Miles and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Data Analysis? How to Visualize Data with Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib &amp; Seaborn Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>605abca5687d62084bf6b7cd</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/exploratory-data-analysis-with-numpy-pandas-matplotlib-seaborn/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T00:11:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Analysis is the process of exploring, investigating, and gathering insights from data using statistical measures and visualizations.  The objective of data analysis is to develop an understanding of data by uncovering trends, relationships, and patterns. Data analysis is both a science and an art. On the one hand it]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK policies will not deliver emission cuts pledge, says climate adviser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/24/uk-policies-will-not-deliver-emission-cuts-pledge-says-climate-adviser</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/24/uk-policies-will-not-deliver-emission-cuts-pledge-says-climate-adviser"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T23:01:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Climate Change Committee says government needs to ‘step up very rapidly’ to meet ‘historic’ targets
Boris Johnson’s government has set “historic” targets on the climate crisis but has failed so far to come up with the policies needed to reach them, the government’s independent advisers on the climate have warned.
The Climate Change Committee published two progress reports on Thursday, showing the UK lagging behind on its key goal of 78% cuts to greenhouse gases by 2035 and making recommendations on how to get back on track.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microservices Architecture – Explained in Plain English]]></title>
        <id>6072ffd4d5756f080ba98b27</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/microservices-architecture-for-humans/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few years, microservices have gone from an overhyped buzzword to something you should understand as a software engineer.  According to an O'Reilly developer survey in 2020:  61% of companies have been using microservices in the last year29% say at least half of their company systems are built]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343076</id>
        <link href="https://www.bram.us/2021/06/21/tablesng-improvements-to-table-rendering-in-chromium/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:37:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I blogged “Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier” recently, I mentioned that the “stickiness” improvement was just one of the features that got better for <table>s in Chrome as part of the TablesNG upgrade…
The post TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342750</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-performant-next-gen-images-in-css-with-image-set/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T19:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS image-set() function has been supported in Chromium-based browsers since 2012 and in Safari since version 6. Support recently landed in Firefox 88. Let’s dive in and see what we can and can’t do today with image-set().…
The post Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create a REST API with .NET 5 and  C#]]></title>
        <id>60d36eb66e1a1407b6b0b16d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-a-rest-api-with-dot-net-5-and-c-sharp/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T18:08:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[.NET is a popular software framework developed by Microsoft. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create a REST API end-to-end from scratch using the latest .NET 5 innovations and Visual Studio Code. The course uses the C# programming language.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create a Great Technical Course]]></title>
        <id>60a406bd906c5207e3a7dfcb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-a-great-technical-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T17:19:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article you will learn how to create a great technical video course. I run the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel where we post technical courses from a variety of contributors. Video courses that follow the guidelines in this article are often a good fit for freeCodeCamp's channel. How to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Weak declaration”]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342669</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/weak-declaration/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK looks at aspect-ratio, a CSS property for layout that, for the most part, does exactly what you would think it does. It’s getting more interesting as it’s behind a flag in Firefox and Safari now, so we’ll have …
The post “Weak declaration” appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experience of having periods during menopause]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re interested to hear how women going through menopause experience their menstrual cycles and periods
An estimated 13 million women in the UK are living with menopause, with 4.5 million of them making up the fastest-growing demographic in the workplace.
We’d like to hear how women experience their periods leading up to and during this time of hormonal change, and how this might be affecting their lives. How are you coping with period changes at work? How are your home and social lives affected?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Online Workshops (July-October 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frontend and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run [online workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A rain vortex and a newborn panda: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/23/a-rain-vortex-and-a-newborn-panda-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/23/a-rain-vortex-and-a-newborn-panda-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:14:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automating Screen Reader Testing On macOS Using Auto VO]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated testing is an important part of any software project, including testing for accessibility. There are already tools for linting and integration testing accessibility, but what about end-to-end testing with real assistive technology? Since I hadn’t seen this before, I set out to build Auto VO, a driver for the VoiceOver screen reader.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cameron Cundiff)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most new wind and solar projects will be cheaper than coal, report finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/23/most-new-wind-solar-projects-cheaper-than-coal-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/23/most-new-wind-solar-projects-cheaper-than-coal-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T09:28:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost two-thirds of renewable energy schemes built globally last year expected to undercut coal costs
Almost two-thirds of wind and solar projects built globally last year will be able to generate cheaper electricity than even the world’s cheapest new coal plants, according to a report from the International Renewable Energy Agency (Irena).
The agency found that the falling cost of new windfarms and solar panels meant 62% of new renewable energy projects could undercut the cost of up to 800 gigawatts (GW) worth of coal plants, or almost enough to supply the UK’s electricity needs 10 times over.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose Energy correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home comforts, apocalyptic futures: Deutsche Börse prize nominees – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/23/home-comforts-apocalyptic-futures-deutsche-borse-prize-nominees-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/23/home-comforts-apocalyptic-futures-deutsche-borse-prize-nominees-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T07:04:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dystopian conflicts and home ownership guides feature in the work of the four nominees for this innovative photography prize
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop! In the name of style – Diana Ross’s best looks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/23/stop-in-the-name-of-style-diana-ross-best-looks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/23/stop-in-the-name-of-style-diana-ross-best-looks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T05:11:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the Supremes singer prepares to release her first new album in 15 years, we look back on her effortless, classic fashion
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melanie Wilkinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logical Fallacies – Definition and Fallacy Examples]]></title>
        <id>607f5fafdd38b9088c2bd0c9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/logical-fallacies-definition-fallacy-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T04:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're debating someone, you want to use all the resources at your disposal to convince them you're right. And that's great – but you should be careful that you don't end up using a logical fallacy to help you make your point. What is a Logical Fallacy?A logical fallacy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police corruption and the unsolved murder of Daniel Morgan – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/23/police-corruption-unsolved-murder-daniel-morgan-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/23/police-corruption-unsolved-murder-daniel-morgan-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The brutal murder of a private investigator in 1987 has become the UK’s most investigated killing – but 34 years later it remains unsolved and mired in new official findings of police corruption
On 10 March 1987, a 37-year-old private investigator named Daniel Morgan was found dead in a south London pub car park with an axe embedded in his head. Despite the arrests of several men, the initial investigation did not lead to any charges and the murder has gone unsolved amid allegations of police corruption. 
The Metropolitan police have previously accepted that corrupt officers shielded the killers. But a new panel inquiry concluded last week that the crime was probably “solvable” had it not been undermined. The force was described as “institutionally corrupt” and its commissioner, Cressida Dick, personally censured for obstruction by an independent inquiry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Duncan Campbell and Alistair Morgan; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[inherit, initial, unset, revert]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342930</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inherit-initial-unset-revert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:20:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are four keywords that are valid values for any CSS property (see the title). Of those, day to day, I’d say I see the inherit used the most. Perhaps because it’s been around the longest (I think?) but also …
The post inherit, initial, unset, revert appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Scraping with PHP – How to Crawl Web Pages Using Open Source Tools]]></title>
        <id>60d2323d6e1a1407b6b0ac4f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-scraping-with-php-crawl-web-pages/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:11:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web scraping lets you collect data from web pages across the internet. It's also called web crawling or web data extraction.  PHP is a widely used back-end scripting language for creating dynamic websites and web applications. And you can implement a web scraper using plain PHP code.  But since we]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Async/Await to Write Better JavaScript Code]]></title>
        <id>60cac8ff4dc1a607ed7b4592</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-async-await-write-better-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a special syntax you can use in JavaScript that makes working with promises easier. It's called “async/await", and it’s surprisingly straightforward to understand and use.  In this article, we'll discuss:  What are asynchronus functions? How promises work in JavaScript Async/Await basics How to use]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use TypeScript and MongoDB to Build a 100 Days of Code Discord Bot]]></title>
        <id>60c13e71d3126007592d5be2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-a-100-days-of-code-bot-for-discord-using-typescript-and-mongodb/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:20:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 100 Days of Code challenge is very popular among new coders and developers looking to level up their skills. It's so popular that our Discord server has an entire channel dedicated to it.  By popular demand, we recently built a Discord bot that helps people track their progress in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Custom Elements in Svelte]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342634</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-custom-elements-in-svelte/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:37:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte fully supports custom elements (e.g. <my-component>) without any custom configuration or wrapper components and has a perfect score on Custom Elements Everywhere. However, there are still a few quirks you need to watch out for, especially around …
The post Using Custom Elements in Svelte appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Rich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342925</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/if-were-gonna-criticize-utility-class-frameworks-lets-be-fair-about-it/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not here to raise a shield protecting CSS utility frameworks. I don’t even particularly like the approach, myself, and nothing is above fair criticism. But fair is a key word there. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve …
The post If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The longest swim: solstice wild swimmers around the UK – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/22/solstice-swimmers-around-the-uk-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/22/solstice-swimmers-around-the-uk-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T12:46:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 4 million people are involved in open-water swimming in Britain. The Outdoor Swimming Society’s longest swim on the longest day event has more than 500 participants – we joined several groups out for solstice swims around the UK on a damp and grey summer’s day
The pandemic has been a tough time for swimmers. Lockdowns and tier systems meant swimming pools were closed for more days than they were open. Outdoor swimming spots were only for use by those local enough to access them easily.
However, despite the restrictions, there has been a huge surge in the popularity of swimming, particularly outdoor swimming in ponds, lakes, reservoirs or the sea.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Ruck ; Photography by; Jonny Weeks, Katherine Rose,  Antonio Olmos, Jim Wileman, Christopher Thomond, David Levene, Teri Pengilley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing With Code: A Modern Approach To Design (Development Challenges)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of innovation in both tools and processes, the struggle between design and development is still real. This article focuses on the best practices for improving the design to development processes and how cutting-edge solutions, such as UXPin powered by Merge technology, can help in facilitating the change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do we have to learn to live with Covid-19? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/22/do-we-have-to-learn-to-live-with-covid-19-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/22/do-we-have-to-learn-to-live-with-covid-19-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T02:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s health editor, Sarah Boseley, weighs up the race between vaccines and variants and explains why the end of the pandemic does not mean the end of Covid-19
A new wave of Covid-19 cases is threatening to disrupt another summer in the UK as the government extends restrictions for England into July amid concern about the rate of spread of the Delta variant. 
The Guardian’s health editor, Sarah Boseley, tells Anushka Asthana that this time around we are in a very different position with most adults now having had two vaccine jabs. However, there is still a prospect of a sharp rise in Covid cases and with it more hospital admissions and deaths. Boris Johnson has said cases of the Delta variant are rising at about 30% a week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Sarah Boseley; produced by Alice Fordham and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342887</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/new-responsive/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una is calling it the new responsive. A nod to the era we were most certainly in, the era of responsive design. Where responsive design was fluid grids, flexible media, and media queries, the new responsive is those things …
The post Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342448</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-css-charts-with-interesting-shapes-glyphs-and-emoji/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:32:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s forego the usual circles and bars we typically see used in charts for more eccentric shapes. With online presentations more and more common today, a quick way to spruce up your web slides and make them stand out is …
The post How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image To Text Conversion With React And Tesseract.js (OCR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have to process data manually because it is served through images or scanned documents? An image-to-text conversion makes it possible to extract text from images to automate the processing of texts on images, videos, and scanned documents. In this article, we look at how to convert an image to text with React and Tesseract.js(OCR), preprocess images, and deal with the limitations of Tesseract (OCR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ayobami Ogundiran)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341511</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-the-outline-property-as-a-collapsable-border/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T20:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outline property in CSS draws a line around the outside of an element. This is quite similar to the border property, the main exception being that outline isn’t a part of the box model. It is often used for …
The post Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carter Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342326</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied the fonts of the top 1000 websites. Here’s what I learned. — Michael Li brings the data. San-serif has total dominance. “[…] it is rare to go below 10px or above 24px.” And poor <h5> always being the 
…
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why brutal protests have been sweeping across Colombia – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/18/why-brutal-protests-have-been-sweeping-across-colombia-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T11:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the Amazon to the Caribbean coast, several weeks of protests have swept Colombia – dozens have died as demonstrators have faced sometimes deadly retaliation from police. 
The catalyst was a proposed tax hike, since withdrawn, in response to the coronavirus crisis. Demands expanded to calls to end inequality, economic disparity and police violence in Colombia – in almost two months, demonstrations have caused food and goods shortages.
Protest leaders have temporarily suspended in-person demonstrations due to a rise in Covid cases, but Joe Parkin Daniels, reporting for the Guardian, explains why this widespread discontent is unlikely to end


 ‘This is a revolution’: the faces of Colombia’s protests
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels, Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a chef became a doggie-treat entrepreneur – with some ‘amazing’ banking support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/from-startup-to-up-and-running/2021/jun/18/how-a-chef-became-a-doggie-treat-entrepreneur-with-some-amazing-banking-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/from-startup-to-up-and-running/2021/jun/18/how-a-chef-became-a-doggie-treat-entrepreneur-with-some-amazing-banking-support"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T09:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since it was launched as a small stall, Daisy’s Dog Empawrium has grown from strength to strength. Here, owner Lisa Gosling explains how a business relationship played a pivotal role through good times and bad 
Kelly Purvor remembers exactly where she was on her birthday in 2017: attending the opening of Daisy’s Dog Deli, a store dedicated to handmade canine treats and accessories, at Bluewater shopping centre in Kent. Purvor’s self-appointed role that day was to stand outside, drumming up business by flyering passersby or ushering them into the shop where owner Lisa Gosling was busy serving customers. “Her support, as always, has been amazing,” says Gosling of the helping hand at the launch of her store (renamed Daisy’s Dog Empawrium in 2019).
Purvor’s relationship with Gosling and her business extends far beyond acting as, appropriately enough, a de facto “barker” that special day. Because she also happens to be Gosling’s local business manager at the Maidstone store of Metro Bank. It’s a working relationship that has grown over two decades, having begun in 2000 when Gosling won a competition for small businesses in the area. Gosling had traded in her long-term career as a chef to launch a business that combined her culinary skills and love of dogs by making hand-crafted canine treats, suitable for pooches with sensitive stomachs who have difficulties eating commercial dog food – such as her own dog, Daisy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Worthy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341948</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/perfect-tooltips-with-css-clipping-and-masking/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clipping and masking have been around for a while now in CSS and even have pretty decent browser support. I recently worked on a project that needed to use a clipping technique for tooltips showing above links in text.
Those …
The post Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Hoebregts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342257</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/start-serving-optimized-images-in-vue/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have become extremely important to the effectiveness of websites. They speak a 1000 words, attract attention, and stimulate emotions.
However, web performance is also a growing problem for most websites. And images are at the heart of many web …
The post Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ImageEngine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inline Styles as Classes (lol)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342358</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inline-styles-as-classes-lol/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re abhorred by using inline styles, just move that style to the class attribute! And then make sure you have CSS in place that, ya know, does what it says on the box. 
I've revolutionized CSS. pic.twitter.com/1AWCldyCwP
— Sam 

…
The post Inline Styles as Classes (lol) appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful and Useless Code Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/useful-and-usless-code-comments/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Nielsen: 
If somebody says a comment isn’t adding any value, I would ask: to whom?
Personally, I’ve never liked the advice that writing obvious comments is bad practice—probably because I write obvious comments all the time.
Jim showed …
The post Useful and Useless Code Comments appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you re-thought your wedding dress during the pandemic?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/15/tell-us-have-you-re-thought-your-wedding-dress-during-the-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/15/tell-us-have-you-re-thought-your-wedding-dress-during-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T13:25:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear if you have changed your mind about your wedding attire during the pandemic 
For couples who decided to get married during the last 18 months, wedding plans have often had to be altered. Pandemic restrictions sparked a rise in pared-back micro-weddings and virtual ceremonies. Perhaps unsurprisingly, this has also has an impact on the day’s dress code, with many brides (in particular) opting for a more relaxed look over a formal wedding dress.
With this in mind, we’d love to hear from those who re-thought their wedding attire during the pandemic. Perhaps you decided to go for a cocktail dress, rather than a floor-skimming evening gown? Or maybe you decided not to wear a dress at all? Tell us about it, and share your photos, here.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flying cars? Electric jets? Five things you need to know about the future of transport]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/smarter-science/2021/jun/03/flying-cars-electric-jets-five-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-future-of-transport</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/smarter-science/2021/jun/03/flying-cars-electric-jets-five-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-future-of-transport"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T09:20:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may still sound like the stuff of science fiction, but some of the biggest companies in the world are investing hugely in previously fanciful transport technologies

From 2030, new petrol and diesel vehicles will be banned in Britain – a sure sign that we’re on the threshold of a transport revolution. But what exactly will this revolution look like? With estimates that the market for autonomous vehicles could be worth almost £42bn in just over a decade, the future of transport looks to be anything but boring. Here are five things you need to know …
Driverless cars take to the roads
While fully autonomous vehicles (where the driver could, in theory, watch a film while the vehicle takes the controls) are still a way off, the first driverless cars – with automated lane-keeping systems that allow drivers to safely take their hands off the wheel – could be on Britain’s roads this year. In Japan, Toyota is building its own smart city, which will function in part as a giant testing facility for autonomous vehicles. Meanwhile, in the US, Waymo – which grew out of Google’s self-driving car project – is trialling driverless “robotaxi” services for the public in parts of Phoenix. The road to the driverless future may still be a little bumpy, but it is showing signs of smoothing out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Waugh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>