<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-11T00:27:57.881Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-11T00:27:57.881Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.6.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden says ‘economic plan is working’, despite disappointing April jobs report – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2021/may/10/biden-economy-infrastructure-bill-covid-vaccines-latest-news-live-updates</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2021/may/10/biden-economy-infrastructure-bill-covid-vaccines-latest-news-live-updates"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T00:09:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden urges companies to raise pay to bring Americans back to work
Republican compares trajectory of the GOP to sinking of the Titanic
US bans sex discrimination against LGBT people in healthcare
Trump’s grip over Republicans hardens
Sign up to receive First Thing – our daily briefing by email

 1.09am BST 
That’s it for me tonight. Here’s what we covered this afternoon:
 Related: Shutdown of US pipeline after cyber-attack prompts worry over gas prices 
 12.34am BST 
With Covid cases dropping, the US State …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabrielle Canon (now) and Joan E Greve (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explainer: What is the deadly ‘black fungus’ seen in Covid patients in India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/11/what-is-the-dangerous-black-fungus-being-seen-in-covid-patients-in-india-mucormycosis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/11/what-is-the-dangerous-black-fungus-being-seen-in-covid-patients-in-india-mucormycosis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:56:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually very rare, mucormycosis has a high mortality rate and is difficult to treat 
A rare black fungus that invades the brain is being increasingly seen in vulnerable patients in India, including those with Covid-19, as the health system continues to struggle in the midst of the pandemic.
The health ministry on Sunday released an advisory on how to treat the infection. In the state of Gujarat, about 300 cases had been reported in four cities, including Ahmedabad, according to data from state-run hospitals…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Davey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nasa spacecraft leaves asteroid Bennu with a belly full of space rock samples]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/10/nasa-spacecraft-asteroid-bennu-space-rock-samples</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/10/nasa-spacecraft-asteroid-bennu-space-rock-samples"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:06:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Osiris-Rex has been flying around the ancient asteroid since 2018 and collected nearly a pound of rubble last fall
With rubble from an asteroid tucked inside, a Nasa spacecraft fired its engines and began the long journey back to Earth on Monday, leaving the ancient space rock in its rearview mirror.
The trip home for the robotic prospector, Osiris-Rex, will take two years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drive for more student diversity paying off, says Oxford University]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/11/drive-for-more-student-diversity-paying-off-says-oxford-university</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/11/drive-for-more-student-diversity-paying-off-says-oxford-university"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Institution doubles proportion of new students from disadvantaged backgrounds in five years
The University of Oxford says it has almost doubled the proportion of students from disadvantaged backgrounds starting their studies, as part of a five-year turnaround resulting in its most diverse ever intake.
The proportion of new students from socio-economically disadvantaged areas rose from 8.2% to 15.9% over the last five years. For the academic year 2020-21, the university also recruited record numbers of state…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British retailers say closures and job losses still a risk despite lockdown easing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/british-retailers-say-closures-and-job-losses-still-a-risk-despite-lockdown-easing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/british-retailers-say-closures-and-job-losses-still-a-risk-despite-lockdown-easing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trade body urges government to deliver on promise to reform business rates to protect sector
Store closures and job losses are a threat to Britain’s retail sector despite an increase in activity following the easing of lockdown restrictions, the government has been warned by the industry’s trade body.
The British Retail Consortium said a pick-up in April as non-essential stores reopened should not be seen as evidence of full recovery and urged ministers to make good on their promises of reform to business r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott Economics editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My head is on fire’: Roger Ballen finds poetry in pain – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/my-head-is-on-fire-roger-ballen-finds-poetry-in-pain-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/my-head-is-on-fire-roger-ballen-finds-poetry-in-pain-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paint, collage and photography combine in Ballen’s tumultuous The Earth Will Come to Laugh and Feast. Italian poet Gabriele Tinti reflects on his work ... 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California declares drought emergency across vast swath of state]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/california-declares-drought-emergency-across-vast-swath-of-state</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/california-declares-drought-emergency-across-vast-swath-of-state"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T22:53:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Majority of counties now under emergency declaration as California faces extensive dry spell and dwindling water supply
California has expanded a drought emergency declaration to a large swath of the nation’s most populated state amid “acute water supply shortages” in northern and central parts of California.
The declaration, expanded by Governor Gavin Newsom on Monday, now includes 41 of 58 counties, covering 30% of California’s nearly 40 million people. The US drought monitor shows most of the state and t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man, 21, charged with murder of PCSO Julia James]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/man-21-charged-with-of-kent-pcso-julia-james</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/man-21-charged-with-of-kent-pcso-julia-james"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:44:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Callum Wheeler charged with murder of woman whose body was found in Kent woodland
A 21-year-old man has been charged with the murder of PCSO Julia James, whose body was found in Akholt Wood near her home in Snowdown, Kent on 27 April.
Callum Wheeler, 21, from Aylesham, has been charged with the murder of Julia James, PCSO, Kent police said on Monday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Queen’s speech to focus on adult learning and easing planning rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/queens-speech-to-focus-on-adult-learning-and-easing-planning-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/queens-speech-to-focus-on-adult-learning-and-easing-planning-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Levelling up agenda accompanied by bills bringing in voter ID and banning conversion practices
Ministers are to unveil a legislative programme aimed at its new electoral strongholds in northern England and the Midlands, with a Queen’s speech focused on adult education and homeownership.
It also features proposals to bring in mandatory voter ID, which has been condemned by US civil rights groups as akin to Republican-style voter suppression. Another plan will pave the way to outlaw conversion practices.
 Con…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker, Aubrey Allegretti and Lisa O'Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topframe]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/topframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is extremely fun. Jeff Lindsay has created Topframe, and writes:
Anybody that knows how to mess around with HTML can now mess around with their desktop computing experience.&#160;Topframe&#160;is an open source tool that lets you 
&#8230;
The post Topframe appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340208</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/migrating-from-parcel-to-snowpack-build-tool-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I find build tooling endlessly interesting, especially right now as we&#8217;re in a juicy next-gen transitional period with players like Vite, wmr, Snowpack, and esbuild. Hugh Haworth has a good run-down of the new players, and we&#8217;ve chatted on &#8230;
The post Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Families review – a surface-level study of abortion anguish]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/10/three-families-review-a-surface-level-study-of-abortion-anguish</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/10/three-families-review-a-surface-level-study-of-abortion-anguish"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gwyneth Hughes’s drama about women affected by draconian anti-termination laws in Northern Ireland was emotive but ultimately superficial
It was only a couple of years ago, I’d warrant, that the majority of people in Great Britain became aware of the fact that, although the 1967 Abortion Act has permitted the termination of unwanted pregnancies for the past 50-odd years, its remit never extended to Northern Ireland. An extraordinary grassroots campaign to give the country’s women the same rights that exist …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fulham relegated as Ashley Westwood and Chris Wood strike for Burnley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/fulham-burnley-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/fulham-burnley-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T20:57:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fulham’s race is run and, even though they have seen fine margins go against them in recent weeks, there was no hard luck story to tell this time. In truth there was little of the devastation seen at the end of recent last-minute heartbreaks, either: once a superior Burnley had scored twice before half-time to make sure of their own Premier League status it was clear, from the stands and quite possibly on the pitch, that there was no way back and Scott Parker’s players knew they were going down long before …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames at Craven Cottage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Alex Ferguson: ‘Did I think we could still beat Bayern in 1999? No chance!’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/alex-ferguson-jason-ferguson-interview-manchester-united-aberdeen-donald-mcrae</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/alex-ferguson-jason-ferguson-interview-manchester-united-aberdeen-donald-mcrae"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T20:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview, the legendary manager and son Jason reflect on the brain haemorrhage that nearly killed him and the film they have just made, his upbringing in Scotland, the lows and highs at Manchester United, his admiration for Steven Gerrard … and that Champions League final 
“You’re lying on your bed and you are on your own,” Sir Alex Ferguson says as he remembers being in hospital exactly three years ago this week when, after suffering a brain haemorrhage, he came close to death. “It can bec…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald McRae</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hut Group strikes complex joint venture deal with SoftBank]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/the-hut-group-joint-venture-deal-softbank-thg</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/the-hut-group-joint-venture-deal-softbank-thg"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:54:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deal values ‘yet to be formed’ technology division of THG at $6.3bn
The Hut Group (THG), the online retailer empire run by billionaire Matthew Moulding, has struck a complex joint venture deal with Japanese investment giant SoftBank that values a “yet to be formed” technology division of THG at $6.3bn (£4.5bn).
The deal, announced on Monday, values THG Ingenuity, which Moulding described as a “social media influencer platform” used to promote products, at about the same amount that the whole company floated…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Golden Globes backlash: Tom Cruise hands back awards and NBC drops broadcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/tom-cruise-nbc-golden-globes-hollywood-foreign-press-association</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/tom-cruise-nbc-golden-globes-hollywood-foreign-press-association"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:52:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor and network join industry figures distancing themselves from Hollywood Foreign Press Association after exposé
Tom Cruise has returned his three Golden Globes in protest after criticisms levelled at the Hollywood Foreign Press Association continue to create problems in the industry.
The actor, who won for Born on the Fourth of July, Jerry Maguire and Magnolia, is one of many to stand up against the HFPA, the small group of international journalists who vote on the awards, after an exposé highlighted fa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bristol pupil died of sepsis on US trip ‘after telling teachers she felt unwell’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/bristol-pupil-died-of-sepsis-on-us-trip-after-telling-teachers-she-felt-unwell</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/bristol-pupil-died-of-sepsis-on-us-trip-after-telling-teachers-she-felt-unwell"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:36:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ana Uglow, 17, collapsed in December 2019 and was pronounced dead at a New York hospital, inquest hears

A teenager died from sepsis on a school trip to New York after telling teachers she felt unwell, an inquest heard.
Ana Uglow, 17, a student at Bristol grammar school, was pronounced dead at Mount Sinai West hospital in December 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No boasting, no gloating, Boris somehow remains on topic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/no-boasting-no-gloating-boris-somehow-remains-on-topic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/no-boasting-no-gloating-boris-somehow-remains-on-topic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Perhaps stunned by the fact that things were finally going OK, PM didn’t even bother to make fun of Labour’s troubles
It wasn’t the results in last week’s elections that niggled. Nor was it that he had made a bit of an idiot of himself by effectively being forced to promote Angela Rayner just hours after he had tried to sack the deputy leader as party chair for her part in running such a rubbish campaign. Only the Labour party could turn a reshuffle into surrealist performance art. Not least by elevating so…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SoftBank’s vote of confidence for THG is deal-making on steroids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/10/softbank-vote-of-confidence-for-thg-is-deal-making-on-steroids</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/10/softbank-vote-of-confidence-for-thg-is-deal-making-on-steroids"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Markets find hard to value Hut Group but Japanese bank seems to like the look of it
The Hut Group, or THG as it’s become, floated at 500p last September, has been as high as 800p and closed on Monday a shade below 600p. In other words, it is a business the market finds hard to value, which is perhaps not surprising since there aren’t many like it.
THG is an e-commerce marketing platform with a bits-and-pieces beauty and nutrition operation that moves in the baffling world of social media influencers. And it…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US ship fires 30 warning shots after Iranian vessels approach fleet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/iran-navy-us-coast-guard-warning-shots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/iran-navy-us-coast-guard-warning-shots"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:07:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coast guard vessel takes action after 13 Iranian fast boats come within 150 yards in strait of Hormuz
A US coast guard ship fired about 30 warning shots as a group of 13 Iranian fast boats sped toward US navy vessels in the strait of Hormuz, in what the Pentagon called “unsafe and unprofessional” maneuvers by the naval arm of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGCN).
The incident marked the second time within the last month that US military vessels have had to fire warning shots because of what they sa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on Keir Starmer’s shadow cabinet reshuffle – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/10/steve-bell-on-keir-starmers-shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/10/steve-bell-on-keir-starmers-shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T19:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stranded whale in Thames put down after suffering injuries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/10/stranded-whale-in-thames-put-down-after-suffering-injuries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/10/stranded-whale-in-thames-put-down-after-suffering-injuries"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:59:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minke whale made it as far as Teddington, south-west London, but rescue teams were unable to save it
As crowds gathered along the banks of the Thames around Teddington weir to catch a glimpse of the little whale that had lost its way upriver, the mood gradually became tinged with sadness at the realisation that the baby minke would probably never make it back out to sea.
The calf had first got stranded on Richmond lock’s boat rollers on Sunday evening. It was finally freed by rescue teams around 1am but wri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cali is the cockpit of chaos as Colombia protests threaten to spiral out of control]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/cali-colombia-protests-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/cali-colombia-protests-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:58:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The presence of armed civilians attacking protesters has added a worrying dimension to a wave of unrest that has claimed 47 lives
On a recent evening, Andrés pulled on his gas mask and helmet and headed for the barricades at the entrance to his rundown neighbourhood in Cali, a city which has become the center of Colombia’s anti-government protests.
But as he approached the roadblock of rocks, rubble and barbed wire, he saw a motorcycle speeding towards him. In an attempt to turn the vehicle back, another de…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels in Cali</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Melinda Gates began divorce moves at time Bill’s meetings with Jeffrey Epstein revealed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/10/melinda-bill-gates-divorce-jeffrey-epstein-meetings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/10/melinda-bill-gates-divorce-jeffrey-epstein-meetings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:52:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wife of world’s fourth-richest man explored options almost two years ago, roughly at time sex criminal Epstein died in jail
Melinda French Gates had concerns about her husband’s dealings with the convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein when she consulted lawyers to explore the option of divorcing the Microsoft billionaire Bill Gates, according to reports.
The billionaire philanthropists announced their decision to divorce last week after declaring their marriage “irretrievably broken” – but did not explain w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York and Rupert Neate</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel launches airstrikes on Gaza Strip after Hamas rocket attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/hamas-fires-rockets-into-israel-in-dispute-over-jerusalem-mosque</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/hamas-fires-rockets-into-israel-in-dispute-over-jerusalem-mosque"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:51:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gaza health ministry says 20 Palestinians were killed in Israeli strikes after Palestinian groups fired rockets into Israel
Tensions between Israel and the Palestinians escalated dramatically on Monday as militant groups in Gaza fired rockets into Israel and Israel responded with strikes on the Palestinian coastal territory following a police raid on the al-Aqsa mosque in Jerusalem that left hundreds injured.
The rocket attacks were launched just minutes after the passing of a Hamas-issued ultimatum for Isr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem and Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elections reflected Britain’s deep divisions over Brexit and Scotland’s future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/elections-reflected-britains-deep-divisions-over-brexit-and-scotlands-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/elections-reflected-britains-deep-divisions-over-brexit-and-scotlands-future"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:39:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservatives ride high in leave-voting areas of England, but face a challenge from Scottish nationalism

Elections 2021 – live updates
Results tracker for the local, Scottish and Welsh polls

The Conservatives are on a high but are at risk of presiding over the breakup of Britain; Labour has yet to develop an effective political strategy to challenge Boris Johnson, while the Liberal Democrats are still stuck in the doldrums.
These were the key messages that emerged from Thursday’s bumper crop of local and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Curtice</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiger briefly on the loose in Texas suburb, viral video shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/tiger-loose-texas-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/tiger-loose-texas-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:32:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[54-second video showed Bengal tiger roaming freely in front of houses before owner seen putting it in his vehicle
A tiger was briefly on the loose in a Houston suburb on Sunday, terrifying residents before its owner grabbed it and fled in a car.
A 54-second video posted on social media showed the Bengal tiger roaming freely in front of houses in the Energy Corridor, 18 miles west of downtown Houston.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Rayner vows to reconnect Labour with working class voters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/labour-has-talked-down-to-voters-for-too-long-says-angela-rayner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/labour-has-talked-down-to-voters-for-too-long-says-angela-rayner"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: deputy leader says party must do more to speak to people in low-wage jobs she grew up with

Opinion: We need to show voters what we stand for – and that Labour is on their side

Labour has talked down to voters for too long Angela Rayner has said, in her first bid to assert her newfound authority as the party’s voice of the working class.
In an article for the Guardian, the deputy leader said Labour would invest tens of billions of pounds in green industries to boost jobs in areas where manufactu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We need to show voters what we stand for – and that Labour is on their side | Angela Rayner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/voters-labour-angela-rayner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/voters-labour-angela-rayner"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My party should learn the lessons of last week’s elections and reconnect with the people it was founded to fight for

Angela Rayner vows to reconnect Labour with working class voters

There’s no getting away from the need to learn the lessons of last Thursday’s elections. As the dust settles, it’s clear that sitting governments in Wales, Scotland and England received a boost and there are undoubtedly other significant factors at play – the vaccine bounce has helped the Tories in England, and former Brexit p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Rayner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Super Thursday: Boris Johnson is unmaking a nation | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/the-guardian-view-on-super-thursday-boris-johnson-is-unmaking-a-nation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/the-guardian-view-on-super-thursday-boris-johnson-is-unmaking-a-nation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:26:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister prefers to centralise power rather than give it away. That is bad news for Britain
Nations are not born; they are made. Whether nations last is entirely up to the people who manufactured them. This provides one important reason to pay attention to the results of last week’s “Super Thursday” elections. In Scotland, the Scottish National party, which has been in power for 14 years, increased its representation in Holyrood. In Wales, Labour upped its vote share by 4% this year, having won 27…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on early years education: England’s toddlers need attention | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/the-guardian-view-on-early-years-education-englands-toddlers-need-attention</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/the-guardian-view-on-early-years-education-englands-toddlers-need-attention"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:23:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A wave of closures should be ringing alarm bells in government. Nurseries are a piece of social infrastructure that we cannot do without
New figures showing a net loss of more than 315 early years providers in England in February and March arrive hard on the heels of a survey that found just one in four maintained (state-funded) nurseries will be able to remain open with current levels of funding. To many parents, and early years workers, the crisis in the sector is no surprise. Nurseries were suffering bef…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson confirms further easing of lockdown in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/boris-johnson-confirms-further-easing-of-lockdown-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/boris-johnson-confirms-further-easing-of-lockdown-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM says social distancing will be left up to ‘personal choice’ as he confirms next phase of roadmap will go ahead as planned

Lockdown easing in England: what will change from 17 May
Coronavirus – latest updates

Social distancing and the 1 metre-plus rule could be scrapped next month, the prime minister has suggested, as he confirmed the next step of England’s lockdown easing but said families and friends should think carefully before deciding to hug.
Heralding a “very considerable” easing of measures, the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jerusalem seethes as the rockets begin on day of rising tension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/jerusalem-seethes-as-the-rockets-begin-on-day-of-rising-tension</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/jerusalem-seethes-as-the-rockets-begin-on-day-of-rising-tension"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:05:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A series of events come together to inflame an already volatile situation in the holy city

It was strikingly clear that the most dangerous moment in Jerusalem’s worst unrest for years would arrive on Monday. After weeks of mounting anger, a series of provocative events were all set to spiral together at once, creating a tinderbox situation that world powers warned needed delicate handling.
The European Union had called on authorities to “act urgently to de-escalate the current tensions in Jerusalem” while …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes and Sufian Taha in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tax dodging concerns over small firms used to pay NHS test-and-trace workers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/tax-dodging-concerns-over-small-firms-used-to-pay-nhs-test-and-trace-workers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/tax-dodging-concerns-over-small-firms-used-to-pay-nhs-test-and-trace-workers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:03:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: call handlers and test-site workers reported issues over their payslips

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Many workers employed across the £37bn NHS test-and-trace service are being paid through networks of opaque small companies that experts fear could be defrauding the Treasury via a notorious tax scheme.
The Guardian investigated after sources working at Covid-19 call centres, testing sites, mobile testing units and laboratories raised concerns about their payslips…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly, Simon Goodley and Joseph Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Emma Hayes turned Chelsea from also-rans to all-conquerors | Suzanne Wrack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/how-emma-hayes-turned-chelsea-from-also-rans-to-all-conquerors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/how-emma-hayes-turned-chelsea-from-also-rans-to-all-conquerors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T18:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea Women are closing in on a historic quadruple but it has taken a remarkable rebuild to get here
It is hard to describe what it has been like to watch what is surely one of the best women’s teams to ever play in England’s top flight. Magical yet intense, sleek yet gritty, there are juxtapositions aplenty in Emma Hayes’s all-conquering Chelsea team.
In many ways it is the marriage of these opposites that has made this team exhilarating and set it on course for a historic quadruple – a feat achieved onl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suzanne Wrack</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IPL likely to be without England players if it restarts, says Ashley Giles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/ipl-likely-to-be-without-england-players-when-it-restarts-says-ashley-giles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/ipl-likely-to-be-without-england-players-when-it-restarts-says-ashley-giles"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:49:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mooted September return would clash with England tours
Giles: ‘If those tours go ahead, I’d expect them to be there’

England players are likely to be ruled out of the Indian Premier League’s mooted resumption later this year following an insistence from Ashley Giles, their team director, that international cricket now takes priority. An outbreak of Covid-19 among the IPL’s franchises forced the tournament to be indefinitely suspended last week with 31 games still outstanding and now organisers are eyeing a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delay to social care reforms will ‘fail more families every day’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/10/delay-to-social-care-reforms-will-fail-more-families-every-day</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/10/delay-to-social-care-reforms-will-fail-more-families-every-day"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:46:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health of thousands of vulnerable people in England and Wales at risk, despite Johnson’s promise to fix crisis

Campaigners and thinktanks have said a failure to announce significant new social care reforms in the Queen’s speech will “fail more families every day” and put the health and wellbeing of thousands of vulnerable people at risk.
Reports suggest the government is to once more delay reforms to the adult social care system in England and Wales after being unable to agree on how to fund them, leaving …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Butler Social policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How evil are weevils? A guide to managing pantry pests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/how-evil-are-weevils-a-guide-to-managing-pantry-pests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/how-evil-are-weevils-a-guide-to-managing-pantry-pests"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Food infested with moths, weevils or other beetles can be a major nuisance, but experts say there’s no need to panic
If you spot web-like filaments in your starchy pantry items such as rice, flour, oats or sugar, or bits of dry dust on shelves and holes in food packets, you could be facing an invasion of insects such as moths or weevils.
Among them you might see white moth caterpillars, which have an alarming resemblance to maggots but are a different species, or grain weevils, which entomologist and food s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Parletta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer’s botched reshuffle exposes his loss of authority | Owen Jones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/keir-starmer-reshuffle-local-election-results-labour-leader</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/keir-starmer-reshuffle-local-election-results-labour-leader"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:17:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now many Labour MPs no longer believe their leader will become prime minister, expect the muttering to grow louder
Before the chaos of the past five days, there were already growing doubts among Labour MPs about Keir Starmer’s leadership – but until now, these worries were largely muffled by relief that anyone other than Jeremy Corbyn was running the party. That has now changed.
For MPs, the belief that Labour may be headed for government imposes an anxious discipline: a leader holding the prospect of polit…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ace Your Coding Interview – Advice from a Senior Software Engineer]]></title>
        <id>60953e202cd0545b5e943a8b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-acing-your-coding-interview-advice-from-senior-software-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical interviews are one of the most stressful parts of landing a job in tech.  You don't know what questions the interviewer is going to ask. What if you have no idea how to solve the problem in front of you? What if you freeze up and look like you]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Riley tells court tweet by Corbyn aide harmed her reputation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/10/rachel-riley-court-corbyn-aide-tweet-harmed-reputation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/10/rachel-riley-court-corbyn-aide-tweet-harmed-reputation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:01:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Countdown presenter is suing Laura Murray over tweet in which she was called ‘dangerous’ and ‘stupid’

The Countdown presenter Rachel Riley has told a high court judge that a tweet by an aide of the then Labour leader, Jeremy Corbyn, seriously harmed her reputation and led to a concerted campaign to get her fired.
Riley is suing Laura Murray over the tweet, posted a short time after Corbyn was hit by eggs thrown by a Brexit supporter during a visit to Finsbury Park mosque on 3 March 2019; the attacker was l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trainer: Kentucky Derby winner faces disqualification due to ‘cancel culture’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/bob-baffert-medina-spirit-kentucky-derby-horse-racing-cancel-culture-disqualification</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/bob-baffert-medina-spirit-kentucky-derby-horse-racing-cancel-culture-disqualification"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bob Baffert says urine-tainted hay may have led to positive test
Medina Spirit failed drug test after winning Kentucky Derby 

Bob Baffert, whose horse faces disqualification from the Kentucky Derby after a failed drugs test, has blamed the situation on “cancel culture”.
Medina Spirit won this month’s Derby by half a length at Churchill Downs but on Sunday it emerged the horse had tested positive for double the legal amount of the steroid betamethasone after the race. Churchill Downs has suspended Baffert f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Lutz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Brexit trade deals mean firms will miss out on freeport benefits]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/post-brexit-trade-deals-mean-firms-will-miss-out-on-freeport-benefits</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/10/post-brexit-trade-deals-mean-firms-will-miss-out-on-freeport-benefits"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:56:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government admits agreements with 23 countries include clauses prohibiting use of tax breaks

Companies operating in freeports being launched under Boris Johnson’s post-Brexit levelling up agenda will not get the full benefits of the new tax efficient zones if they export to some countries, the government has admitted.
Officials said post-Brexit trade deals with 23 nations – including Canada, Norway and Switzerland – included clauses that prohibit manufacturers in freeport-type zones from utilising the tax …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top-down approach has been Labour’s downfall | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/top-down-approach-has-been-labours-downfall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/top-down-approach-has-been-labours-downfall"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to an article by John Harris on where the seeds of Labour’s renewal lie
John Harris is right (Labour’s crisis comes from the huge gap between politics and people, 9 May), but just reconnecting with “the wonders of ordinary life” won’t be enough. Labour should be asking itself some existential questions – what is it for, what does it really want? If the answer is “power above all else”, then it’s not going to happen, because the Tories do that so much better. Voters know that what’s going on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A proper appreciation of arts degrees | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/10/a-proper-appreciation-of-arts-degrees</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/10/a-proper-appreciation-of-arts-degrees"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:34:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lesley Barnes, Michael J Walsh and Marion Hine on the importance of the arts and humanities

The idea that the arts do not matter as much as other subjects is not new (Editorial, 6 May). When my daughter started her A-levels, the head of sixth form told her that it was time to give up her hobby (he meant playing the piano) and concentrate on “proper” subjects. Fortunately, she ignored him, went on to study at the Guildhall and has been performing and teaching for the best part of 30 years.
Lesley Barnes
Gre…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero daily Covid deaths reported in England, Northern Ireland and Scotland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/zero-daily-covid-deaths-reported-in-england-northern-ireland-and-scotland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/zero-daily-covid-deaths-reported-in-england-northern-ireland-and-scotland"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:29:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts caution figures subject to time lags but say news reflects impact of lockdowns and vaccination

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

England has recorded zero daily Covid deaths for the first time since July, in a situation welcomed by experts who said it reflected the impact of lockdowns and vaccination against the disease.
Monday marked the first time since 30 July last year that no deaths within 28 days of positive Covid test were reported in England, following Monday 3 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top Russian doctor at Navalny clinic found after disappearance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/top-russian-doctor-at-navalny-clinic-found-after-disappearance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/top-russian-doctor-at-navalny-clinic-found-after-disappearance"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:27:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alexander Murakhovsky speaks to press three days after going missing while on holiday in a Siberian forest 

The former chief physician of the hospital where the Russian protest leader Alexei Navalny was first treated for novichok poisoning has been found alive days after disappearing into a Siberian forest.
Alexander Murakhovsky emerged from a forest in the Omsk region on Monday three days after vanishing while on holiday, abandoning an all-terrain vehicle (ATV) miles from a hunting lodge where he was stay…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hear me out: why 2005’s House of Wax isn’t a bad movie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/hear-me-out-2005-house-of-wax-paris-hilton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/hear-me-out-2005-house-of-wax-paris-hilton"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:10:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest in our series of writers sticking up for hated films is a call to reconsider Paris Hilton’s surprisingly effective performance in the horror remake
The stars of 2005’s House of Wax remake were all having their moments in Hollywood when they joined the reimagined slasher version of Vincent Price’s 1953 classic. Elisha Cuthbert had just broken out in 2004’s Girl Next Door while Chad Michael Murray was coming off both Freaky Friday and A Cinderella Story. Jared Padalecki starred opposite the Olsen T…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Briscuso</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giro d’Italia: Taco van der Hoorn claims superb solo victory on stage three]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/giro-ditalia-taco-van-der-hoorn-claims-superb-solo-victory-on-stage-three-cycling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/giro-ditalia-taco-van-der-hoorn-claims-superb-solo-victory-on-stage-three-cycling"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:08:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grand Tour debutant pulls off remarkable victory

Cyclist had posted he was ready to quit on Twitter

Taco van der Hoorn took a remarkable solo victory from the breakaway as Filippo Ganna retained the pink jersey on stage three of the Giro d’Italia. The 27-year-old Van der Hoorn, making his Grand Tour debut in this race, held his hand to his mouth in shock as he crossed the line just four seconds before the charging peloton in Canale.
Davide Cimolai won the race for second place just ahead of Peter Sagan, w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All university students in England allowed to return from 17 May]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/10/all-university-students-england-allowed-return-from-17-may</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/10/all-university-students-england-allowed-return-from-17-may"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM confirms further reopening of campuses, although many teaching timetables will already have ended

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

All university students in England are to be finally allowed to return to campus for face-to-face teaching next week, the prime minister confirmed on Monday, although many institutions will already have finished their teaching timetable.
About 1 million students who have continued to study online since Christmas, as other areas of society have b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK government has to show why Scotland should stay in union, says Gove]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/uk-government-show-why-scotland-should-stay-union-michael-gove</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/uk-government-show-why-scotland-should-stay-union-michael-gove"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T16:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cabinet Office minister brushes aside questions about potential legal challenge to another referendum
Michael Gove has said Boris Johnson’s government has to show that Scotland would be better off remaining in the union, after he brushed aside questions about a legal challenge over a Scottish independence referendum.
Gove refused to rule out going to court if Holyrood were to pass a referendum bill but said the overriding priority was for each part of the UK to collaborate on a joint strategy to deal with t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell Scotland editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We even performed it in front of the pope!’ – how we made Godspell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/10/performed-front-of-pope-how-we-made-godspell-jeremy-irons</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/10/performed-front-of-pope-how-we-made-godspell-jeremy-irons"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:59:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Religious groups didn’t like Jesus wearing a Superman shirt or the lack of a resurrection. So we told them the curtain call was the resurrection – when Jesus runs on and takes a bow’
Godspell opened in London in November 1971 and ran at the same time as Jesus Christ Superstar. It was the Rolls-Royce to our Ford Fiesta. I was 23, had just left the Bristol Old Vic company and was auditioning for everything. There were 30 of us lined up along the stage for the audition. I was on the end and taller than everyo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Chris Wiegand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gwyneth Paltrow broke down and ate bread during quarantine. How did you surprise yourself?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/gwyneth-paltrow-pandemic-lowest-point</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/gwyneth-paltrow-pandemic-lowest-point"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:52:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Open thread: the pandemic dragged even celebrities down so how were the rest of us mortals meant to hold it together?
In the latest celebrity attempt to prove they had it just as hard as normal people in the pandemic, Gwyneth Paltrow has admitted she was driven to extremes during quarantine.
Things got dark. She admitted to drinking as many as two cocktails a night during lockdown (quinoa-based whiskey cocktails, of course); and even sometimes eating bread and pasta – shock, horror!
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Poppy Noor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England hope Twickenham will be 50% full for July Tests with USA and Canada]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/england-hope-twickenham-will-be-50-full-for-july-tests-with-usa-and-canada</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/10/england-hope-twickenham-will-be-50-full-for-july-tests-with-usa-and-canada"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:51:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summer tour of North America has been switched to home soil
Saxons revived as England A and will play Scotland A in June

The Rugby Football Union is hopeful Twickenham will be 50% full for England’s summer Tests against the USA and Canada in July after confirming the decision to switch the proposed tour of North America to home soil.
Subject to government guidance, the RFU is optimistic of being allowed to admit 41,000 supporters for the matches against the USA – which will take place on 4 July – and Canad…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is Boris Johnson’s Caribbean holiday under scrutiny?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/why-is-boris-johnsons-caribbean-holiday-under-scrutiny</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/why-is-boris-johnsons-caribbean-holiday-under-scrutiny"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:49:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parliamentary standards watchdog is investigating the funding of the PM’s 10-day trip to Mustique

Boris Johnson being investigated over Caribbean holiday

Boris Johnson is facing yet another investigation into whether donations he received were properly declared. The parliamentary standards commissioner, Kathryn Stone, has announced she is investigating a possible breach of the MPs’ code of conduct over the funding of a 10-day holiday the prime minister and his fiancee, Carrie Symonds, took to Mustique las…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woman deceived by spy cop sees relationship as rape, inquiry hears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/woman-deceived-by-spy-cop-sees-relationship-as-inquiry-hears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/woman-deceived-by-spy-cop-sees-relationship-as-inquiry-hears"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Undercover officer Vince Miller accused of lying after saying he slept with ‘Madeleine’ only once
An undercover police officer has been accused of lying to a public inquiry by a woman who said that he deceived her into a sexual relationship that she regards as rape.
The woman, known only as Madeleine, told the inquiry that the police spy, Vince Miller, deceived her into a sexual relationship that lasted a couple of months. He has claimed that they had a sexual encounter that lasted one night.
 Continue read…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Evans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s chance will come when Johnson’s bogus promises start to crumble | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/labour-johnson-keir-starmer-party-tories</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/labour-johnson-keir-starmer-party-tories"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T15:14:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer’s party must stop the bile-filled civil wars – and wait for the IOUs sprayed out by the Tories to be called in 

Labour is doing what Labour does best after a defeat: picking itself up, dusting itself down and starting all over again by knocking the living daylights out of itself. Since last Friday’s disastrous result in Hartlepool, blame has been scattered in every direction as bile-filled civil wars resume. Whatever happened, Keir Starmer appearing to scapegoat Angela Rayner with a bungled fi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India: dozens of suspected Covid victims wash up on Ganges River banks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/india-dozens-of-suspected-covid-victims-wash-up-on-ganges-river-banks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/india-dozens-of-suspected-covid-victims-wash-up-on-ganges-river-banks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:42:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Locals believe bodies were dumped in river because cremation sites are overwhelmed

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Dozens of bodies believed to be Covid-19 victims have washed up on the banks of the Ganges River in northern India as the pandemic spreads into India’s vast rural hinterland, overwhelming local health facilities as well as crematoriums and cemeteries.
Local official Ashok Kumar said that about 40 corpses washed up in Buxar district near the border between Bihar a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in New Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Scotland’s election result is unlikely to hasten a referendum | Michael Keating]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/scotland-election-result-referendum-independence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/scotland-election-result-referendum-independence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:27:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scots are still evenly split on independence, and a lengthy constitutional stalemate seems likely
Opinion polls for most of the past three years have shown Scotland to be evenly divided between supporters of union and independence. The Scottish parliament election result confirms this again. While the Scottish National party narrowly failed to gain an overall majority, independence supporters (the SNP and the Greens) have 72 of the 129 seats. Scottish electors cast two votes. The first is for a constituency…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Keating</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU citizens applying for settled status face legal limbo due to backlog]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/eu-citizens-applying-for-settled-status-face-legal-limbo-due-to-backlog</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/10/eu-citizens-applying-for-settled-status-face-legal-limbo-due-to-backlog"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:25:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UK settlement scheme closes on 30 June, but Home Office has 320,000 applications to process
Hundreds of thousands of European citizens could find themselves in limbo after 30 June and left without documented legal rights to remain in the UK if the Home Office does not clear a backlog of more than 320,000 applications for post-Brexit residency status, campaigners have warned.
There are just 50 days to go before the government’s EU settlement scheme closes and the most recent government statistics show that o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[La Liga keeps on giving. And taking away. And then giving back again | Sid Lowe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/la-liga-keeps-on-giving-and-taking-away-and-then-giving-back-again-real-madrid-atletico-barcelona-sevilla</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/la-liga-keeps-on-giving-and-taking-away-and-then-giving-back-again-real-madrid-atletico-barcelona-sevilla"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:23:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was billed as the weekend that would decide everything. But the finish line still seems further away than ever
Diego Simeone wasn’t watching the moment his fate fell back into his hands. After 35 exhausting weeks, every second of every game clawing at the nerves, the tension had become too much even for him. On Saturday afternoon, Atlético Madrid drew 0-0 at the Camp Nou; on Sunday night, Real Madrid faced Sevilla at Valdebebas, gifted the chance to go top for the first time in seven months, finally rele…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339203</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/variable-aspect-ratio-card-with-conic-gradients-meeting-along-the-diagonal/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently came across an interesting problem. I had to implement a grid of cards with a variable (user-set) aspect ratio that was stored in a --ratio custom property. Boxes with a certain aspect ratio are a classic problem in &#8230;
The post Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Tudor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marianne Faithfull, AJ Tracey and more: May’s best album reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/ng-interactive/2021/may/10/marianne-faithfull-aj-tracey-and-more-mays-best-album-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/ng-interactive/2021/may/10/marianne-faithfull-aj-tracey-and-more-mays-best-album-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:08:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read all the Guardian and Observer’s four- and five-star album reviews from the last month, spanning pop, classical and more
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK downgrades Covid-19 alert threat level]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/uk-downgrades-covid-19-alert-threat-level</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/uk-downgrades-covid-19-alert-threat-level"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T13:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medical chiefs cut threat level from 4 to 3, pointing to impact of vaccinations and social distancing

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The UK’s four chief medical officers have agreed the Covid-19 alert level should move from level 4 to level 3, thanks to the success of the vaccination programme and social distancing restrictions.
This means the epidemic is in general circulation but transmission of the virus is no longer deemed to be high or rising exponentially.
 Continue re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nepal is being overwhelmed by Covid. We need help | KP Sharma Oli]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/nepal-covid-uk-g7</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/10/nepal-covid-uk-g7"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T13:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are deep bonds between our nations, and so I appeal to the UK, chair of the G7, for urgent assistance

KP Sharma Oli is the prime minister of Nepal

As I write this, my country is battling a new and brutal wave of the Covid-19 pandemic. The rise in the number of infections poses a serious challenge to our brave doctors, nurses, other care providers, citizen volunteers and the entire health service system.
Nepal’s history is one of hardship and struggle, yet this pandemic is pushing even us to our limi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>KP Sharma Oli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clashes in Jerusalem and fireworks in Russia – Monday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/10/clashes-jerusalem-fireworks-russia-monday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/10/clashes-jerusalem-fireworks-russia-monday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T13:11:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s travel green list sends Madeira flight bookings soaring]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/england-travel-green-list-sends-madeira-holiday-flight-bookings-soaring</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/england-travel-green-list-sends-madeira-holiday-flight-bookings-soaring"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T13:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portugal is only major European ‘sun and sand’ destination on list of countries for quarantine-free travel 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Notorious crosswinds can make for some nauseating landings and the relatively short runway is not for the faint-hearted.
Yet after months of lockdown it seems that not even the reputation of its international airport is deterring people in England from looking to Madeira, which has had the biggest jump in popularity among destinations on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn, Hilary Osborne and Sam Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feathers, organza and unironed pyjamas: why fashion can’t get enough of the Mitford mythology]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/10/feathers-organza-and-unironed-pyjamas-why-fashion-cant-get-enough-of-the-mitford-mythology</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/10/feathers-organza-and-unironed-pyjamas-why-fashion-cant-get-enough-of-the-mitford-mythology"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T13:02:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a new adaptation of Nancy Mitford’s The Pursuit of Love on our screens, the peculiarly Mitfordian combination of ballgowns and homemade knits look appealing again
“Elegance in England,” wrote Nancy Mitford “is of such different stuff from that in any other country that it is not easy to make foreigners believe in it at all.” Nancy – and her aristo sisters Diana, Decca, Debo, Pam and Unity – have been part of the case for English elegance since the 30s thanks to a mixture of tweedy suits, ballgowns, tea…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Cochrane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Down boy: why grumpy dogs are more intelligent than happy-go-lucky hounds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/down-boy-why-grumpy-dogs-are-more-intelligent-than-happy-go-lucky-hounds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/down-boy-why-grumpy-dogs-are-more-intelligent-than-happy-go-lucky-hounds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:58:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worried that your canine companion is disobedient, territorial and quick to bark? Research suggests it’s probably a clever clogs 
Name: Grumpy dogs.
Appearance: Just adorable.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Train firm’s ‘worker bonus’ email is actually cybersecurity test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/train-firms-worker-bonus-email-is-actually-cyber-security-test</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/train-firms-worker-bonus-email-is-actually-cyber-security-test"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:43:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[West Midlands Trains workers discover email promising one-off payment is ‘phishing simulation test’
A rail union has hit out at a “cynical and shocking stunt” after a train company emailed staff to promise a bonus to workers who had run trains during the pandemic – only to reveal it was in fact a test of their cybersecurity awareness.
West Midlands Trains emailed about 2,500 employees with a message saying its managing director, Julian Edwards, wanted to thank them for their hard work over the past year und…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It wasn’t pretty at first’: the Welsh wildlife haven born out of disaster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/wales-wildlife-haven-born-out-of-disaster-cwm-ivy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/10/wales-wildlife-haven-born-out-of-disaster-cwm-ivy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decision by National Trust not to fix sea defences at Cwm Ivy has created a salt marsh rich in flora and fauna
Swallows dart above the reed beds while a little egret hunts among the bluey-green marshland grass and a pair of curlews circle, long, curving bills clearly visible, before heading out to sea. It is so quiet that you can hear the crackling sound that mud shrimps make as they feed in their burrows.
For centuries, this parcel of land on the Gower Peninsula in south-west Wales, Cwm Ivy, was an ordinar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experts call for mandatory recycling of products containing rare metals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/10/recycling-rare-metals-climate-green-technology</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/10/recycling-rare-metals-climate-green-technology"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disc drives, circuit boards, fluorescent lamps and batteries for electric vehicles could be among affected products 
Rare elements such as indium, yttrium, neodymium, cobalt and lithium are vital for the production of low-carbon technology, but many are being thrown away because of the lack of a requirement to recycle them, industry experts have warned.
Concern is growing over the future supply of such elements, as the switch to green technology – including electric vehicles, solar panels and low-carbon hea…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bad call: why do characters never say bye on the phone?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/10/why-do-characters-never-say-bye-on-the-phone</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/10/why-do-characters-never-say-bye-on-the-phone"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watch any film or TV show and you’ll notice that nobody ever says goodbye. Are they too busy – or just rude?

In the Guide’s weekly Solved! column, we look into a crucial pop-culture question you’ve been burning to know the answer to – and settle it
I absolutely hate talking on the phone. I am one of those infuriating friends who’d rather have a long, winding text conversation than speak on the phone to arrange a simple plan. People under the age of 60 who still leave voicemails? Seek help. And unknown numb…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Staples</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China tourist left clinging to 100m-high bridge after glass panels smash]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/china-tourist-bridge-glass-panels-smash-longjing-city</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/china-tourist-bridge-glass-panels-smash-longjing-city"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:19:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Man rescued after sudden gusts shattered panels on bridge in Longjing city
A man was left stranded on a glass-bottomed suspension bridge in north-eastern China after sudden gale-force winds shattered the transparent panels around him.
The man was on the 100-metre-high bridge at Piyan Mountain in Longjing city, when it was hit by sudden strong weather, the local tourism department said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Champions League final could be switched to Wembley or Lisbon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/champions-league-final-could-be-switched-from-istanbul-to-wembley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/10/champions-league-final-could-be-switched-from-istanbul-to-wembley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:56:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Uefa holding talks with government over move from Istanbul

Boris Johnson confirms fans will return next week

Wembley and Lisbon are being considered as options for the Champions League final as negotiations continue over moving the showpiece match from Istanbul.
A meeting was held on Monday between Uefa and the UK government over the location of the final, which is to be contested by Manchester City and Chelsea and due to be played on 29 May, but ended without conclusion. Government sources said discussio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners say UK airport expansion plans must be suspended amid new climate goals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/campaigners-say-uk-airport-expansion-plans-must-be-suspended-amid-new-climate-goals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/campaigners-say-uk-airport-expansion-plans-must-be-suspended-amid-new-climate-goals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:42:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In letter to ministers, groups say aviation strategy needed after sector included in binding climate targets
The UK government must suspend all airport expansion plans until it sets out how they fit with its legally binding climate targets and the advice of its own experts, campaigners have warned.
In a letter to ministers, groups opposing planned expansions at eight airports around the country say the government’s recent decision to include aviation in its binding climate targets mean the expansion plans m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: who will you hug first when the restrictions are lifted?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:30:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government is expected to allow hugging in England from 17 May. Whose embrace have you missed?
Hugging and mixing indoors with friends and family is expected to be allowed in England from next week. We’d like to know who you look forward to hugging first once the restrictions are lifted. 
After months of distancing, whose embrace have you missed the most? When did you last see them? Do you have concerns?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French soldiers accuse government of trying to ‘silence’ warnings of civil war]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/french-soldiers-accuse-government-of-trying-to-silence-warnings-of-civil-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/french-soldiers-accuse-government-of-trying-to-silence-warnings-of-civil-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:04:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Second letter from military staff says threat of punishment ‘quite perverse’ and repeats: ‘Civil war is brewing in France’
Serving members of the French military have fired a second salvo at Emmanuel Macron’s government in an open letter accusing it of “cowardice, deceit, perversion”, just weeks after a first letter said the country was heading for “civil war”.
Like the first letter, it appears in the rightwing magazine Valeurs Actuelles. It was reportedly signed anonymously “by active military personnel” a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vermicelli alla Sophia Loren: Rachel Roddy’s recipe for pasta with parsley pesto | A kitchen in Rome]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/10/vermicelli-alla-sophia-loren-rachel-roddy-recipe-for-pasta-parsley-pesto</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/10/vermicelli-alla-sophia-loren-rachel-roddy-recipe-for-pasta-parsley-pesto"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A favourite old cookbook (and a pile of parsley to use up) inspire this simple salsa verde – parsley, anchovies, capers, olives – in a fairytale tangle of vermicelli
The story starts with a pregnant woman stealing parsley from a garden. She gets caught by the owner, a furious ogress, who, as penance, makes the woman promise that one day she will hand over her child. The child is born, and beautiful, and named Petrosinella, the old Italian word for parsley. As she grows, her mother warns her to stay away fro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Roddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘She came to my room and told me about some dead seals she’d seen’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/how-we-met-she-came-to-my-room-and-told-me-about-some-dead-seals-shed-seen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/how-we-met-she-came-to-my-room-and-told-me-about-some-dead-seals-shed-seen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wojtek, 49, and Sonia, 43, met in Wales when she was visiting the UK. After years of long-distance love, they now live in Cali, Colombia
In October 2006, Sonia arrived in the UK from Costa Rica after an exhausting journey. “I was coming to Bangor University for three months to work on my PhD in agroforestry,” she says. At the time, Wojtek was doing a PhD in the same field and had recently returned from studying in Ghana and Cameroon. “I had a house where I rented rooms to other students,” he says. “My frien…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The people who want to keep masking: ‘It’s like an invisibility cloak’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/the-people-who-want-to-keep-masking-its-like-an-invisibility-cloak</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/the-people-who-want-to-keep-masking-its-like-an-invisibility-cloak"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than a year into the pandemic, some people prefer to keep wearing their face mask – even outdoors in public
She’s been fully vaccinated for three weeks, but Francesca, a 46-year-old professor, does not plan to abandon the face mask that she’s come to view as a kind of “invisibility cloak” just yet.
“Maybe it’s because I’m a New Yorker or maybe it’s because I always feel like I have to present my best self to the world, but it has been such a relief to feel anonymous,” she said. “It’s like having a forc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A maddening grief: my year of miscarriages and how I got through it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/maddening-grief-my-year-of-miscarriages-and-how-i-got-through-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/maddening-grief-my-year-of-miscarriages-and-how-i-got-through-it"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navigating an uncharted landscape, I found solace in an unlikely place
After my third consecutive miscarriage I began baking bread.
This was 2019, a year and change before quarantine boredom ignited a sourdough craze that lit up everyone’s lockdown Instagram feeds with images of fresh and hot loaves.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra King</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shaun Ryder: ‘I was a heroin addict for 20-odd years, but there’s been no damage off that’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/10/shaun-ryder-i-was-a-heroin-addict-for-20-odd-years-but-theres-been-no-damage-off-that</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/10/shaun-ryder-i-was-a-heroin-addict-for-20-odd-years-but-theres-been-no-damage-off-that"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From ADHD to alopecia and learning the alphabet at 28, the Happy Mondays singer has had a wild, eventful life. He discusses hedonism, parenting – and why he has to spend so much time correcting Bez

Shaun Ryder is being uncharacteristically quiet. That’s because he’s mistakenly stuck himself on mute and can’t work out how to turn on the microphone of the computer he’s on. We spend a rather amusing (and awkward) five minutes mouthing silently at each other, pointing fingers and shrugging shoulders, while Ryd…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meghan: Covid has wiped out 'generation of economic gain' for women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/video/2021/may/10/meghan-covid-has-wiped-out-generation-of-economic-gain-for-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/video/2021/may/10/meghan-covid-has-wiped-out-generation-of-economic-gain-for-women"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T08:50:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Duchess of Sussex has made her first television appearance since her and Prince Harry's interview with Oprah Winfrey.

Meghan warned women had been 'disproportionately affected' by the pandemic in a pre-recorded message for Global Citizen's Vax Live charity concert.
The Duchess of Sussex said 47 million more women around the world were expected to slip into extreme poverty and called for equitable distribution of Covid vaccines. President Joe Biden, Harry and Jennifer Lopez were among the big names who …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 days of Myanmar’s military coup – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/10/100-days-of-myanmar-military-coup-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/10/100-days-of-myanmar-military-coup-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T07:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Myanmar has been in turmoil since the country’s civilian leader, Aung San Suu Kyi, was deposed on 1 February, triggering a mass uprising of daily protests and a nationwide civil servants’ boycott. As journalists are not officially allowed to report from the country, the photographers’ names have been withheld
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Madonna: Truth or Dare at 30 – the most revealing pop star documentary ever?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/madonna-truth-or-dare-at-30-the-most-revealing-pop-star-documentary-ever</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/10/madonna-truth-or-dare-at-30-the-most-revealing-pop-star-documentary-ever"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T07:09:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 1991 hit film gave us the pop star at her most open, inviting us into her uncensored world, a far cry from the tightly protected celeb docs we see today 
When teenage pop phenomenon Billie Eilish recently unveiled a drastic new image on the cover of Vogue magazine, the internet went into feverish overdrive. Previously distinguished by raven-dark locks and loosely androgynous, body-concealing attire, the singer instead turned to hyper-feminised exaggeration: bombshell-style platinum curls atop a tightly …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lodge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The four fish I would still eat – even after watching Seaspiracy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/10/the-four-fish-i-would-still-eat-even-after-watching-seaspiracy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/10/the-four-fish-i-would-still-eat-even-after-watching-seaspiracy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T06:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hit Netflix documentary encourages viewers to give up seafood altogether. But when it comes to a sustainable diet, I do believe in a few exceptions

Seaspiracy, the buzzy, frenetic, slick, sloppy, confused and gripping documentary that premiered on Netflix in March, is often wrong but mostly right. Led by Ali Tabrizi, and produced by the maker of Cowspiracy, Kip Andersen, the film takes you on a bumpy ride with pit stops at every imaginable ocean horror: from the slaughtered dolphins of Taiji in Japan t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Greenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Semuliki: on the trail of the ADF’s Islamist militants | photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/welcome-to-semuliki-on-the-trail-of-the-adfs-islamist-militants-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/welcome-to-semuliki-on-the-trail-of-the-adfs-islamist-militants-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T06:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photojournalist Hugh Kinsella Cunningham has been embedded with Congolese soldiers in the DRC’s ‘triangle of death’. The elusive insurgents they are hunting have pledged allegiance to Islamic State
At the border between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Uganda, in a vast territory that ranges from the lofty Rwenzori mountains to the lush rainforest of the Semliki valley, one of the world’s most active militant groups is responsible for the massacre of hundreds of civilians.
The ADF (Allied Democratic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Kinsella Cunningham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We thank your government for our full pockets’ – Calais smugglers speak]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/calais-smuggler-gangs-channel-migrants-uk-security</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/calais-smuggler-gangs-channel-migrants-uk-security"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T06:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the UK pours millions into security measures, migrants say the gangs who control the Channel just get more powerful
“Sorry, my battery’s low because I drained it watching YouTube tutorials on how to assemble dinghies,” Abuzar says. He is speaking on a video call from the abandoned shed in Calais he calls home. “I want to join my brother for asylum in the UK, but I have to work for smugglers because I don’t have enough money to pay for the crossing.
“They hide boat parts on the beaches for me to assemble …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mathilda Mallinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump’s grip over Republicans hardens as party cleaves to election ‘big lie’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/republicans-trump-election-big-lie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/10/republicans-trump-election-big-lie"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T06:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Far from losing influence over the party, critics say, Trump has in fact burrowed far into its DNA so that the two are now all but inseparable
Ron DeSantis was exultant. “The way Florida did it I think inspires confidence; I think that’s how elections should be run,” the state governor told reporters last November. “Rather than us be at the centre of a Bush v Gore in 2020, we’re now being looked at as the state that did it right.”
This boast of a smoothly run election just six months ago makes DeSantis’s ac…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The next decade will be all about heat’: can Athens head off climate crisis?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/heat-athens-climate-crisis-mayor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/heat-athens-climate-crisis-mayor"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T04:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mayor overseeing a green regeneration in city where temperatures can already surpass 40C
Like every Athens mayor, Kostas Bakoyannis is acutely aware of the illustrious heritage of one of the world’s oldest cities. After all, he says, it is busts of Pericles and his mistress Aspasia that adorn the entrance of the neoclassical town hall. From the windows of his cavernous office, he can glimpse the Parthenon through the jumble of concrete buildings and antennas.
But Bakoyannis prefers to talk about the present…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Body of arrested Myanmar poet Khet Thi returned to family with organs missing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/body-of-arrested-myanmar-poet-khet-thi-returned-to-family-with-organs-missing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/10/body-of-arrested-myanmar-poet-khet-thi-returned-to-family-with-organs-missing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T02:18:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wife says Khet Thi, whose poetry inspired resistance to junta, died after being taken for interrogation on Saturday
Myanmar poet Khet Thi, whose works declare resistance to the ruling junta, has died in detention and his body was returned with the organs removed, his family said.
A spokesperson for the junta did not answer calls to request comment on the death of Khet Thi, who had penned the line “They shoot in the head, but they don’t know the revolution is in the heart.” His Facebook page said he was 45.
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Post Office scandal – part 1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/10/exposing-the-great-post-office-scandal-part-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/10/exposing-the-great-post-office-scandal-part-1"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T02:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a computer system installed by the Post Office went haywire, it led to the convictions of scores of subpostmasters for theft and false accounting. Lives were wrecked. But after a devastating ruling by the court of appeal, the full truth can now be finally told about the extent of the great Post Office scandal
When the Post Office installed a new accounting system called Horizon across its branches in 1999, it hoped to bring a lumbering and much-loved institution into the 21st century. What happened nex…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Janet Skinner and Richard Brooks; produced by Sami Kent and Ned Carter Miles; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer’s Labour shadow cabinet reshuffle: the winners and losers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/09/keir-starmers-labour-shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-the-winners-and-losers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/09/keir-starmers-labour-shadow-cabinet-reshuffle-the-winners-and-losers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-09T21:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour leader brings new blood into top roles after poor election results on Thursday

Elections 2021 live - latest news and reaction

The Labour leader, Keir Starmer, has embarked on a reshuffle of his top team after a series of disappointing results in Thursday’s elections. Here are the major moves: 
Angela Rayner: moved from party chair and national campaigns coordinator to shadow Cabinet Office minister; remains deputy party leader
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart, Jessica Elgot and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['People got nervous if a bag was left on a chair': Paul Johnson on Northern Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/09/guardian-200-paul-johnson-northern-ireland-rory-carroll</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/09/guardian-200-paul-johnson-northern-ireland-rory-carroll"/>
        <updated>2021-05-09T14:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s current Ireland correspondent speaks to a predecessor to find out how the job has changed over the past 30 years
Paul Johnson has a vivid memory of one of his most dispiriting moments as the Guardian’s Ireland correspondent.
It was April 1986 and he was covering a Democratic Unionist party (DUP) conference. A warmup speaker for the party leader, Ian Paisley, electrified the audience with a suggestion.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Me and my Guardian: ‘I was hooked from the start’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/may/09/me-and-my-guardian-readers-first-discovered-paper-website</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/may/09/me-and-my-guardian-readers-first-discovered-paper-website"/>
        <updated>2021-05-09T13:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian readers around the world tell us how they first discovered the paper and what it has meant to them since
It was the late 60s. Every Sunday during term time a small group of us would take the bus into Bristol, to a small coffee bar with a jukebox.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers, as told to Sophie Zeldin-O'Neill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: sandcastles on America’s final frontier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/may/09/the-big-picture-sandcastles-on-americas-final-frontier</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/may/09/the-big-picture-sandcastles-on-americas-final-frontier"/>
        <updated>2021-05-09T06:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul McDonough’s photographs of the US Pacific coast in the 1970s conjure a sense of a society that has run out of road
Joan Didion, philosopher-in-chief of the American west, once observed that the Pacific coast was a place “in which the mind is troubled by some buried but ineradicable suspicion that things better work out here, because here, beneath that immense bleached sky, is where we run out of continent.”
Paul McDonough’s 1970s photographs from that coast, collected in a new book, Headed West, seem t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic captured in patchwork art – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/08/the-pandemic-captured-in-patchwork-art-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/08/the-pandemic-captured-in-patchwork-art-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T16:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Pinochet-era Chile, a group of women known as the Arpilleristas denounced the violent regime by creating patchwork images out of scraps. That movement is the inspiration behind a new show, All in the Same Storm: Pandemic Patchwork Stories ( 19 May-30 August) , a collaboration between the De La Warr Pavilion in East Sussex and the local Refugee Buddy Project, founded by Rossana Leal. 
The patches, she says, express how people felt in lockdown: “fear, loneliness, gratitude to the NHS”. Created by refugees,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have you been affected by the recent GWR and LNER train cancellations?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/08/have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-gwr-and-lner-train-cancellations</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/08/have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-gwr-and-lner-train-cancellations"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:29:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from those who have been affected by cancellations from Great Western Railway and London North Eastern Railway as they inspect trains for hairline cracks
Great Western Railway and London North Eastern Railway have suspended rail services over concerns about hairline cracks in carriages.
Passengers are being urged not to travel as urgent inspections are carried out in more than 1,000 trains. It comes after hairline cracks were found in several high-speed trains.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faith during the Covid pandemic – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/faith-during-covid-pandemic-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/08/faith-during-covid-pandemic-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-08T09:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Suki Dhanda documents how different religious beliefs have helped people come through the coronavirus crisis and lockdown restrictions in England
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suki Dhanda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Systems Book Recommendations – Learn How to Build and Understand ML Systems]]></title>
        <id>609558382cd0545b5e943c6f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-systems-book-recommendations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T21:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Good friends, good books, and a sleepy conscience: this is the ideal life.” ― Mark TwainI hope you’re reading this blog in your pjs looking forward to a rejuvenating and healthy weekend.  I have been working on multiple projects lately, from creating Machine Learing Engineering and Machine Learning Operations courses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recursion Might Seem Scary – But it Doesn&#x27;t Have to Be]]></title>
        <id>609551f02cd0545b5e943bc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recursion-doesnt-have-to-be-scary/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T16:59:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any concept that we don't fully understand can be scary at first. Recursion is a topic that programming students don't learn right away. But that doesn't mean it needs to be scary or cause anxiety. In fact, recursion is a concept that we can define rather simply. According to Wikipedia:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is CSS a Programming Language?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339781</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-css-a-programming-language/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real distaste for this question. It might seem like a fun question to dig into on the surface, but the way it enters public discourse rarely seems to be in good faith. There are ulterior motives at &#8230;
The post Is CSS a Programming Language? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339574</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:54:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These are a few great links about typography that have been burning a hole in my saved bookmarks folder that I'm just now getting around to sharing. There's good stuff in there, from how to choose typefaces for app design to ideas for how to fix the concept of font sizing in CSS.
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rukmini Iyer’s recipe for baked ricotta with new-season asparagus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:11:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A one-dish wonder full of the joys of spring, The Roasting Tin author’s vibrant, verdant traybake is ready to shop on Ocado.com
This is a lovely seasonal traybake, starring a whole baked ricotta at the centre. Drizzled with olive oil, sea salt and herbs, the warm ricotta works beautifully with the crisp, lemony roast potatoes, the garlic, peas and asparagus. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rukmini Iyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day three: women, from suffragists to sexploitation

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we got wrong: the Guardian’s worst errors of judgment over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-what-we-got-wrong-the-guardians-worst-errors-of-judgment-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/07/guardian-200-what-we-got-wrong-the-guardians-worst-errors-of-judgment-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T06:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fiercely critical of Abraham Lincoln and at times racist, this newspaper’s leader columns did not always get it right

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber

A daily newspaper cannot publish for 200 years without getting some things wrong. This one has made its share of mistakes.
There will always be errors of news judgment given the nature of the work. Tight deadlines meant the sinking of the Titanic was relegated to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Randeep Ramesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I Email…]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339822</id>
        <link href="https://www.caniemail.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:38:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m 85% certain you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Use&#8230;, I bet there is only a 13% chance that you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Email&#8230;. It&#8217;s the same vibe—detailed support information for web platform features—except instead &#8230;
The post Can I Email&#8230; appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noel Clarke and the allegations that have shaken the film and television industry – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalists Lucy Osborne and Sirin Kale discuss the allegations of verbal abuse, bullying and sexual harassment by 20 women against Clarke
On 10 April 2021, the actor, director and writer Noel Clarke was awarded one of the most prestigious accolades bestowed by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts, the prize for outstanding British contribution to cinema. But 13 days before presenting Clarke with his award, Bafta was informed about the existence of several allegations of verbal abuse, bullying an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Lucy Osborne, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is &quot;Lifting State Up&quot; in React?]]></title>
        <id>609409c201fc34080ef81f97</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-lifting-state-up-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T21:41:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a simple and practical example what it means to "lift state up" in React, and how it can help you build your applications. Lifting state up is a common pattern that is essential for React developers to know. It helps you avoid more complex (and often unnecessary) patterns]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340015</id>
        <link href="https://betterprogramming.pub/apparently-you-can-use-route53-as-a-blazingly-fast-database-dd416b56b005"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T20:03:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Route53 is DNS management service by AWS. DNS is absolutely not a database, and yet here&#8217;s Nicholas Martin writing up some very clever trickery originally done by Corey Quinn:
When you think about it, DNS configuration is actually a 
&#8230;
The post Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339936</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-googles-new-page-experience-update-means-for-images-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T19:57:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to forget that, as a search engine, Google doesn’t just compare keywords to generate search results. Google knows that if people don’t enjoy their experience on a web page, they won’t stay on the page long enough to &#8230;
The post What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn How to Use the Chrome DevTools to Troubleshoot Websites]]></title>
        <id>609415eb2cd0545b5e943534</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-how-to-use-the-chrome-devtools-to-troubleshoot-websites/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:26:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome DevTools is a set of web developer tools built directly into the Google Chrome browser. They can be super helpful for web developers. We just published a crash course that will teach you how to use Chrome DevTools to improve your productivity as a web developer. You will learn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optional Types in Swift – How to Use and Unwrap Optionals]]></title>
        <id>60939bde01fc34080ef81a19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/optional-types-in-swift/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T16:06:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're coming from Java, C++, or other object-oriented languages, chances are that you've never come across optional types or "optionals". And you might be quite surprised to know that such a concept exists in Swift. Optionals are a fundamental topic that you need to thoroughly understand to code in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339586</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-state-pseudo-classes-in-chrome/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T14:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is an increasing number of “custom” features on the web platform. We have custom properties (--my-property), custom elements (&#60;my-element&#62;), and custom events (new CustomEvent('myEvent')). At one point, we might even get custom media &#8230;
The post Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Šime Vidas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how have you been affected by the fishing row in Jersey?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/06/tell-us-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-fishing-row-in-jersey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/06/tell-us-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-fishing-row-in-jersey"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T09:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Jersey about how they feel about the situation. Share your views and experiences
Around 80 French boats have been met by two British naval patrol boats off the coast of Jersey, as French fishers protest over post-Brexit fishing rights.
The French boats gathered at the port in St Helier and are protesting over new licences that restrict the number of days they can operate in shared waters for the first time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Jewish parents used Guardian ads to save their children’s lives - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/06/how-jewish-parents-used-guardian-ads-to-save-their-childrens-lives-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/06/how-jewish-parents-used-guardian-ads-to-save-their-childrens-lives-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T02:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This month is 200 years since the Guardian was first established in Manchester. For the Guardian’s world affairs editor, Julian Borger, a part of that history is deeply personal. In 1938, there was a surge of classified ads in the Guardian as parents – including his grandparents – scrambled to get their children out of the Reich. What became of the families?
On Wednesday 3 August 1938, a short advertisement appeared on the second page of the Manchester Guardian, under the title “Tuition”. 
“I seek a kind pe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Julian Borger, Ruthie Elkana and Danny Segal, produced by Courtney Yusuf, Elizabeth Cassin and  Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astro]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339563</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/astro/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:49:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t even look at code or documentation for Astro (publicly) yet — it&#8217;s an in-progress idea — but you can watch a video of Fred showing it off to Feross. 
I gotta admit: it looks awesome. I&#8217;m bullish &#8230;
The post Astro appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python and OpenCV Course –Create Computer Vision Apps in the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>609307e801fc34080ef8191e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-computer-vision-apps-in-the-cloud-with-opencv-and-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:11:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a library of programming functions mainly aimed at real-time computer vision.  We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to use OpenCV in the cloud with Python. Misbah Mohammed created this course. He has a lot of experience with machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339954</id>
        <link href="https://infrequently.org/2021/04/progress-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T16:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The bombshell article of the week is from Alex Russell of Google/Chrome. Alex has long been super critical of Apple, particularly about how there is literally no option to run any other browser than Safari on iOS. This article isn&#8217;t &#8230;
The post Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Vendor Prefixing Dead?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339518</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-vendor-prefixing-dead/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T14:18:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let‘s take a quick stroll down memory-lane to revisit how vendor prefixing CSS properties came to be. I hope I don’t trigger PTSD for anyone!
It‘s not clear who started prefixing, or when it began exactly. What is clear, is &#8230;
The post Is Vendor Prefixing Dead? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob O'Leary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339455</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/16px-or-larger-text-prevents-ios-form-zoom/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:16:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a great &#8220;Today I Learned&#8221; for me from Josh W. Comeau. If the font-size of an &#60;input&#62; is 16px or larger, Safari on iOS will focus into the input normally. But as soon as the font-size is &#8230;
The post 16px or Larger Text Prevents iOS Form Zoom appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339867</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-backup-roll-back-your-woocommerce-site-without-losing-orders/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T21:15:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a dilemma: what happens if your WooCommerce site has a problem and the quickest and best way to fix it is to roll back to a previous version? The dilemma is, if you roll back the database, you would &#8230;
The post Jetpack Backup: Roll Back Your WooCommerce Site Without Losing Orders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Face, the facts: 10 ways to combat oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/face-the-facts-10-ways-to-combat-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/face-the-facts-10-ways-to-combat-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From embracing toner to staying hydrated, here’s how to look after an oil-prone complexion
Analyse your skin 
Start by doing a quick home test: wash your face, and if your skin produces oil 20 minutes afterwards, it’s likely you have oily skin. Online analyses can also be a good way to understand what your skin needs to feel its best, so try the diagnostic tool at SkinCeuticals – especially helpful given that a face-to-face consultation with a dermatologist isn’t an option for the time being.
 Related: Tack…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beatrice Aidin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node.js Async Await Tutorial – With Asynchronous JavaScript Examples]]></title>
        <id>609011fd8eb3fb07cf09a034</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-js-async-await-tutorial-with-asynchronous-javascript-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A complete guide to Node.js async await]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy a Directory in Linux – How to cp a Folder in the Command Line in Linux and Unix (MacOS)]]></title>
        <id>608f5ad48eb3fb07cf099ddb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/copy-a-directory-in-linux-how-to-cp-a-folder-in-the-command-line-in-linux-and-unix-macos/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T15:33:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To copy files or directories in Unix-based operating systems (Linux and MacOS), you use the cp command. The cp command is a relatively simple command, but its behavior changes slightly depending on the inputs (files vs directories) and the options you pass to it. To view the documentation or manual]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339449</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/lets-use-x-x-x-x-for-talking-about-specificity/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was just chatting with Eric Meyer the other day and I remembered an Eric Meyer story from my formative years. I wrote a blog post about CSS specificity, and Eric took the time to point out the misleading nature &#8230;
The post Let’s use (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have you stayed in a Covid quarantine hotel in the UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/26/have-you-spent-time-in-a-covid-quarantine-hotel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jan/26/have-you-spent-time-in-a-covid-quarantine-hotel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T11:24:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from travellers who have had to stay in a quarantine hotel in the UK
Quarantine rules for travellers to the UK have been in place since January. One of the measures saw the introduction of quarantine hotels for people arriving to the country.
We’d like understand what it’s like to spend time in a ‘Covid hotel’ in the UK. How are you finding the conditions in the hotel you’re staying at? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Fetch Data in React from a GraphQL API]]></title>
        <id>6090187c8eb3fb07cf09a060</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/5-ways-to-fetch-data-react-graphql/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T17:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go through the five best ways that you can fetch data with React from a GraphQL API. While there are a couple of popular libraries which are made to interact with GraphQL APIs from a React application, there are many different ways to fetch data with GraphQL. I've included]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums&nbsp;


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heroin to Holyrood? Man behind 'illegal' drug van runs for Scottish parliament – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Krykant, who operates a van in Glasgow where people can safely take illegal drugs, is running for Holyrood as part of a campaign calling for the Scottish government to establish legal sites.&nbsp;
A former&nbsp;heroin&nbsp;addict, he is pushing for drug reform in Scotland, which has a reported drug deaths rate 15 times higher than the European average. "People are dying out there,' says Krykant, who is able to treat addicts who overdose in his van. Could interventions such as his change Scotland's sta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Cherry, Maeve Shearlaw and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From using unexpected tools to practical prepping advice: how to nail DIY with TikTok]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:35:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tackling a new DIY project can be intimidating – especially if you’ve never tried it before. Tom Druker overcame his fears with help from short videos
Like most of us, I’ve spent much of the past year staring at walls. I moved house shortly before the first lockdown and managed to channel at least some existential anxiety into painting the house. But after that, I hit a wall. So to speak.
I was not raised in a DIY-competent environment. My dad is less DIY and more GSI (get someone in), so while I understand…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Druker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early &mdash; when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[George Floyd: a landmark moment for justice in America? – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/apr/22/george-floyd-a-landmark-moment-for-justice-in-america-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/apr/22/george-floyd-a-landmark-moment-for-justice-in-america-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T11:28:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The murder trial of Derek Chauvin drew the attention of the world to Minneapolis, the focal point of the Black Lives Matter movement after the murder of George Floyd. In some parts of the city people have reclaimed the streets, while others are under military occupation. With the area reeling from yet another recent police killing, Oliver Laughland and Tom Silverstone spent time with activists, lawyers, witnesses and members of the Floyd family to see how this landmark moment in American racial justice is s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland, Tom Silverstone, Amudalat Ajasa, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the UK government sidestepped the data on coronavirus – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T11:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This time last year, NHS bosses asked doctors and nurses to ‘wear aprons’ and&nbsp;work without protective full-length gowns&nbsp;when treating Covid-19 patients, as hospitals were within hours of running out of supplies.
This is just one example of how the UK government has been slammed for its handling of the pandemic, through a series of missteps, U-turns, lockdowns, denials – and more than 150,000 deaths.
Twelve months on, the Guardian's Pamela Duncan looks at three major areas where officials were out …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Duncan, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Mistakes To Avoid In Your Technical Interviews]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the technical interview process leaves something to be desired; it’s often riddled with anxiety and stress. In this article, we’ll take a look at seven of the most common mistakes candidates make in their technical interviews and explore ways you can avoid them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Emma Bostian)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Get Web Design Clients Fast (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Selling is key to growing your web design business, but it doesn’t have to be complicated! With clear goals, customer research, and proven closing techniques, anyone can find new clients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephen Roe)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Cats With Love: New Navigation, Guides And Workshops]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Smashing, we’ve been busy over the last few months. We’ve set up new workshops, redesigned our navigation, refined performance and improved accessibility. There are subtle UX changes coming in, and we’d love to share what we’ve been cooking.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overflow Issues In CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-14T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we will explore the causes of overflow issues and how to solve them. We will also explore how modern features in the developer tools (DevTools) can make the process of fixing and debugging easier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ahmad Shadeed)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Video Streaming App With Nuxt.js, Node And Express]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be building a video streaming app using Nuxt.js and Node.js. Specifically, we’ll build a server-side Node.js app that will handle fetching and streaming videos, generating thumbnails for your videos, and serving captions and subtitles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Deven Rathore)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To HTML Email]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently we’ve covered CSS generators, SVG generators and accessible front-end components. This time we look into HTML email, with tools, templates and guides for designers and developers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>