<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-15T00:31:59.460Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-15T00:31:59.460Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK-Australia post-Brexit trade deal agreed in broad terms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/15/uk-australia-trade-deal-agreed-and-set-to-be-announced-on-tuesday</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/15/uk-australia-trade-deal-agreed-and-set-to-be-announced-on-tuesday"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:23:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Agreement struck on Monday night and details expected to be announced on Tuesday morning
Details of a trade deal between the UK and Australia will be announced on Tuesday morning, the Guardian understands.
A Department for International Trade spokesperson confirmed that the broad terms had been struck on Monday night, after Boris Johnson and the Australian prime minister, Scott Morrison, had dinner at Downing Street.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland left feeling Schick, and a parrot – Euro 2020 Football Daily]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/15/scotland-schick-spain-sweden-slovakia-euro-2020-football-daily</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/audio/2021/jun/15/scotland-schick-spain-sweden-slovakia-euro-2020-football-daily"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:02:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Rushden is joined by Barry Glendenning, Jim Burke, Jacob Steinberg and Ewan Murray to discuss Scotland’s 2-0 defeat to Czech Republic
Rate, review, share on Apple Podcasts, Soundcloud, Audioboom, Mixcloud, Acast and Stitcher, and join the conversation on Facebook, Twitter and email.
On the podcast today: Scotland are sunk by Patrick Schick in their opening game at Hampden Park, the Czech striker’s long-distance lob sealing a dispiriting 2-0 defeat for Steve Clarke’s side.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Max Rushden with Barry Glendenning, Jim Burke, Ewan Murray and Jacob Steinberg. Produced by Joel Grove.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers ‘knowingly underfunding’ childcare sector in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/15/ministers-knowingly-underfunding-childcare-sector-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/15/ministers-knowingly-underfunding-childcare-sector-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:01:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Early Years Alliance investigation finds government is ‘shamelessly’ driving costs up and quality down 
Ministers have been accused of “shamelessly, knowingly” underfunding the early years sector in England over the past decade, driving childcare costs up and quality down, after a two-year investigation by a body representing the sector.
Private government briefing documents uncovered during the investigation reveal that 2020-21 early years funding rates for the Conservatives’ free childcare offer for three- and four-year-olds are less than two-thirds of what the government believed was needed to fully fund the scheme, according to the Early Years Alliance (EYA).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fears England breast cancer deaths may rise as Covid hits screenings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/15/fears-england-breast-cancer-deaths-may-rise-covid-hits-screenings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/15/fears-england-breast-cancer-deaths-may-rise-covid-hits-screenings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charity warns 10,600 fewer women started treatment for the disease in past year, compared with year before

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Progress in reducing breast cancer deaths may be under threat, a leading charity has warned, as figures reveal more than 10,000 fewer patients in England started treatment for the disease in the past year compared with the year before.
According to an analysis of NHS England figures by Cancer Research UK (CRUK), about 38,000 fewer cancer patients began treatment between April 2020 and March 2021, compared with the same period a year earlier. Just under 28% of these were breast cancer patients, equating to about 10,600 people.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Ascot day one: Lucky Vega can storm the Palace for Harrington | Greg Wood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/15/royal-ascot-day-one-lucky-vega-can-storm-the-palace-for-jessica-harrington-horse-racing-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/15/royal-ascot-day-one-lucky-vega-can-storm-the-palace-for-jessica-harrington-horse-racing-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Irish colt can grab the main prize on the opening day of British Flat racing’s most prestigious meeting
A Classic winner and third, several Guineas flops with obvious potential to bounce back and two up-and-comers from the Heron Stakes combine to make Tuesday’s renewal of the St James’s Palace Stakes the most open for nearly two decades.
Poetic Flare is the marginal favourite overnight after a battling performance to win the 2,000 Guineas at Newmarket and then a return to form in the Irish equivalent last time. He was just half-a-length in front of Lucky Vega (4.20) at Newmarket, however, and Jessica Harrington’s colt, who is likely to head to stud in Australia after the race on Tuesday, is the pick of the prices at around 7-1 to retire as a dual Group One winner.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Less than 1% of UK travel insurance policies offer full Covid cover, says Which?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/15/uk-travel-insurance-policies-full-covid-cover-which</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/15/uk-travel-insurance-policies-full-covid-cover-which"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T23:01:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Consumer body rated only two of the 263 policies analysed as ‘complete’

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Less than 1% of UK travel insurance policies provide people with full comprehensive cover for Covid-related disruption, research by Which? has found.
The consumer body analysed 263 travel insurance policies and rated only two as “complete”, meaning they protected travellers against a full range of possibilities.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United’s Joel Glazer admits ‘silence gave impression we don’t care’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/manchester-united-joel-glazer-fans-forum-minutes-heaton-sancho</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/manchester-united-joel-glazer-fans-forum-minutes-heaton-sancho"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:48:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glazer says ‘staying in background’ was the wrong approach
Tom Heaton to rejoin United, Jadon Sancho talks ongoing

The Manchester United executive vice-chairman, Joel Glazer, has conceded that his family’s silence has given fans the impression they do not care about the club.
Glazer made the admission in a two-hour meeting with the United fans’ forum earlier this month, the minutes of which have now been published. The meeting was arranged after the club’s involvement in the short-lived European Super League project sparked a fresh wave of protests against the Glazer family.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[System Design Interview Tutorial – The Beginner&#x27;s Guide to System Design]]></title>
        <id>60873d1fdd38b9088c2c0842</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/system-design-interview-practice-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:46:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[System Design is an important topic to understand if you want to advance further in your career as a software engineer. Even if you are just beginning your coding journey, it's a good idea to get a head start on learning about system design.  Early in your career you will]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Custom Pagination Component in React]]></title>
        <id>60bce373acb62507dd1d9f19</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-custom-pagination-component-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We often work with web applications that need to fetch large amounts of data from a server through APIs and render it on the screen. For example, in a Social media application we fetch and render users' posts and comments. In an HR dashboard we display information about candidates who]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Mickelson eyes career grand slam on his home course at US Open]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/phil-mickelson-eyes-career-grand-slam-on-his-home-course-at-us-open</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/phil-mickelson-eyes-career-grand-slam-on-his-home-course-at-us-open"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mickelson needs US Open victory to complete grand slam
Torrey Pines is in golfer’s home city of San Diego

Phil Mickelson believes he has a “unique opportunity” to complete the career grand slam in his home city of San Diego on the back of his stunning US PGA Championship triumph.
Just nine days before rolling back the years at Kiawah Island to become golf’s oldest major champion, Mickelson had reluctantly accepted a special exemption for the 121st US Open at Torrey Pines, where he will celebrate his 51st birthday on Wednesday, the day before the event starts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342294</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-tables-with-sticky-header-and-footers-got-a-bit-easier/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It wasn’t long ago when I looked at sticky headers and footers in HTML <table>s in the blog post A table with both a sticky header and a sticky first column. In it, I never used position: sticky on …
The post Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lloyd Webber’s Cinderella could go on despite lockdown extension, PM hints]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/lloyd-webbers-cinderella-could-go-on-boris-johnson-hints</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/lloyd-webbers-cinderella-could-go-on-boris-johnson-hints"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T21:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson says government is in talks with composer, who is ‘surprised’ to hear of the proposed pilot

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Andrew Lloyd Webber’s latest production could be exempt from the delay in lockdown easing, Boris Johnson hinted in his Downing Street briefing announcing the four-week postponement of the relaxation of all rules.
Last week, Lord Lloyd-Webber said he was determined to open his theatres on 21 June regardless of whether rules are relaxed, and was prepared to be arrested if authorities try to intervene.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southgate praises Chilwell and Sancho for positivity despite Croatia omission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/gareth-southgate-ben-chilwell-jadon-sancho-euro-2020-england-croatia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/gareth-southgate-ben-chilwell-jadon-sancho-euro-2020-england-croatia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T21:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pair missed out on matchday squad for opening Euro 2020 win
‘That’s a team – that’s what it’s about,’ says Southgate

Gareth Southgate has praised Ben Chilwell and Jadon Sancho for responding positively to being left out of England’s squad against Croatia, saying their professionalism played a part in the team making a winning start to Euro 2020.
England’s manager experienced the downside of squads being increased to 26 when he had to tell two outfield players they would not be involved against Croatia. Uefa regulations state teams must name two goalkeepers on the bench in their 23-man matchday squads and that left Southgate with some awkward decisions to make before his side’s opening game in Group D.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Men who helped Nissan boss Carlos Ghosn flee Japan admit their role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/men-who-helped-nissan-boss-carlos-ghosn-flee-japan-admit-their-role</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/men-who-helped-nissan-boss-carlos-ghosn-flee-japan-admit-their-role"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T21:27:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael and Peter Taylor tell Tokyo court of their part in spiriting away executive in musical instrument case
Two Americans charged with helping former Nissan chair Carlos Ghosn flee Japan while he was facing accusations of financial misconduct have told a court that they took part in a scheme for him to escape the country.
Statements by Michael Taylor and his son, Peter, on the opening day of their trial in Tokyo suggested the pair don’t plan to fight charges of assisting a criminal, which carry a possible penalty of up to three years in prison.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AP in Tokyo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ireland After Partition review – a fascinating look at the fragile peace now at risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/14/peter-taylor-ireland-after-partition-review-a-fascinating-look-at-the-fragile-peace-now-at-risk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/14/peter-taylor-ireland-after-partition-review-a-fascinating-look-at-the-fragile-peace-now-at-risk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T21:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Taylor’s poignant and timely documentary examines a century of sectarian conflict – and Britain’s role from day one 
It was like an Irish version of Martin Luther King’s dream. Instead of little black boys and black girls joining hands with little white boys and white girls, six Catholic and six Protestant kids from Belfast splashed each other as they played in a lake in Wales.
The veteran BBC reporter Peter Taylor filmed this rare initiative to counter sectarian division nearly half a century ago. He reprises the footage here for Peter Taylor: Ireland After Partition (BBC Two), a film made to mark a century since the partition of the island of Ireland and his half-century as an Englishman trying to understand sectarian divisions caused by his countrymen, by that still-thriving beast, perfidious Albion.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biosecure bubble can help forge stronger Lions bonds, insists Ken Owens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/biosecure-bubble-can-help-forge-lions-bonds-says-ken-owens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/biosecure-bubble-can-help-forge-lions-bonds-says-ken-owens"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T21:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Training under way at Lions’ Jersey training base
Owens: ‘It’s easier to get those social connections going’

The British & Irish Lions hooker Ken Owens believes the strict Covid-19 restrictions facing the squad can act as a strength rather than a weakness for the upcoming tour of South Africa. Training got under way on Monday for the 26 players who have arrived at the Lions’ pre-tour training base in Jersey and Owens insists the biosecure bubble will make team-bonding easier.
Last night the Lions were due to allocate key responsibilities including overseeing entertainment and laundry while, as was the case four years ago, choir practice is expected to be introduced again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain and Sweden rue missed chances after Euro 2020 stalemate in Seville]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/spain-sweden-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/spain-sweden-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T20:58:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard this one before. It was noisy in Seville, but the roof was never truly raised at La Cartuja, the sound that lingered from Spain’s opening game at Euro 2020 instead the whistles of supporters who had watched their team dominate possession, complete 918 passes for 85% of possession, setting a new tournament record, but just not find a way through.
Before them was a tight, defensive organised Swedish team satisfied with the final score – a team Luis Enrique described as having “decided to defend and base everything on long balls” - which helped to explain it, as did a goalkeeper who made two wonderful saves, but there was familiarity in the frustration too. Only six members of this Spain squad played at the last World Cup in Russia, where they were knocked out by the hosts despite playing a thousand passes in Moscow, but some of the issues remain.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe at Stadium La Cartuja Sevilla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wimbledon finals to allow full crowd capacity with 45,000 at Euro 2020 final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/wembley-to-host-up-to-45000-fans-for-euro-2020-final-and-semi-finals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/wembley-to-host-up-to-45000-fans-for-euro-2020-final-and-semi-finals"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T20:44:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boost in crowd numbers for Euro 2020 semi-finals and final
Other moves to end social distancing pushed back until 19 July

The final weekend of Wimbledon will be played on Centre Court in front of a capacity crowd – the first at a sporting event since the UK went into lockdown as the Covid-19 pandemic took hold.
The tournament, which gets under way on 28 June, will begin with 50% ground capacity before the finals on 10 and 11 July are played out in front of a 15,000-capacity crowd. The government has confirmed plans for up to 20 pilot events across sport and entertainment, with Wimbledon and football’s Euro 2020 the big winners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dangerous heatwave grips US south-west as temperatures hit 120F in some areas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/us-heatwave-southwest-utah-california-nevada-arizona</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/us-heatwave-southwest-utah-california-nevada-arizona"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T20:36:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[California, Nevada, Arizona and Utah face extreme heat, worsening drought and raising risk of wildfires
Dangerously hot temperatures across the US south-west will continue to climb this week, reaching higher than 120F (49C) in some areas, exacerbating the region’s already-dire drought conditions and increasing the risk of new fire ignitions.
Extreme heat will be felt across much of Utah, along with southern and central California, Nevada and Arizona.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabrielle Canon in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Roving tabindex Attribute Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>60c3b862d3126007592d689b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-roving-tabindex-attribute-explained-with-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever used the CSS order or direction properties? You've probably used them dozens of times, but did you realize that these properties will cause a disconnect between what's being displayed and what's actually in the DOM? Using the order property will create a disconnect between the visual presentation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson maxes out his credit with Tory MPs: ‘It’s 19 July and I really mean it this time’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/johnson-maxes-out-his-credit-with-tory-mps-its-19-july-and-i-really-mean-it-this-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/johnson-maxes-out-his-credit-with-tory-mps-its-19-july-and-i-really-mean-it-this-time"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fresh from his Cornish beach minibreak, PM returns to face Covid reality – and his furious backbenchers
It hardly came as a massive shock. Indeed, given the surge in coronavirus cases over the past few weeks, the surprise would have been if Boris Johnson had chosen to relax all remaining lockdown restrictions in England on 21 June. But it was unquestionably a disappointment – to the prime minister as well as several million others. Boris likes to be the feel-good man: taking on the role of the sensible purveyor of bad news rather cramps his style.
So it was a somewhat subdued Johnson – it didn’t help that he was still coming down from his G7 Cornwall high – who entered the Downing Street briefing room, flanked by Chris Whitty and Patrick Vallance. There was a time in the early days of the pandemic when the chief medical officer and the chief scientific adviser were ingenues who, unknowingly, frequently allowed themselves to be used as human shields for government incompetence. Now they have both wised up and their presence was as much to make sure Boris didn’t have a last-minute change of heart as to do the heavy lifting of explaining the science and epidemiology.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public inquiry opens into Met police killing of unarmed Jermaine Baker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/public-inquiry-opens-into-met-police-killing-of-unarmed-jermaine-baker</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/public-inquiry-opens-into-met-police-killing-of-unarmed-jermaine-baker"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:35:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bug picked up occupants of car in which Baker was shot saying they did not have a real gun, inquiry told 
A public inquiry into the death of an unarmed man shot by a Metropolitan police marksman during a foiled prison break has heard that a bug in the getaway car picked up the occupants saying they did not have a real gun.
The opening day of the hearing on Monday also heard that Jermaine Baker may have been asleep shortly before armed police descended on the car and he was shot.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK regulator warns Google about accepting scam adverts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/uk-regulator-warns-google-about-accepting-scam-adverts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/uk-regulator-warns-google-about-accepting-scam-adverts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:25:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FCA tells MPs it will take action against social media and search engines that host online frauds
The City regulator has warned it will take legal action against Google and social media companies if they continue to accept advertisements for online financial scams that have flourished during the pandemic. 
The Financial Conduct Authority’s head of enforcement, Mark Steward, told the Treasury select committee on Monday that the UK had been blocked until recently from taking action against online platforms that failed to screen financial adverts to make sure they were approved by an FCA-authorised firm or individual.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Backup Squarespace-Managed Styles using AWS Cloud]]></title>
        <id>60c794e64dc1a607ed7b25ba</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-backup-squarespace-managed-styles-using-aws-cloud/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:19:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while ago, I was doing side gig for a client who had a website hosted on Squarespace. They asked me to implement an advanced design for a page that wasn't possible with the site's current DIY tools. For an experienced and battle-tested web developer like me, this was a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JD Group boss defends bonus despite retailer accepting Covid support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/jd-group-boss-defends-bonus-despite-retailer-accepting-covid-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/jd-group-boss-defends-bonus-despite-retailer-accepting-covid-support"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:10:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Near-£6m for Peter Cowgill came as group took more than £100m in business rates relief and furlough

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The boss of the retailer JD Group has defended receiving a multimillion-pound bonus during the coronavirus pandemic at the same time as the firm accepted more than £100m in government support.
Peter Cowgill, the executive chairman, was awarded almost £6m in bonuses during the 12 months since February 2020, and admitted on Monday that investors might oppose the payout at next month’s annual meeting. But he said he had only received one long-term incentive plan (LTIP) in eight years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Henny Beaumont on young people, education and Covid-19 – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/14/henny-beaumont-on-young-people-education-and-covid-19-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/14/henny-beaumont-on-young-people-education-and-covid-19-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T19:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henny Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Restaurants and pubs ‘face collapse’ during extended England lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/restaurants-and-pubs-face-collapse-during-extended-england-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/14/restaurants-and-pubs-face-collapse-during-extended-england-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:59:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business groups call for government to support hospitality industry including nightclubs and bars

‘Very depressing’: delay to full reopening a bitter blow to pubs
Opinion: hospitality firms need clarity about unpaid rent

Business groups have warned that pubs, bars, restaurants and nightclubs face significant hardship or collapse after the easing of Covid-19 restrictions in England was postponed for four weeks without new financial support from the government.
Full reopening without measures such as social distancing will not be allowed until 19 July, Boris Johnson said on Monday, with a review in two weeks’ time “unlikely” to result in an earlier relaxation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies and Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PM announces four-week delay to Covid lockdown easing in England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/pm-announces-four-week-delay-to-covid-lockdown-easing-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/pm-announces-four-week-delay-to-covid-lockdown-easing-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:51:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson says more time needed to tackle Delta variant but signals he will not tolerate further suspension

Coronavirus in the UK – latest updates
What we know about the delay to ending lockdown in England

Boris Johnson has halted the final easing of lockdown restrictions in England and ordered a four-week delay to speed up the vaccination programme, but signalled afterwards he would not tolerate any further suspension.
The prime minister said 19 July was a “terminus date” and that all restrictions on social contact could be lifted, barring the emergence of a gamechanging new variant.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Aubrey Allegretti and Nicola Davis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Betting firms won £1.3m in stolen money from gambling addict]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/14/betting-firms-won-13m-in-stolen-money-from-gambling-addict</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/14/betting-firms-won-13m-in-stolen-money-from-gambling-addict"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:48:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andy May convicted of fraud in case that highlights need for industry reform, say campaigners
Betting firms won £1.3m in stolen money from a gambling addict without establishing where the funds came from, it has emerged, reigniting concern about whether firms do sufficient due diligence on punters who lose large sums.
Andy May, 44, was sentenced at Norwich crown court on Monday to four years for fraud after admitting siphoning funds from the clothing company where he was a senior manager earning more than £50,000 a year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitality firms urgently need clarity from Sunak about £2.5bn of unpaid rent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/14/hospitality-firms-urgently-need-clarity-from-sunak-about-25bn-of-unpaid-rent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/14/hospitality-firms-urgently-need-clarity-from-sunak-about-25bn-of-unpaid-rent"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:38:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Giving landlords and tenants six months to work out a deal on arrears could stop an wave of bankruptcies in the sector

Restaurants and pubs ‘face collapse’ in extended lockdown
‘Very depressing’: delay to full reopening a bitter blow to pubs

If it really is a case of “one more heave” on vaccinations before restrictions on the hospitality sector can be eased, what’s the best way to ensure the country’s pubs, restaurants and nightclubs survive to take a shot at recovery?
The two most important measures may be these. First, an extension of six months to the ban on landlords evicting tenants. Second, a government-backed framework for the two sides to share the accumulated pain of unpaid rents.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[McConnell: ‘Highly unlikely’ I would let Biden fill supreme court seat in 2024]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/14/mitch-mcconnell-supreme-court-stephen-breyer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/14/mitch-mcconnell-supreme-court-stephen-breyer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:37:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senate minority leader’s remarks prompt increasing calls for Stephen Breyer to step down during Biden administration
The Senate minority leader, Mitch McConnell, said on Monday it was “highly unlikely” he would allow Joe Biden to fill a supreme court vacancy arising in 2024, the year of the next presidential election, if Republicans regained control of the chamber.
 Related: Senior DoJ official to exit amid outcry over seizure of Democrats’ records 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Best African Language Datasets for Data Science Projects]]></title>
        <id>60c4b35ed3126007592d71bc</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/african-language-datasets-for-data-science-projects/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:37:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Africa has over 2000 languages, but these languages are not well-represented in the existing Natural Language Processing ecosystem.  One challenge is the lack of useful African language datasets that we can use to solve different social and economic problems. In this article, I have compiled a list of African language]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin refuses to guarantee Navalny will survive prison]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/vladimir-putin-refuses-to-guarantee-navalny-will-survive-prison</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/vladimir-putin-refuses-to-guarantee-navalny-will-survive-prison"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:31:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In US TV interview, Russian leader deflects allegations over cyber-attacks and human rights
Vladimir Putin has refused to give any guarantee that the opposition leader Alexei Navalny will get out of prison alive, saying his continued detention was not his decision and noting the poor state of medical care in Russian jails.
In an extended and testy interview with NBC News before Putin’s Geneva summit with Joe Biden, the Russian president deflected a string of allegations about his government’s role in cyber-attacks on the west. He also fended off questions about his government’s human rights record by making counter-allegations against the US.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICC prosecutor seeks investigation into Philippines ‘war on drugs’ killings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/icc-seeks-investigation-into-philippines-war-on-drugs-killings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/icc-seeks-investigation-into-philippines-war-on-drugs-killings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:28:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police are accused of unlawfully killing thousands of civilians between 2016 and 2019 during drug crackdown
The international criminal court’s chief prosecutor has sought authorisation to open an investigation into crimes against humanity during the Philippines’ deadly “war on drugs”, in one of her last acts before stepping down this week.
Fatou Bensouda asked judges at the world’s only permanent war crimes court to authorise an investigation into allegations that police unlawfully killed as many as tens of thousands of civilians between 2016 and 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wembley park stabbings: boyfriend screamed when he found sisters’ bodies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/trial-hears-how-two-sisters-were-found-dead-in-london-park</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/trial-hears-how-two-sisters-were-found-dead-in-london-park"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Partner of Nicole Smallman breaks down as he tells Old Bailey of search for her and her sister Bibaa Henry

The boyfriend of one of two sisters stabbed to death in a park has described the horrifying moment he found their lifeless bodies in bushes.
Nicole Smallman, 27, and Bibaa Henry, 46, were allegedly attacked by Danyal Hussein, 19, who is said to have believed he had made a blood pact with a demon to win the lottery.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342229</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-tricks-chronicle-xxxx/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a little link roundup of some off-site stuff I’ve done recently. As I’m wont to do from time to time. 
DevJourney Podcast
#151 Chris Coyier from ceramics to CSS-Tricks and CodePen‘
Chris took us from playing on 
…
The post CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I don’t feel any the wiser’: uncertainty as wedding Covid rules eased]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/uncertainty-wedding-covid-rules-eased-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/uncertainty-wedding-covid-rules-eased-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:13:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In theory, couples in England can invite full guest list from 21 June – but it is not so straightforward

Weddings with more than 30 people can go ahead as England’s Covid limit lifted
Coronavirus – latest updates

After months of having to choose just 30 close relatives and friends to celebrate their nuptials with, couples in England will in theory be allowed to invite their full guest list from 21 June. 
But the rules are not so straightforward: commercial venues will need to carry out a risk assessment beforehand, and the maximum number of guests will be dictated by how many socially distanced tables of six they have the space to seat. Dancing and singing are banned, unless you are in a private garden, and no more than six guests are permitted in private homes.
The news brings to an end an anxious few days for many couples planning weddings, even if for many the rule change will not enable them to throw the parties they had hoped for.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jedidajah Otte, Alfie Packham and Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News launch gains more viewers than BBC or Sky news channels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/gb-news-launch-gains-more-viewers-than-bbc-or-sky-news-channels</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/gb-news-launch-gains-more-viewers-than-bbc-or-sky-news-channels"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:13:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Proud to be British’ new channel has backers including US Discovery and a Dubai-based fund 
The launch of GB News was watched by more people than both the BBC News channel and Sky News despite several technical glitches on opening night, according to data released on Monday.
The television news channel, which claims to “lend an ear to some of Britain’s marginalised and overlooked voices”, launched at 8pm on Sunday with a mission statement delivered to camera by its chairman, Andrew Neil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson and Jim Waterson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on delaying lockdown easing: sadly unavoidable | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/the-guardian-view-on-delaying-lockdown-easing-sadly-unavoidable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/the-guardian-view-on-delaying-lockdown-easing-sadly-unavoidable"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:12:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The exponential spread of the Delta variant, and the uncertainties surrounding it, mean pausing the roadmap is justified
Since February, when Boris Johnson unveiled a four-step roadmap to ending all Covid restrictions in England, progress has been steady and at times relatively serene compared with the periods of abject confusion and chaos that went before. The successful rollout of the vaccination programme allowed targets to be met, including the substantial “step three” easing of restrictions on 17 May.
But as Boris Johnson recognised in his press conference today, the spread of the new Delta variant – which now accounts for 96% of Covid cases in the United Kingdom – has upended calculations. Latest data suggests it is 40-80% more transmissible than the Alpha variant, which originated in Kent. The variant partly evades vaccines and appears to increase the risk of hospitalisation. Hospital admission rates are increasing by 50% a week and 61% in the north-west. A significant third wave is thus under way and the government’s scientific advisers do not know the extent to which current rates of vaccination and acquired immunity will keep it in check. A summer surge in hospitalisations could overwhelm an already overstretched NHS.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on lobbying: say yes to tougher rules | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/the-guardian-view-on-lobbying-say-yes-to-tougher-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/the-guardian-view-on-lobbying-say-yes-to-tougher-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:11:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public trust is damaged when a former PM and ministers are caught up in a cronyism scandal, and must be repaired
Ministers will wait until the final version of a report on lobbying is published before announcing which of its recommendations they plan to accept. Given the damage caused by the close involvement of a former prime minister, David Cameron, in the Greensill lobbying scandal, and the fact that ministers have now been defeated twice in court over the improper award of contracts, the delay is an unwise as it is unsurprising.
By far the best course for the prime minister would be to indicate now that he will do as Lord Evans, chair of the committee on standards in public life (and a former head of MI5), advises. The measures are hardly revolutionary. A ban on ministers and senior civil servants lobbying for five years after leaving office makes sense. So does the suggestion that the public appointments watchdog should get new powers, including the right to prevent ministers taking certain jobs. Given the pace of change in institutions, the current two-year prohibition on lobbying is too short, making it likely that ministers will end up trying to influence former colleagues. There clearly are circumstances in which a rapid move from government to a particular private-sector role would not be appropriate. The proposal for new penalties for rule-breakers is logical too: if rules are to be treated seriously, infractions must be punished.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NSA whistleblower Reality Winner released from prison]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/reality-winner-nsa-whistleblower-released-prison</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/reality-winner-nsa-whistleblower-released-prison"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-intelligence contractor convicted of leaking report on Russian interference in US election released for good behavior
Reality Winner, a former intelligence contractor convicted of leaking a report about Russian interference in the US election in 2016, has been released from prison.
Winner’s attorney, Alison Grinter Allen, made the announcement via Twitter, saying the former National Security Agency (NSA) contractor had been released into a residential re-entry programme for good behavior.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jürgen Klinsmann: ‘We were singing Football’s Coming Home at Euro 96’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/jurgen-klinsmann-germany-euro-96-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/14/jurgen-klinsmann-germany-euro-96-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Captain of Germany’s Euro 96 winners on the current side’s need to right some wrongs, Joachim Löw’s reign and Manchester memories
Jürgen Klinsmann is arranging a 25th-anniversary celebration for Germany’s victorious Euro 96 squad this September. Despite everything – the humiliating exit from the last World Cup, the 6-0 drubbing by Spain, the home defeat by North Macedonia and the end of an era for Joachim Löw – he believes Manuel Neuer can host one of his own in 2046. Germany’s fortunes may fluctuate but Klinsmann knows better than most that the expectations never do. He fulfilled and fuelled them, after all.
 Related: Euro 2020 team guides part 22: Germany 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s Covid lockdown lifting: is a four-week delay enough?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/englands-covid-lockdown-lifting-is-a-four-week-delay-enough</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/englands-covid-lockdown-lifting-is-a-four-week-delay-enough"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T17:35:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Even a short pause is expected to reduce the number of people going to hospital as more people are vaccinated

PM announces delay to lockdown easing
What we know about the delay

The roadmap out of lockdown – England’s strategy to return to a life more normal – was heavy on dates from the start. The first three steps, in March, April and May, passed so smoothly that a crucial point was easily forgotten: reopening rested on data, not dates, at least that was what scientific advisers hoped. Well, now the data has spoken.
England is not in lockdown today. Children are back at school. Cafes, restaurants and pubs are open. People can mix indoors, albeit in small numbers. Thousands can watch football matches. As the country moved from one step to another, more contact between people was expected to fuel cases, hospitalisations and even deaths. To keep them to a minimum, we have the vaccination programme.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin price back above $40,000 after Elon Musk comments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/tesla-will-resume-accepting-bitcoin-when-it-uses-more-clean-energy-says-musk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/tesla-will-resume-accepting-bitcoin-when-it-uses-more-clean-energy-says-musk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T17:26:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla CEO says transactions made in digital currency will resume once crypto mining is greener

The price of bitcoin hit a three-week high on Monday, climbing back above $40,000 after Elon Musk said that Tesla would resume allowing transactions made in the digital currency once crypto mining becomes greener.
The electric car company’s latest change of direction on its acceptance of bitcoin once again highlighted the continuing ability of Tesla’s billionaire chief executive to influence the price of bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 on pace to be deadliest yet for trans and gender non-conforming Americans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/us-trans-transgender-deaths-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/us-trans-transgender-deaths-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T17:16:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Human Rights Campaign records at least 28 killings so far
More transgender dead so far than in six full recent years

This year is on track to be the deadliest for transgender and gender non-conforming people in the US, according to the Human Rights Campaign.
 Related: ‘A war on 100 fronts’: mapping the anti-trans laws sweeping America 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Oladipo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antony Gormley hopes Crosby statues last 1,000 years after reset]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/14/antony-gormley-hopes-crosby-statues-last-1000-years-after-reset</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/14/antony-gormley-hopes-crosby-statues-last-1000-years-after-reset"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T17:04:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artist personally oversaw rescue operation for his ‘industrial fossils’ after several toppled into the mud
Antony Gormley says he hopes his “iron men” on a Merseyside beach will still exist in at least 1,000 years as “industrial fossils”, after helping to excavate 10 that had been subsumed by Irish Sea mud.
One hundred cast-iron statues modelled on Gormley were installed in 2005 at Crosby beach, spread across 3km (2 miles) of the foreshore and stretching almost 1km out to sea.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graham Thorpe backs the Hundred to help England’s struggling Test batsmen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/graham-thorpe-the-hundred-can-help-england-struggling-test-batsmen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/14/graham-thorpe-the-hundred-can-help-england-struggling-test-batsmen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T17:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Assistant coach says players will be able to relax

Minimal Championship cricket before India series

Graham Thorpe hopes the Hundred allows England’s batsmen to relax before their five Test series against India and believes their mental approach is proving more of a hindrance than any technical problems.
Thorpe, the assistant coach, and Marcus Trescothick, the elite batting coach, have plenty of work to do with their charges before the first Test against India on 4 August after the 1-0 defeat against New Zealand exposed shortcomings.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rich countries urged to come up with detailed plans to cut emissions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/rich-countries-urged-to-come-up-with-detailed-plans-to-cut-emissions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/rich-countries-urged-to-come-up-with-detailed-plans-to-cut-emissions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:53:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Laurence Tubiana, a key player in 2015 Paris summit, says UK and others must explain how they will achieve climate goals
Rich countries must come forward with detailed plans on how they hope to meet their climate targets, and Boris Johnson must forge much closer relationships with developing countries to bring about the breakthrough needed on the climate crisis this year, one of the architects of the Paris agreement has said.
The G7 summit, which ended on Sunday in Cornwall, achieved much less than campaigners had hoped, with no significant new cash forthcoming for the world’s poorest and most vulnerable, on the frontlines of climate breakdown.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nato summit: leaders declare China presents security risk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/nato-summit-china-russia-biden-cyber-attacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/nato-summit-china-russia-biden-cyber-attacks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:49:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Communique is first time alliance has asserted it needs to respond to Beijing’s growing power
Nato leaders have declared China presents a security risk at their annual summit in Brussels, the first time the traditionally Russia-focused military alliance has asserted it needs to respond to Beijing’s growing power.
The final communique, signed off by leaders of the 30-member alliance at the urging of the new US administration, said China’s “stated ambitions and assertive behaviour present systemic challenges to the rules-based international order”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh Defence and security editor and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US election officials still plagued by threats for certifying Trump defeat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/us-election-officials-threats-trump-defeat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/us-election-officials-threats-trump-defeat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:39:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A barrage of death threats against officials and volunteers from ex-president’s supporters could make recruiting poll workers harder
Late on the night of 24 April, the wife of Georgia’s top election official got a chilling text message: “You and your family will be killed very slowly.”
A week earlier, Tricia Raffensperger, wife of the Georgia secretary of state, Brad Raffensperger, had received another anonymous text: “We plan for the death of you and your family every day.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda So, Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virtual intimacy: is the era of actual sexual contact under threat?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/virtual-intimacy-is-the-era-of-actual-sexual-contact-under-threat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/virtual-intimacy-is-the-era-of-actual-sexual-contact-under-threat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A survey shows that nearly half of young, single Americans haven’t had any physical intimacy with anyone since the pandemic started, and two thirds are planning on sticking with virtual intimacy post-Covid

Name: Virtual intimacy.
Age: As old as the telephone, or possibly even the postage stamp.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should Labour go big on radical change? | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/should-labour-go-big-on-radical-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/should-labour-go-big-on-radical-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:26:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to former leader Ed Miliband’s thoughts on a future direction for the party
Ed Miliband clearly understands how the Conservative party, despite claiming to have “changed”, is a “long way from grasping the political direction or scale” of the changes needed (Forget incremental change: the left shouldn’t be afraid of thinking big, 10 June). Up against a government that sees “levelling-up” only in terms of regional investment, and education of the disadvantaged simply as a vote-winning ploy rather than a commitment to provide equality of opportunity, Labour has not only to prioritise “big change”, but ensure all policies are based on fairness and justice. Promising a government that would never run down NHS infrastructure, underfund state schools, allow 21st-century universities to be dominated by privately educated students, cut overseas aid needlessly, or require a well-minded football star to persuade it to feed hungry children, would do for starters.
Clarity in the message, especially in view of it always being distorted by the rightwing press, is vital, as Miliband knows to his cost, so a principled version of a “Dominic Cummings” to revamp Labour’s propaganda machine might also be required.
Bernie Evans
Liverpool
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neo-Nazi ex-Ukip member jailed for 18 years for terror offences]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/ex-ukip-member-dean-morrice-given-23-year-sentence-for-terror-offences</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/ex-ukip-member-dean-morrice-given-23-year-sentence-for-terror-offences"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:17:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dean Morrice described by judge as ‘dangerous neo-Nazi’ who pumped out racist propaganda online
A former Ukip member who posted violent racist, antisemitic and Islamophobic propaganda online and collected the means for making bombs has been jailed for 18 years.
Dean Morrice had ball bearings, pipes and instructions for an improvised explosive device (IED) by the time his home was raided last year, and the judge at Kingston crown court said it was “fortunate” that police arrested him when they did.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two leaders of very different Catholic values | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/two-leaders-of-very-different-catholic-values</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/two-leaders-of-very-different-catholic-values"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:16:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Dolan contrasts Boris Johnson’s faith with Joe Biden’s, while Zaki Cooper says that religion should inspire but not dictate an individual’s political agenda
I suspect that many left-leaning Roman Catholics regard the fact that Boris Johnson is Britain’s first Catholic prime minister as more a matter of regret than pride, and certainly not “a watershed moment” for the nation’s Catholics, as Catherine Pepinster suggests (A Catholic prime minister in No 10 is a watershed moment, 11 June).
Nor was this moment entirely unpredictable. Some of the most prominent Tory Brexiters – Bill Cash, Iain Duncan Smith and Jacob Rees-Mogg – are also fellow Catholics, while the days of the Church of England being effectively the Conservative party at prayer, while Labour was seen as the preference of Irish Catholic working-class communities, have long passed. In terms of electoral allegiance, Catholics have been steadily deserting the Labour party, as they advance in educational attainment, employment income and influence among the right.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Hardie’s cycling club jettisons socialism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/keir-hardies-cycling-club-jettisons-socialism</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/keir-hardies-cycling-club-jettisons-socialism"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:11:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Majority of National Clarion Club members vote to remove ‘divisive’ word from its constitution
It has long been Britain’s most political cycling club, counting the suffragettes and the Labour party founder Keir Hardie among its pelotons.
Founded in a Labour church in Birmingham in 1894 as a two-wheeled spin-off of the Clarion leftwing magazine, the Clarion Cycling Club’s early members used to pedal around the countryside putting socialist stickers on cows and trees, spreading leftist propaganda like fertiliser.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did you solve it? Ace of spades]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/14/did-you-solve-it-ace-of-spades</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/14/did-you-solve-it-ace-of-spades"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T16:04:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The solutions to today’s headbangers
Earlier today I set you the following two puzzles:
1. Deck dilemma
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Bellos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If British people understood taxes better, perhaps we would vote for them to be fairer | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/understood-taxes-better-vote-fairer-taxlab</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/understood-taxes-better-vote-fairer-taxlab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:56:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new website aims to explain the complex UK tax system, and is revealing the huge inequalities embedded within it

Tax is the social contract that binds citizens together. Tax is not a “burden”, but the price we pay for civilisation. Vaccines are just the latest reminder of the good that taxes do. But what if most people – even those who think themselves well-informed – know little of the tax they pay, where it goes or how fairly it falls? Democracy depends on citizens understanding what they vote for; ignorance breeds dangerous misconceptions.
TaxLab, an information service unveiled by the Institute for Fiscal Studies, is a wonder of elegant clarity, its impartial explainers revealing what everyone should know: and it’s guaranteed to surprise most people. Two years in construction, the Economic and Social Research Council (ESRC) and the Friends Provident Foundation funded it to create a better-informed electorate. A mouse-click shows that people in Britain pay less tax (in 2019 figures), at 33% of GDP, than the EU average of 39%, while in Denmark it’s 46%. Put in your pay and TaxLab shows exactly where you stand in the income pecking order: people wildly miscalculate, both rich and poor, placing themselves too near the middle. Young people are generous to older people, but if they understood the tax biases benefiting retired people they might be more likely to vote.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minneapolis: woman killed and three injured after car drives into protesters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/minneapolis-woman-killed-car-protesters-police</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/14/minneapolis-woman-killed-car-protesters-police"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:42:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Driver arrested after being treated at an area hospital while police haven’t confirmed a motive for the attack
A woman is dead and three others injured after a car was driven into a crowd of anti-police brutality protesters in Minneapolis on Sunday night, Minneapolis police confirmed on Twitter.
The driver was arrested and is in police custody after being treated at an area hospital, according to police. The police have not confirmed a motive for the attack.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Oladipo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peonies envy: do I really love blowsy flowers or has Instagram destroyed my ability to think?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/peonies-envy-do-i-really-love-blowsy-flowers-or-has-instagram-destroyed-my-ability-to-think</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/peonies-envy-do-i-really-love-blowsy-flowers-or-has-instagram-destroyed-my-ability-to-think"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:27:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of posts suggest that everyone loves big, bright blooms. So I guess I do too

On an enforced mid-walk pause as the elderly dog licks a lamppost in confusion, my husband’s eyes alight on the nearest garden. “Ugh,” he says. “That’s ugly.” A thrill of delicious horror runs through me: he is pointing at a peony. A bubblegum-pink one, sure, but a peony: it’s like saying you hate puppies, or your mum.
“You hate those?” I ask him, scandalised. “But … they’re peonies!”
He shrugs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Beddington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK weather: hottest day of year so far as temperature hits 28.6C]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/uk-weather-hottest-day-year-so-far-temperature-heathrow</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/uk-weather-hottest-day-year-so-far-temperature-heathrow"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:22:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement at Heathrow airport in west London beats previous high of 28.2C set earlier in June

The UK recorded its hottest day of the year so far as temperatures soared to 28.6C (83.84F) in London following a weekend of high temperatures and sunshine across the country.
The temperature reached 28.8C (83.48F) at Heathrow airport in west London on Monday, following the previous high for 2021 of 28.2C recorded in Northolt, north-west London, on 2 June, the Met Office said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delta variant Covid symptoms ‘include headaches, sore throat and runny nose’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/delta-variant-covid-symptoms-include-headaches-sore-throat-and-runny-nose</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/delta-variant-covid-symptoms-include-headaches-sore-throat-and-runny-nose"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:20:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers warn that UK’s most widely established variant may be mistaken for milder illness

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Headaches, a sore throat and a runny nose are the most common symptoms associated with the UK’s most widely established Covid variant, researchers have said.
The data, collected as part of the app-based Zoe Covid symptom study, suggests that the Delta variant first detected in India feels like a “bad cold”, according to Tim Spector, a professor of genetic epidemiology at King’s College London, who is leading the work.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Father of missing girl killed her to silence sexual abuse claims, court told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/father-of-missing-girl-killed-her-to-silence-sexual-abuse-claims-court-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/14/father-of-missing-girl-killed-her-to-silence-sexual-abuse-claims-court-told"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:19:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parents of Bernadette Walker, 17, from Peterborough, told police she had run away, says prosecutor
A teenager who disappeared last summer and whose body has never been found was murdered by her father to silence her claims he sexually abused her, a court has heard.
Bernadette Walker, a 17-year-old photography student from Peterborough, was last seen alive on 18 July last year when her father, Scott Walker, 51, collected her from his parents’ house where she had spent the night.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray Midlands correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best albums of 2021 so far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/14/the-best-albums-of-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/14/the-best-albums-of-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:16:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From drill’s high watermark to Tuareg rock, Colombian pop and London jazz, here are our music editors’ picks of the best LPs from the first half of the year
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas, Alexis Petridis and Laura Snapes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bard day’s work: what I learned from eavesdropping on RSC rehearsals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/14/bard-days-work-what-i-learned-from-eavesdropping-on-rsc-rehearsals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/14/bard-days-work-what-i-learned-from-eavesdropping-on-rsc-rehearsals"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:15:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Royal Shakespeare Company is letting the public watch the usually secret processes towards performance – from clapping games to verse sessions
The creative process normally takes place behind closed doors. But the RSC has boldly upended that idea by streaming its Open Rehearsal Project for Henry VI Part One. What this means, in practice, is that cameras are admitted for three sessions each day. At 10am we watch a half-hour company warm-up. From noon, for 90 minutes, we get to see either a class (movement, combat, verse-speaking) or the rehearsal of a scene. Then at 6pm we eavesdrop on a green-room chat, in which company members mull over progress so far. After dipping in and out for the first fortnight – and there’s still more than a week to go before a streamed performance on 23 June – I’m intrigued by how much I’ve learned.
But are open rehearsals a good idea? There was a pivotal moment when Gregory Doran – who shares direction of the project with Owen Horsley – quoted a letter he’d received from an actor who said “the rehearsal room is sacrosanct – actors must not be exposed like this”. I spoke to a veteran actor who said she too was horrified by the idea of the public witnessing the trial and error that takes place in a rehearsal room.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Billington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damaris Hayman obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/14/damaris-hayman-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/14/damaris-hayman-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T15:09:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor who often played boisterous games mistresses, discreet secretaries and jolly passers-by
The actor Damaris Hayman, who has died aged 91, was perhaps the last conduit to a bygone age of British comedy, her toothy bonhomie and breezy eccentricity making her a reliable supporting player to many of the big and small screen comedy stars from the 1950s to the 80s.
With a slight sibilance, a jaunty air and tally-ho demeanour, she was, comedically, almost the missing link between Joyce Grenfell and Miranda Hart – the embodiment of the kind of genteel humour required for boisterous games mistresses, discreet secretaries, jolly passers-by and, latterly, dotty old ladies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Hadoke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black hair takes centre stage as London fashion week focuses on identity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/14/london-fashion-week-show-put-beauty-of-black-hair-centre-stage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/14/london-fashion-week-show-put-beauty-of-black-hair-centre-stage"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T14:34:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Priya Ahluwalia aims to switch narrative to black hair being a ‘thing of beauty’
A poem written in the aftermath of Syria’s six-day war of 1967, the Brixton riots of 1985 and the joy and burden of heritage have all been reflected in key shows at this year’s London fashion week as political identity took centre stage.
And that was no different in the latest show from the British designer Priya Ahluwalia, which put black hair front and centre. Afro hair continues to be political: in the workplace, in schools and in a society that doesn’t connect it to identity. It’s even the star of its own literary satire in Zakiya Dalila Harris’s The Other Black Girl.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan Deputy fashion editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr Christian Jessen on how we made TV’s Embarrassing Bodies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/how-we-made-embarrassing-bodies-christian-jessen-on-tvs-intimate-hit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/how-we-made-embarrassing-bodies-christian-jessen-on-tvs-intimate-hit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T14:13:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘We were a lifesaver for people with things – such as wonky boobs – that the NHS might only consider cosmetic’
I had done some TV before and a friend told me about a fly on the wall series that needed a male doctor. I thought: “What have I got to lose?” Originally, though, the show was called Embarrassing Illnesses, but after pressure from us doctors, the producers changed it. We shouldn’t be calling illnesses embarrassing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Caitlin Tilley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delta variant of Covid spreading rapidly and detected in 74 countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/delta-variant-of-covid-spreading-rapidly-and-detected-in-74-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/delta-variant-of-covid-spreading-rapidly-and-detected-in-74-countries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T14:03:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Concerns over impact on poorer countries, while richer governments try different containment measures

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The Delta variant of Covid-19, first identified in India, has been detected in 74 countries and continues to spread rapidly amid fears that it is poised to become the dominant strain worldwide.
Outbreaks of the Delta variant have been confirmed in China, the US, Africa, Scandinavia and Pacific rim countries. Scientists report that it appears to be more transmissible, as well as to cause more serious illness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Viewing Booth review – seeing is believing in the Israel-Palestine conflict]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/14/the-viewing-booth-review-seeing-is-believing-in-the-israel-palestine-conflict</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/14/the-viewing-booth-review-seeing-is-believing-in-the-israel-palestine-conflict"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T14:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Volunteers respond to politically polarised film footage from Israel and the Palestinian territories in this critical look at interpretation 
Even though he tries to maintain a cool, scientific demeanour, Israeli director Ra’anan Alexandrowicz finally lets slip a twinge of despair at the end of this interesting geopolitical Rorschach test. Alexandrowicz sits studiously behind a monitor as he invites a succession of volunteers to enter an adjacent booth. There, they have a choice of 40 clips to watch, snippets of life in Israel, while he asks them to share their thoughts on what they see. Half of the clips are from rightwing Israeli sources; the other half are from B’Tselem, an Israeli human-rights organisation that aims to document abuses of power in Palestinian territories.
Alexandrowicz quickly zeroes in on the pensive Maia, a Jewish American who supports Israel, but brings an insistent scepticism to everything she watches. He is the director of pro-Palestine documentaries such as The Inner Tour (2001) and The Law in These Parts (2011) – and believes her to be his ideal audience: a possible convert.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phil Hoad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Northern Ireland protocol isn't perfect – but the UK and EU can make it work | David Phinnemore]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/northern-ireland-protocol-uk-eu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/northern-ireland-protocol-uk-eu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:39:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The wrangling over the agreement will end if both sides honour their commitment to pragmatism
Brexit, by definition, was always going to be disruptive. And the harder the Brexit, the greater the disruption.
Leaving a customs union and a single market, even if you subsequently secure a free trade agreement, means the reintroduction of customs formalities, regulatory checks and other non-tariff barriers. And if you agree with the European Union that part of the state will de facto remain in the EU’s customs territory and its internal market for goods, those frictions will be within the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Phinnemore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342070</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/securing-your-website-with-subresource-integrity/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you load a file from an external server, you’re trusting that the content you request is what you expect it to be. Since you don’t manage the server yourself, you’re relying on the security of yet another third party …
The post Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khari McMillian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC report clears staff over rehiring of Martin Bashir]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/bbc-report-clears-staff-over-rehiring-of-martin-bashir</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/bbc-report-clears-staff-over-rehiring-of-martin-bashir"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:25:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inquiry says there were ‘shortcomings’ in process, but no one involved knew of methods Bashir used to secure Diana interview
An investigation into the BBC’s rehiring of Martin Bashir as its religious affairs correspondent in 2016 has cleared all of those involved in his recruitment, while also finding there were some “shortcomings” in the process.
The rapid internal investigation, led by the longstanding BBC executive Ken MacQuarrie, found that none of those involved in rehiring Bashir had knowledge of the deceitful methods he had used to secure the famous Panorama interview with Diana, Princess of Wales, in 1995.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Israeli government is just as bad as the last, says Palestinian PM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/naftali-bennett-israel-world-leaders-welcome</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/naftali-bennett-israel-world-leaders-welcome"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T12:56:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohammad Shtayyeh condemns Naftali Bennett’s announcements in support of Israeli settlements 
Benjamin Netanyahu’s ousting closes one of the “worst periods” of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict but the new government headed by a settler advocate, Naftali Bennett, is just as bad as the last, the Palestinian prime minister has said.
“We do not see this new government as any less bad than the previous one, and we condemn the announcements of the new prime minister Naftali Bennett in support of Israeli settlements,” Mohammad Shtayyeh said, referring to hundreds of thousands of Jewish Israelis who have taken land in the occupied West Bank.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem, and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK and EU try to settle standoff over Northern Ireland Brexit checks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/uk-and-eu-try-to-settle-standoff-over-northern-ireland-brexit-checks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/14/uk-and-eu-try-to-settle-standoff-over-northern-ireland-brexit-checks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T12:43:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit minister and EU Commission official to meet this week as tensions remain high

The Brexit minister Lord Frost and the European Commission vice-president, Maroš Šefčovič, are expected to meet virtually this week to try to break the deadlock over Brexit checks in Northern Ireland.
But as the countdown begins to a 30 June ban on the sale of chilled meats, including sausages, from Great Britain in Northern Irish supermarkets, tensions between the EU and Boris Johnson’s government remain heightened.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll and Daniel Boffey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s be having you! Which football team has the best famous fans?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/which-football-team-has-the-best-famous-fans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/14/which-football-team-has-the-best-famous-fans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T12:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Stormzy at Manchester United to Idris Elba at Arsenal, who’s got the starriest fanbase?

It didn’t take more than a few minutes after the final whistle of the Champions League final last month for the cameras to find Liam Gallagher in the stands looking sad. It wasn’t really a surprise to see him in Porto – listen to Gallagher and his elder brother Noel speak for more than a few seconds and one of them will mention being a die-hard Manchester City fan. Back when City’s neighbours, Manchester United, were hoovering up trophies in the 90s (and earning a possibly unfair reputation for having more fans in Surrey than the north-west), that Gallagher patronage gave City cool points. But are Man City still the league leaders when it comes to famous fans?
 Related: The Guide: Staying In – sign up for our home entertainment tips 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ITV apologises after reporter threatens to ‘bang out’ man]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/itv-apologises-after-reporter-threatens-to-bang-out-man</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/14/itv-apologises-after-reporter-threatens-to-bang-out-man"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Callum Watkinson swears at member of public who disrupted live broadcast in Birmingham

ITV has apologised after one of its reporters was filmed swearing and threatening to “bang out” a member of the public who disrupted him during a live broadcast.
Callum Watkinson, a reporter at ITV Central, launched into the tirade during filming next to Centenary Square, Birmingham, after a man apparently deliberately disrupted a live broadcast by walking into the back of the shot.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray Midlands correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trans rally and a foul flower: Monday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/14/trans-rally-foul-flower-monday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/14/trans-rally-foul-flower-monday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:33:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ned Beatty: the good ol’ boy who made playing the ordinary guy look easy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/14/ned-beatty-the-good-ol-boy-who-made-playing-the-ordinary-guy-look-easy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/14/ned-beatty-the-good-ol-boy-who-made-playing-the-ordinary-guy-look-easy"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:20:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From his breakthrough in Deliverance to a memorable turn in Toy Story 3, the authenticity of Beatty’s middleman gone bad made him the perfect co-star – and often stole the show

Ned Beatty dies aged 83

If ever a character actor personified the “good ol’ boy” archetype of Hollywood’s new cinema of the 1970s it was Ned Beatty from Louisville, Kentucky, whose broad, open, good-natured face seemed so often to be covered with a sheen of sweat – either from suppressed guilt, or tension, from discomfort in whatever sweltering southern clime he happened to find himself. His was a smiley face bounded by its prosperous double-chin and nascent combover, a face that lent reality and approachability to the movies: an authentic and worldly presence.
Ned Beatty had the hardest role to play: the middle-ranking ordinary guy: lawyer, cop, official, politician and maybe, effectively, the wingman to the conventionally better-looking male leads, and in his 70s movie heyday this tended to mean Burt Reynolds, with whom he starred in six films, including, of course, Beatty’s brilliant and brutal breakthrough: Deliverance (1972), written by James Dickey and directed by John Boorman, in which Reynolds’s sinister alpha male businessman leads his buddies Beatty, Jon Voight and Ronny Cox on a vacation canoeing trip through the deepest Georgia wilderness only to come into horrible contact with hillbillies playing banjos and bearing grudges.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fag end: 21 unusual ways to quit smoking, from changing your teeth to taking more showers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/fag-end-21-unusual-ways-to-quit-smoking-from-changing-your-teeth-to-taking-more-showers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/fag-end-21-unusual-ways-to-quit-smoking-from-changing-your-teeth-to-taking-more-showers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If patches, hypnosis and self-help books don’t work, maybe it’s time to think laterally. Readers reveal the unlikely methods that encouraged them to kick the habit
I smoked 10 to 20 a day, but finally quit 11 years ago. I found getting a glass of water when the cravings hit worked really well. By the time I went to the kitchen, poured it and drank it, the peak of the craving had usually passed. It also helped me to realise that you can ride out a craving. The first three weeks were the hardest. Michael, artist and educator, Scotland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Cultural appropriation is a two-way thing’: Yinka Shonibare on Picasso, masks and the fashion for black artists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/14/masks-monsters-masterpieces-yinka-shonibare-picasso-africa</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/14/masks-monsters-masterpieces-yinka-shonibare-picasso-africa"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T11:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Picasso was so enthralled by African art, he used it to start a revolution. But did it give rise to a fantasy of Africa that still endures? British-Nigerian artist Shonibare tells us why he’s revisiting that seismic moment 
In 1998, in a hilarious work called Diary of a Victorian Dandy, Yinka Shonibare inserted himself, impeccably attired, into the sitting rooms, drawing rooms, billiards rooms and bedrooms of high society Victorian Britain, invariably causing a sensation in each of the perfectly mocked-up photographs. The work mimics William Hogarth’s The Rake’s Progress, but instead of ending up in Bedlam, like Hogarth’s protagonist, Shonibare the Dandy triumphs over white society at everything from financial dealing to fine conversation. It all climaxes with him having a great time in a brothel with no apparent guilt or punishment. Well, it was the 1990s – and Shonibare was a bona fide Young British Artist. Also, he says with a laugh, “Hogarth was the first YBA.”
Shonibare has played plenty of games with art and history since, including refitting a model of HMS Victory – that most British of all vessels, the flagship of the Battle of Trafalgar – with sails of (supposedly) African batik fabric and sticking it in a giant bottle. But now the British-Nigerian artist is turning his attention to the birth of modern art in Picasso’s Paris. Not many artists come away from an encounter with Pablo looking good. A 2012 Tate exhibition about the Spaniard and modern British art left Henry Moore and Francis Bacon looking very small indeed. But Shonibare engages with the old Minotaur in a relaxed, funny yet profoundly insightful way.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccines are working – but these charts show why England is delaying reopening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/covid-vaccines-are-working-but-charts-show-right-delay-reopening-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/covid-vaccines-are-working-but-charts-show-right-delay-reopening-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccines are reducing Covid deaths but data shows parts of the country remain unprotected

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Two-thirds of the population in England are insufficiently protected against the Delta coronavirus variant, exclusive data analysis by the Guardian can reveal.
Despite promising signs that the vaccine is working – including record low hospital admissions in relation to the number of cases – this lack of immunity is critical to the government’s decision to further ease restrictions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kirk, Anna Leach, Niko Kommenda and Cath Levett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The rush to ‘go electric’ comes with a hidden cost: destructive lithium mining | Thea Riofrancos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/electric-cost-lithium-mining-decarbonasation-salt-flats-chile</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/14/electric-cost-lithium-mining-decarbonasation-salt-flats-chile"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:45:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the world moves towards electric cars and renewable grids, demand for lithium is wreaking havoc in northern Chile
The Atacama salt flat is a majestic, high-altitude expanse of gradations of white and grey, peppered with red lagoons and ringed by towering volcanoes. It took me a moment to get my bearings on my first visit, standing on this windswept plateau of 3,000 sq km (1,200 sq miles). A vertiginous drive had taken me and two other researchers through a sandstorm, a rainstorm and the peaks and valleys of this mountainous region of northern Chile. The sun bore down on us intensely – the Atacama desert boasts the Earth’s highest levels of solar radiation, and only parts of Antarctica are drier. 
I had come to the salt flat to research an emerging environmental dilemma. In order to stave off the worst of the accelerating climate crisis, we need to rapidly reduce carbon emissions. To do so, energy systems around the world must transition from fossil fuels to renewable energy. Lithium batteries play a key role in this transition: they power electric vehicles and store energy on renewable grids, helping to cut emissions from transportation and energy sectors. Underneath the Atacama salt flat lies most of the world’s lithium reserves; Chile currently supplies almost a quarter of the global market. But extracting lithium from this unique landscape comes at a grave environmental and social cost.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thea Riofrancos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘He bought me a toothbrush to keep at his flat – and I panicked’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/how-we-met-he-bought-me-a-toothbrush-to-keep-at-his-flat-and-i-panicked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/how-we-met-he-bought-me-a-toothbrush-to-keep-at-his-flat-and-i-panicked"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Helen, 47, and Ray, 49, met in 1999 when she interviewed his band for a magazine. They got together in 2001 and now live in Staffordshire with their two sons
Helen landed her dream job at the end of the 1990s, working as a writer for Total Guitar magazine. She was living in Bath, travelling across the country for gigs whenever she got the chance. In May 1999, she went to Reading to interview the band Witness, who were supporting Hurricane #1, and met the lead guitarist, Ray. “The band were so friendly and down to earth,” she remembers. “I met a lot of musicians who were egotistical, but Ray wasn’t like that.” 
Witness had been working on their first album in Bristol, where Ray was based at the time. “We’d done a few interviews, but that one felt like a big deal,” he says. “We were worried about what to say and I thought she might ask lots of technical guitar questions that I didn’t know how to answer.” But the interview went “really well” and he was taken with Helen. “She caught my eye and I thought: ‘She’s nice.’” 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘These races are epic’: why ultrarunning is soaring in popularity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/these-races-are-epic-why-ultrarunning-is-soaring-in-popularity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/these-races-are-epic-why-ultrarunning-is-soaring-in-popularity"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T09:23:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The events can be gruelling and even dangerous, yet more and more people are signing up
John Stocker hadn’t slept in three-and-a-half days when he finally crossed the finish line after running more than 337 miles in an ultramarathon event in Suffolk, stopping only at brief intervals for food and rest.
Of the 123 people who started the race in Knettishall Heath on 5 June, he was the last person still running 81 hours later on Tuesday evening, and had to summon all of his physical and mental strength to get around the last lap.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how would a delay in lifting lockdown restrictions affect your wedding plans?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/tell-us-how-would-a-delay-in-lifting-lockdown-restrictions-affect-your-wedding-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/tell-us-how-would-a-delay-in-lifting-lockdown-restrictions-affect-your-wedding-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T09:18:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from engaged couples about how a lockdown extension would affect their wedding or civil partnership plans
The prime minister is expected to announce on Monday that the national lockdown timetable will be extended by two to four weeks. However, the government may relax the rules in some cases, such as lifting the limit on wedding guest numbers.
We would like to hear from engaged couples about how this might affect their wedding or civil partnership plans. You can let us know using the form below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It was so nasty. He laughed in my face’: How to love and trust again after a big romantic betrayal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/it-was-so-nasty-he-laughed-in-my-face-how-to-love-and-trust-again-after-a-big-romantic-betrayal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/14/it-was-so-nasty-he-laughed-in-my-face-how-to-love-and-trust-again-after-a-big-romantic-betrayal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T09:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a long-term partner cheats on you it can be devastating, but it is possible to move on in time. Here, experts and Guardian readers explain how best to rebuild your life
Sarah and her husband were anchored in a remote harbour – more than a year into their round-the-world sailing voyage, and decades into their relationship – when she read a message on his tablet that made her collapse to the floor of their boat. It was from a man on a gay pornography website. Others like it revealed six years of betrayal by her husband, including a long-term relationship with a married man.
Sarah was one of many Guardian readers who responded to our invitation to share experiences of betrayal. Although every respondent’s circumstances were unique, and they were of different nationalities, backgrounds, ages and sexualities, there was one thing that linked all their experiences: mind-shattering suffering. I could understand why in his Inferno Dante reserved his ninth and deepest circle of hell for those who committed treachery. Avishai Margalit, the philosopher and author of On Betrayal, tells me that whether we are reading Dante or the Bible, Shakespearean tragedy, Greek mythology or Guardian readers’ stories, we can empathise with the pain of someone betrayed. It endures across time and space, culture and history.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Moya Sarner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giulio Regeni’s last messages before his death in Egypt counter spy claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/14/giulio-regeni-last-messages-before-his-death-in-egypt-counter-spy-claims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/14/giulio-regeni-last-messages-before-his-death-in-egypt-counter-spy-claims"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T08:55:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook messages from the Italian student killed in Cairo in 2016 show his concerns about studying in the country
The Facebook messages written by the Cambridge student Giulio Regeni in the weeks leading up to his murder give the lie to any notion he was a spy or political agitator.
Even before he left England, Regeni was concerned about the risks he might face doing his thesis on trade unions in Egypt, a sensitive subject in the country.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anthony Harwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Promises and protests at the G7 in Cornwall – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/promises-and-protests-at-the-g7-in-cornwall-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/promises-and-protests-at-the-g7-in-cornwall-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T08:35:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our photographer looks back on three days of politics and demonstrations during the summit in Carbis Bay
With more than 6,000 police deployed to Cornwall for the G7 summit in Carbis Bay, there were surreal sights everywhere: armed officers on residential streets, snipers on rooftops, marine units in St Ives harbour and battleships in the sea. Many residents revelled in the opportunity to catch a glimpse of the action as world leaders and diplomats were convoyed into Carbis Bay, while others objected to the draconian restrictions which included a so-called “ring of steel” around the neighbourhood.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonny Weeks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The woman who forced the US government to take UFOs seriously]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/leslie-kean-ufo-reporter-us-government-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/leslie-kean-ufo-reporter-us-government-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T08:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1999, Leslie Kean was handed a 90-page report of UFO sightings by pilots. After publishing her first story on the subject, she was hooked
If it wasn’t for the French dossier, UFOs might not have dominated Leslie Kean’s life for the past two decades.
In 1999, the independent journalist was handed a scoop by a French colleague: a 90-page report of UFO sightings by military and commercial pilots. The document, called UFOs and Defense: For What Must We Prepare Ourselves? (in French: Les OVNI et la Défense: À Quoi Doit-On Se Préparer?), was eventually published by a French military thinktank.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Soo Youn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘No human survives alone’ … Misan Harriman’s portraits for Refugee Week – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/gallery/2021/jun/14/no-human-survives-alone-misan-harrimans-portraits-for-refugee-week-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/gallery/2021/jun/14/no-human-survives-alone-misan-harrimans-portraits-for-refugee-week-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T08:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today is the start of Refugee Week, coordinated in the UK by Counterpoint Arts. The acclaimed photographer and new chair of the Southbank Centre Misan Harriman has photographed prominent supporters of refugees under the theme We Cannot Walk Alone, a line from Martin Luther King’s I Have a Dream speech. Depicting individuals from diverse backgrounds who have chosen to ‘walk with others’, the series aims to promote a fairer world where everyone is valued
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Portraits by Misan Harriman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bird costs less than a pint: welcome to Britain’s poultry capital]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/bird-costs-less-than-pint-welcome-to-britains-poultry-capital-hereford-shropshire-powys</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/bird-costs-less-than-pint-welcome-to-britains-poultry-capital-hereford-shropshire-powys"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than a quarter of UK chickens come from just three counties – putting Hereford, Shropshire and Powys at the centre of a booming industry and a row over intensive farming
Growing up on the family farm in rural Herefordshire, Richard Corbett’s fondest memories are of tinkering in his father’s workshop. “I always assumed I’d be a farmer,” says the 55-year-old. “But if I’m honest, as a teenager I preferred messing about with machinery.”
Today, Corbett’s engineering passion is channelled into maintaining his beloved road bike, and the family farm is a multimillion-pound concern. The vast majority of that annual turnover comes from rearing chickens.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Eveleigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plastic rafting: the invasive species hitching a ride on ocean litter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/plastic-rafting-the-invasive-species-hitching-a-ride-on-ocean-litter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/14/plastic-rafting-the-invasive-species-hitching-a-ride-on-ocean-litter"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is now so much ocean plastic that it has become a route for invasive species, threatening native animals with extinction
Japan’s 2011 tsunami was catastrophic, killing nearly 16,000 people, destroying homes and infrastructure, and sweeping an estimated 5m tons of debris out to sea.
That debris did not disappear, however. Some of it drifted all the way across the Pacific, reaching the shores of Hawaii, Alaska and California – and with it came hitchhikers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Russell Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tibet: on the roof of the world – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/14/tibet-on-the-roof-of-the-world-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/14/tibet-on-the-roof-of-the-world-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China recently eased Covid travel restrictions for foreign visitors to Tibet in an effort to boost tourism. Beijing is aiming for 61 million visitors a year by 2025, more than 15 times the number of Tibet’s inhabitants. Foreign journalists, normally not permitted to travel to the autonomous region, were also taken on a visit organised by the government
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Frayer, Getty Images</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Really surreal’: moment BLM activist rescued far-right protester from mob]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/really-surreal-moment-blm-activist-rescued-far-right-protester-from-mob</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/really-surreal-moment-blm-activist-rescued-far-right-protester-from-mob"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patrick Hutchinson’s decision to carry a far-right protester to safety became the defining image of last summer’s anti-racist movement
Patrick Hutchinson doesn’t normally attend protests. He says he prefers to bring about change through other means. But when he saw a video of Tommy Robinson calling on far-right activists to descend on London last summer to protect national monuments, the 50-year-old grandfather of four knew he couldn’t stay at home and just watch things unfold on TV.
“I felt obligated because I grew up in the 90s and 80s, when the National Front was constantly terrorising the black community,” he said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What went wrong with the Covid-19 response in the US? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/14/what-went-wrong-with-the-us-covid-19-response-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/14/what-went-wrong-with-the-us-covid-19-response-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author and journalist Lawrence Wright has been writing about pandemics for decades. So when Covid-19 struck the US, he was ideally placed to report on the political response
At the beginning of 2020 the author Lawrence Wright published a novel in which he imagined a deadly virus outbreak that swept the globe. He couldn’t have predicted that as that book hit the shops real life was eerily mimicking his plot. As a reporter for the New Yorker, Wright had been reporting on pandemics for decades and was ideally placed to chart the spread of Covid-19. 
He tells Anushka Asthana that what unfolded was to become America’s deadliest year, with half a million people lost to the virus. Inside the White House, there were experts desperately trying to influence the president to change course on key decisions. But the story of the initial Covid response, argues Wright, was one of a significant political failure.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Lawrence Wright; produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News review – Andrew Neil’s alternative BBC? Utterly deadly stuff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/13/gb-news-review-andrew-neils-alternative-bbc-utterly-deadly-stuff</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/13/gb-news-review-andrew-neils-alternative-bbc-utterly-deadly-stuff"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T22:36:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ‘anti-woke’ news channel had Andrew Neil and Alan Sugar, but no Piers Morgan – and the opening night felt like the furthest thing from appointment TV imaginable. I give it a year
“Now is the time to do news differently,” said Andrew Neil as GB News went live on Sunday night. “We are committed to covering the people’s agenda, not the media’s agenda.” Not in the first hour you weren’t. Instead, Neil spent it introducing his new colleagues while – be still irony – indicting the woke numpties from traditional news channels stuck in the narcissistic Westminster bubble. There may have been news breaking during the hour (indeed it was scrolling on a ticker at the bottom of the screen) but it went unreported.
No matter. First up was Neil Oliver, former BBC archaeology presenter turned GB News current affairs presenter, whom Neil introduced as the King of Scotland. An ill-omened title, given that the last title holder was Idi Amin. “I seem to have come to the fore with opinions,” he told Andrew Neil. “People talk to me all the time. They come up to me when they’re walking the dogs. They no longer feel their voices or voices like theirs are out in the mainstream.” The thing to do, Neil baby, is not to slow down.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the world’s most fertile fishing ground is facing a ‘unique and dire’ threat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/why-the-worlds-most-fertile-fishing-ground-is-facing-a-unique-and-dire-threat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/14/why-the-worlds-most-fertile-fishing-ground-is-facing-a-unique-and-dire-threat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T20:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China’s Pacific fishing fleet has grown by 500% since 2012 and is taking huge quantities of tuna

Read more of our Pacific Plunder series here

Since long before the steel-hulled fishing boats from foreign countries arrived in the South Pacific its people have had their own systems for sharing the ocean’s catches.
In the New Zealand territory of Tokelau, in the middle of the region, the 1,400 people living on its three atolls practise a system called inati, which ensures every household gets fish.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Field</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The weekend’s best photos: high dives and a rare-breed dog – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/13/weekend-best-photos-high-dives-rare-breed-dog-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/13/weekend-best-photos-high-dives-rare-breed-dog-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T13:50:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Blason</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten cooks who changed the way we eat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/gallery/2021/jun/13/ten-cooks-who-changed-the-way-we-eat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/gallery/2021/jun/13/ten-cooks-who-changed-the-way-we-eat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Rayner picks the cookbooks that have made a real difference to the British dinner table and explains why these are his go-to recipe books for home chefs 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Rayner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’re causing our own misery’: oceanographer Sylvia Earle on the need for sea conservation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/12/were-causing-our-own-misery-oceanographer-sylvia-earle-on-the-need-for-sea-conservation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-12T07:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Queen of the Deep’ says it is not too late to reverse human-made damage to oceans and preserve biodiversity
The world has the opportunity in the next 10 years to restore our oceans to health after decades of steep decline – but to achieve that, people must wake up to the problem, join in efforts to protect marine areas and stop eating tuna, according to the oceanographer and deep sea explorer Sylvia Earle.
“We are at the most exciting time maybe ever to be a human, because we’re armed with knowledge,” said Earle, also known as the Queen of the Deep and “her Deepness”. Earle has also set numerous records for deep sea diving, and was the first woman to serve as chief scientist of the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is a Disaster Recovery Plan? How to Use RTO and RPO to Protect your Business]]></title>
        <id>60b72d5facb62507dd1d777b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/disaster-recovery-plan-what-are-rto-and-rpo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T22:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're in the world of tech, you will inevitably run into a work-related disaster now and then. These setbacks come in many forms such as cyber-attacks, theft, leaks, and corruption. And every business must be ready to face these things and plan for them. Sir Benjamin Franklin famously said,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342429</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/safari-15-new-ui-theme-colors-and-a-css-tricks-cameo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a 33-minute video (and resources) over on apple.com covering the upcoming Safari changes we saw in the WWDC keynote this year in much more detail. Look who’s got a little cameo in there:
Perhaps the most noticeable thing there …
The post Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Possibilities of Syndication]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342237</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-possibilities-of-syndication/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s the one word that isn’t an adjective in the acronym RSS. 
Really Simple Syndication.
Update: Lol there are literally two mistakes there. RSS is an initialism not an acronym, and “Really” is an adverb not an adjective. 
RSS …
The post The Possibilities of Syndication appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Center Anything in CSS Using Flexbox and Grid ✨]]></title>
        <id>6063b9189618b008528a9d81</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-center-objects-using-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T20:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I'm gonna show you how you can center and align your content with CSS. Along the way, we'll look at various alignment techniques. So, let's get started! 🥇 Table of Contents -> How to Use Flexbox to center anything horizontally center anything vertically center both horizontally & Vertically How]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Design Keyboard Accessibility for Complex React Experiences]]></title>
        <id>5f9c97e9740569d1a4ca1768</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/designing-keyboard-accessibility-for-complex-react-experiences/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T19:10:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How you can design an inclusive and accessible org chart experience and solutions to common development challenges you will face.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ask Good Technical Questions – the Ultimate Guide]]></title>
        <id>60bc0444acb62507dd1d9a31</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-ask-good-technical-questions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:39:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing how to ask effective technical questions is an essential skill every software engineer should have.  You may be stuck with a bug, unable to figure out why your program isn't working correctly, or you might be having trouble learning how to implement a certain algorithm. In all of these]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Level Up Your React Conditionals]]></title>
        <id>60c24cf8d3126007592d61d5</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-react-conditionals/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T16:04:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you write conditionals correctly within your React applications?  Good conditionals are an essential part of any React application. We use conditionals to show or hide elements or components in our applications.  In short – to be an effective React developer, you must know how to write good conditionals. Let's go]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342164</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/adding-shadows-to-svg-icons-with-css-and-svg-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would we need to apply shadows to SVG?
Shadows are a common design feature that can help elements, like icons, stand out. They could be persistent, or applied in different states (e.g. :hover, :focus, or :active) 
…
The post Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Olawanle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your ingenious holiday packing hacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/11/tell-us-about-your-ingenious-holiday-packing-hacks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T11:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on what to pack and how to maximise your wardrobe while travelling
For those of us lucky enough to be able to go on holiday this summer, there’s always one issue: what to pack? And more importantly, how to pack efficiently.
With this in mind, we want to hear about your best packing hacks. Perhaps you’ve discovered the secret to maximising your wardrobe? Or maybe you swear by soap and shampoo bars over liquid toiletries, to avoid leakage in your luggage? Whether it’s a must-have gadget, or a space-saving tip, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rukmini Iyer’s trio of summer salads: chicken, butter beans and feta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/jun/11/rukmini-iyers-trio-of-summer-salads-chicken-butter-beans-and-feta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/jun/11/rukmini-iyers-trio-of-summer-salads-chicken-butter-beans-and-feta"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T10:51:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Roasting Tin author on three ways to add colour and crunch to your summer feasting table
These recipes highlight that a few good ingredients need little more than a simple dressing to shine.
In all three, the star ingredient – from my favourite Navarrico jarred butter beans to free-range chicken and good feta cheese – has a short stint marinating in a herby lemon and olive oil dressing before stirring it through with a handful of complementary ingredients.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rukmini Iyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GB News enters the culture war - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/11/gb-news-enters-the-culture-war-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T02:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To its critics, it is a British Fox News; to its creators, it is a vital correction to a liberal London-centric media. Can Andrew Neil’s upstart news channel change the face of British broadcasting?
For years, Britain’s rolling news landscape has been dominated by Sky and the BBC. On Sunday, a new rival, GB News, is entering the fray – and although its chairman and most famous face, Andrew Neil, insists that any comparisons to Fox News are idiotic, many see an echo in its plan to use outspoken presenters to discuss the most controversial issues of the day. 
But Neil insists that the plan is not to tack to the right, but to address an audience which he says has been let down by the existing broadcasters – and which he believes is crying out for a channel that addresses its concerns. As the channel’s newly hired team race to be ready for their debut, Anushka Asthana asks the Guardian’s media editor, Jim Waterson, whether GB News is bound to be a participant in the so-called culture war – and whether a British audience really wants to see a radical departure from the more traditional model that dominates today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Jim Waterson; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put a Background on Open Details Elements]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342050</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/put-a-background-on-open-details-elements/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T00:16:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One thing that can be just a smidge funky about the <details> element is that, when open, it’s not always 100% clear what is inside that element and what isn’t. I’m not saying that always matters or that it’s a …
The post Put a Background on Open Details Elements appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341894</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/equal-columns-with-flexbox-its-more-complicated-than-you-might-think/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As awesome as flexbox is, what it’s doing under the hood is actually a little strange because, by default, it is doing two things at once. It first looks at the content size which is what we would get if by declaring width: max-content on an element. But on top of that, flex-shrink is also doing some work allowing the items to be smaller, but only if needed.
Let’s break those two down and see how they work together.
The post Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-headless-cms-with-fauna-and-vercel-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will learn and use headless CMS, Fauna, and Vercel functions to build a blogging platform, Blogify After that, you can easily build any web application using a headless CMS, Fauna and Vercel functions.
The post Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ikeh Akinyemi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 and a crucial moment for the climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T02:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s richest democracies will come together in Britain this week with global heating high on the agenda. Can they match big promises with concrete action? 
The damage wrought by the coronavirus pandemic has been huge, but it pales in comparison to the potential risks associated with the climate crisis. With the world coalescing around the importance of limiting temperature rises to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, the next 10 years are the last chance to meet that goal - and with the Cop26 summit in Glasgow later this year, the G7 summit in Cornwall this week is the next staging post in a crucial six months to settle on a way forward.
But even as many countries set out significant pledges to do their part, the reality of their policies is often far behind. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s environment correspondent, Fiona Harvey, about what must happen to catch up with those commitments – and what this summit will tell us about the likelihood of making changes that are crucial to averting catastrophe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Fiona Harvey; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cornucopia of Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340967</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-cornucopia-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know about y’all, but my feeds have been flooded with articles about CSS Container Queries these past few weeks. The buzz about container queries actually started back in December after Miriam Suzanne posted a proposal (picking up on …
The post A Cornucopia of Container Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[target=blank]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341916</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/targetblank/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does that make your eye twitch a little bit? Like… it’s a typo. It should be target="_blank" with an underscore to start the value. As in…
<a target="_blank" href="https://codepen.io"Open CodePen in a New Tab
</a
Welp, that’s correct syntax!…
The post target=blank appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have an example of UK car-led town planning you want to change?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/do-you-have-an-example-of-uk-car-led-town-planning-you-want-to-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of examples of car-led redevelopment where you live 
We’d like to find out how your UK town or city was redesigned for road vehicles.
From the 1950s onwards many towns and cities across the UK adopted car led planning in line with rising car ownership. Today, many residents in urban areas hope to have more environmentally friendly spaces and cleaner air which is at odds with past car led redevelopment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of your amazing sheds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about the impressive garden sheds you have built and customised
During lockdown some people have taken to sprucing up their sheds, whether it’s to give them a new lease of life or to create a haven away in the garden.
We would like to hear about your amazing sheds, however humble, and what they mean to you. If you have customised yours, what inspired you? What do you use it for?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341982</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/looking-at-wcag-2-5-5-for-better-target-sizes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever experienced the frustration of trying to tap a button on a mobile device only to have it do nothing because the target size is just not large enough **and it’s not picking up on your press? Maybe …
The post Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Todd Libby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341884</id>
        <link href="https://alex.party/posts/2021-05-31-css-trickz-an-experiment-with-netlify-s-on-demand-builders/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress sites have an API by default. Wanna see this site’s most recent posts, with just a specific set of data… in JSON format? Here ya go. Alex Riviere made a joke site using that.
At first, the site …
The post CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To the manor booked: Britain’s historic homes and castles turned hotels – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/beautifully-british-escapes/gallery/2021/may/20/to-the-manor-booked-britains-historic-homes-and-castles-turned-hotels-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/beautifully-british-escapes/gallery/2021/may/20/to-the-manor-booked-britains-historic-homes-and-castles-turned-hotels-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:59:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Illustrious inhabitants, illicit romances and ghostly guests – plus suites, spas, bars and hotel breakfasts. Whether you’re after Victorian castles or Grade I Tudor houses, take your next minibreak in a heritage home
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Mellor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>