<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-17T00:30:03.446Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-17T00:30:03.446Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First astronauts to blast off for China’s new space station]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/17/first-astronauts-blast-off-for-china-new-space-station-tiangong</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/17/first-astronauts-blast-off-for-china-new-space-station-tiangong"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T23:46:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hugely prestigious event for China as Beijing prepares to mark 100th anniversary of ruling Communist party
The first astronauts for China’s new space station are due to blast off for the country’s longest crewed mission to date, a landmark step in establishing Beijing as a major space power.
The trio will launch on a Long March-2F rocket for the Tiangong station, where they will spend three months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number of EU citizens seeking work in UK falls 36% since Brexit, study shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/17/number-of-eu-citizens-seeking-work-in-uk-falls-36-since-brexit-study-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/17/number-of-eu-citizens-seeking-work-in-uk-falls-36-since-brexit-study-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T23:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figures from the jobs website Indeed expose the impact on employers as they struggle to recruit staff
The number of EU citizens searching for work in Britain has fallen by more than a third since Brexit, according to a study that exposes the impact on UK employers as they struggle to recruit staff.
Figures from the jobs website Indeed show searches by EU-based jobseekers for work in the UK were down by 36% in May from average levels in 2019. Low-paid jobs in hospitality, the care sector and warehouses recorded the biggest declines at 41%.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social media stars under fire for flouting rules on advertising]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/17/social-media-stars-under-fire-for-flouting-rules-on-advertising</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/17/social-media-stars-under-fire-for-flouting-rules-on-advertising"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T23:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advertising Standards Authority launches roll-call of offenders who fail to to make clear paid-for endorsement
Social media stars Jodie Marsh, Chloe Khan, Lucy Mecklenburgh and Chloe Ferry have been named and shamed by the UK advertising watchdog for repeatedly flouting social media advertising rules, and face being fined or having their posts deleted.
The Instagram stars have become the first influencers to be named on a dedicated roll call of offenders launched by the Advertising Standards Authority (ASA). The ASA added that if they did not start to follow the rules, further sanctions could include online ads shaming them,the removal of their posts or financial penalties.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Gamechanging’ £10m environmental DNA project to map life in world’s rivers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/17/gamechanging-environmental-dna-project-to-map-life-in-worlds-rivers-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/17/gamechanging-environmental-dna-project-to-map-life-in-worlds-rivers-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T23:01:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[eBioAtlas programme aims to identify fish, birds, amphibians and land animals in freshwater systems from the Ganges to the Mekong


Concealed by the turbid, swirling waters of the Amazon, the Mekong and the Congo, the biodiversity of the world’s great rivers has largely remained a mystery to scientists. But now a multimillion-pound project aims to describe and identify the web of life in major freshwater ecosystems around the world with “gamechanging” DNA technology.
The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) and UK-based environmental DNA (eDNA) specialists NatureMetrics have launched a partnership to take thousands of water samples from freshwater river systems like the Ganges and the Niger delta to identify the fish, birds, amphibians and land animals that live in and around them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Double-jabbed UK tourists could skip amber-list quarantine under proposals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/16/vaccinated-british-travellers-could-skip-quarantine-on-return-under-new-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/16/vaccinated-british-travellers-could-skip-quarantine-on-return-under-new-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T22:54:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers looking at loosening travel restrictions for fully vaccinated travellers returning to England

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

British travellers who have had two Covid vaccines could be allowed quarantine-free entry into England under plans being considered by ministers, the Guardian understands.
As the government grapples with allowing more trips abroad while trying to prevent the importation of new variants, changes are being considered to the traffic light system under which places are graded according to their Covid case and jab rate, determining whether and how people coming from them must isolate.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than half of Europe’s cities still plagued by dirty air, report finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/europe-cities-still-plagued-dirty-air-report-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/europe-cities-still-plagued-dirty-air-report-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T22:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data shows only 127 of 323 cities had acceptable PM 2.5 levels despite drop in emissions during lockdowns

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

More than half of European cities are still plagued by dirty air, new data shows, despite a reduction in traffic emissions and other pollutants during last year’s lockdowns.
Cities in eastern Europe, where coal is still a major source of energy, fared worst of all, with Nowy Sącz in Poland having the most polluted air, followed by Cremona in Italy where industry and geography tend to concentrate air pollution, and Slavonski Brod in Croatia.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russian war games set stage for Biden and Putin’s head-to-head]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/russian-war-games-set-stage-for-biden-and-putins-head-to-head</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/russian-war-games-set-stage-for-biden-and-putins-head-to-head"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T22:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moscow may not play fair, but observers can take solace in reaffirmed declaration against nuclear war
On the day that Joe Biden met Vladimir Putin in Geneva, the Russians held war games moving their nuclear missiles around, while Nato warplanes were scrambled to intercept Russian fighters over the Baltic.
If Biden had wanted to illustrate his emphasis on the need for stability and dialogue between Washington and Moscow, he could not have arranged it better.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[White couple who got vaccines meant for First Nation are fined but not jailed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/canada-rodney-ekaterina-baker-vaccines-indigenous</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/canada-rodney-ekaterina-baker-vaccines-indigenous"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:57:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[White River First Nation had sought six months in jail for Canadian millionaires Rodney and Ekaterina Baker
The millionaire Canadian couple who chartered a private plane to a remote community and jumped the coronavirus vaccine queue to receive doses intended for elderly Indigenous people have been fined C$2,300 but were not sentenced to jail after pleading guilty to breaking public health rules.
The size of the fine imposed on the former casino executive Rodney Baker and his wife, the actor Ekaterina Baker, on Wednesday prompted frustration amid members of the White River First Nation, many of whom wanted the couple to face stiffer repercussions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Horizon Special: The Vaccine review – meet the superheroes who saved the planet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/horizon-special-the-vaccine-review-meet-the-superheroes-who-saved-the-planet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/horizon-special-the-vaccine-review-meet-the-superheroes-who-saved-the-planet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:30:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This masterful, mind-boggling film gets up close with the scientists who huddled over computers in their PJs to save millions of lives. The wonder of it!
There is a dizzying sense of scale imparted by the Horizon special on the coronavirus vaccine. On the one hand, you have the pathogen – so tiny as to be invisible to the naked eye even as it replicates by fatal millions inside a host, although the damage it does is all too apparent. And then you have the uniting of entire continents’ worth of scientists, each with a world of knowledge to bring to the fight against the microscopic enemy. The wonder of it, the harnessing of intellectual might, the logistics, the commitment necessary to condense into months what could easily have taken a decade was all powerfully evoked by Horizon’s 90-minute film The Vaccine (BBC Two). Plus, it did all that without getting in the way of the science, the facts or the story itself.
And what a story. Horizon begins with Dr George Fu Gao of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, who first read on 30 December 2019 that something was happening in Wuhan. He got samples from patients, used next-generation sequencing technology to identify a new pathogen behind a new disease within days, and released the information globally so that those five continents’ worth of virologists could get to work. Dr Teresa Lambe of Oxford University remembers “huddling over my computer in my pyjamas, designing a vaccine”. That was on 1 January 2020.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer picks ‘Stronger Together’ slogan used by Hillary Clinton to rebrand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/keir-starmer-picks-stonger-together-slogan-used-by-hillary-clinton-to-rebrand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/keir-starmer-picks-stonger-together-slogan-used-by-hillary-clinton-to-rebrand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overhaul is set to focus on channelling the solidarity shown by the British public during the pandemic
Keir Starmer has picked the election slogan of US presidential candidate Hillary Clinton, “Stronger Together”, to badge the wide-ranging policy review that will lay the groundwork for Labour’s next manifesto.
Party chair Anneliese Dodds said the “Stronger Together” overhaul, which she will oversee, would focus on channelling the solidarity shown by the British public during the pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harry Maguire declares himself fit for England’s match against Scotland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/harry-maguire-declares-himself-fit-for-englands-match-against-scotland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/harry-maguire-declares-himself-fit-for-englands-match-against-scotland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United captain has been out with ankle injury
‘I’m available for selection, I’m looking forward to it’

Harry Maguire has declared himself fit and available for England’s Euro 2020 match against Scotland on Friday. The Manchester United captain had previously targeted the final group game against the Czech Republic next Tuesday for his comeback from ankle ligament damage.
Having returned to training with the England squad last Thursday, he has pushed on quicker than expected and he says that it will now be up to Gareth Southgate whether he is selected. England go into the Scotland match with their tails up after Sunday’s 1-0 win against Croatia. Scotland lost 2-0 to the Czech Republic on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Gutted’ Kieran Tierney cursing luck and desperate to face England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/kieran-tierney-fitness-scotland-england-wembley-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/kieran-tierney-fitness-scotland-england-wembley-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Scotland defender laments missing the Czech Republic game and says he has a 50-50 chance of playing at Wembley
It was not supposed to be this way. When Scotland qualified for Euro 2020, Kieran Tierney was earmarked as one of the stars of the team. The nation’s return to a major tournament was viewed as Tierney’s latest chance to display his talents on a grand stage.
Instead, when Scotland took on the Czech Republic at Hampden Park on Monday, Tierney was confined to a hotel room near Darlington. A calf problem, which may also keep the defender out of Friday’s meeting with England, meant Tierney could not even travel to support his teammates as they slipped to a 2-0 defeat. He does nothing to mask his disappointment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Split – How to Split a String into an Array in JS]]></title>
        <id>60c088e5d3126007592d56f1</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-split-how-to-split-a-string-into-an-array-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:19:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In general, a string represents a sequence of characters in a programming language.  Let's look at an example of a string created using a sequence of characters, "Yes, You Can DO It!". In JavaScript, we can create a string in a couple of ways: Using the string literal as a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inline Styles as Classes (lol)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342358</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inline-styles-as-classes-lol/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:11:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re abhorred by using inline styles, just move that style to the class attribute! And then make sure you have CSS in place that, ya know, does what it says on the box. 
I've revolutionized CSS. pic.twitter.com/1AWCldyCwP
— Sam 

…
The post Inline Styles as Classes (lol) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eddie Jones uses Cristiano Ronaldo as role model for England players]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/eddie-jones-uses-cristiano-ronaldo-as-role-model-for-england-players</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/eddie-jones-uses-cristiano-ronaldo-as-role-model-for-england-players"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T21:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England coach highlights Portugal footballer’s work ethic
Jones wants to unearth players for the 2023 World Cup

Eddie Jones has held Cristiano Ronaldo up as the example to follow for England’s bright young things as the head coach sets about unearthing players capable of taking leading roles at the 2023 World Cup.
Jones has selected 22 uncapped players in a provisional squad for this summer’s fixtures with training getting under way this week in Teddington. Players from the four Premiership semi-finalists are still to be added before the Tests against USA and Canada, but with 12 senior stars away with the British & Irish Lions – and several more rested – Jones is ready to give a number of youngsters their shot.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skewness and Kurtosis – Positively Skewed and Negatively Skewed Distributions in Statistics Explained]]></title>
        <id>60b8cb0aacb62507dd1d82ea</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/skewness-and-kurtosis-in-statistics-explained/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:56:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll explain two important concepts in statistics: skewness and kurtosis. And don't worry – you won't need to know very much math to understand these concepts and learn how to apply them. What are Density Curves?Let's first talk a bit about density curves, as skewness and kurtosis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denmark to make loud and clear their love for stricken Christian Eriksen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/denmark-plan-10th-minute-christian-eriksen-tribute-during-belgium-match</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/denmark-plan-10th-minute-christian-eriksen-tribute-during-belgium-match"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:55:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Play will stop in the 10th minute of Thursday’s game against Belgium and there will follow acclaim for the midfielder
A little after 6pm local time, Christian Eriksen may well expect the windows of his temporary lodgings to start shaking. He can see Parken, Denmark’s national stadium, from his room in Rigshospitalet and one can only imagine how dislocating it must feel to watch thousands of red shirts funnel through the glorious summer heat while his teammates prepare to face Belgium inside. On the off chance he could not hear the fans before, their noise will resonate loud and clear in the 10th minute of the game: play will stop and they will rise as one to acclaim their No 10 in a show of appreciation, love and sheer relief that he is listening at all.
“It is a crazy situation for him to be in,” said Kasper Hjulmand, the Denmark head coach. Eriksen should have been out there doing what he has done since 2010, making his side tick.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames in Copenhagen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Better React Apps with These Simple Tricks]]></title>
        <id>60ca25704dc1a607ed7b408c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-better-react-apps-with-these-tricks/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's a list of amazing tricks that you can use to improve your React applications instantly. These tips will not only make your code cleaner and more reliable, but they also aim to make your development experience easier and overall more enjoyable.  Give these techniques a try in your React]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locatelli fires Italy past Switzerland and through to Euro 2020 knockout stage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/italy-switzerland-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/italy-switzerland-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:52:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is not a drill. Six days into Euro 2020, Italy became the first team to qualify for the knockout stages courtesy of two brilliant goals from Manuel Locatelli and another from Ciro Immobile, and a display of collective strength that should put the rest of the field on notice. Spirited and united, quick on the ball and ravenous without it, efficient and entertaining, this Italy team has been the revelation of the tournament so far, and here Switzerland had no answers.
There is something of Liverpool’s 2019-20 title winners in Roberto Mancini’s Italy side, a thoroughly modern 4-3-3 formation with daringly high full-backs, brilliant pressing wingers and an ability to control possession without ever fetishising it. Amid a carnival atmosphere at the Stadio Olimpico, Italy put the game to bed within an hour, stretching their unbeaten run to 29 games, of which the last 10 have been clean-sheet wins.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rafael Benítez hoping to become Everton manager after talks with club]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/rafael-benitez-hoping-to-become-everton-manager-after-talks-with-club</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/rafael-benitez-hoping-to-become-everton-manager-after-talks-with-club"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spaniard is leading candidate to replace Carlo Ancelotti
Appointment would be controversial given Liverpool links

Rafael Benítez is hoping to receive a formal offer to become Everton’s new manager after holding positive talks with the club.
The Spaniard has emerged as a candidate for the post, which has been vacant ever since Carlo Ancelotti’s shock return to Real Madrid at the start of the month. Everton’s board, led by majority shareholder, Farhad Moshiri, have mulled over a number of candidates and looked set to hire the former Wolves manager Nuno Espírito Santo. But subsequent reservations within the club’s hierarchy regarding the suitability of the Portuguese has led to Benítez becoming the frontrunner.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter and Sachin Nakrani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woman allegedly raped at New York Airbnb received secret $7m settlement – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/airbnb-new-york-woman-allegedly-raped-settlement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/airbnb-new-york-woman-allegedly-raped-settlement"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:36:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airbnb taskforce that ‘cleans up only after disaster strikes’ intervened after alleged attack, reports Bloomberg Businessweek
An Australian woman who was allegedly raped at knifepoint in an Airbnb apartment in New York received a secret settlement of $7m which included restrictions on what she could say about the incident, according to a media investigation into the vacation listings giant’s “guest safety” policies .
The 29-year-old was attacked in a property near the tourist magnet and central Manhattan crossroads of Times Square early on New Year’s Day in 2016, Bloomberg Businessweek reported, prompting the swift intervention of a dedicated Airbnb crisis management “taskforce”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real Madrid confirm Sergio Ramos will leave after 16 years at club]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/real-madrid-confirm-sergio-ramos-will-leave-after-16-years-at-club</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/real-madrid-confirm-sergio-ramos-will-leave-after-16-years-at-club"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:34:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[35-year-old to depart at end of month when contract expires
Ramos to hold goodbye press conference on Thursday

After 16 seasons, 671 games, 101 goals, five league titles and four European Cups, Sergio Ramos is leaving Real Madrid. The club’s captain will say his final goodbye on Thursday, 13 days before his contract formally runs out.
 Related: Spain leave Sergio Ramos out of Euro 2020 squad and call up Aymeric Laporte 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Page hails Gareth Bale’s courage after captain drives Wales to victory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/robert-page-hails-gareth-bale-after-captain-drives-wales-to-victory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/16/robert-page-hails-gareth-bale-after-captain-drives-wales-to-victory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forward recovered from missed penalty to set up two goals
‘Without his two assists we don’t win that game,’ says Page

Robert Page praised Gareth Bale’s character after the Wales captain recovered from a penalty miss to help put his country on the verge of qualifying for the knockout stages of Euro 2020.
Bale squandered a chance to double Wales’s advantage but had laid on Aaron Ramsey’s opener and then set up Connor Roberts to earn a crucial 2-0 victory against Turkey.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at the Baku Olympic Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could Chrissy Teigen just try sending a text next time? | Harron Walker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/16/chrissy-teigen-michael-costello-leona-lewis-texting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/16/chrissy-teigen-michael-costello-leona-lewis-texting"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:05:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After apologizing on Monday, Teigen was accused of bullying Michael Costello, who then was accused of bullying Leona Lewis. Maybe it’s time to pause the posts
In 2018, the New Republic deputy editor Katie McDonough wrote a piece for Jezebel that I spiritually consult to this day. (Full disclosure: I was a Jezebel contributor at the time.)
“Why tweet when you can text?” she asked, and … well, that’s basically it. Sometimes, you can just text the thing you want to tweet.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harron Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden warns US will hit back if Russia continues with cyber strikes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/biden-to-meet-putin-at-highly-anticipated-summit-in-geneva</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/biden-to-meet-putin-at-highly-anticipated-summit-in-geneva"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:51:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US president hails ‘good and positive’ talks but added ‘proof of the pudding is in the eating’
The US will retaliate if Russia continues to carry out malicious cyber-attacks against American targets, Joe Biden said on Wednesday, after holding “good and positive” talks in Geneva with Russia’s president, Vladimir Putin.
Speaking after their first face-to-face summit, Biden said he had made clear the Kremlin had to “abide by the rules of the road” or face unspecified consequences. Putin was aware the US possessed “unrivalled” cyber capacities, Biden stressed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Geneva and Luke Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPs accuse Lex Greensill of ‘disrespect’ over refusal to attend steel inquiry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/mps-accuse-lex-greensill-disrespect-steel-inquiry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/mps-accuse-lex-greensill-disrespect-steel-inquiry"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:44:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour MP leading business committee says financier must appear in front of parliamentarians
MPs have accused financier Lex Greensill of acting suspiciously and being disrespectful towards parliament by refusing to appear in front of an inquiry into the steel industry and one of Greensill Capital largest borrowers, Liberty Steel.
The business, energy and industrial strategy (BEIS) committee claimed Greensill had failed to give legitimate reasons for rebuffing multiple requests to answer live questions in front of parliamentarians at the end of the month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Met police chief wins her job back after tribunal says sacking was unfair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/black-met-police-chief-wins-her-job-back-after-tribunal-says-sacking-was-unfair</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/black-met-police-chief-wins-her-job-back-after-tribunal-says-sacking-was-unfair"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:43:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supt Robyn Williams was dismissed in March 2020 after being convicted for possessing a child abuse video that she never viewed
A black police chief dismissed from the Metropolitan police has won her job back after a tribunal said her sacking was unfair.
Supt Robyn Williams was dismissed in March 2020 after being convicted for possessing a child abuse video that she was sent unsolicited via WhatsApp and never viewed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead ‘murder hornet’ near Seattle is first found in US this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/seattle-murder-hornet-us-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/seattle-murder-hornet-us-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Entomologists say it’s first confirmed report from Snohomish county and seems to be unrelated to 2019 and 2020 discoveries
Scientists have found a dead Asian giant hornet north of Seattle, the first so-called murder hornet found in the country this year, federal and state investigators said Wednesday.
Entomologists from the state and US Agriculture departments said it’s the first confirmed report from Snohomish county, north of Seattle, and appears to be unrelated to the 2019 and 2020 findings of the hornets in Canada and Whatcom county, along the Canadian border, that gained widespread attention.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acclaimed British cellist has passport cancelled by Home Office]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/acclaimed-british-cellist-has-passport-cancelled-by-home-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/acclaimed-british-cellist-has-passport-cancelled-by-home-office"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spokesperson apologises to 22-year-old musician Sheku Kanneh-Mason for error and pledges to issue replacement
A British cellist who was the first black winner of the BBC Young Musician award in 2016 and played at the wedding of Prince Harry and Meghan has had his passport cancelled by the Home Office.
Sheku Kanneh-Mason, 22, who was born and raised in Nottingham and appeared alongside his siblings on ITV’s variety show Britain’s Got Talent in 2015, sent off his British passport as part of an application for an additional passport to assist with applications for visas and international work permits.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Grierson Home affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plan to oblige care staff to have Covid jab and England easing delay confirmed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/matt-hancock-confirms-plan-to-require-care-staff-to-have-covid-vaccine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/matt-hancock-confirms-plan-to-require-care-staff-to-have-covid-vaccine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock makes vaccine announcement before MPs vote to approve 19 July lockdown end date

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers are to go ahead with plans to oblige care home staff to have coronavirus vaccinations as a condition of work and will consult on extending the obligation to NHS workers, Matt Hancock has confirmed.
Speaking in the Commons before MPs overwhelmingly agreed a four-week delay to the final easing of Covid restrictions in England, the health secretary also said such a requirement could in future be extended to seasonal flu vaccines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker, Denis Campbell and Robert Booth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s Heather Knight narrowly misses century before India fight back]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/englands-heather-knight-falls-narrowly-short-of-century-before-india-fightback</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/englands-heather-knight-falls-narrowly-short-of-century-before-india-fightback"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:17:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day one of four: England 269-6 v India
Captain Knight scores 95 but her exit sparks mini collapse

Heather Knight fell agonisingly short of becoming the first Englishwoman to score a Test century since she herself achieved the feat in 2013, with the captain trapped leg before wicket for 95 by her former Western Storm teammate Deepti Sharma in the 79th over of the first day of Test cricket between these sides since 2014.
Knight, who arrived at the crease shortly before lunch, batted for two sessions in a chanceless innings that was dominated by her beautifully timed cover drive. Though she chanced her arm with DRS, which is in use for the first time in women’s Test cricket, it was more in hope than expectation and the on-field decision had to stand.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raf Nicholson at the County Ground, Bristol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful and Useless Code Comments]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342630</id>
        <link href="https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2021/useful-and-usless-code-comments/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:08:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jim Nielsen: 
If somebody says a comment isn’t adding any value, I would ask: to whom?
Personally, I’ve never liked the advice that writing obvious comments is bad practice—probably because I write obvious comments all the time.
Jim showed …
The post Useful and Useless Code Comments appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on the Climate Change Committee’s criticism of the UK government – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/16/martin-rowson-on-the-climate-change-committees-criticism-of-the-uk-government-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/16/martin-rowson-on-the-climate-change-committees-criticism-of-the-uk-government-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T19:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cummings texts show Boris Johnson calling Matt Hancock ‘totally hopeless’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/cummings-texts-show-boris-johnson-calling-matt-hancock-totally-hopeless</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/cummings-texts-show-boris-johnson-calling-matt-hancock-totally-hopeless"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:54:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former aide publishes 7,000-word essay attacking Johnson’s ‘chronic dysfunction’ and revealing PM’s scathing verdict on health secretary

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage


Dominic Cummings launched a new onslaught on Boris Johnson and Matt Hancock on Wednesday, publishing texts from the prime minister calling his health minister “totally fucking hopeless”. 
In a 7,000-word essay, he also mocked the prime minister, saying he intended to leave office after the next election to “have fun and make money”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot and Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rory McIlroy confident of breaking major hoodoo with victory in US Open]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/rory-mcilroy-confident-of-breaking-major-hoodoo-with-victory-in-us-open</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/rory-mcilroy-confident-of-breaking-major-hoodoo-with-victory-in-us-open"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Irishman has not won a major in seven years
McIlroy: ‘It’s about having that mentality I had as a 22-year-old’

Rory McIlroy is bullish about his chances of ending his seven‑year major hoodoo when the 121st US Open shoves off on Thursday morning. The world No 11 said he has charted progress since formally teaming up with the English swing coach Pete Cowen in an effort to revive his fortunes and enters the season’s third major with renewed confidence after a productive week of practice in Florida.
“I’m feeling good about where my game is,” McIlroy said. “It’s about going out there and playing as free as I can and having that mentality that I had as a 22‑year‑old and just trying to get into that mindset.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bryan Armen Graham at Torrey Pines</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cressida Dick could face investigation over Daniel Morgan case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/cressida-dick-could-face-investigation-over-daniel-morgan-case</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/cressida-dick-could-face-investigation-over-daniel-morgan-case"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police watchdog may take action after inquiry finds Metropolitan police chief obstructed its efforts
The Metropolitan police commissioner, Cressida Dick, could face a new disciplinary investigation after the official inquiry into Daniel Morgan’s murder and corruption in the force found she had hampered its efforts to get to the truth, the Guardian has learned.
The police watchdog believes the issues raised could be sufficiently serious to merit using its special powers to order a referral, and warned public confidence may be damaged by the bombshell findings of the panel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS mental health trust fined £1.5m over care failures that led to 11 deaths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/nhs-mental-health-trust-fined-15m-over-care-failures-that-led-to-11-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/nhs-mental-health-trust-fined-15m-over-care-failures-that-led-to-11-deaths"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:38:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Judge says Essex Partnership University NHS foundation trust had failed to prevent suicides
An NHS mental health trust has been fined £1.5m over serious lapses in care that led to the death of 11 patients who were found hanging.
Mr Justice Cavanagh, the judge who imposed the fine, said a “litany” of failings in safety standards had been identified at Essex Partnership University NHS foundation trust (EPUT) over many years, which meant that it had failed to “prevent suicides”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings: key claims in his latest attack on government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/dominic-cummings-key-claims-in-his-latest-attack-on-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/dominic-cummings-key-claims-in-his-latest-attack-on-government"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:18:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Boris Johnson’s former aide repeatedly criticises Matt Hancock and claims PPE system collapsed

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Dominic Cummings has delivered yet more incendiary claims – backed up with some new evidence – in an attempt to tackle what he says is an “Orwellian” rewriting of history by the government about mistakes made during the Covid pandemic.
In a more than 7,000-word essay published on the online platform Substack, he made a series of allegations under the broad headline: “The PM on Hancock: ‘totally fucking hopeless’”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Aubrey Allegretti and Heather Stewart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Funeral directors must make prices clearer, says UK regulator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/funeral-directors-prices-clearer-uk-regulator</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/funeral-directors-prices-clearer-uk-regulator"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Legally enforceable rules come as inquiry reveals many customers are overcharged by at least £400
Funeral directors across the UK must publish clear price lists and will be banned from paying hospitals and care homes for referrals under new measures to help bereaved families.
The legally enforceable rules are being brought in after an investigation by the competition watchdog found UK consumers were typically being overcharged by at least £400 – and possibly a lot more – when they paid for a funeral.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man jailed for life over killing that sparked femicide outcry in France]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/man-jailed-life-killing-sparked-femicide-outcry-france</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/man-jailed-life-killing-sparked-femicide-outcry-france"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:06:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bruno Garcia-Cruciani’s murder of Julie Douib in Corsica became a rallying call against domestic killings
A man who murdered the mother of their two children on the island of Corsica in March 2019 has been sentenced to life in prison in a case that caused an outcry over domestic killings of women in France.
Julie Douib was shot dead by her former partner of 14 years, Bruno Garcia-Cruciani, a few days after learning that prosecutors had closed a case she brought against him for threatening behaviour, harassment and assault.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Bastia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half the trees in two new English woodlands planted by jays, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/half-the-trees-in-two-new-english-woodlands-planted-by-jays-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/half-the-trees-in-two-new-english-woodlands-planted-by-jays-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T18:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former fields were naturally regenerated with oak trees growing from acorns buried by the birds
More than half the trees in two new woodlands in lowland England have been planted not by landowners, charities or machines but by jays.
Former fields rapidly turned into native forest with no plastic tree-guards, watering or expensive management, according to a new study which boosts the case for using natural regeneration to meet ambitious woodland creation targets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Trump DoJ reports show how loyalists can deform the administration of justice | Lawrence Douglas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/donald-trump-administration-department-of-justice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/donald-trump-administration-department-of-justice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We knew Trump sought to use the neutral administration of justice as a tool for settling scores with enemies. But the scope of the operation is disturbing
In 1941, the German Jewish lawyer and political scientist Ernst Fraenkel published a slender volume called The Dual State. One of the first scholarly treatments of the Third Reich, Fraenkel understood Hitler’s state to be characterized by an unusual “dual” character. In large measure, the state operated by arbitrary decree – something Fraenkel called rule by “prerogative”. This “prerogative state” essentially functioned as a form of institutionalized lawlessness. At the same time, the Third Reich also maintained elements of a “normative state” – that is, an administration of justice that remained, at least formally, bound by operative law.
Without drawing any false equivalence with the Nazi state, we can say that the Trump administration likewise demonstrated this dual aspect. This emerges with disturbing clarity in recent reports documenting the lengths Donald Trump went toward turning the Department of Justice (DoJ) into a partisan tool. The Department of Justice, we must bear in mind, is a vast agency with more than 100,000 lawyers, many of whom are exceptionally skilled and principled civil servants dedicated to upholding the rule of law. Yet the reports of the past week make clear how loyalists installed in key positions can rather radically deform the administration of justice while remaining within the formal confines of the law.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lawrence Douglas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on post-Brexit trade: counting the wrong things | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/the-guardian-view-on-post-brexit-trade-counting-the-wrong-things</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/the-guardian-view-on-post-brexit-trade-counting-the-wrong-things"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:44:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government’s obstinate refusal to treat the EU as a valued trading partner is making Britain poorer
The agreement reached with Australia this week is celebrated by the UK government as a landmark trade deal – the first that isn’t a rollover of old European Union membership terms. But that honour surely belongs to a treaty that was signed by Boris Johnson in December 2020. It is the trade and cooperation agreement (TCA) covering the exchange of goods between Britain and 27 other nations.
But those nations constitute the European single market, which Mr Johnson does not appear to count as a valuable trading partner, despite its proximity.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on socialism and cycling: fellow travellers | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/the-guardian-view-on-socialism-and-cycling-fellow-travellers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/the-guardian-view-on-socialism-and-cycling-fellow-travellers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legacy of the radical bike-riding clubs of a century ago lives on
Cycling’s radical traditions are part of Britain’s social history. Recalling her teenage years in the 1890s, the great suffragette Sylvia Pankhurst wrote beautifully about the band of carefree lefties with whom she rode out of Manchester each weekend. Criss-crossing rural Lancashire and Cheshire, her cycling club was one of many associated with the Clarion, a popular socialist weekly newspaper. The more earnest socialists of the time saw this crowd as ideological dilettantes, too keen on having a good time. And their trips do seem to have been rather fun.
While there was some political evangelism and propagandising, “good fellowship” was the main object of the exercise: “At our journey’s end,” Pankhurst wrote in a 1931 edition of the Clarion, “was always an enormous shilling tea, in which phenomenal quantities of bread and butter and tinned fruit disappeared, then a walk round and frequently afterwards a brief ‘sing-song’.” A favourite anthem was a marching song written by the utopian socialist Edward Carpenter. “England, arise! The long, long night is over” resounded outside many rural pubs on Sunday afternoons. How many regulars were converted to the cause is not clear.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson’s truths about Door Matt and lies about the Delta variant are no big surprise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/johnsons-truths-about-door-matt-and-lies-about-the-delta-variant-are-no-big-surprise</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/johnsons-truths-about-door-matt-and-lies-about-the-delta-variant-are-no-big-surprise"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:39:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On his role in the spread of the Delta variant, press freedom and the G7 spa weekend … the PM was bluster as usual
Tell us something we didn’t know. One of the comforts – or disappointments, according to your taste – of Dominic Cummings’ 7,000-word blog, published online shortly before prime minister’s questions, is finding that everybody behaved exactly as you would expect.
So when we learn that Boris Johnson thought Matt Hancock was “totally fucking hopeless” in the early months of the pandemic, that the government was too slow to lockdown and that Johnson himself was useless at chairing meetings, preferring instead to avoid all confrontation before leaving the room singing Rule, Britannia!, it hardly comes as any great shock. Good though the detail may be.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leftwing rivals in Unite leadership race fail to agree unity candidate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/leftwing-rivals-unite-leadership-race-fail-agree-unity-candidate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/leftwing-rivals-unite-leadership-race-fail-agree-unity-candidate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:33:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Situation raises prospect that all three will enter final ballot and potentially split the left vote
The contest to become the next leader of the Unite union is set for another twist after three leftwing rivals for the position failed to agree upon a unity candidate.
Sharon Graham, the only female candidate, has told friends she will put her name forward for the final ballot despite two days of talks with fellow leftwing candidates Steve Turner and Howard Beckett.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder. Do I tell my manager? My children? My partner? | Leading questions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/17/ive-been-diagnosed-with-an-autism-spectrum-disorder-do-i-tell-my-manager-my-children-my-partner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/17/ive-been-diagnosed-with-an-autism-spectrum-disorder-do-i-tell-my-manager-my-children-my-partner"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The value of telling your mental health story is well-publicised, writes advice columnist Eleanor Gordon-Smith. But though it is less visible, privacy has value too
I have recently been diagnosed as having high-functioning ASD, what used to be called Asperger’s. It is helpful, as I approach 60, to understand why relationships, social situations and oral communications are so challenging for me, particularly in the work context.
But many seem to express the view that “everybody has a diagnosis these days”. Others remain discriminatory, so at this stage I’ve only told one person – a friend in the UK (herself diagnosed as bipolar). Do I tell a manager at work? My teenage children? My partner?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eleanor Gordon-Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex Gallagher: the 10 funniest things I have ever seen (on the internet)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/17/alex-gallagher-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/17/alex-gallagher-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We asked citizens of the internet to send us the funniest things in their extremely online neighbourhood. Here’s what Alex Gallagher supplied
There’s no way of dressing it up or making it out to be a more noble, onerous pursuit than it is: I am deeply online.
In the decade and a half that I’ve been plugged into the mainframe I’ve increasingly developed a concerning Pavlovian response to the internet, wherein joy is analogous to whatever cursed content my cyber-spelunking has managed to unearth that day.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Gallagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teach Yourself Data Analytics in 30 Days]]></title>
        <id>60ca30af4dc1a607ed7b4197</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/teach-yourself-data-analytics-in-30-days/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:19:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can learn the basics of Data Analytics with 30 days of practice.  We just released a Data Analytics course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. The course includes a 40-minute video, as well as a website and Jupyter notebooks. If you follow the plan laid out in these course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK in talks to build battery ‘gigafactories’ for electric cars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/uk-talks-build-battery-gigafactories-electric-cars-lg-samsung-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/uk-talks-build-battery-gigafactories-electric-cars-lg-samsung-government"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:13:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ford, LG and Samsung among companies in discussions with government and local authorities
The UK government has held talks with six manufacturers about building “gigafactory” electric car battery plants as part of its efforts to improve the prospects of the British automotive industry.
The US carmaker Ford and the Korean electronics conglomerates LG and Samsung are among the companies that have had early-stage discussions with the government or local authorities, it is understood.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding autism: we still have a long way to go | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/understanding-autism-we-still-have-a-long-way-to-go</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/understanding-autism-we-still-have-a-long-way-to-go"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:09:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to a piece by John Harris about moving beyond an awareness of the condition to practical steps to help those living with it
John Harris is right (Enough ‘autism awareness’. The necessity now is action, 13 June). It is now time that we had some action to improve lives for autistic people. Is it time to move on from autism awareness, though? I think not. Without a general knowledge of what constitutes autism and what people with autism live with, and without an understanding that each person with autism is different and will need a unique approach, there will be no useful action.
I work for families who have an autistic child and who are worried about their experience of school. This work is largely in mainstream schools, where the majority of children with autism are educated. Generally, the effort made by the school to understand both the condition and how it affects their particular pupil is dismal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clarion call from cyclists to carry on the fight for socialism on two wheels | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/clarion-call-from-cyclists-to-carry-on-the-fight-for-socialism-on-two-wheels</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/clarion-call-from-cyclists-to-carry-on-the-fight-for-socialism-on-two-wheels"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T17:08:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who think socialism is irrelevant should leave the National Clarion Cycling Club and form their own club, says Jim Grozier. For Charles Jepson and his breakaway organisation, the link between cycling and socialism is unbroken
Those behind the recent “coup” in the National Clarion Cycling Club (Keir Hardie’s cycling club jettisons socialism, 14 June) have, like so many others nowadays, misunderstood the concept of inclusion, treating it like a mantra to be trotted out without actually thinking. Inclusion can only be invoked in order to remove irrelevant obstacles to joining an organisation.
For almost all organisations, gender, ethnicity, religion, sexual orientation and many other attributes are irrelevant, so they should not be an obstacle. Not so when it comes to political leanings in the context of an overtly political cycling club. One might as well try to persuade the Spurs supporters’ club to admit a card-carrying Arsenal fan. Those who are so unaware of the current political situation as to think socialism “irrelevant” should do the decent thing, leave the Clarion and form their own club, to which they would then be free to invite whoever they wish.
Jim Grozier
Brighton & Hove Clarion Cycling Club
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxford Circus to be turned into pedestrian piazzas this year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/oxford-circus-to-be-turned-into-pedestrian-piazzas-this-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/oxford-circus-to-be-turned-into-pedestrian-piazzas-this-year"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T16:41:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Transformation of London shopping district aims to address air quality, pedestrian congestion and traffic
The area around Oxford Circus in London is to be transformed into two pedestrianised piazzas after years of deliberation.
Work is due to start this year and will include “significant improvements to the public spaces”, as well as additional planting and seating in the shopping and leisure district, Westminster city council and the crown estate announced on Wednesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Ascot day three: Subjectivist to threaten Stradivarius’s Gold Cup bid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/royal-ascot-day-three-subjectivist-to-threaten-stradivarius-gold-cup-bid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/16/royal-ascot-day-three-subjectivist-to-threaten-stradivarius-gold-cup-bid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T16:41:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stradivarius attempts to equal Yeats’s record by winning a fourth Gold Cup but this looks his toughest test yet
Stradivarius has seen off all-comers in the staying division since his first Group One win at Goodwood in August 2017 but winning a fourth Gold Cup, to equal Yeats’s record, promises to be his toughest assignment yet at this meeting.
Serpentine, last year’s Derby winner, is a completely unknown quantity at this trip, while Trueshan has a shout on his Champions Day form if significant rain arrives.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Von der Leyen signs off first of EU’s Covid recovery fund plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/von-der-leyen-signs-off-first-of-eus-covid-recovery-fund-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/von-der-leyen-signs-off-first-of-eus-covid-recovery-fund-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T16:02:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Portugal is first country to get green light for €16.6bn investment under EU’s €800bn fund

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ursula von der Leyen has signed off on the first plans by EU member states to spend Brussels’ €800bn (£687bn) Covid recovery fund, as she sought to reverse the reputational damage inflicted on the bloc by the pandemic during a visit to Portugal and Spain.
Speaking in Lisbon, the European Commission president said she believed the Next Generation EU fund, which has been weighed to prioritise digital and green projects, would be a “European success”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey  in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghislaine Maxwell subjected to raw sewage in New York jail, lawyer says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/ghislaine-maxwell-new-york-jail-sewage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/16/ghislaine-maxwell-new-york-jail-sewage"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T16:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attorney for the British socialite, who is fighting sex trafficking charges, says Maxwell also faces ‘hyper-surveillance’ from guards
Ghislaine Maxwell, the British socialite fighting federal sex trafficking charges in New York, remains subjected to raw sewage, water deprivation, “hyper-surveillance” by overbearing guards and other unacceptable treatment in jail, according to her lawyer.
Maxwell, 59, is preparing for a possible November trial on charges she procured four underage girls for the late financier Jeffrey Epstein to sexually abuse. Maxwell has pleaded not guilty and faces up to 80 years in prison if convicted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agenciies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK asks EU to suspend Northern Ireland sausage ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/uk-asks-eu-to-suspend-northern-ireland-sausage-ban-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/16/uk-asks-eu-to-suspend-northern-ireland-sausage-ban-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T16:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit minister Lord Frost asks for ‘a bit of breathing space’ to negotiate deal and head off trade war

The UK has asked the EU to suspend an imminent ban on the sale of British sausages in Northern Ireland to give both sides “breathing space” to negotiate an agreement on the Brexit protocol and avert a trade war.
Lord Frost, the Brexit minister, was speaking days after Boris Johnson warned he would do “whatever it takes” to protect Northern Ireland’s position as part of the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent and Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three miscarriage rule before receiving help is unacceptable, says MP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/three-miscarriage-rule-before-receiving-help-is-unacceptable-says-mp</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/three-miscarriage-rule-before-receiving-help-is-unacceptable-says-mp"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Olivia Blake, who miscarried first child last year, has secured debate in parliament to ‘rethink narrative around miscarriage’
An MP who miscarried her first child last year says women should not have to endure three miscarriages before receiving support, before a debate on the subject in parliament.
Olivia Blake, the MP for Sheffield Hallam, spoke in parliament last year about going to A&E on her own in early pregnancy while her partner had to wait in the car due to Covid restrictions. She described the isolating experience of “being unable to have a hug or someone to hold my hand or support me on hearing the news that I was having a miscarriage”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One of the joys of Euro 2020? Watching casual football fans suffer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/one-of-the-joys-of-euro-2020-watching-casual-football-fans-suffer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/one-of-the-joys-of-euro-2020-watching-casual-football-fans-suffer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For fair-weather supporters tournaments offer a taste of the pain – as well as the joy – of being a seasoned follower
Football is about pleasure and pain, a zero-sum ball game. The level of joy we feel at a goal or a victory is mirrored precisely in the pain of others. This pain is, in a sense, at the heart of football fandom; for without despair, there can be no joy.
I recall Colin Moynihan, as minister for sport in the last years of the Thatcher government, saying something well-meaning, but specious about football. It was along the lines of the game being a good thing for the economy because when their team won, its supporters’ productivity would improve. Didn’t they have spads in those days? Surely someone should have explained that the opposite would also apply for the productivity of supporters of the losing side. If he had been a passionate fan of a club, he would have known this to be true.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Chiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[France and Spain to ease mask-wearing as Covid vaccine schemes gather pace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/france-and-spain-to-ease-mask-wearing-as-covid-vaccine-schemes-gather-pace</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/france-and-spain-to-ease-mask-wearing-as-covid-vaccine-schemes-gather-pace"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:35:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French will no longer have to wear masks outside and curfew to end while Spain also planning to lift rule

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

France and Spain are moving to ease rules around wearing face masks outside, in a development attributed by both countries to their Covid-19 vaccination campaigns.
In France, people will no longer be required to wear masks outdoors from Thursday, though they will still be obligatory on public transport, in sports stadiums and other crowded places. A nightly curfew will end as of Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris and Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The BBC’s defenders must also be its harshest critics over Martin Bashir | Dorothy Byrne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/bbcs-defenders-critics-martin-bashir-tv-journalist-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/bbcs-defenders-critics-martin-bashir-tv-journalist-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:34:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reappointing the TV journalist in 2016 was bad enough, but the report clearing staff over this matter is embarrassing
For many years, as head of news and current affairs at Channel 4, the first thing I did every morning was read the Daily Mail or, on my day of rest, its sister paper, the Mail on Sunday. I’m guessing from the revelations this week that that isn’t something top BBC News executives do.
I read the Mail because it carries a lot of great stories, many of them actually true. Also, what the Mail says today, a Conservative politician is likely to say tomorrow and I like to hear news first from its true source. In contrast, it seems some BBC News supremos know nothing at all about some major stories, even when those stories are about their own institution, if they have not been broadcast on the BBC.
This week the BBC published a hilarious report into how on earth, or indeed in heaven, they managed to appoint as their religious affairs correspondent one of the most notorious television journalists of our time, Martin Bashir, and then promote him to editor, religion – which in British establishment terms is just one step down from the Archbishop of Canterbury. Some have asked if it was part of an evil BBC cover-up, but even Satan himself would draw the line at something this ridiculous.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dorothy Byrne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sigue Sigue Sputnik at a Newcastle B&B: Homer Sykes’ best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/16/sigue-sigue-sputnik-newcastle-bb-homer-sykes-best-photograph-love-missile-f1-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/16/sigue-sigue-sputnik-newcastle-bb-homer-sykes-best-photograph-love-missile-f1-11"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:20:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘The landlady was shocked to see them – and their hair’
It was 1986 and I’d been on the road with Sigue Sigue Sputnik for a couple of days. They’d played a gig in Leeds the previous night and we’d just arrived at a little bed and breakfast in Newcastle upon Tyne. I dumped my stuff in my room and went down to the bar where I got speaking to the landlady. I was kind of just hanging around when two members of the band, Neal X and Yana YaYa, came down to order drinks. The landlady hadn’t seen them at this point … and she hadn’t seen their hair. She was, shall we say, shocked. I happened to be there so it made a picture.
That’s how I always work. I watch, I wait … and hopefully I see one of these magic moments. If you’re patient then something will usually happen. It’s all about being prepared and seeing clearly. I’m not a setter-upper of photographs. You couldn’t set up an image like this even if you tried. If you had a team of people in there and a crew and an art director and a whole mob of people you’d lose the spontaneity. It’s the finger in the landlady’s mouth that makes the image – she’s looking up at Neal X and his hair and his cowboys T-shirt, which was based on a design by Jim French. Her expression is fantastic. She’s not horrified; she’s smiling and thinking: “What the hell is going on here?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It has the feel of a little local pub!’: Guardian readers on their extraordinary DIY sheds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/16/it-has-the-feel-of-a-little-local-pub-guardian-readers-on-their-extraordinary-diy-sheds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/16/it-has-the-feel-of-a-little-local-pub-guardian-readers-on-their-extraordinary-diy-sheds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:11:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From an allotment shelter built out of old doors to a storage shack turned into a chapel, here are some of the best of our readers’ creations
This is my pandemic project: a garden pub shed, called the Doghouse. It is custom-built from timber with a Firestone rubber roof. Lockdown finally gave me the time to build it and I tried to reuse or recycle materials where I could. The doors and windows were from a friend’s old conservatory. The timber herringbone and boards, plus the back bar shelving, are pallet wood, which I burnished with a chainmail pad, and oiled to give it a nice worn look. I built the bar and canopy from scratch using leftover framing timber. The bench was built from a recycled bed headboard and I used a mattress for the seat. The table and chairs were a local Gumtree find, and the bar memorabilia and pumps were from eBay. I’m probably proudest of the bar. It has the feel and character of a little local pub – we often eat dinner there for a change of scenery. Our two children love it. But we will, of course, still support our local pub whenever we can. Gavin Thomasson, 42, design manager, Ipswich 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the Earth review – Ben Wheatley’s trippy occult horror is a fine return to form]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/16/in-the-earth-review-ben-wheatley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/16/in-the-earth-review-ben-wheatley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This low-budget folk-horror is back in Wheatley’s weird, sly world as Joel Fry and Ellora Torchia get lost in the forest 
Here is a low-budget, low-profile film that scampers through the undergrowth up to a horrible folk-horror epiphany, with undeadpan comedy and a gibbering shroom meltdown, percussively hammered home with strobe lightning flashes and skull-splittingly loud snaps. At one point, we are encircled by a fog, which a frowning scientist describes as a “suspension of mushroom spores and water droplets in the air”. It was one of those rare moments in the cinema when you are glad of a mask. 
This is a return to home territory for its writer-director Ben Wheatley, maybe reminiscent of his 17th-century Leveller freakout A Field in England from 2013, which was about civil war deserters captured by an alchemist and finding the world turned upside down. And there are admittedly some familiar tropes: forests where mobile phone signals are impossible, a local myth represented in ancient woodcuts. But for me In the Earth is a return to form, after Wheatley’s interesting but basically uncertain dabble last year in period romantic drama for Netflix with a new version of Daphne Du Maurier’s Rebecca with Armie Hammer and Lily James. In the Earth brings us back to Wheatley’s classic world of occult loopy weirdness and cult Britmovie seediness, with a new topical dimension of pandemic paranoia, and what keeps you watching is its unreadable, almost undetectable thread of black comedy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Can I get Amanda Huggenkiss?’: the return of punning prank calls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/can-i-get-amanda-huggenkiss-the-return-of-punning-prank-calls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/can-i-get-amanda-huggenkiss-the-return-of-punning-prank-calls"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:59:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bart Simpson was a big fan, and the prank call has always been the curse of phone-in shows – as GB News discovered this week
Name: Prank calls.
Age: The oldest known dates from 1884, and involved telephoning undertakers in Rhode Island to summon them to the homes of not-dead people.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cotton plantations and non-consensual kisses: how Disney became embroiled in the culture wars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/16/how-disney-became-embroiled-in-the-culture-wars</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/16/how-disney-became-embroiled-in-the-culture-wars"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:58:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The company has been addressing its historical racism and sexism, adding disclaimers to films and altering theme park rides. But these moves have stirred contempt as well as approval
Very little ammunition is required for a culture war these days, so long as your troops are primed to mobilise at the drop of a blog. Julie Tremaine and Katie Dowd, two writers for the online newspaper SFGate, discovered this last month. Their review of the revamped Snow White ride at Disneyland was generally positive, but queried a new scene showing the prince giving Snow White the all-important “true love’s kiss”. 
“A kiss he gives to her without her consent, while she’s asleep, which cannot possibly be true love if only one person knows it’s happening,” they wrote. “It’s hard to understand why the Disneylan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Rose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It is obscene’: Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie pens blistering essay against social media sanctimony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/16/chimamanda-ngozi-adichie-social-media-sanctimony</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/16/chimamanda-ngozi-adichie-social-media-sanctimony"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:45:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The novelist describes helping two writers who went on to insult her online, and condemns era of ‘angels jostling to out-angel one another’
Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie has written a detailed essay about the conduct of young people on social media “who are choking on sanctimony and lacking in compassion”, who she says are part of a generation “so terrified of having the wrong opinions that they have robbed themselves of the opportunity to think and to learn and to grow”.
Titled It Is Obscene, the essay was published by the Nigerian novelist and feminist on her website on Tuesday night. It attracted so much attention that her website temporarily crashed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid cases have peaked in Blackburn, official figures show]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/covid-cases-have-peaked-in-blackburn-official-figures-show</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/covid-cases-have-peaked-in-blackburn-official-figures-show"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:44:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Infections in England’s worst-affected council area fall steadily since 7 June, says PHE

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Covid cases in Blackburn with Darwen, the local authority with England’s highest infection rate, have peaked, Public Health England figures indicate.
PHE data shows a total of 897 cases in Blackburn with Darwen for the seven days to 10 July, giving the town a rolling rate of 599 cases per 100,000 people.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My wallet never leaves my bedside’: why cashless will soon be king]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/16/my-wallet-never-leaves-my-bedside-why-cashless-will-soon-be-king</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/16/my-wallet-never-leaves-my-bedside-why-cashless-will-soon-be-king"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Douglas Wood, 35, swipes his phone and goes – as do most people his age and younger, he says
• Cashless society draws closer with only one in six payments now in cash
Like most 35-year-olds, Douglas Wood says the fact he has gone entirely cashless means his wallet rarely, if ever, gets an outing and now sits next to his bed gathering dust.
The product manager who lives in Hammersmith, west London, says he has used cash only twice in the past year – both times to pay for a £6 haircut, and only then because the barber insisted on being paid in cash.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miles Brignall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whether or not Labour wins Batley and Spen, the party is in deep trouble | Owen Jones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/labour-batley-and-spen-jeremy-corbyn-scottish-voters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/labour-batley-and-spen-jeremy-corbyn-scottish-voters"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:27:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who felt listened to under Jeremy Corbyn feel sidelined – or, like Scottish voters before them, simply used
In the streets of the West Yorkshire constituency of Batley and Spen, voters are uttering phrases that have in the past chilled the bones of Labour canvassers in the party’s fallen heartlands of Scotland and the so-called red wall. “Labour have abandoned us,” say some; “we are going to teach them a lesson,” say others. They are disproportionately – but not exclusively – Muslims in a constituency in which a fifth of voters are of Asian heritage, and their disillusionment has an angry edge.
Ahead of the byelection on 1 July, the Labour hierarchy appears to be stuck in the patterns of remote complacency that we have seen before. The mistakes that saw its historic loss of Hartlepool in the May bylection, and the collapse of core parts of its support over the course of a generation, risk being repeated again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342353</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-i-used-the-waapi-to-build-an-animation-library/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:26:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Web Animations API lets us construct animations and control their playback with JavaScript. The API opens the browser’s animation engine to developers and was designed to underlie implementations of both CSS animations and transitions, leaving the door open to …
The post How I Used the WAAPI to Build an Animation Library appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Okiki Ojo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World’s third largest diamond discovered in Botswana]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/worlds-third-largest-diamond-discovered-in-botswana</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/worlds-third-largest-diamond-discovered-in-botswana"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T14:11:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mining firm Debswana presents the 1,098-carat stone to the country’s president, Mokgweetsi Masisi
The diamond firm Debswana has announced the discovery in Botswana of a 1,098-carat stone that it described as the third largest of its kind in the world.
The company’s acting managing director, Lynette Armstrong, presented the stone, which was found on 1 June, to the country’s president, Mokgweetsi Masisi, on Wednesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in Gaborone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putin and Biden meet for talks in Switzerland – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/16/putin-and-biden-meet-for-talks-in-switzerland-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/16/putin-and-biden-meet-for-talks-in-switzerland-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:53:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After shaking hands for the cameras, the US president, Joe Biden, and his Russian counterpart, Vladimir Putin, plunged into hours of face-to-face talks on Wednesday at a lush lakeside Swiss mansion. It was a highly anticipated summit at a time of heightened tensions between the two countries
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[George RR Martin, console-less games and a Final Fantasy fail: the biggest news from E3 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/the-biggest-news-from-e3-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/the-biggest-news-from-e3-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:26:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s online-only E3 video game expo was hardly the usual explosion of blockbuster games, but there were still some standout stories 
We all wanted to see Metroid Prime 4, the long-anticipated first-person science-fiction shooter-adventure that has been in development at Nintendo for an absolute age. But instead we got a whole new Metroid – a 2D one in the vein of the SNES and Game Boy Advance classics, the first game in the series in this style for about 19 years. Metroid Dread features Samus Aran being chased by distressing, transforming drone-robots who appear to be largely impervious to her ever-expanding array of weapons, and it looks genuinely scary. It’ll be out on 8 October on Nintendo Switch.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We could lose it all’: UK jazz tries to get its groove back after Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/we-could-lose-it-all-uk-jazz-tries-to-get-its-groove-back-after-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/we-could-lose-it-all-uk-jazz-tries-to-get-its-groove-back-after-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:20:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world-class British jazz scene was hit hard by the pandemic. As live shows and in-person collaboration resume, Steam Down, Soweto Kinch and more discuss the future
Music moves differently depending on the space it’s played in. A typical pre-Covid Wednesday evening at the Matchstick Piehouse in London would see its arch space filled with writhing bodies as the jazz collective Steam Down spilled off the stage, their music in dialogue with our yelps, claps and calls to the band.
But on a humid night in May, during the first week of socially distanced indoor performances beginning again, the music took a different route. Playing two Steam Down sessions to a 30-person, seated and masked audience, the seven-person band launched into an extended riff on Nas’s The World Is Yours and bandleader Ahnansé’s liquid tenor solo bounced off the walls while a train rumbled overhead. Steam Down’s music loudly reverberated around us as we danced in our seats, feet vigorously tapping to the beat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ammar Kalia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why do male politicians love taking their shirts off for photo ops?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/why-do-male-politicians-love-taking-their-shirts-off-for-photo-ops</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/why-do-male-politicians-love-taking-their-shirts-off-for-photo-ops"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost as important as saving lives, the Covid jab has given politicos a great reason to get their kit off in public

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Since the miracle invention of a vaccination for Covid-19, a second discovery has been made: male politicians absolutely love taking their shirts off for a photo opportunity. In the UK, you are more likely to find a Conservative MP bare-chested than a Labour one – Brendan Clarke-Smith and Johnny Mercer are the poster boys of the movement, resplendent in chest hair as they pose for the cameras.
Internationally, there are subtle variations: French ministers like to drape or hold their spare sleeve over their exposed nipple, while proudly exposing tremendous biceps and noble shoulders. Their finance minister, Olivier Véran, in particular, looks as if he’s been caught unawares straight from the shower by a hot delivery driver at the start of an 1980s porn film.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Met chief defends Cressida Dick over Daniel Morgan findings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/ex-met-chief-defends-cressida-dick-over-daniel-morgan-findings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/16/ex-met-chief-defends-cressida-dick-over-daniel-morgan-findings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Blair of Boughton criticises independent panel judgment and calls Dick ‘finest officer of generation’
The Metropolitan police commissioner, Cressida Dick, has been defended by one of her predecessors after an independent inquiry censured her personally for obstruction and found Scotland Yard to be “institutionally corrupt”.
Ian Blair, who served as commissioner from 2005 to 2008, criticised the findings of an independent panel inquiring into the unsolved 1987 murder of Daniel Morgan.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olympic trials, a hilltop swing and a masked statue: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/16/olympic-trials-a-hilltop-swing-and-a-masked-buddhist-statue-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/16/olympic-trials-a-hilltop-swing-and-a-masked-buddhist-statue-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T12:51:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate activists take Norway to human rights court over Arctic oil plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/climate-activists-take-norway-european-human-rights-court-arctic-oil-drilling-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/16/climate-activists-take-norway-european-human-rights-court-arctic-oil-drilling-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T12:49:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activists allege decision to grant oil exploration licences violated right to healthy environment
Six climate activists and two environmental NGOs have taken Norway to the European court of human rights (ECHR), arguing the Nordic country’s plans to drill for oil in the Arctic are harming young people’s futures.
The activists, Greenpeace and Young Friends of the Earth, want the court to rule that Oslo’s 2016 decision to grant 10 Barents Sea oil exploration licences violated article 112 of Norway’s constitution, which guarantees the right to a healthy environment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley Europe correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how is your school marking the end of the academic year?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/16/tell-us-how-is-your-school-marking-the-end-of-the-academic-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/16/tell-us-how-is-your-school-marking-the-end-of-the-academic-year"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T12:48:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from teachers, parents and young people about how they’re marking final years’ end of school 
End of year proms have been cancelled or postponed at secondary schools after the extension of the national lockdown in England.
We would like to hear about what primary and secondary schools are planning to do for their leavers at the end of the academic year. Is your primary or secondary school planning anything particularly inventive? Let us know below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greenpeace Euro 2020 parachutist lucky not to be shot down, says politician]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/police-hold-greenpeace-activist-after-euro-2020-parachute-stunt-goes-awry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/police-hold-greenpeace-activist-after-euro-2020-parachute-stunt-goes-awry"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T12:45:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bavarian minister says activist could have ‘paid with life’ for stunt before Germany v France game in Munich

A Greenpeace protester who parachuted into the stadium before Germany’s Euro 2020 match against France in Munich was lucky not to have been shot down by anti-terror marksmen enforcing a no-fly zone, a state minister has said.
Two people were injured when the activist lost control of his powered paraglider, which had a motor attached to his back, and hit overhead camera wires attached to the stadium roof. Fans ducked as he careered towards the spectator area, narrowly missing the stands and demolishing technical equipment before crashing in front of the German penalty area.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospitality workers: how are you coping without cash tips?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/hospitality-workers-how-are-you-coping-without-cash-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/hospitality-workers-how-are-you-coping-without-cash-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:43:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from waiters and other hospitality workers about how they have been coping without cash tips since the pandemic
Cash tips make up a significant part of the income of waiters and other hospitality workers in the UK. We would like to hear from employees about how they have been coping without these tips since the pandemic. Have you lost income as a result? Has your employer done anything to address this issue? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Care home workers: share your thoughts on mandatory Covid vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/16/care-home-workers-share-your-thoughts-on-mandatory-covid-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:34:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from care home staff on their thoughts about vaccines among reports ministers will make them mandatory
Ministers are planning to announce that Covid vaccinations are to become mandatory for care home staff in England, with them considering extending the move to all NHS staff.
We would like to hear from care home workers on their thoughts about mandatory vaccines and what their experiences have been like.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon blames social media for struggle with fake reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/amazon-blames-social-media-for-struggle-with-fake-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/amazon-blames-social-media-for-struggle-with-fake-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:24:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firm says sites are slow to act when warned that fake reviews are being solicited on their platforms
Amazon has blamed social media companies for its failure to remove fake reviews from its website, arguing that “bad actors” turn to social networks to buy and sell fake product reviews outside the reach of its own technology.
The company says it removed more than 200m suspected fake reviews before they were seen by customers in 2020 alone, but nonetheless has faced continued criticism for the enormous scale of fake and misleading reviews that make it on to its store.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I don’t want to remember these things’: dark pop poet John Murry on surviving rape, heroin and family strife]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/john-murry-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/16/john-murry-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:23:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The singer-songwriter talks about his relative William Faulkner, his violent childhood and drugs – and saves a surprise until the end
If you’re after cheery crowdpleasers, John Murry is not your man. Murry is 41, barely known, and has never come close to denting the charts. Yet he has been compared to the great existential pop poets Nick Cave, Leonard Cohen and Scott Walker. And with good reason – he has a rich baritone, writes gorgeous ballads and is half in love with death. The titles of his first two albums, The Graceless Age and A Short History of Decay, reflect the melancholy at the heart of his work. The title of his third, The Stars Are God’s Bullet Holes, is equally bleak. Yet, it turns out that Murry has a surprise in store.
The singer-songwriter is related to the Nobel-prize winning American novelist William Faulkner. Like Faulkner, he paddles along his stream of consciousness – sometimes ferociously. You get a sense of what his songs are about, but seldom know for sure. Take the new album’s opener, Oscar Wilde (Came Here to Make Fun of You). We get the references to terrorist attacks and the images of foreboding, but the meaning is left to us.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make the perfect cheese empanadas – recipe | Felicity Cloake's The perfect…]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/how-to-make-the-perfect-cheese-empanadas-recipe-felicity-cloake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/how-to-make-the-perfect-cheese-empanadas-recipe-felicity-cloake"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are so many variations on South America’s favourite patties, who’s to say which is the best? But that won’t stop our resident perfectionist from giving it her best shot ...
Elisabeth Lambert Ortiz claimed that one could write a small book on empanadas, empanaditas, pasteles, pastelitos, empadinhas and pastèzinhos … namely, “those delicious turnovers, patties and pies, stuffed with meat, poultry, fish, shellfish and other mixtures, and baked or fried, which are so popular throughout Latin America”. Such is the variety on offer, in fact, I’d suggest it would probably be quite a large book. As writer Naomi Tomky notes, perhaps a little wistfully, on Serious Eats, “it would take a lifetime of non-stop empanada-eating to try all of the infinite combinations of doughs, fillings and cooking methods that are so closely tied to the specific culture, flora and fauna in each region of Latin America”.
That’s a challenge I’d happily take on, but the Guardian has refused to extend my deadline, so I’ve chosen to concentrate on the simple, cheese-stuffed sort found almost everywhere. Even then, the range is such from country to country that (as ever) the below should be seen more as an introductory guide than a definitive recipe. Portable, cheap and infinitely versatile, easy to make vegan, gluten-free and even (relatively) healthy, empanadas are surely the ultimate democratic party food. Well … after crisps, anyway.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felicity Cloake</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure will build on Bank of England not to fall behind the curve with inflation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/pressure-will-build-on-bank-of-england-not-to-fall-behind-the-curve-with-inflation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/16/pressure-will-build-on-bank-of-england-not-to-fall-behind-the-curve-with-inflation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:57:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Threadneedle Street believes the above-target 2.1% figure will prove temporary

UK inflation jumps to 2.1% as petrol and clothing prices rise
Business live updates: UK inflation moves above Bank’s target
See all our coronavirus coverage

Inflation is on the march. After the easing of lockdown in May, Britain has raced from economic bust to boom, with the rate of consumer price inflation hitting 2.1% – above expectations and breaching the Bank of England’s 2% target rate.
Driven by the rising cost of petrol, clothing and recreation in the month indoor hospitality reopened, the latest snapshot will fuel concern that the cost of living is spiralling out of control. But it must also be taken with a pinch of salt.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince Harry is doing a special trauma therapy called EMDR. It worked for me | Christina Wyman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/prince-harry-is-doing-a-special-trauma-therapy-called-emdr-it-worked-for-me</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/16/prince-harry-is-doing-a-special-trauma-therapy-called-emdr-it-worked-for-me"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:21:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harry has said that living with the death of his mother, Diana, Princess of Wales makes him feel ‘helpless’ and ‘hunted’. I’ve been there

In an interview last month with Oprah for their jointly produced docuseries about mental health, The Me You Can’t See, Prince Harry made a deeply personal disclosure. Harry said he sought a special therapy program, EMDR, to process the death of his mother, Diana, Princess of Wales. He described how living with the trauma of her death makes him feel “helpless”, “hunted”, and as if “there is no escape”.
Before I was officially diagnosed with PTSD, painful childhood memories consumed my daily life, sometimes rendering me incapable of completing daily tasks. My PTSD was caused by a tumultuous childhood in a home with an alcoholic father and a rage-filled mother who lashed out at everything around her, including her children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Wyman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is bivvying? How to have a night of adventure – without a tent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/16/bivvying-night-adventure-close-to-home-camping-without-tent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/16/bivvying-night-adventure-close-to-home-camping-without-tent"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Armed with long experience, our writer gives the lowdown on getting there, the best equipment and picking your spot for a great night in the wild
When I bivvy I’m not in search of sleep. I know I’ll wake up frequently, feeling restricted by my sleeping bag. Bivvying is camping at its simplest: sleeping outside without a tent and minimal gear.
It isn’t about a comfortable night’s rest. It’s about squeezing an adventure into a humdrum week; it’s about being in nature, hearing hedgehogs snuffling and waking to the dawn chorus. It’s a short, sharp dose of escapism that has become even more restorative in the past 15 months. And, while I’ve bivvyed on Dartmoor, on Scotland’s west coast and in places in-between, most of the time I’ve been within 10 miles of my home in Bournemouth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Susanne Masters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Where should we go?’: thousands left homeless as Karachi clears waterways]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/where-should-we-go-thousands-left-homeless-as-karachi-clears-waterways</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/where-should-we-go-thousands-left-homeless-as-karachi-clears-waterways"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T09:12:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Pakistan’s supreme court backs bulldozing of homes blamed for floods, critics say government has no proper plans for residents
Maqsooda Bibi, 62, did not know the house she had lived in all her life would be demolished, forcing her whole family to become homeless. But on Monday, Pakistan’s supreme court backed the Sindh government in bulldozing her home and hundreds of others, legalising the eviction of thousands who live along narrow waterways – nullahs – that crisscross Karachi. 
The verdict came as Bibi and hundreds of others held a protest outside the court. “We hoped that the court would ask the government not to make us homeless, but it did the opposite. Our children also protested on Sunday and urged the supreme court to stop demolition. It seems no one here cares for the future of the poor.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shah Meer Baloch in Karachi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best TV of 2021 so far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/the-best-tv-of-2021-so-far</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/16/the-best-tv-of-2021-so-far"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T08:55:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Russell T Davies’s Aids-era opus to royal family bombshells with Oprah, here are the television highlights of the year up to now
Mitchell and Webb returned after a four-year wait with a second helping of Simon Blackwell’s cuckoo-in-the-nest comedy. And the duo’s talent for red herrings and all-out Peep Show-style ridiculousness meant it somehow outdid the ace first outing.
What we said: “In setting and ambience, Back is as drearily British as Brexit, but its dense dialogue – roughly every third word is hilarious – ensures it is also kin to glossy American cousins such as Succession (written by Blackwell’s old collaborator Jesse Armstrong) and Veep (on which Blackwell has writer and executive producer credits), all of which can be traced back to a common ancestor in Armando Iannucci’s The Thick of It. It is only Back’s characters that are parochial; everything else about this show is world class.” Read the full review
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah J Davies, Kate Abbott and Ammar Kalia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s not easy’: seven working parents around the world – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/its-not-easy-seven-working-parents-around-the-world-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/its-not-easy-seven-working-parents-around-the-world-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T07:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographers Linda Bournane Engelberth and Valentina Sinis document the lives of working parents from Botswana to the UK for Unicef
If investing in family-friendly policies is good for business, then many companies are missing a trick. Giving parents and families adequate time, resources and services to care for children, while staying in their jobs and improving their skills and productivity, pays off according to employers. But for many, in all parts of the world, paid parental leave and childcare are not a reality. And that can compromise the first critical years of life – a time when the combination of the right nourishment, environment and love can strengthen a developing brain and give a baby the best start.
Evidence suggests family-friendly policies pay off in healthier, better-educated children and greater gender equality, and are linked to better productivity and the ability to attract and retain workers. Momentum for change is growing with an increasing number of businesses beginning to see the value. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dad and dad: a journey into gay fatherhood – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/16/dad-and-dad-a-journey-into-gay-fatherhood-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/16/dad-and-dad-a-journey-into-gay-fatherhood-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since same-sex marriage became legal across the US, there has been a baby boom in the gay community – from New York City to Utah – as these touching images show 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ascot resumes after lockdown – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/16/ascot-resumes-after-lockdown-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/16/ascot-resumes-after-lockdown-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Racegoers have returned to Royal Ascot for the first time since the pandemic began. Punters dressed in outlandish hats, summer dresses, smart suits and masks will cheer on the jockeys over the next four days at the Berkshire race course
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Poland’s chicken boom behind its devastating bird flu outbreak?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/is-polands-chicken-boom-behind-its-devastating-bird-flu-outbreak</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/is-polands-chicken-boom-behind-its-devastating-bird-flu-outbreak"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T05:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite industry denials, many believe unchecked growth and the high density of farms created perfect conditions for the epidemic
• Read more: A bird costs less than a pint: welcome to Britain’s poultry capital
“I’ve lost everything,” says Andrzej Lewandowski, an egg producer from the village of Brudnice in Żuromin county, about 100km north of Warsaw. Żuromin and the neighbouring county of Mława are the hub of Poland’s chicken industry.
“I had to kill 140,000 hens. I lost 500,000 eggs, 40 tonnes of feed and soon I’m going to give up 250 tonnes of cereals I was going to use to make feed,” says Lewandowski about measures to eliminate a bird flu outbreak on his farm.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wojciech Kość</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK failing to protect against climate dangers, advisers warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/uk-failing-to-protect-against-climate-dangers-advisers-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/uk-failing-to-protect-against-climate-dangers-advisers-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T05:01:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is ‘absolutely illogical’ not to tackle the risks of heatwaves and power blackouts, says Climate Change Committee
The UK government is failing to protect people from the fast-rising risks of the climate crisis, from deadly heatwaves to power blackouts, its official climate advisers have warned.
The climate change committee said action to improve the nation’s resilience is not keeping pace with the impacts of global heating, many of which are already causing harm. The CCC’s experts said they were frustrated by the “absolutely illogical” lack of sufficient action on adaptation, particularly as acting is up to 10 times more cost-effective than not doing so.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jellied, smoked, baked in pies – but can the UK stop eels sliding into extinction?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/a-rewilding-project-on-uk-rivers-aims-to-stop-eels-sliding-to-extinction-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/16/a-rewilding-project-on-uk-rivers-aims-to-stop-eels-sliding-to-extinction-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T05:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centuries-old trade has been thwarted by trafficking and now Brexit. An unusual rewilding mission hopes to aid a 4,000-mile migration back to British rivers

Podcast: Inside the world of wildlife trafficking

An unusual rewilding mission is under way just off the M5 motorway. Eels the length of a little finger have finished their 6,600km (4,000-mile) migration from the salty Sargasso Sea in the Atlantic to the brackish water of the Bristol Channel. They have spent two years floating on ocean currents and are hoping to settle in the Somerset Levels. It is one of the planet’s most mysterious wildlife migrations.
Three fishers wait for eels on the banks of the River Parrett outside Burrowbridge with a large square net at the ready. The new arrivals look like threads of glass, fizzing with energy. I let out an involuntary squeal as the first batch arrive, much to the mirth of the fishers. “That’s rubbish! You haven’t been doing this long enough if you’re getting excited about catching 10 [eels] at this time of year,” says Steve George, who is a fencer by trade.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Weston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High in the Himalayas, villagers hit by Covid are left to fend for themselves]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/high-in-the-himalayas-villagers-hit-by-covid-are-left-to-fend-for-themselves</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/high-in-the-himalayas-villagers-hit-by-covid-are-left-to-fend-for-themselves"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T04:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In India’s remote peaks, the pandemic’s toll is worsened by lack of medical facilities, roads and information
Phalguni Devi has spent a fortnight living in a cattle shed. Looking out on a rainy afternoon in early June, she worries that if the rain does not let up, her fever will worsen.
Devi, 51, shares the shed with a cow and two cats, and this has taken its toll. Herbal concoctions have not worked and the visit to a pharmacist in the nearest town, in the Nijmola valley in the Himalayas, which took an entire day, did not help.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cheena Kapoor in Nijmola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From packed streets to silence: documenting the fall of Hong Kong]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/from-packed-streets-to-silence-documenting-hong-kong-authoritarianism</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/16/from-packed-streets-to-silence-documenting-hong-kong-authoritarianism"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T04:20:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two years ago photojournalist Laurel Chor covered mass protests against the extradition bill. She looks back at how the city has changed in their wake
I had never seen so many people before in my life. On 9 June 2019, hundreds of thousands of people dressed in white marched slowly but steadily across Hong Kong island.
The heat and humidity were almost unbearable, but protesters from all walks of life came prepared with neck towels, folding fans, and umbrellas to shield the sun. It’s never easy to capture the scale of a crowd, but the intense, palpable energy emanating from the masses of people who had united for common values isn’t something a photograph could ever convey.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laurel Chor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel’s unlikely coalition: is this the end for Netanyahu?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/16/israels-unlikely-coalition-is-this-the-end-for-netanyahu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/16/israels-unlikely-coalition-is-this-the-end-for-netanyahu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T02:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israel has a new coalition government made up of eight very different parties. But having ousted Benjamin Netanyahu, can it hold together?
Israel’s longest-serving leader, Benjamin Netanyahu, was ousted from office on Sunday by a coalition of rival parties from across the political spectrum. Yair Lapid, a centrist former TV news anchor, won a confidence vote in parliament by 60 to 59 seats giving the new coalition a razor-thin majority.
The Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, Oliver Holmes, tells Rachel Humphreys that Netanyahu’s downfall was marked by jubilant celebrations from his political opponents. But the new coalition of eight parties is far from stable. Dahlia Scheindlin tells Rachel that despite the momentous week in Israeli politics it may not produce a significant change of course on the biggest issues facing the country. And it may not be the last act for Netanyahu in Israeli politics. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Oliver Holmes and Dahlia Scheindlin; produced by Ned Carter Miles and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detect Unused Classes in… HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342198</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/detect-unused-classes-in-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T23:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually, when “unused” comes up in conversation regarding CSS, it’s about removing chunks of CSS that are not used in your site or, at least, the styles not currently in use on a specific page. The minimal amount of CSS …
The post Detect Unused Classes in… HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps Engineering Course for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>60c91b2b4dc1a607ed7b389a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/devops-engineering-course-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T21:33:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps is becoming an in-demand role at many software companies. We just released a DevOps Engineering course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. Learn all about DevOps in this comprehensive course for beginners with three technical tutorials. Colin Chartier created this course. He is the co-founder and CEO at LayerCI.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Does &#x27;this&#x27; Mean in JavaScript? The this Keyword Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>60c72a0ad3126007592d7e2a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-this-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T21:19:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To understand what this truly means in JavaScript, let's take a look at a very similar concept in the English Language: Polysemy. Let's consider the word "run". Run is a single word which could mean many different things depending on the context. “I will run home” – means to move quickly]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Charge as a Freelance Developer – and Why You Should Avoid Being the Cheapest]]></title>
        <id>60c8912c4dc1a607ed7b2fff</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-to-charge-as-a-freelance-developer-dont-be-the-cheapest/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T21:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a freelance developer, knowing how much to charge for a project can often feel like a gamble. It's easy to wonder "Am I setting my price too high?" This is normally the first question that comes to mind. And your brain will probably meet this question with a resounding]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Media Queries in Times of @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342519</id>
        <link href="https://mxb.dev/blog/media-queries-in-times-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T19:51:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Max Böck took me up on my challenge to look through a codebase and see how many of the @media queries could ultimately become @container queries.
I took the bait and had a look at some of my projects – 
…
The post Media Queries in Times of @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python Decorators – How to Create and Use Decorators in Python With Examples]]></title>
        <id>60c3dcb3d3126007592d6c6d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-decorators-explained-with-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T17:57:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Python decorators allow you to change the behavior of a function without modifying the function itself. In this article I will show you how to create and use decorators. You will see how easy it is to use this advanced Python feature. In this article I will discuss the following]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the Strangler Fig Pattern and How it Helps Manage Legacy Code]]></title>
        <id>602aaaf60a2838549dcc5c7f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-the-strangler-pattern-in-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T17:43:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any sufficiently old codebase eventually starts to contain legacy code. Architecture, performance, comments, and more begin to degrade the moment after they are written. Some parts of the codebase last longer than other parts, but inevitably new coding standards emerge to reduce technical debt. Then you have to rework a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British farmers: what do you think of the UK-Australia trade deal?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/15/british-farmers-what-do-you-think-of-the-uk-australia-trade-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/15/british-farmers-what-do-you-think-of-the-uk-australia-trade-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T16:56:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear how British farmers feel about the information that has so far emerged about the new trade agreement, and how they believe it might impact them
The National Farmers’ Union (NFU) has called for more information about protections for UK farmers in a new trade deal with Australia, amid fears the UK might face a potential flood of cheaper meat, and concerns about a lack of detail on animal welfare and environmental safeguards.
The British government said UK food standards would not be relaxed, but has so far not provided details on areas such as higher levels of antibiotics used in Australian meat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Open Any Repo in VS Code Without Cloning It]]></title>
        <id>60b7cb6aacb62507dd1d7c1a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/you-can-now-edit-anything-on-github-in-vs-code-without-cloning/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T16:06:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can now open anything (that you have access to) on GitHub directly from VS Code.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just How Niche is Headless WordPress?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342248</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/just-how-niche-is-headless-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T14:31:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wonder where headless WordPress will land. And by “headless” I mean only using the WordPress admin and building out the user-facing site through the WordPress REST API rather than the traditional WordPress theme structure.
Is it… big? The future …
The post Just How Niche is Headless WordPress? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It used to run black’: images of a river reborn – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/15/it-used-to-run-black-images-of-a-river-reborn-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/15/it-used-to-run-black-images-of-a-river-reborn-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T06:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Ogmore is an unremarkable river ... or is it? Dan Wood’s photographs capture a place of childhood mischief and intrigue
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s behind the mass protests in Colombia?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/15/behind-mass-protests-colombia-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/15/behind-mass-protests-colombia-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T02:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A demonstration against tax rises has morphed into a mass movement against the government, says Joe Parkin Daniels in Bogotá
An attempt by the Colombian government to introduce sweeping tax changes in response to the coronavirus crisis was met earlier this year by angry protests. Thousands of people flooded on to the streets throughout the country for four consecutive days. It was enough to prompt President Iván Duque to withdraw his tax plans, but by then it was too late to stop the protests. 
Ever since, more and more Colombians have been coming out to protest. Joe Parkin Daniels, who has been reporting on the demonstrations for the Guardian for weeks, tells Rachel Humphreys that they now encompass people from all sections of Colombian society, with a multitude of causes. One thing ever present is a fury at the growing inequality that has been exacerbated by the Covid crisis. As police have cracked down hard on the protesters, more than 50 people have died, with no end to the protests in sight. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Joe Parkin Daniels; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342294</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-tables-with-sticky-header-and-footers-got-a-bit-easier/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T22:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It wasn’t long ago when I looked at sticky headers and footers in HTML <table>s in the blog post A table with both a sticky header and a sticky first column. In it, I never used position: sticky on …
The post Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342229</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-tricks-chronicle-xxxx/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T18:20:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a little link roundup of some off-site stuff I’ve done recently. As I’m wont to do from time to time. 
DevJourney Podcast
#151 Chris Coyier from ceramics to CSS-Tricks and CodePen‘
Chris took us from playing on 
…
The post CSS-Tricks Chronicle XXXX appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342070</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/securing-your-website-with-subresource-integrity/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T13:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you load a file from an external server, you’re trusting that the content you request is what you expect it to be. Since you don’t manage the server yourself, you’re relying on the security of yet another third party …
The post Securing Your Website With Subresource Integrity appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khari McMillian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What went wrong with the Covid-19 response in the US? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/14/what-went-wrong-with-the-us-covid-19-response-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/14/what-went-wrong-with-the-us-covid-19-response-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author and journalist Lawrence Wright has been writing about pandemics for decades. So when Covid-19 struck the US, he was ideally placed to report on the political response
At the beginning of 2020 the author Lawrence Wright published a novel in which he imagined a deadly virus outbreak that swept the globe. He couldn’t have predicted that as that book hit the shops real life was eerily mimicking his plot. As a reporter for the New Yorker, Wright had been reporting on pandemics for decades and was ideally placed to chart the spread of Covid-19. 
He tells Anushka Asthana that what unfolded was to become America’s deadliest year, with half a million people lost to the virus. Inside the White House, there were experts desperately trying to influence the president to change course on key decisions. But the story of the initial Covid response, argues Wright, was one of a significant political failure.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Lawrence Wright; produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342429</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/safari-15-new-ui-theme-colors-and-a-css-tricks-cameo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:38:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a 33-minute video (and resources) over on apple.com covering the upcoming Safari changes we saw in the WWDC keynote this year in much more detail. Look who’s got a little cameo in there:
Perhaps the most noticeable thing there …
The post Safari 15: New UI, Theme Colors, and… a CSS-Tricks Cameo! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Possibilities of Syndication]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342237</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-possibilities-of-syndication/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T21:25:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That’s the one word that isn’t an adjective in the acronym RSS. 
Really Simple Syndication.
Update: Lol there are literally two mistakes there. RSS is an initialism not an acronym, and “Really” is an adverb not an adjective. 
RSS …
The post The Possibilities of Syndication appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342164</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/adding-shadows-to-svg-icons-with-css-and-svg-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T14:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why would we need to apply shadows to SVG?
Shadows are a common design feature that can help elements, like icons, stand out. They could be persistent, or applied in different states (e.g. :hover, :focus, or :active) 
…
The post Adding Shadows to SVG Icons With CSS and SVG Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Olawanle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put a Background on Open Details Elements]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342050</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/put-a-background-on-open-details-elements/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T00:16:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One thing that can be just a smidge funky about the <details> element is that, when open, it’s not always 100% clear what is inside that element and what isn’t. I’m not saying that always matters or that it’s a …
The post Put a Background on Open Details Elements appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341894</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/equal-columns-with-flexbox-its-more-complicated-than-you-might-think/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As awesome as flexbox is, what it’s doing under the hood is actually a little strange because, by default, it is doing two things at once. It first looks at the content size which is what we would get if by declaring width: max-content on an element. But on top of that, flex-shrink is also doing some work allowing the items to be smaller, but only if needed.
Let’s break those two down and see how they work together.
The post Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-headless-cms-with-fauna-and-vercel-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will learn and use headless CMS, Fauna, and Vercel functions to build a blogging platform, Blogify After that, you can easily build any web application using a headless CMS, Fauna and Vercel functions.
The post Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ikeh Akinyemi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katie Piper and Candice Brathwaite on how emotions affect their complexions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/living-with-sensitive-skin/2021/may/20/katie-piper-and-candice-brathwaite-on-how-emotions-affect-their-complexions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:40:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you break out in a rash when you’re stressed, you’re not alone. Find out how two women in the public eye cope when anxiety affects their skin – and discover the science behind the spots
Spots, rashes and flushing can often affect your emotions, making you self-conscious or even embarrassed. But did you know that, conversely, heightened emotions can aggravate your skin, making it vulnerable to breakouts – and that this is scientifically recognised?
“It’s been shown, on a molecular level, that there are changes to the chemicals in the skin when we get stressed,” says consultant dermatologist Dr Justine Hextall. “The blood vessels dilate and then you often get a flushed red face.” Stress will change the skin barrier, the outer layer of skin cells and the ceramides, cholesterols and fatty acids that hold them together, making inflammation more likely.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fielding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>