<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-27T00:51:22.128Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-27T00:51:22.128Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.9.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solskjaer: Manchester United ‘did not turn up’ for Europa League final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/ole-gunnar-solskjaer-united-did-not-turn-up-for-europa-league-final</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/ole-gunnar-solskjaer-united-did-not-turn-up-for-europa-league-final"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T23:41:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Villarreal win trophy after penalty shootout marathon
Manager says season cannot be considered a ‘success’

Ole Gunnar Solskjaer declared Manchester United’s season was unsuccessful after his team “didn’t turn up” for their Europa League final against Villarreal.
United were beaten 11-10 in a remarkable penalty shootout that featured 21 converted spot-kicks before goalkeeper David de Gea’s final attempt was saved by his opposite number, Gerónimo Rulli. His stop ensured United’s four-year wait for silverware continues and brought Villarreal their first trophy from their first major final. It also made Unai Emery the most decorated coach in the competition with four triumphs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK lifeguards gear up for busiest summer as millions head for coast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/27/uk-lifeguards-gear-up-for-busiest-summer-as-millions-head-for-coast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/27/uk-lifeguards-gear-up-for-busiest-summer-as-millions-head-for-coast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Good weather, foreign travel bans and lockdown exhaustion will propel 30 million to beach in coming months
The Royal National Lifeboat Institution (RNLI) and HM Coastguard are braced for their busiest ever summer, with research showing that 30 million people plan to head to the UK coast over the coming months.
The two organisations launched a safety campaign on Thursday, urging visitors to choose beaches patrolled by lifeguards.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proms to welcome back live audiences for 52 concerts over six weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/27/proms-welcome-back-live-audiences-52-concerts-six-weeks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/27/proms-welcome-back-live-audiences-52-concerts-six-weeks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Organisers hope season will be part of ‘curtain up’ on return of live music to full venues
Prom concerts with physical audiences and patriotic last-night stompers will be back this summer, with a season organisers hope will be “curtain up” on the return to live music as we knew it.
While a normal season features about 90 concerts over eight weeks, last year just 14 concerts played to an empty Royal Albert Hall. The BBC said the plan this summer was for 52 concerts over six weeks, with audiences. “And we pray it will be a full audience,” said the Proms director, David Pickard.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Brown Arts correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinedine Zidane decides to end his second stint as Real Madrid manager]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/zinedine-zidane-to-leave-real-madrid-manager</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/zinedine-zidane-to-leave-real-madrid-manager"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T22:39:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frenchman departs at end of difficult season for Spanish club
Zidane to leave with immediate effect after failing to win title

Zinedine Zidane has decided to leave Real Madrid with immediate effect, bringing to an end his second stint as manager at the Spanish club.
 Related: Super League rebel trio hit back after Uefa launch disciplinary proceedings 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Romano and Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Villarreal beat Manchester United 11-10 on penalties to win Europa League final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/villarreal-manchester-united-europa-league-final-2021-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/villarreal-manchester-united-europa-league-final-2021-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T22:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United suffered European heartache after a cruel 11-10 penalty shootout defeat via the unfortunate boot of David de Gea, who stroked his kick to the left of Gerónimo Rulli, whose save made him Villarreal’s hero.
It is always hard for whoever loses this way and for the goalkeeper to miss the vital spot-kick seems particularly cruel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Jackson at the Gdansk Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tax soaring private jet use to fund green flying, says report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/climate-ticket-tax-private-jet-users</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/climate-ticket-tax-private-jet-users"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T22:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taxes of €325m a year should be used to fund zero-carbon aviation technology, report suggests
Climate-heating emissions from private jet flights have soared in Europe since 2005, according to a report. It calls for wealthy fliers to pay ticket taxes of €325m a year to fund the acceleration of zero-carbon aviation technology.
Carbon emissions from private flights rose by 31% from 2005-19, the report says, and private aviation had rebounded to pre-pandemic levels by August 2020, when 60% of public flights were grounded.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giphy API Tutorial – How to Generate Animated Text GIFs with ReactJS]]></title>
        <id>60a44b9f906c5207e3a7e098</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/giphy-api-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial you will create an app that generates dynamic animated text using Giphy's API with ReactJS. After that I'll go over some of the other API features Giphy provides that you can use to make other interesting projects. You can find the code for the tutorial here. Video]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German scientists say they can help improve vaccines to prevent blood clots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/german-scientists-say-they-can-help-improve-vaccines-to-prevent-blood-clots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/german-scientists-say-they-can-help-improve-vaccines-to-prevent-blood-clots"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:37:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AstraZeneca and Johnson & Johnson jabs have caused rare blood clots but scientists say they can be redesigned to avoid problem

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A team of German scientists believe that they have worked out why some people given the AstraZeneca and Johnson & Johnson vaccines against Covid-19 develop blood clots – and claim they can tell the manufacturers how to improve the vaccine to avoid it.
The key is in the adenovirus – the common cold virus that is used to deliver the spike protein of the coronavirus into the body, say Rolf Marschalek, a professor at Goethe university in Frankfurt, and colleagues. The mRNA vaccines developed by Pfizer/BioNTech and Moderna do not use this delivery system and there have been no blood clotting cases linked to them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley Health editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Hawking’s office and archive gifted to UK to settle tax bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/26/stephen-hawkings-office-and-archive-gifted-to-uk-to-settle-tax-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/26/stephen-hawkings-office-and-archive-gifted-to-uk-to-settle-tax-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientist’s treasure trove and personal objects to go to Science Museum and Cambridge University Library
A vast treasure trove of papers and personal objects belonging to Stephen Hawking, from dizzying black hole theories to scripts for the Simpsons, have been acquired for the nation.
It was announced on Thursday that Hawking’s archive and the contents of his university office have been acquired through the Acceptance in Lieu scheme, which allows families to offset tax.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Brown Arts corespondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Before We Die review – a weak, bleak hour that’s totally lost in translation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/before-we-die-review-a-weak-bleak-hour-thats-totally-lost-in-translation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/before-we-die-review-a-weak-bleak-hour-thats-totally-lost-in-translation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Based on a Swedish series, this dire Channel 4 police drama boasts downright woeful acting – and a script that seems cobbled together via Google Translate
Channel 4’s new drama Before We Die is based on a Swedish series of the same name. It figures: viewing it felt exactly like watching something where all the important things had been lost in translation.
A pace that might perhaps have fostered a sense of dread in the original here tips over into simple slowness. The story – shifted from Stockholm to Bristol – follows senior police detective Hannah Laing (Lesley Sharp). Hannah is being forced to do a desk job in the hope that it will encourage her to retire and make way for new blood, a story that unfolds no more than steadily. She is on bad terms with her son, Christian (Patrick Gibson), because, two years before the story proper begins, she had him arrested for drug dealing during a nightclub raid. (To be fair, she thought he would get a suspended sentence rather than the prison term he ended up serving. We’ve all been there with our recalcitrant teens.)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hookworms: abuse allegations against ex-frontman Matthew Johnson withdrawn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/hookworms-abuse-allegations-against-ex-frontman-matthew-johnson-withdrawn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/hookworms-abuse-allegations-against-ex-frontman-matthew-johnson-withdrawn"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T20:59:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson has withdrawn a lawsuit for libel and malicious falsehood regarding claims made by musician Alanna McArdle on behalf of another woman
The musician Alanna McArdle has formally withdrawn allegations of sexual and mental abuse made against former Hookworms frontman Matthew Johnson in October 2018 on behalf of another woman, known as L.
He in turn has withdrawn his libel lawsuit against McArdle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Snapes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Jose shooting: nine dead, including gunman, after attack at California rail yard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/san-jose-shooting-police-gunman-railyard</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/san-jose-shooting-police-gunman-railyard"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T20:34:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say the shooter was an employee of the Valley Transportation Authority, which operates the light rail facility
A shooting that erupted in the early hours of Wednesday morning at a light rail maintenance yard in San Jose, California, has left at least nine people dead, including the gunman.
Local leaders have described the violence as a “terrible, terrible” tragedy as authorities search for a motive.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 150 feared drowned in Nigeria boat disaster]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/more-than-150-feared-drowned-in-nigeria-boat-disaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/more-than-150-feared-drowned-in-nigeria-boat-disaster"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T20:27:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Overloaded vessel sank in the Niger River with four confirmed dead, according to local officials
More than 150 people were missing and feared drowned in northwest Nigeria on Wednesday after an overloaded boat ferrying passengers to a market sank in the Niger River, local officials said.
The boat was travelling between central Niger state and Wara in north-west Kebbi state when it went down, National Inland Waterways Authority local manager Yusuf Birma told reporters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AFP in Kano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Associated Press vows to defend staff against online attacks after Emily Wilder firing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/26/associated-press-emily-wilder-defend-staff</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/26/associated-press-emily-wilder-defend-staff"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T20:04:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The news agency has admitted to mishandling the situation and said they fired the reporter for breaching social media policies
Management at the Associated Press have told staff that they stand behind their decision to fire newly hired reporter Emily Wilder who was targeted by a Republican smear campaign regarding her pro-Palestinian advocacy while a student.
However, they also admitted to mishandling the situation and vowed to defend their staff against online attacks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cummings lambasts Johnson in damning account of Covid crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/boris-johnson-is-unfit-to-be-prime-minister-says-dominic-cummings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/boris-johnson-is-unfit-to-be-prime-minister-says-dominic-cummings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T20:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ousted aide says failure to grasp situation meant ‘tens of thousands of people died who didn’t need to die’

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Boris Johnson is unfit to be prime minister after presiding over a chaotic and incompetent pandemic response that caused many thousands of unnecessary deaths, his former chief aide Dominic Cummings claimed in an excoriating attack.
In a seven-hour hearing before MPs in Westminster, Cummings gave a damning account of the government’s approach, laying much of the blame on Johnson and the health secretary, Matt Hancock.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s a real honor’: Karine Jean-Pierre makes history at White House briefing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/karine-jean-pierre-white-house-press-briefing-biden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/karine-jean-pierre-white-house-press-briefing-biden"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:46:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jean-Pierre becomes first openly gay person to brief White House press corps and first Black woman to do so in 30 years
“Hi, everybody! Welcome!”
So, with a rustle of papers, began a new chapter in the White House briefing room on Wednesday when Karine Jean-Pierre became the first openly gay person to address reporters on behalf of the US president.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vanessa Redgrave no longer set to appear in Kevin Spacey film]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/26/vanessa-redgrave-kevin-spacey-film-franco-nero</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/26/vanessa-redgrave-kevin-spacey-film-franco-nero"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:45:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor had been linked to her husband Franco Nero’s Italian drama, set to be Spacey’s comeback after sexual misconduct accusations
Vanessa Redgrave will not be starring in a new film alongside Kevin Spacey despite previous reports attaching her to the project.
The 84-year-old actor had been linked to her husband Franco Nero’s Italian drama L’uomo Che Disegno Dio, translated as The Man Who Drew God, but in a new statement from her representatives, she is now no longer involved.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cummings brought to life what many already knew about Johnson’s failures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/cummings-brought-to-life-what-many-already-knew-about-johnsons-failures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/cummings-brought-to-life-what-many-already-knew-about-johnsons-failures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: PM’s former adviser is self-interested and inconsistent, yet his attack had the ring of plausibility
Late-night battles, expletive-ridden rants, Jaws references and Spiderman memes – the dramatic details of Dominic Cummings’ seven-hour testimony captivated Westminster on Wednesday.
But strip away all the chaos and colour, and the bleak picture left behind was of a prime minister utterly unsuited to the historic and unprecedented task he was handed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings stars in his own jaw-dropping, grubby, delusional miniseries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/dominic-cummings-the-movie-jaw-dropping-grubby-and-delusional</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/dominic-cummings-the-movie-jaw-dropping-grubby-and-delusional"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:14:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dom’s hearing was certainly entertaining, but families of the bereaved deserved better than politically-honed truths
Not so much a parliamentary hearing, more an eight-hour Netflix miniseries. The one where a lone delusional narcissist drives into town to take revenge on a whole bunch of other delusional narcissists. With a bit of Independence Day and Spider-Man thrown in.
Dominic Cummings’ appearance before the joint science and technology and health select committee always promised to be good box office and it didn’t disappoint. By the end of the session the body count included Boris Johnson, Matt Hancock, half the senior civil servants in Downing Street, Cobra, Carrie Symonds and Dilyn the dog. Not forgetting Cummings himself. It’s not in Dom’s makeup to resist a self-inflicted wound.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on Dominic Cummings giving evidence to MPs – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/26/martin-rowson-on-dominic-cummings-giving-evidence-to-mps-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/26/martin-rowson-on-dominic-cummings-giving-evidence-to-mps-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cummings says Boris Johnson ‘unfit for job’ of PM amid Covid crisis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Lan: In the age of apartheid, theatre resisted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/26/even-in-apartheid-south-africa-theatre-resisted-david-lan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/26/even-in-apartheid-south-africa-theatre-resisted-david-lan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T19:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The theatre director and writer looks back at the spirit of protest that fuelled daring dramas staged in South Africa 50 years ago
I grew up in South Africa during the bleak, violent, seemingly never-ending iron age of apartheid. In 1971, when I was studying acting at Cape Town University, the National Party government built a monolithic 1,500-seat theatre complex in a commanding position near the centre of the city. The Afrikaner Nationalists had an easy rule of thumb by which to distinguish between the value of white people and black people – we have culture and they don’t. The purpose of the monolith, with its elaborate stairways, fancy colonnades and picture windows, was to declare and celebrate this belief. White musicians, actors and dancers were to perform to exclusively white audiences.
Afrikaans theatre was bursting with contradictions. The finest Afrikaans playwright was William Shakespeare. From the 1950s to the 70s, Afrikaans-language productions of the European modernists – Pirandello, Maeterlinck, Strindberg and especially Chekhov – toured to church halls all over the country. Uncle Vanya was a quintessential Afrikaans cultural experience.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Lan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Woman sues employer who fired her for calling police on Black birdwatcher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/amy-cooper-black-bird-watcher-sues-employer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/amy-cooper-black-bird-watcher-sues-employer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:57:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amy Cooper, who said Christian Cooper was ‘threatening her life’, is accusing the company of falsely portraying her as racist
Amy Cooper, the white woman who falsely told police that Black birdwatcher Christian Cooper had threatened her in New York City’s Central Park, is suing her employer for false dismissal.
In a complaint filed on Tuesday night in Manhattan federal court obtained by Reuters, Cooper claims she was fired by her former employer, the financial advisory firm Franklin Templeton, without proper investigation of the incident and accused the company of falsely portraying her as racist.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore in New York and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden orders US intelligence to intensify efforts to study Covid’s origins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/joe-biden-us-intelligence-community-covid-19-origins-china</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/26/joe-biden-us-intelligence-community-covid-19-origins-china"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President also asks US intelligence community to explore the unlikely possibility that virus origins trace to Chinese lab

US politics – live updates

Joe Biden has ordered the US intelligence community to intensify its efforts to study the origins of coronavirus, adding that it will continue to press for China to participate in a full investigation.
The president said he received a report earlier this month with the “most up-to-date analysis of the origins of Covid-19”, but had asked intelligence agencies to “redouble” their efforts to identify a “definitive conclusion” on how the virus was first transmitted in humans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joan E Greve in Washington and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Has Marks and Spencer really got it right at last? | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/26/has-marks-and-spencer-really-got-it-right-at-last</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/26/has-marks-and-spencer-really-got-it-right-at-last"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve heard the argument before, but now it does seem the moment of maximum danger has passed
Green shoots at M&S? That was chairman Archie Norman’s boast as he peered through the thicket of exceptional charges that dominated yet another set of annual results and turned a small headline pre-tax profit of £41.6m into a large statutory loss of £201m.
“We are emerging from the chrysalis of Covid as a reshaped business and I think for the first time for three and half years there is a lot to feel confident about,” he declared.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friends: the Reunion review – The One That Is a Nostalgia Fest and No More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/friends-the-reunion-review-the-one-that-was-a-nostalgia-fest-and-no-more</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/friends-the-reunion-review-the-one-that-was-a-nostalgia-fest-and-no-more"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:38:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The magic between the six Friends as they return to the apartment is undeniably cheering. But no one needs to see James Corden – or Justin Bieber dressed as a potato

There was never any real danger that Friends: the Reunion would let in too much light upon the magic that was created in 1994 and held, on average, 25 million US viewers a week in its thrall for the next decade. The special was intended to mark the launch of the US streaming service HBO Max (and as sand kicked in the face of their rival Netflix, from whom it has poached the entire 236-episode run). Although Covid delayed things, it was still never going to be anything other than a nostalgic celebration of times past-but-still-in-lucrative-syndication.
The reunion marks the first time the six actors – probably for those 10 years the most famous in the world – have all been together publicly since the show ended. They arrive one by one on the re-created set. David Schwimmer first, calm and thoughtful, noting original features and the spot “Jen and I had our first kiss”, followed by Lisa Kudrow, Jennifer Aniston (dissolving into happy tears), ebullient Matt LeBlanc (“What are you guys doing here!”), Courteney Cox (happily tearful too) and finally a nervy Matthew Perry (“Could you BE any later!” cries LeBlanc).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Batley teacher suspended after showing Charlie Hebdo image can return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/26/batley-teacher-suspended-after-showing-charlie-hebdo-image-can-return</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/26/batley-teacher-suspended-after-showing-charlie-hebdo-image-can-return"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:36:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigation finds teacher ‘genuinely believed’ Prophet Muhammad picture had educational purpose
A teacher who ignited protests at a school in West Yorkshire after using a controversial image of the prophet Muhammad in class has been cleared of causing deliberate offence and told he can have his job back.
The teacher was suspended in March for showing pupils a drawing taken from the French satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo during a religious studies classes at Batley grammar school, provoking complaints from parents and protests outside the school’s gates.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Adams and Maya Wolfe-Robinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kelly Clarkson to replace Ellen DeGeneres on US daytime TV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/kelly-clarkson-ellen-degeneres-nbc-talk-how</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/kelly-clarkson-ellen-degeneres-nbc-talk-how"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NBC says pop singer’s eponymous talkshow will replace Ellen’s slot once the daytime titan steps down in autumn next year
NBC has announced that Kelly Clarkson will take the daytime slot vacated by the talkshow anchor Ellen DeGeneres, once her eponymous show ends in 2022.
The network announced on Wednesday that the 39-year-old pop singer – the original American Idol, judge on the popular competition show The Voice and host of her own talkshow owned and produced by NBC’s syndication arm – will take over DeGeneres’s slot on NBC-owned and affiliated stations in fall next year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Horton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Chevron suffer shareholder rebellions over climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/exxonmobil-and-chevron-braced-for-showdown-over-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/exxonmobil-and-chevron-braced-for-showdown-over-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:17:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exxon loses two board seats to activist hedge fund

US oil giants ExxonMobil and Chevron have suffered shareholder rebellions from climate activists and disgruntled institutional investors over their failure to set a strategy for a low-carbon future.
Exxon failed to defend its board against a coup launched by dissident hedge fund activists at Engine No. 1 which successfully replaced two Exxon board members with its own candidates to help drive the oil company towards a greener strategy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea return 800 Champions League tickets amid fan anger at cost and rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/chelsea-return-800-champions-league-tickets-amid-anger-at-cost-and-rules</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/chelsea-return-800-champions-league-tickets-amid-anger-at-cost-and-rules"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans accuse Uefa over restrictions for final in Porto
CST board member: ‘Selling tickets for €400 is outrageous’

Chelsea have returned more than 800 tickets out of their allocation of 5,800 for the Champions League final with Manchester City in Porto. 
The returned tickets were part of a charter package, which included subsidised flights at £200, but supporters have balked at the price and the apparent restrictions connected to the package deal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media and Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Cummings’ testimony: a vivid portrait of failure | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/the-guardian-view-on-cummings-testimony-a-vivid-portrait-of-failure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/the-guardian-view-on-cummings-testimony-a-vivid-portrait-of-failure"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:04:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s former adviser is not the most reliable narrator, but his damning account of the prime minister’s flaws is supported by all the evidence
A year ago, Dominic Cummings gave a press conference from the garden of 10 Downing Street to explain why he, as the prime minister’s most powerful adviser, should be allowed to breach lockdown rules when ordinary citizens were confined to their homes. His explanation, involving the claim to have tested his eyesight by driving with his family in the car, was famously improbable.
That episode damages Mr Cummings’ credibility as a witness before a committee of MPs seeking to learn lessons from the government’s handling of the pandemic. No one who watched Wednesday’s testimony was left doubting that he intended to settle scores and divert blame away from himself. He apologised for mistakes that were made, but as a prelude to self-exculpation, even over that family trip to County Durham. His regret was not having acted sooner to contradict a prevailing government view last March that the virus should be allowed to run through the population, generating natural immunity. He had been right all along, and should have forced the prime minister to act, he said. Well he would, wouldn’t he, as Mandy Rice-Davies might have observed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on inflation: the revival that’s nothing like the 1970s | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/the-guardian-view-on-inflation-the-revival-thats-nothing-like-the-1970s</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/the-guardian-view-on-inflation-the-revival-thats-nothing-like-the-1970s"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:03:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the 2008 crash, hawks worried about debt. Amid this one, they’re fretting about price rises. They were wrong then, and they’re likely to be wrong now
Inflation is back. That old foe of central bankers, mugger of pensioners and fashion staple of the 1970s is once again in the news. Its return is being talked about at Threadneedle Street and at the US Federal Reserve. It is creeping into newspaper headlines and on to market-watchers’ worry lists. But some perspective is essential: the price rises of today are nothing like those we saw half a century ago, because the world we live in is nothing like that one. Many of the fears expressed over any sign of rising prices are misplaced.
Economists are perhaps not the first people you might want to hear from about fashion, but one guaranteed revival for this spring/summer is: price rises. They will be in the news a great deal over the coming months. Last week’s news of a doubling of the inflation rate is just the beginning. The primary reason for that is mechanical. Last year saw many parts of the economy put in deep freeze to prevent the spread of Covid; with the reopening of pubs, restaurants and clothes shops, and the return of high street spending, prices will tick up. In this sense, inflation is to be welcomed as a sign of economic growth after a record slump. Another factor will not have passed motorists by: fuel prices, both at the petrol pump and to heat homes, are on an upward march.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers accused of hypocrisy over ‘toothless’ environment bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/ministers-accused-of-hypocrisy-over-toothless-environment-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/ministers-accused-of-hypocrisy-over-toothless-environment-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners say bill that ministers call ‘ambitious’ fails to protect green spaces, air quality or wildlife, and is ‘riddled with loopholes’
Ministers have been accused of hypocrisy in bringing forward a “toothless” environment bill that will fail to protect against developers concreting over valuable green space, lack provisions for improving air quality, and contain what campaigners said were inadequate protections for wildlife.
The government voted down amendments to its flagship environment bill on Wednesday that would have strengthened the powers of a watchdog, given local communities more say over planning and development, and expanded protections for habitats.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Contribute to Open Source  Projects – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60abe7fb11ffb70827ef63a6</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-contribute-to-open-source-projects-beginners-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a developer, you've probably come across the term "open source." If you've ever wondered what it's all about and how to contribute, you are in exactly the right place.  I put aside all my fears about how and what to contribute during Hacktoberfest 2020, and made]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Basic Terraform Syntax in 20 minutes]]></title>
        <id>606f4f5fd5756f080ba96b65</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/terraform-syntax-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll give you a brief overview of the configuration syntax of Terraform.  Terraform's docs provide the most comprehensive look at its syntax. But this article should serve as a condensed quick start introduction that'll give new users a simplified overview. We'll focus on the basic structures without]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family pride at Max Mosley’s victory over Rupert Murdoch | Brief letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/family-pride-at-max-mosleys-victory-over-rupert-murdoch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/family-pride-at-max-mosleys-victory-over-rupert-murdoch"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:51:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mosley v Murdoch | lager louts | Steve Bell’s If ... | Cummings needs a trim | lastminute.gov
We’re saddened to hear of the death of our cousin Max Mosley (Obituary, 24 May). Although we are from different branches of the infamous Mitford sisters, we have admired Max for his fight against invasion of privacy. Our mother, Jessica Mitford, would have cheered him on for his victorious trouncing of the avaricious and conscienceless Rupert Murdoch.
Constancia Romilly
Cold Spring, New York, USA
Benjamin Treuhaft
Coventry
• The Albion in Chester was not just “family-unfriendly” (Letters, 24 May); the publican occasionally took umbrage from complaining customers. One complaint, in a pub known for the quality of its beer, led to a prominent bar sign: “Of course it tastes like piss. It’s lager.”
David Fletcher
Buckley, Flintshire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant tortoise found in Galápagos a species considered extinct a century ago]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/galapagos-giant-tortoise-found-species-considered-extinct</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/galapagos-giant-tortoise-found-species-considered-extinct"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:39:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ecuador confirms turtle found two years ago on Fernandina Island is a Chelonoidis phantasticus species 
Ecuador has confirmed that a giant tortoise found in 2019 in the Galápagos Islands is a species considered extinct a century ago.
The Galápagos national park is preparing an expedition to search for more of the giant tortoises in an attempt to save the species.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Quito</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The lives lost to hospital-acquired Covid | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/the-lives-lost-to-hospital-acquired-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/the-lives-lost-to-hospital-acquired-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian readers respond to our report that up to 8,700 patients died after catching Covid in English hospitals, with some sharing their own stories
Thank you for your excellent article (Up to 8,700 patients died after catching Covid in English hospitals, 24 May). My wife was admitted to Basildon hospital in early September for a 10-hour heart bypass operation, and afterwards was in intensive care for three weeks before being transferred to general wards for recovery. The ward Pam went to had a Covid outbreak after a few days, and she contracted it. She was moved into a total of five wards – all had Covid at some stage – and she finally passed away on 18 November. Pam was a very nervous person and I dread to think what was going through her mind, as I was unable to have contact with her for her final seven weeks. I have yet to come to terms with her situation and passing.
Pam received marvellous treatment from the medical staff, even allowing me and family and friends to send emails, which a nurse read out to her. However, early in the pandemic a Nightingale hospital was built at the ExCeL centre to accommodate a significant number of patients; it has barely been used. I contend that if all the Covid patients within a 30-mile radius had been transferred there, it would have kept all the other hospitals in the catchment area free of the virus, and allowed them to operate normally, thus preventing a significant number of deaths. I am convinced that had such a policy been adopted, Pam would still be alive today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie awarded joint custody of children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/brad-pitt-angelina-jolie-joint-custody</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/brad-pitt-angelina-jolie-joint-custody"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:33:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decision comes after criticism by Jolie of judge’s decision not to let children testify 
Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie have been awarded joint custody following a protracted court battle.
The former couple have been in dispute for five years over access to their six children and hired a private judge, John Ouderkirk, to oversee the case.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Film</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of YouTube comments on Sky News Australia video celebrate BLM activist being shot in head]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/thousands-of-youtube-comments-on-sky-news-australia-video-celebrate-blm-activist-being-shot-in-head</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/thousands-of-youtube-comments-on-sky-news-australia-video-celebrate-blm-activist-being-shot-in-head"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: The racist and violent comments appear below a video news report about Sasha Johnson who was shot in the head in London
Sky News Australia’s YouTube channel has published more than 9,000 comments mostly celebrating and mocking the shooting of a Black Lives Matter activist in Britain who is fighting for her life.
The racist and violent comments, which could be described as hate speech, appear below a short video news report uploaded on Monday about the activist Sasha Johnson. Johnson remains in a critical condition after sustaining a gunshot wound to her head in an incident in south London.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda Meade</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British & Irish Lions players given first Covid vaccine doses before tour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/british-irish-lions-players-given-coronavirus-jabs-before-tour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/british-irish-lions-players-given-coronavirus-jabs-before-tour"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:19:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[South Africa-bound squad assembled in London
First match of tour scheduled for 3 July in Johannesburg

The British & Irish Lions squad heading to South Africa next month had their first coronavirus vaccine doses during a pre-tour gathering in London on Wednesday.
Along with Great Britain’s Olympic team members, those involved in the Lions tour have had special dispensation from the government to be vaccinated ahead of schedule, with second Covid jabs set to be administered next month during the squad’s planned training camp in Jersey.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German voters’ view of personal wealth causes problems for the left]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/german-voters-view-of-personal-wealth-causes-problems-for-the-left</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/german-voters-view-of-personal-wealth-causes-problems-for-the-left"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:15:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: left-of-centre parties struggle to cut through as survey shows ‘everyone thinks they are middle class’
It is a country with levels of wealth inequality more similar to the US than France, and one where the richest 10% of the population already owned two-thirds of the national wealth before the pandemic further widened the gap.
Yet the inequality of German society and how to fix it is likely to play a minor role in the race to September elections this year, with those parties expected to offer solutions – the centre-left Social Democratic party (SPD) and the leftwing Die Linke – struggling in the polls.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uber agrees historic deal allowing drivers to join GMB union]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/uber-agrees-historic-deal-allowing-drivers-to-join-gmb-union</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/uber-agrees-historic-deal-allowing-drivers-to-join-gmb-union"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:05:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First agreement between a gig economy service and a union will not include Eats delivery riders
Uber is to recognise the GMB trade union in the UK for its private hire drivers, marking the first deal between a union and a gig economy ride-hailing service.
Under the recognition deal, the GMB will have access to drivers’ meeting hubs to help and support them. It will also be able to represent drivers if they lose access to the Uber app, and it will meet quarterly with management to discuss driver issues and concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antonio Conte leaves Inter over plan to sell €80m of players this summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/antonio-conte-leaving-inter-over-plan-to-sell-80m-of-players</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/antonio-conte-leaving-inter-over-plan-to-sell-80m-of-players"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:59:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conte departs weeks after leading club to Serie A title
Simone Inzaghi and Allegri among potential replacements

Antonio Conte has left his job as manager of Internazionale, three and a half weeks after leading the club to their first Serie A title in 11 years.
After talks on Wednesday the former Chelsea manager and the club agreed to part ways, with the 51-year-old receiving a payout of €7m (£6m). He had one year remaining on a contract with a €13m salary.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Romano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belarus president calls backlash against plane incident a ‘planned provocation’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/belarus-president-accuses-west-of-launching-hybrid-modern-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/belarus-president-accuses-west-of-launching-hybrid-modern-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:59:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European countries begin to block flights from Minsk, with flight to Barcelona turned around at Polish border
Alexander Lukashenko has made his first public remarks defending his grounding of a Ryanair flight last week, accusing the west of launching a “hybrid modern war” against Minsk and calling the backlash over the incident a “planned provocation”.
Addressing a session of parliament, Lukashenko also appeared to suggest the plane could have been shot down because it was flying over a nuclear power plant when it was diverted by the Belarusian government, which appeared to have concocted a bomb threat and scrambled a Mig-29 to ensure the plane landed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweden’s gun violence rate has soared due to gangs, report says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/fatal-shootings-have-risen-in-sweden-despite-fall-across-europe-report-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/fatal-shootings-have-risen-in-sweden-despite-fall-across-europe-report-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:47:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Of 22 European countries analysed, only Sweden had recorded a significant rise in deaths since 2000
Sweden is the only European country where fatal shootings have risen significantly since 2000, leaping from one of the lowest rates of gun violence on the continent to one of the highest in less than a decade, a report has found.
The report, by the Swedish national council for crime prevention (BRA), said the Scandinavian country had overtaken Italy and eastern European countries primarily because of the violent activities of organised criminal gangs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley Europe correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a GraphQL API Using Laravel]]></title>
        <id>60abc59d11ffb70827ef6304</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-graphql-api-using-laravel/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll walk you through how to set up your own GraphQL API using PHP and Laravel. Two years ago, I started working professionally as a backend developer. And I was very intimidated by all the technology I didn't yet know. Words like Docker, Kubernetes, and GraphQL seemed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis could trigger sewage surge in English rivers, MPs told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/climate-crisis-sewage-discharge-english-rivers-environment-investment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/climate-crisis-sewage-discharge-english-rivers-environment-investment"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:31:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Environmental body calls for investment in nature-based solutions to stem rise in discharge
There will be a rise in the scale of sewage discharge into rivers and waterways due to extreme weather events as a result of the climate crisis, MPs have been told.
Nature-based solutions must be a top priority for the government and the water regulator, Ofwat, when it comes to water companies’ investment over the coming decades, MPs heard. By 2050, the English sewerage system would face a 55% increase in water flowing through the network as a result of increased urbanisation and the removal of natural surfaces, which help water drain away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Koepka v DeChambeau: The deliciously petty spat that could save golf]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/brooks-koepka-bryson-dechambeau-golf-argument-video-pga-championship</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/brooks-koepka-bryson-dechambeau-golf-argument-video-pga-championship"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:19:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The mundanity underpinning the Brooks Koepka-Bryson DeChambeau feud puts a fine point on just why golf rivalries can be so entertaining
The latest installment in the long-simmering feud between Brooks Koepka and Bryson DeChambeau came to pass on Monday night when a leaked snippet from an interview with Koepka at last week’s PGA Championship surfaced and quickly went viral.
In the 45-second clip, Koepka, the famously nonchalant four-time major champion, is starting to respond to an anodyne question from Golf Channel’s Todd Lewis after Friday’s second round before abruptly stopping short. DeChambeau, who’s managed to supplant Patrick Reed as the sport’s biggest heel, ambles first into his eyeline then behind him through the background of the shot, clickety-clacking down the sidewalk in his metal spikes and goofy newsboy cap while yammering away in full throat to his caddy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bryan Armen Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot tub health kick: why a long bath is almost as good for you as a long run]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/hot-tub-health-kick-why-a-long-bath-is-almost-as-good-for-you-as-a-long-run</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/hot-tub-health-kick-why-a-long-bath-is-almost-as-good-for-you-as-a-long-run"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:18:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have discovered that prolonged immersion in a piping hot bath has many of the same medical benefits as aerobic exercise
Name: Hot baths.
Age: First used by the ancient Egyptians 4,000 years ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anger over British teachers’ response to pro-Palestine protests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/26/anger-over-british-teachers-response-to-pro-palestine-protests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/26/anger-over-british-teachers-response-to-pro-palestine-protests"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:12:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leeds headteacher forced to apologise after saying Palestinian flag was seen as ‘call to arms’
The recent Middle East conflict has prompted a wave of pro-Palestine protests in British schools and controversy over the staff response, with pupils being accused of antisemitism and one headteacher describing the Palestinian flag as a “call to arms”.
Mike Roper, the headteacher of Allerton Grange high school in Leeds, was forced to apologise after he claimed in an assembly that some people saw the flag as a “symbol of antisemitism”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nazia Parveen Community affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paulo Mendes da Rocha obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/paulo-mendes-da-rocha-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/paulo-mendes-da-rocha-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:11:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the greats of Brazilian modernist architecture whose tough, often austere concrete buildings were conceived as public places
Hovering like a wafer-thin concrete halo, held aloft by six chiselled triangular blades, the Paulistano Athletic Club was a futuristic arrival to the Jardim América quarter of São Paulo when it opened in 1958. The concrete blades sprang from an elevated platform, each one resting on an impossibly minimal edge, rising to a point where pairs of taut cables held a steel roof shell in tension, suspended above the gymnasium space below. The ground level was kept open, designed as a free public plane, allowing views into the action from all around.
The architect of this bold balancing act was Paulo Mendes da Rocha, who has died aged 92, after a 60-year career as one of the greats of Brazilian modernism. The athletic club, which catapulted him to national prominence at the age of 30, exemplified the approach he would pursue for the coming decades: it was a feat of concrete acrobatics on a heroic scale, driven by a singular idea, and conceived as a truly public place.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Wainwright</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson under pressure from Biden and activists in run-up to G7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/boris-johnson-under-pressure-from-biden-and-activists-in-run-up-to-g7</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/boris-johnson-under-pressure-from-biden-and-activists-in-run-up-to-g7"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:58:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US pushing UK hard over minimum corporate tax and swift action on global Covid vaccinations
Boris Johnson is facing mounting pressure from Joe Biden and grassroots activists to be bolder at next month’s G7 summit amid signs that rows over vaccines and tax will dominate what the prime minister hoped would be a low-key event.
The chancellor, Rishi Sunak, kicks off two weeks of intense international diplomacy ahead of the June gathering of the leaders of major western economies in Cornwall when he hosts a virtual meeting of finance ministers and central bank governors on Friday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belarus regime uses video confessions as a tool to silence dissent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/belarus-regime-uses-video-confessions-tool-silence-dissent-raman-pratasevich</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/belarus-regime-uses-video-confessions-tool-silence-dissent-raman-pratasevich"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:51:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Raman Pratasevich and Sofia Sapega are just the latest to be forced into the widespread tactic
The videos are formulaic: Raman Pratasevich and his girlfriend, Sofia Sapega, each sit alone in front of a camera in a police station and deliver their “confessions” as though a loaded gun is pointed at their heads.
“I’m also the editor of the Telegram channel Black Book of Belarus that publishes personal information about employees of the interior ministry,” said Sapega, quickly repeating a memorised statement in a video released late on Tuesday that could lead to years in jail.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jacob Zuma trial: South Africa’s ex-president denies corruption charges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/jacob-zuma-trial-south-africas-ex-president-denies-corruption-charges</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/jacob-zuma-trial-south-africas-ex-president-denies-corruption-charges"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:48:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zuma accuses lawyers of working ‘to bolster a narrative’ as trial begins over $2.5bn arms deal 
Jacob Zuma, the former president of South Africa, accused prosecutors of seeking to malign a political leader rather than find the truth as he denied charges of corruption at the first major hearing of his trial.
Zuma, 79, faces charges of bribery, fraud, racketeering and money laundering relating to a $2.5bn (£2bn) deal to buy European military hardware to upgrade South Africa’s armed forces in 1999 when he was deputy president.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke in Johannesburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU citizens who miss UK settled status cutoff to lose some free healthcare]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/eu-citizens-who-miss-settled-status-cut-off-will-immediately-lose-free-uk-healthcare</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/eu-citizens-who-miss-settled-status-cut-off-will-immediately-lose-free-uk-healthcare"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:44:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those who miss 30 June deadline will immediately be charged for non-urgent NHS treatment
EU citizens who fail to secure settled status by the 30 June deadline will immediately lose access to free non-urgent NHS healthcare, despite a government pledge to be “extremely understanding” about late applications.
Some details of how swiftly different departments will apply hostile environment policies to EU citizens who have not secured the new post-Brexit immigration status by the cutoff date have emerged in responses to a series of parliamentary questions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Dominic Cummings circus is an indictment of the entire governing class | Aditya Chakrabortty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/dominic-cummings-circus-indictment-governing-class-failures-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/dominic-cummings-circus-indictment-governing-class-failures-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:36:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today’s punch-up obscured how many of the failures that left the UK so fatally exposed to the pandemic still remain
Who better to judge the true significance of Dominic Cummings’ Big Day Out at parliament than Dominic Cummings himself? Not the grave-faced, shaven-headed man we’ve been watching, ladling out his revenge cold, but an earlier incarnation. Before he became chief adviser to Boris Johnson, before he compromised his own government’s lockdown rules by driving the family to Barnard Castle; before all of that, when he was just a guy holed up in a bunker with his blog, composing screeds about Bismarck, he anticipated the absurdity of today’s carnival: “The political-media system,” he wrote in a 2017 post, “actively suppresses thinking about, and focus on, what’s important.”
Westminster demands a diversion and, over the months leading up to this hearing, Cummings has made himself its distractor-in-chief. Ever happy to fatten the beast he only pretends to despise, he has drip-fed journalists poison about his former confidants. And a grateful press hyped up the coming “Domageddon”, describing him as the “terrifying” kamikaze genius prepared to slay the prime minister or, at the very least, detonate Matt Hancock for “lying”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aditya Chakrabortty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good stories and players abound as county cricket seizes rare spotlight | Andy Bull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/good-stories-and-players-abound-as-county-cricket-seizes-rare-spotlight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/good-stories-and-players-abound-as-county-cricket-seizes-rare-spotlight"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:29:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Stevens to Hameed, the County Championship has made the most of a brief hiatus in other forms of the game
Forewarned about the cruelty of April, I was entirely unprepared for the viciousness of May. At times these past few weeks have felt like an elaborate skit, a running bait-and-switch in which we were repeatedly lured outdoors by the promise of sunshine and then hit by a hailstorm when we’d made it halfway around the corner. I’ve spent most of it waiting, for the clouds to go, for the rain to stop, for the summer to come, for lockdown to lift, for this sense of listlessness to shift. In the meantime the County Championship has been a welcome distraction, one consolation of a rather damp and miserable spring.
The championship often feels like something that goes on in the background of summer. When the Test matches are on, it’s a distant birdsong. But it has come into its own these past few weeks. This seems to have happened almost by accident. In his history of the competition, Summer’s Crown, Stephen Chalke compared it to the British constitution. “It emerged in its own haphazard way, and it survived and adapted to the consequences.” The format has “never seemed satisfactory for long, and it has seldom stood on its own feet financially”, Chalke writes. It has lasted 131 years, and has had almost as many iterations.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Bull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Licence to content: Amazon’s MGM takeover gives it access to Bond and beyond]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/amazon-mgm-takeover-james-bond</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/amazon-mgm-takeover-james-bond"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:12:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another worrying step in the monopolisation of entertainment, the internet giant’s $8.45bn splurge is about adding reams of classic Hollywood IP for its film-making arm to feast on

Just over two years ago, the Disney takeover of most of 21st Century Fox created an even bigger monster out of the two existing monsters, and pushed the movie business further towards a de facto monopoly of two or three humongous corporate entities gradually merging together to make a great big amorphous mass, spawning endless content. Now the blobbification process has gone further, with Amazon snapping up MGM for $8.45bn (£5.97bn).
That’s a hefty price, according to some, considering the debt that MGM carries and the fact that MGM’s star property James Bond, the global cash cow that keeps on giving milk, is in fact partly owned by Eon Productions, perhaps the last boutique franchise player in the world. Eon’s right to control every aspect of 007 is fiercely defended by its owners Barbara Broccoli and Michael G Wilson from their handsome offices in Piccadilly (rather like the old MI6 building). The suits at Amazon will have to consult Broccoli and Wilson over everything to do with 007.
There was a time of course when a classic Hollywood studio such as MGM (or Metro Goldwyn Mayer Studios Inc) could be associated with a particular kind of film: in this case, the gorgeous musicals of the golden age. In the last century, they were associated with their talent – “more stars than the heavens” was Louis B Mayer’s boast, and after this era, MGM’s capital would reside in its back catalogue. That’s certainly what Amazon is buying now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[France to impose Covid quarantine on visitors from UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/france-to-impose-covid-quarantine-on-visitors-from-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/france-to-impose-covid-quarantine-on-visitors-from-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:03:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[France joins Germany in restricting travellers from Britain amid fears over spread of variant

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

France will impose a compulsory quarantine on travellers arriving from the UK from next week amid mounting concern over the rapid spread of the coronavirus variant first identified in India, the government has said. 
Clément Beaune, the French Europe minister, said on Wednesday that starting on Monday, travellers arriving from the UK who are not either French nationals or residents will have to demonstrate an essential reason for their journey.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time limit on lab-grown human embryos is relaxed by experts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/26/time-limit-on-lab-grown-human-embryos-is-relaxed-by-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/26/time-limit-on-lab-grown-human-embryos-is-relaxed-by-experts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T15:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International body paves way for key research as it lifts ban on growing embryos beyond 14 days

The ban on growing human embryos in the lab beyond 14 days has been relaxed by an international body of experts, paving the way for research that could help to unpick issues ranging from why recurring miscarriages occur to improving IVF.
The decades-old rule is laid down in the law in a number of countries, including the UK and Australia, and was previously stipulated in guidelines from the International Society for Stem Cell Research (ISSCR). These guidelines set out standards that are used by scientists, journals and research bodies around the world, and can also influence policymakers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Court orders Royal Dutch Shell to cut carbon emissions by 45% by 2030]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/court-orders-royal-dutch-shell-to-cut-carbon-emissions-by-45-by-2030</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/26/court-orders-royal-dutch-shell-to-cut-carbon-emissions-by-45-by-2030"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:48:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oil giant told plans should be brought into line with Paris climate agreement
A court in the Hague has ordered Royal Dutch Shell to cut its global carbon emissions by 45% by the end of 2030 compared with 2019 levels, in a landmark case brought by Friends of the Earth and over 17,000 co-plaintiffs.
The oil giant’s sustainability policy was found to be insufficiently “concrete” by the Dutch court in an unprecedented ruling that will have wide implications for the energy industry and other polluting multinationals.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ear and nostril waxing is exquisitely painful – but just what I needed | Adrian Chiles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/an-ear-and-nostril-waxing-is-exquisitely-painful-but-just-what-i-needed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/an-ear-and-nostril-waxing-is-exquisitely-painful-but-just-what-i-needed"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:46:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was introduced to the joys of male hair removal by a man with a cut-throat razor in 1987. Then last weekend I expanded my horizons

I’ve only ever had three proper cut-throat razor shaves. The first was in Mostar, Bosnia-Herzegovina, in 1987. I had been travelling around Yugoslavia for a month and was in need of a haircut. In a pleasingly antiquated barbershop near the famous old bridge, a nice young woman gave me a brisk, unfussy cut.
As she executed some finishing touches, she asked whether I would care for a shave, too, while I was there. “Why not?” I said, and since neither of us could think of a reason why not, the deal was done. She patted my shoulder and went out the back of the shop saying something along the lines of: “I’ll go and get my grandad.” I thought I must have misheard, until she reappeared with a gentleman who was either her grandfather or great-grandfather. He was plainly the head of this shop’s shaving department. The girl brushed on some shaving cream and disappeared outside for a smoke.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Chiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire breathing and a beach graduation: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/26/fire-breathing-and-beach-graduation-wednesday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/26/fire-breathing-and-beach-graduation-wednesday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:17:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amish girls on holiday at the beach: Dina Litovsky’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/beach-amish-girls-holiday-dina-litovskys-best-photograph</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/beach-amish-girls-holiday-dina-litovskys-best-photograph"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:17:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Seeing them with cellphones was shocking at first – seeing one on a hoverboard felt like science fiction’
I picked this image because it’s one of only a few where I got to know the people in the photograph. I usually take a fly-on-the-wall approach, observing groups at a distance. I’m interested in exploring how people kick back, and most of my projects are connected by leisure and contemporary culture. I did a series called Bachelorette, documenting the cultural ritual of bachelorette parties, as a night of release for women. Another looked at the nightlife in Manhattan’s high-gloss Meatpacking district – a microcosm of sexual politics. But I didn’t interact with the people in those pictures or get their names.
Photographing the Amish vacationing started as an assignment for the New Yorker. They sent me to Florida, where the Amish and Mennonites have been spending their holidays since the 1920s, in a square mile of Sarasota called Pinecraft. I went back four more times, just for myself, renting an apartment in the neighbourhood.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Amy Fleming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Super Mario Bros, Zelda, and Space Invaders with Kaboom.js]]></title>
        <id>60aced0011ffb70827ef6d96</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-mario-zelda-and-space-invaders-with-kaboom-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video course I show you how to build three popular games using the latest game development library for JavaScript called Kaboom.js. This course is exciting for two reasons: First of all, I am going to be introducing a new technology designed especially for game development in JavaScript.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Tories finally tackle Islamophobia in their party? | Miqdaad Versi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/tories-finally-tackle-islamophobia-singh-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/26/tories-finally-tackle-islamophobia-singh-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tick-box approach to the Singh report’s recommendations won’t be enough. A fundamental culture change is needed 
The Singh investigation into racism in the Conservative party provides a historic opportunity for the party to reset its relationship with Muslim communities.
Not because the investigation was a complete whitewash. It wasn’t. There were serious concerns at the start that the investigation was established with restrictive terms of reference that excluded systemic racism, had an adviser who believed the idea of Islamophobia should be “junked”, and selected a peer reviewer who came from a thinktank that devoted an entire anthology to attacking the very idea of Islamophobia. Despite this, the investigation was not entirely toothless. Important recommendations include an overhaul of the complaints process, the reopening of cases that have fallen short of the expected standards and an outreach strategy focusing on meaningful engagement with Muslim communities.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miqdaad Versi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hillsborough families attack ‘ludicrous’ acquittals of police]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/hillsborough-trial-of-former-south-yorkshire-police-officers-collapses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/26/hillsborough-trial-of-former-south-yorkshire-police-officers-collapses"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:49:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two former officers and solicitor accused of perverting course of justice have no case to answer, judge rules
Bereaved Hillsborough disaster families have condemned the “ludicrous” decision to acquit two former South Yorkshire police officers and the force’s former solicitor on charges of perverting the course of justice, bringing to a close their 32-year fight for justice.
Peter Metcalf, 72, a former solicitor for the force, and the then Ch Supt Donald Denton, 83, and DCI Alan Foster, 74, had been accused of changing 68 officers’ statements to withhold important evidence and criticisms of the police operation, and “mask the failings” of the force.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pork pie hats and politics: Coventry pays tribute to 2 Tone legacy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/pork-pie-hats-and-politics-coventry-pays-tribute-to-2-tone-legacy-specials-ska-selecter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/26/pork-pie-hats-and-politics-coventry-pays-tribute-to-2-tone-legacy-specials-ska-selecter"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:45:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major exhibition charts rise of record label that spawned musical and cultural movement in late 1970s
Scrawled on the back of an Embassy cigarette packet are Jerry Dammers’ first attempts to define the 2 Tone “rude boys” after a question from the press in the late 1970s. They like “bluebeat and ska … reggae and soul” and wear “trilbys, bowler and pork pie hats … pinstripe suits, button-down shirts and checked scarves”.
Dammers, who founded the 2 Tone record label in Coventry in 1979, little knew how the description he jotted down would become the image of a hugely popular musical and cultural movement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray Midlands correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Farewell Friday Night Dinner: the joyous Jewish sitcom that became a national treasure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/farewell-friday-night-dinner-the-joyous-jewish-sitcom-that-became-a-national-treasure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/26/farewell-friday-night-dinner-the-joyous-jewish-sitcom-that-became-a-national-treasure"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:10:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This brilliantly odd slice of comedy gold has lit up our screens for 10 years. As its creator announces it has come to an end, we give thanks for all the belly laughs and squirrel gags 

In early 2011, something strange happened. A sitcom centred on the weekly gatherings of the Goodman family debuted on Channel 4, jam-packed with intricate slapstick, infantile pranking and idiosyncratic terms of endearment (“Hello bambinos!”). But it wasn’t merely Friday Night Dinner’s comic language that made it an unexpected joy. Incredibly, the show was the second sitcom about a British Jewish family to arrive on UK screens in the space of six months, after Simon Amstell’s Grandma’s House. Honestly, you wait a lifetime for a show about British Jews and two come along at once.
Yet while Grandma’s House – the bleaker and more awkward of the two – bowed out after two series, Friday Night Dinner kept going. To date, it has had six series and 37 episodes, charming audiences with a chaotic mix of brotherly, practical-joke-based warfare, motherly mollycoddling, stomach-churning condiment consumption (dad Martin) and terrifying social ineptitude (neighbour Jim). This Friday, it celebrates its 10th anniversary with a documentary in which cast members including Tamsin Greig, Paul Ritter, Simon Bird and Tom Rosenthal, plus famous fans, relive the scrapes and squirrel quips that made Friday Night Dinner one of the most treasured comedies in recent memory – and the longest-running Channel 4 sitcom since Peep Show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Aroesti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five arrested after shooting of Sasha Johnson in Peckham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/26/arrests-made-in-relation-to-sasha-johnson-peckham-shooting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/26/arrests-made-in-relation-to-sasha-johnson-peckham-shooting"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:04:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four men and a 17-year-old boy in custody on suspicion of attempted murder 
Five people have been arrested on suspicion of attempted murder in relation to the shooting of the activist Sasha Johnson in Peckham, south London, on Sunday.
The Met police said officers based in Southwark and Lambeth stopped a 17-year-old on Tuesday and arrested him on suspicion of possession of an offensive weapon and possession with intent to supply class A drugs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It resembled a chinchilla’: 10 men who changed their hair radically in lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/10-men-changed-hair-radically-in-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/10-men-changed-hair-radically-in-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T12:48:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the film extra who now gets parts as wizards rather than lawyers to the office workers who just decided to go for it, readers who have tried something new with their locks explain why
Before the pandemic, my personal image was dictated by the constraints of corporate office culture, and I always felt tense. But while furloughed, as I was for most of the last year and a half, I found myself with a lot of time to relax, go for walks, listen to jazz and spend more time in the kitchen experimenting with vegetables. I realised that my hair was changing, too, and there was no pressure from anyone to get it cut. The length of my hair became symbolic of my new ability to appreciate the simple things in life. I’ve retrained, and my capacity for self-expression has multiplied. I have so many more options when I style it in the morning. Will, plumber, Bristol
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock should have been sacked for lying, says Dominic Cummings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/matt-hancock-should-be-sacked-for-lying-says-dominic-cummings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/26/matt-hancock-should-be-sacked-for-lying-says-dominic-cummings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T12:42:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former No 10 aide accuses health secretary of ‘criminal’ behaviour, in string of incendiary allegations

See all our coronavirus coverage

Dominic Cummings said he called for Matt Hancock to be sacked “almost every day” due to alleged “criminal” behaviour but claimed Boris Johnson was advised to retain the health secretary because “he’s the person you fire when an inquiry comes along”.
The prime minister’s former top adviser levelled incendiary allegations at the health secretary, including that he held back tests and lied to the public and fellow ministers. No 10 said the prime minister retained “full confidence” in Hancock.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foakes’ dressing-room slip lets Billings and Hameed into England Test squad]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/ben-foakes-slip-in-dressing-room-lets-sam-billings-and-haseeb-hameed-into-england-cricket-test-squad</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/26/ben-foakes-slip-in-dressing-room-lets-sam-billings-and-haseeb-hameed-into-england-cricket-test-squad"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T12:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Foakes tears hamstring after accident in Surrey dressing room
Jofra Archer begins rehabilitation after elbow surgery

Haseeb Hameed and the uncapped Sam Billings have been called up to England’s Test squad for the upcoming series against New Zealand after Ben Foakes tore his hamstring when slipping on the dressing room floor at the Oval while wearing socks.
Foakes was due to keep wicket in the absence of the rested Jos Buttler but the freak injury suffered following Surrey’s draw at home to Middlesex means Gloucestershire’s James Bracey will make his Test debut behind the stumps at Lord’s next week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Jordan’s closest allies plot to unseat its king?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/did-jordans-closest-allies-plot-to-unseat-its-king</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/did-jordans-closest-allies-plot-to-unseat-its-king"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T11:45:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alleged sedition and a royal family feud may have been driven by a broader plan to reshape the Middle East 
The phone call that shook the Jordanian government came in the second week of March this year. On the line to the General Intelligence Directorate (GID) in Amman was the US Embassy, seeking an urgent meeting about a matter of national importance. The kingdom’s spies were startled. Danger was brewing on the home front, they were told, and could soon pose a threat to the throne.
Within hours, the GID had turned its full array of resources towards one of the country’s most senior royals, Prince Hamzah bin Hussein, a former crown prince and half-brother of the king, whom the Americans suspected was sowing dissent and had begun rallying supporters. By early April, officials had placed Hamzah under house arrest and publicly accused the former heir and two close aides of plotting to unseat King Abdullah.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov in Amman and Michael Safi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU citizens win right to access personal data held by Home Office]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/26/eu-citizens-win-right-access-personal-data-held-home-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/26/eu-citizens-win-right-access-personal-data-held-home-office"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T11:24:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Appeal court ruling means people denied settled status or immigration visas can see records used in the case
EU citizens have won the right to get full access to records about them held by the Home Office or any other body after a legal battle by campaigners.
Three judges at the court of appeal unanimously overturned an earlier high court decision that their case had no legal merit and ruled the Data Protection Act 2018 (DPA) unlawfully denied them access to their data through an “immigration exemption” clause.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s cooler to hang Lennon’s guitar than a Picasso’: pop culture wins out at auctions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/26/its-cooler-to-hang-lennons-guitar-than-a-picasso-pop-culture-wins-out-at-auctions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/26/its-cooler-to-hang-lennons-guitar-than-a-picasso-pop-culture-wins-out-at-auctions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T11:21:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sales of items from celebrities such as Janet Jackson and K-poppers BTS are trending – and reframing what goes under the hammer
Is celebrity merchandise the new Monet? Auction houses are in flux, with more and more pop culture items being sold under the hammer for six and seven-figure sums.
Last month, Julien’s Auctions in Beverly Hills hosted a three-day auction of Janet Jackson’s personal belongings, including some of her most iconic stage outfits. Buyers included Kim Kardashian, who snagged Jackson’s outfit from the music video for her 1993 classic If for $25,000 (£18,000) and, on Instagram, said she was “such a fan” of the singer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to cook the perfect chicken with 40 cloves of garlic – recipe | Felicity Cloake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/26/perfect-chicken-40-cloves-garlic-recipe-felicity-cloake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/26/perfect-chicken-40-cloves-garlic-recipe-felicity-cloake"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T11:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our resident perfectionist takes on the classic French dish of garlic-flavoured chicken in garlic sauce, which is nowhere near as garlicky as you might imagine
Flicking through my parents’ copy of Nigel Slater’s Real Food as an impressionable teenager, one impossibly daring recipe leapt out: chicken with 40 cloves of garlic may have already been a bit old hat in Nigella Lawson’s childhood, but in the provinces, such a quantity still seemed, as Lawson notes, “somehow dangerously excessive”. An older colleague at my first summer job always wrinkled her nose if I’d as much as sniffed a clove the night before, so 40 would probably have moved her to tears. (Unsurprisingly, I never plucked up the courage to test her.)
The idea is often described as Provençal, though Elizabeth David makes reference to similar dishes from both the Dauphiné, slightly farther north, and the Béarn, in the south-west of France, so, in the absence of firm evidence to the contrary, it seems more than likely that chicken was prepared with large amounts of garlic wherever large quantities of garlic were grown. The elevation of that bulb to star turn seems to have occurred in the US, where in 1954 James Beard published the first recipe calling for the now sacrosanct 40 cloves – which, as Betty Trussell points out, was at that point tantamount to joining the Communist party – and sparked far more than 40 imitations. It pops up in Gourmet magazine, the New York Times and the Silver Palate Cookbook before crossing the Atlantic to find favour with the Galloping Gourmet, Graham Kerr, and Keith Floyd, to name just two. Almost everyone has their own take, and I’m sure they’re all delicious, but who does it best?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felicity Cloake</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Councils in Covid hotspots criticise advice to ‘minimise’ travel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/councils-in-covid-hotspots-criticise-advice-to-minimise-travel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/councils-in-covid-hotspots-criticise-advice-to-minimise-travel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T10:47:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local leaders say latest guidance – updated following criticism – was not what was agreed at meeting on Tuesday

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers are facing fresh opposition from local authorities over updated travel advice urging people to minimise travel to areas with higher coronavirus cases.
The government revised its official guidance on Tuesday following criticism that it had introduced a lockdown “by stealth” by urging people to avoid all but essential travel to eight Covid hotspots in England.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Halliday North of England corespondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May design news: skateboards, stations and sculpture]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/may-design-news-skateboards-stations-and-sculpture</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/may-design-news-skateboards-stations-and-sculpture"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T10:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British railways get a makeover, the joy of knitting and 10 years of the Hepworth Wakefield 
Building for the future should be the aim of all good design. This month’s news stories have some great examples of architects and creatives trying to do just this. Charitable education initiative Skateistan is building safe places for children to learn and have fun in Afghanistan, South Africa and Thailand in the hope of reaching some of the world’s most vulnerable children. Meanwhile, creatives from six continents are exhibiting designs offering solutions to the challenges of our times at the London Design Biennale. Very different projects, both with the aim of making the world better.
To receive more stories about art, architecture, design and sustainable living, sign up to the monthly Design Newsletter here
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sex-mad and spectacular: 17 incredible facts about cicadas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/sex-mad-and-spectacular-17-incredible-facts-about-cicadas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/sex-mad-and-spectacular-17-incredible-facts-about-cicadas"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T10:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once every 17 years, trillions of cicadas emerge from beneath the ground in the US. They taste like tinned asparagus, are sometimes attracted to power tools – and can number 1.3m an acre

Brood X is upon us. Across the US billions, if not trillions of cicadas have emerged from below the ground, a biblical plague that occurs every 17 years. Gene Kritsky wouldn’t miss it. “This is special,” he says. An entomologist at Mount St Joseph University in Cincinnati, Kritsky has studied periodical cicadas for nearly 40 years. Brood X, the subject of three of his books, holds a particular place in his heart. In the middle of back-to-back interviews during his busiest professional period since 2004 (“It happens, every 17 years”), he found time to share his favourite facts with us.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elle Hunt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what are your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T09:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This bank holiday weekend will be the first opportunity for many to visit loved ones who live further away. We’d like to hear about your plans
What were your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend – the first opportunity many of us have had to visit grandparents and loved ones who live further away?
What impact have these new No-Go zones had on your arrangements: are you going to adapt or abandon your visits – or are you going ahead, as planned?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italian cable car brakes ‘tampered with’, say prosecutors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/italian-cable-car-brakes-tampered-with-say-prosecutors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/italian-cable-car-brakes-tampered-with-say-prosecutors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T08:37:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crash investigators say emergency brakes had been deactivated to avoid disruptions to service

The emergency brakes on a cable car that crashed in northern Italy on Sunday, killing 14 people, had been “tampered with”, prosecutors said as three people were arrested on charges of suspected involuntary manslaughter and negligence.
The three, including the owner of the firm that manages the Stresa-Mottarone aerial tramway near Lake Maggiore in the Piedmont region, are alleged to have made a “conscious gesture” by “tampering” with the emergency brakes in order to “avoid disruptions” to the cable car service, Ansa reported, citing the chief public prosecutor, Olimpia Bossi.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida in Rome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May’s super flower moon lights up the night skies – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/26/mays-super-flower-moon-lights-up-the-night-skies-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/26/mays-super-flower-moon-lights-up-the-night-skies-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T07:14:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The May full moon, known as the flower moon, coincided with it being at its closest to the Earth during its orbit, making it appear larger and brighter. May’s supermoon also coincides with a lunar eclipse in which the moon will turn red, but that will be visible only in parts of South America, Australia and south-east Asia. This celestial incident, known as super flower blood moon, is the only full lunar eclipse of this year

Here’s how to take a good picture of the full supermoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My body dysmorphia means I can’t let go and enjoy sex]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/my-body-dysmorphia-means-i-cant-let-go-and-enjoy-sex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/my-body-dysmorphia-means-i-cant-let-go-and-enjoy-sex"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T07:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hate having someone focus on me in bed and question if I’m enjoying it. I’m more confident if I’ve been drinking, but still not enough
I’m nearly 37, and have never had a fulfilling sex life. I can’t let go, because of my severe body dysmorphia and some unresolved issues from my childhood. I hate having someone focus on me, my breathing and the lack of sound I make, as well as questioning if I’m enjoying it. It makes me even less likely to relax and let go. If I were more confident in myself, my sex drive would be higher; I’d be more open-minded and experimental – I know exactly what I like. I’m more confident if I’ve been drinking, but still not enough. I need to get over this before it’s too late. I cause damage in my relationships, and it isn’t helped by my inability to communicate. I am very guarded and protective of myself.
You know exactly what your issues are, and are wonderfully aware and analytic about your triggers and responses – yet you seem to think you can continue in the same vein and miraculously have a different result. Take action now to seek treatment for all the things you have identified – body dysmorphia and unresolved childhood issues – and possibly generalised anxiety. These things are all treatable. Seek good therapy with someone you respect and trust, and – when appropriate – add sex therapy. Using alcohol to tolerate sex creates its own set of problems. You deserve to feel better, to have better sex and better relationships, not to mention an overall better quality of life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Stephenson Connolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Highway of death’: animals pay ultimate price on Brazil’s most dangerous road for wildlife]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/highway-of-death-animals-pay-ultimate-price-on-brazils-most-dangerous-road-for-wildlife-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/highway-of-death-animals-pay-ultimate-price-on-brazils-most-dangerous-road-for-wildlife-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:29:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 3,000 animals die on the country’s BR-262 road each year, but legal action by activists is forcing authorities to take notice
The last time Schwartz’s tracking monitor registered his location, he was standing at the edge of the “highway of death”. A massive male giant anteater, he was roaming his habitat in the Brazilian Cerrado – a vast tropical savanna that neighbours the world’s largest tropical wetland, the Pantanal – when he disappeared next to the federal highway officially known as the BR-262. No more GPS datapoints, collected every 20 minutes, were recorded. 
But biologists and veterinarians from the Institute for the Conservation of Wild Animals’ (ICAS) Anteaters and Highways Project, who had placed the collar on him, were sure of what happened.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jill Langlois</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The war against snails: can gardeners ever win?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/war-against-snails-can-gardeners-ever-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/war-against-snails-can-gardeners-ever-win"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the past few weeks, the slugs and snails have risen in British gardens – and they are hungry. Before you reach for the shovel or pellets, experts suggest some other options
If there is anything likely to send even the most mild-mannered gardener on a murderous rampage, it is waking one morning to find the lettuce has been shredded and the carefully nurtured young plants have been razed overnight. In the past few weeks, the slugs and snails have risen – and they are hungry. It’s not that there are more than usual this year – experts don’t think that’s the case – but after a cold and dry April, perhaps the ones that are emerging are doing so with a vengeance and heading for the hostas. Go out at dusk with a torch, particularly if it has been raining. “It’s quite shocking what you find sometimes,” says Charles Dowding, an organic gardener and author. “You suddenly see these swarms of slugs everywhere.”
It is tempting to view gastropods as the enemy, and to start a war that can include search and destroy techniques alongside biological weapons and traps. Less extreme options include gently relocating them, or surrounding their victims with protective barriers. But what is clear is that for most gardeners doing nothing is not an option: in its annual pest ranking, the Royal Horticultural Society (RHS) found that slugs and snails were again gardeners’ biggest foe, after sliding down the chart in recent years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emine Saner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave front: thought-provoking art on England’s south-east coast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/waterfronts-exhibition-englands-creative-coast-art-sculpture-project</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/waterfronts-exhibition-englands-creative-coast-art-sculpture-project"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new Waterfronts exhibition – part of the England’s Creative Coast project – brings contemporary sculpture to seaside towns to attract, and challenge, visitors
I’m escaping a downpour in the Margate shelter where TS Eliot sat in 1921 scribbling The Waste Land. I’m not the only one: holidaying families huddle in waterproofs, wet dogs shake, tinny music emanates from smartphones, and a boy skips rhythmically with a rope. All the while the rain lashes the low-tide sand beyond.
I’m here to see the town’s newest public artwork, April is the Cruellest Month, its title inspired by Eliot’s poem. Positioned next to the shelter, it’s a lifesize sculpture of Daniel Taylor, a soldier who served in Iraq, by Chicago-based artist Michael Rakowitz.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Emms</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California dreams: the natural wonders of Wynn Bullock – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/26/california-dreams-the-natural-wonders-of-wynn-bullock-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/26/california-dreams-the-natural-wonders-of-wynn-bullock-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new exhibition collects the stunning black and white photography Bullock took of his family and their surroundings in Monterey, Big Sur and beyond
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese Communist party’s 100th anniversary preparations – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/26/chinese-communist-partys-100th-anniversary-preparations-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/may/26/chinese-communist-partys-100th-anniversary-preparations-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chinese Communist party is promoting a campaign to study its history before the 100th anniversary in July. ‘Red’ tourism to historically significant hotspots like Yan’an and Xibaipo has increased accordingly
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: do you have multiple chronic pain conditions?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/26/tell-us-do-you-have-multiple-chronic-pain-conditions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/26/tell-us-do-you-have-multiple-chronic-pain-conditions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T05:07:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you been diagnosed with long Covid, endometriosis, fibromyalgia, migraine, ME/CFS or another chronic pain condition? We’d like to hear from you
A person with a chronic pain condition can sometimes start to accumulate more than one, which is known as a chronic overlapping pain condition.
As part of a project on long Covid and other chronic conditions, we would like to hear from individuals about their experience seeking treatment for them. What overlapping conditions do you have? If you’ve been diagnosed with long Covid, did you have any pre-existing chronic pain conditions? Does your healthcare practitioner treat one or all conditions?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grace Spence Green: the medical student who was paralysed by a falling man – and found new purpose]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/26/grace-spence-green-the-medical-student-who-was-paralysed-by-a-falling-man-and-found-new-purpose</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/26/grace-spence-green-the-medical-student-who-was-paralysed-by-a-falling-man-and-found-new-purpose"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T05:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Her life changed instantly when she was crushed at a shopping centre. But through radical acceptance she gained friends, greater empathy and a passion for changing people’s perspectives
It helps to think of it as the day she saved someone else’s life. That it has brought Grace Spence Green many other positives – increased empathy, good friends, a new perspective – is what she thinks about often, even if she also describes it as “the most traumatic day of my life”.
On an October afternoon in 2018, she was walking through Westfield shopping centre in east London at the precise moment a man three floors up decided to jump. He landed on Spence Green, breaking her back, injuring her spinal cord and fracturing her neck. It was surreal, she says, to wake up “when I didn’t think I was asleep”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emine Saner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis inflicting huge ‘hidden costs’ on mental health]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/climate-crisis-inflicting-huge-hidden-costs-mental-health</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/26/climate-crisis-inflicting-huge-hidden-costs-mental-health"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T05:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vicious circle of climate impacts, trauma and depression must be broken, say scientists
The climate crisis is damaging the mental health of hundreds of millions of people around the world but the huge costs are hidden, scientists have warned.
Heatwaves are increasing rates of suicide, extreme weather such as floods and wildfires are leaving victims traumatised, and loss of food security, homes and livelihoods is resulting in stress and depression. Anxiety about the future is also harming people’s mental health, especially the young, the scientists said in a report.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The sex-toy stuff would not fly today’ – the mag that gripped ‘lesbian mecca’ San Francisco]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/sex-toy-lesbian-mecca-franco-stevens-curve-magazine-ahead-documentary-san-francisco</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/26/sex-toy-lesbian-mecca-franco-stevens-curve-magazine-ahead-documentary-san-francisco"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T05:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three decades ago, Franco Stevens turned a win at the horses into a glossy lesbian mag. As Curve’s astonishing story hits cinemas, she relives a heady time of sex clubs, ‘leather days’ and topless staff
In 1991, Franco Stevens was 23, broke and working in an LGBT bookshop in San Francisco. She thought the world needed a glossy lesbian magazine, but she didn’t have the money to launch one. So she took out 12 credit cards, borrowed the maximum on each, then gambled it all on a horse race. The horse came in. She took the money and put it on another horse, which also won, and then another, which did the same. With her winnings, she set up Deneuve.
“I almost felt like, ‘Well, if this is meant to be, it will happen’,” she says, from her home in the city’s Bay area. She lives with her wife, their two sons of college age, and a younger boy whom they call “a son of the heart”, who splits his time between their house and “his biological home”. Stevens is in her 50s, bright and sharp, and seems like the kind of person who quietly gets a lot of things done. “I mean, I wasn’t going into it completely blind. I grew up with horse racing, so I know this business from a different angle.” Plus she had the recklessness of youth. “I just felt like, I’ve lived in my car, I’ve had nothing to eat – if it’s meant to be, it will be. And my bankruptcy would be off my record by the time I was 30. So it seemed like everything lined up.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Mob boss’ Assad’s dynasty tightens grip over husk of Syria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/bashar-al-assad-tightens-grip-on-power-as-syria-goes-to-polls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/26/bashar-al-assad-tightens-grip-on-power-as-syria-goes-to-polls"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T04:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Country’s emergence as a mafia state leaves today’s election result in little doubt
Tyrant, war criminal, mob boss or, to his loyalists, their shrewd saviour: views about Bashar al-Assad rarely fall in between. As the Syrian leader faces a presidential poll on Wednesday – the result a foregone conclusion – a truer test of the authority he wields across a broken country has taken shape away from the political banners and faux campaigning.
In battered towns and villages, ravaged by a decade of savagery, the now veteran president has been clawing back losses, consolidating himself as the only figure who could plot a course from the ruins of the region’s most devastating modern conflict. Slowly, over the past year, Assad and his extended family have been shoring up their influence. Seldom seen during much of the crisis, he has become a fixture in what remains of Syria’s industrial heartland, visiting factories, pressing employees on their hardships, and hosting delegations with an ease few observed at the height of the fighting.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Britain becoming a hostile environment for EU citizens? | Podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T02:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid travel restrictions begin to be lifted, a new, far less welcoming post-Brexit attitude is greeting EU citizens at the UK border 
EU citizens living and working in the UK are being met with suspicion and in some cases refused entry at the UK border for the first time in their lives, after the implementation of new post-Brexit rules and the lifting of Covid travel restrictions. 
Chloe, a pastry chef from Denmark, tells Anushka Asthana that, because she could not produce a return ticket, she was denied entry at Calais to the UK recently and forced to make the long drive back to Denmark. It is becoming a familiar story, with other EU citizens reporting hostility from officials and some being held at immigration detention centres. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rafael Behr; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep Calm and Hack The Box – Valentine]]></title>
        <id>60ac3a2711ffb70827ef6aec</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/keep-calm-and-hack-the-box-valentine/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T22:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walkthrough for Hack The Box Valentine machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use React-Hook-Form to Build Beautiful Forms with Chakra UI]]></title>
        <id>60a93b0011ffb70827ef5b0d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-react-hook-form-with-chakra-ui/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T20:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In HTML, it’s the default behavior for forms to redirect to a new page whenever they're submitted. So in order to provide dynamic functionality, React uses a strategy called controlled components. If you have recently gone through a React course, you probably didn't like this part, because there are]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Outback camel trek: one woman’s 5,000km journey across Australia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/gallery/2021/may/26/outback-camel-trek-one-womans-5000km-journey-across-australia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/gallery/2021/may/26/outback-camel-trek-one-womans-5000km-journey-across-australia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T17:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After working with camels for five years, 32-year-old Sophie Matterson decided to embark on an epic trek across Australia, with nothing but the animals she had come to love for company. She trained five of them to carry her provisions before beginning a 5,000km coast-to-coast walk from Australia’s western-most point in Shark Bay, Western Australia, to the eastern-most point in Byron Bay, New South Wales
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brook Mitchell for Getty Images</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Best Practices for New Developers – How to Create Portfolio-Worthy Work]]></title>
        <id>608706aedd38b9088c2c012c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-design-best-practices-for-new-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a beginner developer, it can be difficult to find ways to use your limited knowledge to support yourself. And at the same time, you won't be able to hone your skills if you aren't using them full time.  It's a precarious spot that I remember being in when]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences of the UK adult social care system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/25/tell-us-about-your-experiences-of-the-uk-adult-social-care-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/25/tell-us-about-your-experiences-of-the-uk-adult-social-care-system"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T16:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from you or the person you care for about your experiences of adult social care in the UK
The government has persistently refused to set out plans to reform the funding of adult social care, despite repeated promises.
In the meantime, almost nine out of 10 local authorities in England expect to make cuts in adult social care services this year, 2021-22. As the Kings Fund recently put it, while we wait for funding reforms “more families are being failed every day.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: do you live in a Covid hotspot affected by the variant from India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking to speak with people who have had to change their plans due to new travel advice about hotspots in England
New travel advice urging people not to travel in or out of Covid hotspots in England affected by the variant first identified in India has been released, but not announced by the government. Eight areas are affected including Bedford, Blackburn and Darwen, Bolton, Burnley, Kirklees, Leicester, Hounslow, and North Tyneside.
We are looking to speak with people in England who have been affected by the B.1.617.2 variant, and who have had to change their plans or behaviour due to the new advice.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two lives changed by the death of George Floyd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/25/two-lives-changed-by-the-death-of-george-floyd-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/25/two-lives-changed-by-the-death-of-george-floyd-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T02:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year ago, the murder of George Floyd caused outrage in Minneapolis – and kicked off a protest movement that spread across the world. How do the young Black people at the heart of the story live with his legacy?
A year after George Floyd was murdered, the movement instigated by his death has spread across the US and the world, but Black people in Minneapolis are still living with the emotional fallout from that day. Anushka Asthana speaks to Amudalat Ajasa, who was still a student when she heard the news and marched in protest against police brutality against Black people before becoming a Guardian contributor earlier this year. Amudalat looks back on how the crisis has changed her sense of her city and why she felt compelled to document the movement as it took shape.
They also discuss Amudalat’s interview with Chris Martin, the 19-year-old Black man who sold George Floyd a packet of cigarettes and then watched in disbelief as he died on the sidewalk outside. He told how he wrestled with a sense of guilt over his decision to report that the $20 bill Floyd used to pay might be fake, and reflected on how the guilty verdicts after he testified at Derek Chauvin’s trial helped him understand he bore no responsibility.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Amudalat Ajasa; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive produced by Archie Bland and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Node Environment Variables with a DotEnv File for Node.js and npm]]></title>
        <id>60abc6d011ffb70827ef630f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-node-environment-variables-with-a-dotenv-file-for-node-js-and-npm/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T00:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Environment variables are variables that are set outside of a program, often through a cloud provider or operating system.  In Node, environment variables are a great way to securely and conveniently configure things that don't change often, like URLs, authentication keys, and passwords. How to Create Environment VariablesEnvironment variables are]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep Calm and Hack The Box – Nibbles]]></title>
        <id>60626dc29618b008528a9589</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/keep-calm-and-hack-the-box-nibbles/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T00:20:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walkthrough for Hack The Box Nibbles machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[proxy-www]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341153</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/justjavac/proxy-www"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T19:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like a good trick. What if… a URL was…  a promise… that fetched said URL?
www.codepen.io.then((response) ={
  console.log(response);
});
That’s what @justjavac did with JavaScript Proxys. A clever trick, that. Don’t @ me about the practicality. Trick…
The post proxy-www appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340626</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wrangling-control-over-pdfs-with-the-adobe-pdf-embed-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T13:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By our last estimate, there are now more PDFs in the world than atoms in the universe (not verified by outside sources) so chances are, from time to time, you’re going to run into a PDF document or two. Browsers …
The post Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raymond Camden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic scam artists making millions during lockdown – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/24/the-pandemic-scam-artists-making-millions-during-lockdownn-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/24/the-pandemic-scam-artists-making-millions-during-lockdownn-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T02:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Rose got an email about a missed parcel, she thought nothing of arranging a new delivery – a mistake that would ultimately cost her thousands. The Guardian’s money editor, Hilary Osborne, reveals the scale of a lucrative new scam

Email and text frauds are nothing new – but with a boom in online shopping during the coronavirus crisis, their anonymous perpetrators have hit on a lucrative twist. Rachel Humphreys hears from Rose, who thought little of filling out a web form to arrange the redelivery of a pot of face cream and set off a chain of events that would wind up with a fraudster emptying her bank account. 

Rachel also speaks to Hilary Osborne, the Guardian’s money and consumer editor, who has been investigating the scale of the new wave of coronavirus scams and hearing from readers whose lives have been turned upside down – through the loss of their savings, but also a sense of shame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Hilary Osborne; produced by Ned Carter Miles and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG) From Scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn CSS!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340933</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/learn/css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:51:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ooo look at this mighty SEO flex from Google: Learn CSS! Well deserved — this is great content. Twenty-three chapters taking you through all the fundamentals of CSS with extra content, like relevant podcasts, interactive examples, and even quizzes to …
The post Learn CSS! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340715</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/can-we-create-a-resize-hack-with-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you follow new developments in CSS, you’ve likely heard of the impending arrival of container queries. We’re going to look at the basics here, but if you’d like another look, check out Una’s “Next Gen CSS: @container” article. …
The post Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jhey Tompkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fit-content and fit-content()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340897</id>
        <link href="https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2021/04/fitcontent_and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s some hardcore deep-dive CSS nerdery from PPK. If you can wrap your mind around min-content (the smallest an element can be based on the content it contains) and max-content (the largest the content of an element can push it) …
The post fit-content and fit-content() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>