<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-20T00:35:10.524Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-20T00:35:10.524Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stench of death pervades rural India as Ganges swells with Covid victims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/stench-death-pervades-rural-india-ganges-swells-covid-victims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/stench-death-pervades-rural-india-ganges-swells-covid-victims"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T00:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stigma and cost of wood leave families with no choice but to immerse their dead in river 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

There was a time before when the Ganges was “swollen with dead bodies”.
In 1918, when the great flu pandemic swept through India and killed an estimated 18 million people, the water of this river – upon which so many lives depended – was filled with the stench of death.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen and Saurabh Sharma in Ghazipur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US House votes to create 9/11-style commission to investigate capitol attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/us-house-capitol-attack-commission-vote</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/us-house-capitol-attack-commission-vote"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:58:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vote falls largely along party lines with 35 Republicans joining Democrats to pass the bill, which still faces hurdles in the Senate
The House of Representatives has voted in favor of a bill that would create a 9/11-style commission to investigate the deadly attack on the Capitol in January.
The vote fell largely along party lines, with 35 Republicans joining Democrats in passing the measure, while 175 Republicans voted against, aligning themselves with former president Donald Trump, who was impeached by th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joan E Greve in Washington and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Korea’s balancing act will test Biden’s plan to get tough with China]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/south-korea-balancing-act-test-biden-plan-get-tough-china</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/south-korea-balancing-act-test-biden-plan-get-tough-china"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:44:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Seoul’s navigation of geopolitical landscape in east Asia hints at limits of united front with US
When the South Korean president goes to Washington DC on Friday, his discussions with Joe Biden about China will test the limits of the US president’s rhetoric to “work with [its] allies to hold China accountable”. It will also exhibit the dilemma faced by middle-sized powers such as South Korea.
The White House spokesperson, Jen Psaki, said last month that Moon Jae-in’s visit “will highlight the iron…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni China affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340731</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Public Beta of the Notion API dropped! Woot! Here’s their guide. I’ve been a Notion user and fan for a long time, for both personal and professional team use. They even sponsored a few videos around here a …
The post Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fatal attraction: rare corpse flower draws hundreds of onlookers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/corpse-flower-san-francisco-bay-area</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/corpse-flower-san-francisco-bay-area"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:16:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A San Francisco Bay Area nursery owner showcased the giant blooming flower to neighbors at an abandoned gas station
More than 1,000 people have flocked to an abandoned gas station in the San Francisco Bay Area to get a whiff of a corpse flower, named for the stench it emits when it blooms, which has been compared to rotting flesh.
Solomon Leyva, a nursery owner in Alameda who deals in exceptionally rare plants, had been posting on social media about his amorphophallus titanum. When he saw a lot of interest …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cecil Rhodes statue at Oxford college should go, says independent report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/19/cecil-rhodes-statue-at-oxford-college-should-go-says-independent-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/19/cecil-rhodes-statue-at-oxford-college-should-go-says-independent-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T22:33:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: commission’s finding follows number of protests over colonial legacy at Oriel College 
A independent commission set up to examine the future of Oxford University’s controversial statue of British imperialist Cecil Rhodes has recommended its removal.
The commission was set up last June after Oxford University’s Oriel College voted in favour of removing its statue. The commission was asked to look into the issue after a statue of the slave trader Edward Colston was torn down in Bristol at the heigh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin Community affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK railways to be simplified but still substantially privatised]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/19/uk-rail-overhaul-privatised-great-british-railways-</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/19/uk-rail-overhaul-privatised-great-british-railways-"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government sets out ‘bold new vision’ for Great British Railways that includes focus on efficiency
The rail industry will be simplified but still substantially privatised as a rebranded Great British Railways, the government will pledge when it publishes long-awaited overhaul on Thursday.
A white paper will place control of rail infrastructure and services under the new arm’s-length public body, with franchises replaced by contracts that will incentivise private firms on punctuality and efficiency rather th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nat Phillips flourishes at both ends in Liverpool’s win at Burnley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/burnley-liverpool-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/burnley-liverpool-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:16:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is appropriate that in this strangest of seasons Liverpool are on the verge of Champions League qualification courtesy of the unlikeliest of leaders. After Alisson’s heroics at West Bromwich Albion came Nat Phillips’ commanding night at Burnley; and now only Roy Hodgson, taking charge of Crystal Palace for the final time, stands between them and a fifth successive season among the European elite.
Phillips epitomised Liverpool’s performance at Turf Moor along with the character that has hauled Jürgen Klop…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter at Turf Moor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Web3? The Decentralized Internet of the Future Explained]]></title>
        <id>60a42386906c5207e3a7dfe2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet is going through a paradigm shift. Learn the differences between Web2 and Web3, and why many developers and companies are shifting their approach in building apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Psychedelic Drug Trial review – a mind-bending magic mushroom mission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/19/the-psychedelic-drug-trial-review-a-mind-bending-magic-mushroom-mission</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/19/the-psychedelic-drug-trial-review-a-mind-bending-magic-mushroom-mission"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Helmed by Prof David Nutt, this documentary follows volunteers as they swap antidepressants for psilocybin ... and it’s the closest they’ve come to joy in years

In 2008, Prof David Nutt was made chair of the government’s Advisory Council on the Misuse of Drugs. A year later, Nutt, a neuropsychopharmacologist, was sacked by the same government after insisting – I paraphrase minimally – that fags and booze were more dangerous than cannabis and ecstasy. Twelve years on, he is still clearly furious about it – …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windrush scandal: 21 people have died before receiving compensation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/windrush-scandal-21-people-have-died-before-receiving-compensation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/windrush-scandal-21-people-have-died-before-receiving-compensation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T20:47:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 500 people have been waiting more than a year for claim to be handled, Home Office data shows
The Home Office has revealed that 21 people have died while waiting for Windrush compensation claims to be paid, amid continuing concern that the scheme is taking too long to make payments to elderly people affected by the scandal.
The number has more than doubled since November, when figures showed that nine people had died without receiving the redress they had applied for.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idaho teacher disarmed school shooter and hugged her until help arrived]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/idaho-school-shooter-teacher-krista-gneiting-disarmed-student</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/idaho-school-shooter-teacher-krista-gneiting-disarmed-student"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T20:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Krista Gneiting said she was trying to help one of the students who had been shot when she saw the girl holding the gun
When a student opened fire at an Idaho middle school, teacher Krista Gneiting directed children to safety, rushed to help a wounded victim and then calmly disarmed the sixth-grade shooter, hugging and consoling the girl until police arrived.
Parents credited the math teacher’s display of compassion with saving lives. While two students and the school custodian were shot in the incident on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Rigby, Idaho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pépé and Martinelli sink Crystal Palace to keep Arsenal’s European hopes alive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/crystal-palace-arsenal-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/crystal-palace-arsenal-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T20:07:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A visibly emotional Roy Hodgson took the microphone on the turf he has venerated since childhood, said his thank yous and farewells, and a pin could be heard dropping high in one of the Selhurst Park stands. The stars could hardly have aligned any better in every aspect bar the result that had just passed: the long-awaited return of 6,500 supporters had coincided with a poignant departure and any sadness was offset by pleasure at the fact so many were there to herald Crystal Palace’s storied manager.
“It’s …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames at Selhurst Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m hooked on Mare of Easttown. Piecing it together slowly each week is half the thrill | Josephine Tovey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/im-hooked-on-mare-of-easttown-piecing-it-together-slowly-each-week-is-half-the-thrill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/im-hooked-on-mare-of-easttown-piecing-it-together-slowly-each-week-is-half-the-thrill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T20:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watching the whodunit unfold incrementally is a reminder of the television beforetimes – of delayed gratification and a collective audience experience
Escapism takes many forms, and my current preference is to leave my perfectly fine life behind for an hour every Monday and immerse myself in the bleak goings-on of a small town in America’s frigid rust belt, a place riven with intergenerational trauma and torn apart by missing girls, addiction and murder.
Which is to say, I am hooked on Mare of Easttown.
 Co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josephine Tovey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The living heart of Australia’: fracking plans threaten fragile channel country]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/20/the-living-heart-of-australia-fracking-plans-threaten-fragile-channel-country</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/20/the-living-heart-of-australia-fracking-plans-threaten-fragile-channel-country"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T20:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The locals are divided as energy companies eye the gas resources buried kilometres below the sensitive Queensland floodplain region

Read more of our Modern Outback series here
Sign up for email notifications from our Modern Outback series

Dude Kidd’s ute barrels between a fence line and a sand dune as eagles circle over some unidentified quarry under the magic light of an outback sunset.
“Did you see anything on the ground … a carcass?” asks Kidd. We reply in the negative. “They’ll be after grasshoppers.”…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Readfearn Photographs: David Maurice Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Florida researchers trace origins of monkey colony to farm escape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/florida-monkey-colony-origins-researchers-farm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/florida-monkey-colony-origins-researchers-farm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T19:58:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some disappeared from Dania Chimpanzee Farm in 1948 into mangrove swamp where descendants live today
A colony of monkeys has lived for about 70 years in urban south Florida, near jets taking off from a nearby airport and fuel storage tanks.
No one was quite sure where they came from. Until now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ollie Watkins punishes flat Tottenham to give Aston Villa deserved win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/tottenham-aston-villa-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/19/tottenham-aston-villa-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T19:15:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the end of a fraught game for Tottenham, when their collective fragility was laid bare, Harry Kane wandered around the pitch, although he did not stray too close to the edges.
It felt for a moment as though he was leading a lap of appreciation after the final home game of the season, with 10,000 fans back in attendance, but it was a curious sight, with most of his teammates having sloped off.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner at Tottenham Hotspur Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 30% one-day fall in bitcoin’s value looks like a turning point | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/19/the-30-one-day-fall-in-bitcoins-value-looks-like-a-turning-point</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/19/the-30-one-day-fall-in-bitcoins-value-looks-like-a-turning-point"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T19:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elon Musk and the People’s Bank of China were the culprits but it could easily have been something else
The cry from the bitcoin and crypto brigade during previous bursts of volatility was YOLO, or you only live once. That’s an easy thrill-seeking motto to utter when prices decline by the odd 10%. It becomes harder to cling to when the price is down by 30% in a day, and 50% in a month, and there’s panic in the air.
For true crypto believers, every decline is a buying opportunity – and, indeed, there was a l…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers consider diluting plan to relax Covid rules as India variant surges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/uk-cases-of-covid-indian-variant-up-28-in-two-days-says-hancock</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/uk-cases-of-covid-indian-variant-up-28-in-two-days-says-hancock"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T19:03:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary indicates plans for ‘freedom day’ in England on 21 June could be knocked off track

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers are considering diluting plans for “freedom day” in England on 21 June and delay the end of all social distancing rules, as new figures showed another sharp increase in the Covid variant first detected in India.
The health secretary, Matt Hancock, said no announcement would be made until 14 June on whether all restrictions will be lifte…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Heather Stewart, Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Morgan murder: panel refuses to hand over report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/daniel-morgan-panel-refuses-to-hand-over-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/daniel-morgan-panel-refuses-to-hand-over-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T19:02:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Priti Patel demanded that findings be handed over prior to publication
The independent panel investigating the Daniel Morgan scandal is refusing the home secretary’s demands to hand over its report before it can be published, as senior police sources say nothing in the case affects national security.
Priti Patel provoked fury on Tuesday by demanding the findings be handed over for review prior to publication, angering both the Morgan family and members of the panel conducting the inquiry.
 Continue reading.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on Johnson’s Covid report card – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/19/martin-rowson-johnsons-covid-report-card-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/19/martin-rowson-johnsons-covid-report-card-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:45:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buy a copy of this cartoon from our print shop
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US calls on Israel to ‘de-escalate’ Gaza violence in push for ceasefire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/us-calls-on-israel-to-de-escalate-gaza-violence-in-push-for-ceasefire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/us-calls-on-israel-to-de-escalate-gaza-violence-in-push-for-ceasefire"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden takes tougher line in phone call with Benjamin Netanyahu, but Israel and Hamas deny truce is imminent

Joe Biden has told Benjamin Netanyahu that he expects “a significant de-escalation today on the path to a ceasefire” between Israel and militants in Gaza, in a notable toughening of the US president’s language on the conflict.
The White House said that in a phone call on Wednesday, “the two leaders had a detailed discussion on the state of events in Gaza, Israel’s progress in degrading the capabi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood, Julian Borger in Washington and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Deal For Artists: an unearthed film on how arts funding should work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/19/new-deal-for-artists-documentary-orson-welles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/19/new-deal-for-artists-documentary-orson-welles"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:28:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For its 40th anniversary, the Orson Welles-narrated documentary about Franklin D Roosevelt’s post-depression artist program is getting a vital re-release
In America, the culture war over state funding of arts programs never really ends, but rather assumes slightly altered forms over time. The latest battle lines have formed around Broadway, in desperate need of an infusion of cash from the government to survive the pandemic, much to the chagrin of budget-slashing conservatives. Not so long ago, the debate c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Bramesco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hancock dashes Britons’ hopes of an overseas summer holiday]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/hancock-says-travel-rules-clear-and-hints-at-green-list-caution</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/hancock-says-travel-rules-clear-and-hints-at-green-list-caution"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:14:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary says green list unlikely to expand while one Tory MP questions point of amber list

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers and scientists have in effect warned Britons not to place much hope in the idea of an overseas holiday this year, saying travel to almost all countries remains off-limits and hinting that the “green list” of permitted destinations is unlikely to grow quickly.
The robust stance is likely to anger Conservative backbenchers who are warning…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Truss defends UK plans for post-Brexit trade deal with Australia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/liz-truss-defends-uk-plans-for-post-brexit-trade-deal-with-australia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/liz-truss-defends-uk-plans-for-post-brexit-trade-deal-with-australia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cabinet said to be split over impact on British farmers with warnings about environmental implications
Liz Truss has defended plans for a post-Brexit trade deal with Australia amid reports of a cabinet split over the impact on British farmers of granting tariff-free access to the UK market.
The trade secretary said a deal with Australia would benefit farmers across the UK by opening up a key market while also paving the way for growth in exports across Asia. She promised that the government would protect Br…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The perfect partner: how age affects what men and women find attractive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/the-perfect-partner-how-age-affects-what-men-and-women-find-attractive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/the-perfect-partner-how-age-affects-what-men-and-women-find-attractive"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Young men look for an attractive partner and young women emphasise personality but as we age, everyone agrees physical attributes are overrated
The characteristics that attract people to an ideal partner differ between men and women, but become more similar with age, a survey of more than 7,000 Australian online dating users has found.
Researchers asked 7,325 Australians aged between 16 and 65 to rate the importance of nine characteristics of potential partners on a scale of 0 to 100.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jofra Archer will return to peak fitness for England, insists bowling coach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/jofra-archer-will-return-peak-fitness-england-claims-bowling-coach-jon-lewis-cricket</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/jofra-archer-will-return-peak-fitness-england-claims-bowling-coach-jon-lewis-cricket"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T18:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fast bowler misses New Zealand series with injury
‘We want him to help us win Ashes,’ says Jon Lewis

Jofra Archer has set his sights on returning as a force in Test cricket amid an upbeat prognosis from England’s bowling coach, Jon Lewis, that his current elbow injury does not present a long-term threat to his career.
After reporting soreness in the elbow during his first-team comeback for Sussex last week, Archer missed out on selection for next month’s two-Test series against New Zealand. He was due to s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow churches subjected to anti-Catholic abuse after Rangers win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/glasgow-churches-subjected-to-anti-catholic-abuse-after-rangers-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/glasgow-churches-subjected-to-anti-catholic-abuse-after-rangers-win"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:56:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aftermath of Scottish Premiership victory on Saturday marred by vandalism, unrest and abusive behaviour
A number of churches in and around Glasgow were subject to vandalism and anti-Catholic abuse over the weekend, the Guardian has learned, as Rangers supporters rampaged through the city centre on Saturday.
Windows were smashed at the St Maria Goretti church estate in Cranhill, north-east Glasgow. At another church, which has asked not to be identified, a banner with anti-Catholic slogans was draped across …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’m scared!’: body-cam video shows deadly arrest of Black man in Louisiana]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/louisiana-state-troopers-ronald-greene-body-cam-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/louisiana-state-troopers-ronald-greene-body-cam-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[State troopers seen stunning, punching and dragging Ronald Greene as he apologized for high-speed chase in 2019 arrest
Louisiana state troopers were captured on body-camera video stunning, punching and dragging a Black man as he apologized for leading them on a high-speed chase – footage of the man’s last moments alive that the Associated Press obtained after authorities refused to release it for two years.
“I’m your brother! I’m scared! I’m scared!” Ronald Greene can be heard telling the white troopers as …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Menopause study to uncover impact on senior women in the City]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/financial-sector-takes-part-in-survey-about-impact-of-menopause</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/financial-sector-takes-part-in-survey-about-impact-of-menopause"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:55:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Standard Chartered says menopause should be discussed as a workplace issue 
Major UK banks, insurers and asset managers are taking part in a landmark survey on menopause, amid fears that a lack of support may be hindering gender equality and blocking women from taking senior roles across the City.
Standard Chartered, which has commissioned the women’s rights charity the Fawcett Society to survey more than 300,000 workers in the financial sector, said the menopause must be considered a “workplace issue”.
 Co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin falls almost 30% after China crackdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/bitcoin-falls-30-after-china-crackdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/bitcoin-falls-30-after-china-crackdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:50:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital currency under pressure from payment crackdown and tweets from Elon Musk
The price of bitcoin fell by almost 30% on Wednesday, after a Chinese government crackdown on banks’ use of cryptocurrencies accelerated a long-predicted sell-off, in a day of chaotic trading.
The world’s largest digital currency tumbled to about $30,000 (£21,000) amid frenzied trading, a drop of more than 50% since it hit record highs of more than $64,000 in mid-April. However, by 10pm UK time, the bitcoin price had risen back…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff and Graeme Wearden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on post-Brexit trade: only hard choices are left | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/the-guardian-view-on-post-brexit-trade-only-hard-choices-are-left</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/the-guardian-view-on-post-brexit-trade-only-hard-choices-are-left"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:32:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson likes to pretend that free-trade deals are easy and have no downside. Talks with Australia are proving him wrong
There is agreement across the Conservative party that free trade is a good thing, in theory. Unity is harder to sustain over practical detail, as has become clear through negotiations on a deal with Australia.
The agreement has immense symbolic value. It would be the first substantial post-Brexit deal that was not a rollover of terms that were available under EU membership. The prim…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on US bishops versus the president: Biden is on the angels’ side | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/the-guardian-view-on-us-bishops-versus-the-president-biden-is-on-the-angels-side</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/the-guardian-view-on-us-bishops-versus-the-president-biden-is-on-the-angels-side"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:31:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The president’s backing of abortion rights is not a reason to deny him holy communion 
Joe Biden wears his Catholicism on his sleeve. The American president carries the rosary beads of his late son, Beau, around his wrist, and each Sunday he attends mass in Washington, or in his home state of Delaware. After Mr Biden’s election to the White House last year, Pope Francis sent him a copy of his book on the Covid pandemic, Let Us Dream. In it, Francis calls for a new spirit of solidarity in societies which hav…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[During lockdown, some people barely kept in touch. How do I re-evaluate my friendships?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/during-lockdown-some-people-barely-kept-in-touch-how-do-i-re-evaluate-my-friendships</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/during-lockdown-some-people-barely-kept-in-touch-how-do-i-re-evaluate-my-friendships"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many of us were left behind by friends saying, ‘Sorry! It’s been a crazy week,’ writes Eleanor Gordon Smith. The trouble is, it has been a crazy week/month/year
During lockdown, a couple of people who’d say they’re good friends have barely kept in touch. Both live a few minutes from me and know I live alone. I’ve always made time for them over the years; one has a grown-up family, the other is single. I’ve gone weeks sometimes without even a text message, I’m the one who initiates phone chats (rare), and se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eleanor Gordon-Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Optimize for Change in Software Development]]></title>
        <id>60a469ec906c5207e3a7e1b9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-optimize-for-change-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine that you work at Magic Money Corp, which runs on just three lines of JavaScript: let input = { step1: 'collect underpants' } doStuff(input)  profit(input) // $$$!!! Now imagine that something's wrong with doStuff and you need to take it down for maintenance. What happens if you temporarily comment out the second]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US and Iran aim for final round of talks on reviving nuclear deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/us-and-iran-to-hold-talks-on-reviving-nuclear-arms-control-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/us-and-iran-to-hold-talks-on-reviving-nuclear-arms-control-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:23:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Progress suggests agreement may be possible before Iranian presidential election in June
US and Iranian negotiators are are aiming for a final round of talks in Vienna next week on the terms for Washington’s re-entry to the nuclear deal, the Iranian chief negotiator has said, implying a deal is possible before the Iranian presidential election in June.
The delegations, meeting in Vienna in a fourth round of talks, agreed on Wednesday to return to national capitals to receive final instructions on the remain…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job prospects vary widely for graduates in England, data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/19/job-prospects-vary-widely-for-graduates-in-england-data-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/19/job-prospects-vary-widely-for-graduates-in-england-data-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figures published by Office for Students show large differences in outcomes between universities and subjects
The proportion of students in England who land in graduate-level jobs varies widely between universities and subjects studied, according to data published by the Office for Students (OfS) that is likely to fuel the government’s efforts to restrict entry to “low-quality” courses.
Graduates of Imperial College London were the most likely to complete their studies and go on to either a professional occ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Adams Education editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you an amateur investor affected by the crash of cryptocurrencies?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/tell-us-are-you-an-amateur-investor-affected-by-the-crash-of-cryptocurrencies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/tell-us-are-you-an-amateur-investor-affected-by-the-crash-of-cryptocurrencies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:10:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of cryptos are losing value after China signalled a Bitcoin crackdown. We’d like to hear from small investors – what will you do next?
Amid a sudden crash of cryptocurrencies including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Dogecoin and Cardano, we’d like to hear from amateur investors on how they feel about this latest bout of extreme market volatility affecting alt coins.
Whether you have invested a lot or a little in cryptos, we’re keen to hear what you’ll do next, whether you’ll hold or sell, whether you’ve lost m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DNA study sets out to establish true origins of Christopher Columbus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/dna-study-sets-out-to-establish-true-origins-of-christopher-columbus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/dna-study-sets-out-to-establish-true-origins-of-christopher-columbus"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:05:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Was the explorer from Italy, Spain, Portugal or elsewhere? Researchers hope to find out once and for all
Spanish researchers have launched a new attempt to finally settle the dispute over the true origins of Christopher Columbus after various theories have claimed the explorer hailed from Portugal or Spain, rather than Italy as most scholars agree.
“There is no doubt on our part [about his Italian origin], but we can provide objective data that can … close a series of existing theories,” said José Antonio L…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vanished hen harriers prompt RSPB call for local community vigils]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/vanished-hen-harriers-prompt-rspb-call-for-local-community-vigils</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/vanished-hen-harriers-prompt-rspb-call-for-local-community-vigils"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents urged to help keep persecuted raptors safe after two males disappear from Geltsdale nature reserve, Cumbria 
People in Cumbria are being urged to watch over a pair of hen harriers who have begun nesting on a nature reserve as police investigate the disappearance of two other of the endangered raptors.
Two male hen harriers vanished from RSPB Geltsdale last week in what the police described as “suspicious circumstances”, just when both were providing nesting females with food. As a result both nest…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate change could make overwinter ‘zombie’ fires more common]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds burn area from fires that survive winter varies depending on warmth of summers
In the boreal forests of the far northern hemisphere, where the climate is warming faster than almost anywhere else, some wildfires are surviving winter snows and picking up again in spring.
Now scientists from the Netherlands and Alaska have figured out how to calculate the scope of those “zombie fires” that smoulder year-round in the peaty soil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I am seeking justice’: Tulsa massacre survivor, 107, testifies to US Congress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/viola-fletcher-tulsa-race-massacre-congress-oldest-survivor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/viola-fletcher-tulsa-race-massacre-congress-oldest-survivor"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:36:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Viola Fletcher is the oldest survivor of the racist attack on the city’s ‘Black Wall Street’ in 1921 that left up to 300 dead

The Ground Breaking review: indispensable history of the Tulsa Race Massacre

For nearly a century she was denied a voice by a culture of silence. Finally, at the age of 107, Viola Fletcher got a national stage on Wednesday to bear witness to America’s deep history of racial violence.
 Related: On eve of Trump visit, Tulsa still haunted by memory of white supremacist massacre 
 Cont…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally some clarity from Boris Johnson over amber list holidays | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/finally-some-clarity-from-boris-johnson-over-amber-list-holidays</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/finally-some-clarity-from-boris-johnson-over-amber-list-holidays"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:24:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM reverts to his familiar tropes after Labour leader’s challenge to his Covid hokey-cokey
You couldn’t blame Keir Starmer for trying to solve the mystery of the government’s messaging on foreign travel. After all, in the last 24 hours it has changed from amber list countries being open to visits for family and friends, to then being closed to all travel, to being closed to only essential travel for business and family illness, to essential travel including foreign holidays. It’s just that prime minister’s …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiger Woods targets Ryder Cup role as Kiawah contenders ready for US PGA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/woods-ryder-role-revealed-as-collin-morikawa-prepares-us-pga-defence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/woods-ryder-role-revealed-as-collin-morikawa-prepares-us-pga-defence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:24:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Year’s second major begins at Kiawah Island on Thursday
US captain Steve Stricker wants Woods as an assistant

Tiger Woods, in the midst of recuperation from a serious car accident, is already playing a key role in the US team’s preparations for the Ryder Cup later this year.
Steve Stricker, the US captain, has revealed Woods’s involvement and confirmed he will have the 15-time major winner at Whistling Straits in Wisconsin as one of his assistants if he possibly can.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray at Kiawah Island</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The rise of ‘cardening’: why people are growing plants in cars – and everywhere else]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/19/the-rise-of-cardening-why-people-are-growing-plants-in-cars-and-everywhere-else</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/19/the-rise-of-cardening-why-people-are-growing-plants-in-cars-and-everywhere-else"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:23:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic planting craze continues apace, with cacti grown on dashboards. Not to mention the gardens springing up in fire stations and along railway sidings
Name: Cardening.
Age: New, according to social media users who have been sharing pictures of it during the pandemic, but in-depth research by the Pass notes team has found a reference dating to 2007, when a man in Minneapolis recommended cardening as a way to combat road rage.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the hidden burdens of motherhood | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/19/understanding-the-hidden-burdens-of-motherhood</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/19/understanding-the-hidden-burdens-of-motherhood"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:12:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers give their views on Eliane Glaser’s piece on the cult of the perfect mother
Thank you for publishing such an interesting and nuanced article written by Eliane Glaser (Parent trap: why the cult of the perfect mother has to end, 18 May). We need more articles like this one to encourage a continued discussion on the deep issues involving her incisive point that “motherhood is feminism’s unfinished business”. I am looking forward to the publication of Glaser’s book Motherhood: A Manifesto later this mon…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children in care need full records to put together a life story | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/children-in-care-need-full-records-to-put-together-a-life-story</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/children-in-care-need-full-records-to-put-together-a-life-story"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:11:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jill Sheldrake of the Together Trust on the difficulties that heavily redacted care files can cause
Kirsty Capes offers a powerful account of the impact of receiving heavily redacted care files (‘The secret of my identity devastated me’: could official records reveal the truth about my childhood?, 15 May). Our identity and sense of belonging are tied up in the memories of our childhood, but for children in care their records are often the only thing they have to piece together their life story. Unfortunatel…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lewis Hamilton urges Monaco GP to act over lack of overtaking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/lewis-hamilton-f1-urges-monaco-gp-to-act-over-lack-of-overtaking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/lewis-hamilton-f1-urges-monaco-gp-to-act-over-lack-of-overtaking"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘It needs to change, we have had the same format for years’
Lando Norris signs new contract with McLaren

Lewis Hamilton has insisted the Monaco Grand Prix must change if it is to appeal to fans. The world champion highlighted the difficulties in overtaking on the narrow streets of Monte Carlo, which boasts a spectacular location but often less than stellar racing. 
Hamilton, who leads the Formula One world championship by 14 points from Red Bull’s Max Verstappen, has won in Monaco three times but with mode…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giro d’Italia: Egan Bernal leaves rivals in the dust as Schmid wins stage 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/giro-ditalia-egan-bernal-leaves-rivals-in-the-dust-as-schmid-wins-stage-11</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/giro-ditalia-egan-bernal-leaves-rivals-in-the-dust-as-schmid-wins-stage-11"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colombian rider extends lead over GC contenders
Stage victory goes to Mauro Schmid in Montalcino

Mauro Schmid secured his first Grand Tour win on stage 11 of the Giro d’Italia, a 162-kilometre ride from Perugia to Montalcino, while Egan Bernal extended his lead in the general classification.
Switzerland’s Schmid pulled clear of the peloton early on and battled it out with Alessandro Covi after a thrilling race, pipping the young Italian on the line to secure the stage win in the 21-year-old Swiss rider’s d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Losing byelection would be ‘curtains’ for Keir Starmer, says Diane Abbott]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/losing-byelection-would-be-curtains-for-keir-starmer-says-diane-abbott</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/losing-byelection-would-be-curtains-for-keir-starmer-says-diane-abbott"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour left wing would back leadership run by Andy Burnham if party loses Batley and Spen, Corbyn ally says

Diane Abbott on Andy Burnham and the Labour leadership 

Keir Starmer should resign if Labour loses the Batley and Spen byelection, the former shadow home secretary Diane Abbott has said, suggesting the party’s left wing would endorse a leadership run by Andy Burnham.
Her intervention comes as Sadiq Khan became the second prominent Labour mayor to reach out to the rest of the country, writing in the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid ‘booster’ trial will give third vaccine dose to UK volunteers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/19/covid-booster-trial-will-give-third-vaccine-dose-to-uk-volunteers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/19/covid-booster-trial-will-give-third-vaccine-dose-to-uk-volunteers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists to test seven vaccines for possible protection against new variants in effort to avert winter surge in infections

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Thousands of volunteers will be injected with a third dose of Covid-19 vaccine as part of a trial to investigate which ones could be used as “booster” doses to protect against new variants and prevent hospitals from being overwhelmed by a potential fresh wave of infections this winter.
The Cov-Boost trial – the first in t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State Funeral review – the eerie last rites of Stalin’s Soviet Union]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/19/state-funeral-review-joseph-stalin-ussr-russia-sergei-loznitsa</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/19/state-funeral-review-joseph-stalin-ussr-russia-sergei-loznitsa"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T16:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Massed mourners hail the dictator’s flower-clad body in a film that gives long-lost footage a new and unnerving lease of life
For this very disquieting film, which is like a two-hour bad dream, Sergei Loznitsa has assembled hitherto unseen footage in colour and black-and-white that was shot in the Soviet Union in 1953; it shows the official obsequies for the death of Stalin, whose body is seen lying in state, surrounded by lush flowers, like a Marxist-Leninist Ophelia. All this was reportedly intended for a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Burnham: unlikely heir to the left's leadership ambitions? | Diane Abbott]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/northern-andy-burnham-labour-keir-starmer-byelection-manchester</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/northern-andy-burnham-labour-keir-starmer-byelection-manchester"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester’s mayor has come a long way from his past as an identikit New Labour apparatchik
Inevitably there has been speculation about the future of the current Labour leader in the face of a ruinous set of local election results for the party, including the loss of the Hartlepool byelection. Now the idea of Andy Burnham as the next leader of the party is gaining traction after an impressive performance in the Manchester mayoral election. One poll found he would be the favourite to replace Keir Starmer, ah…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Abbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two young boys in the heart of LA gangland: Merrick Morton’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/two-young-boys-heart-of-la-gangland-merrick-mortons-best-photograph-drive-by</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/two-young-boys-heart-of-la-gangland-merrick-mortons-best-photograph-drive-by"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:51:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’ve taken shots of people pointing their guns at me – and one gang wanted to be photographed doing a drive-by shooting. I refused’
I’ve been shooting street gangs in Los Angeles since the early 80s. For whatever reason, I always seemed to gravitate towards the gangs with the potential for violence. A contact in the LA county probation department helped me get started. He took me to some of the people on his caseload and, from there, I started to drive around the neighbourhoods with my photographs, stoppin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas governor signs extreme six-week abortion ban into law]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/texas-abortion-ban-law-greg-abbott</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/texas-abortion-ban-law-greg-abbott"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:42:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senate Bill 8 bars abortion at six weeks with no exception for rape or incest, amounting to a near-total ban
The Texas Republican governor Greg Abbott has signed into law one of the most extreme six-week abortion bans in the US, despite strong opposition from the medical and legal communities, who warn the legislation could topple the state’s court system and already fragile reproductive healthcare network.
“This bill ensures that every unborn child who has a heartbeat will be saved from the ravages of abor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mary Tuma in Austin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How quickly Boris Johnson’s triumph has given way to doubt and instability | Martin Kettle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/boris-johnson-triumph-covid-cummings-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/boris-johnson-triumph-covid-cummings-election"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:41:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid, Cummings and confused messaging are fast taking the shine off the prime minister’s election victories
Treachery, the crafty French diplomat Talleyrand argued, is largely a matter of dates. Boris Johnson, who is no less of a political cynic than Talleyrand, would be wise to remember that this may also be true of triumph. It is only a fortnight since voters flocked to Johnson’s Conservatives in England’s local elections. At that moment, Johnson commanded the political scene, apparently untouchable, to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Kettle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU citizens: how have you been affected by the ‘hostile environment’ policy?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/eu-citizens-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-hostile-environment-policy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/eu-citizens-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-hostile-environment-policy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:25:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from EU citizens who have encountered issues at the UK border and other difficulties related to the policy
Following Brexit, some EU citizens have been caught up in the UK’s “hostile environment” policy and have reported being held in airport detention rooms and sent to immigration removal centres.
We would like to hear from EU citizens about how they have been affected by the “hostile environment” policy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bob Dylan is turning 80. Happy birthday to the man who taught me about gratitude – and shame | Adrian Chiles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/adrian-chiles-happy-birthday-bob-dylan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/adrian-chiles-happy-birthday-bob-dylan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:23:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I can link big moments of my life to the great man. It’s just unfortunate that some of the memories make me wince
I had been looking forward to reading and listening to all the stuff marking Bob Dylan’s 80th birthday. Then I heard a trail for a radio play called Dinner With Dylan, going out on Saturday afternoon. The title jolted me back 40 years to a dark moment of shame and embarrassment in my otherwise pretty blameless school days. It was 1981, when I was 14, and long before I had a Dylan collection to r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Chiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turkey to ban plastic waste imports]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/turkey-to-ban-plastic-waste-imports</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/turkey-to-ban-plastic-waste-imports"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:15:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greenpeace investigation revealed British recycling left to burn on beaches and roadsides
Turkey is banning the import of most plastic waste after an investigation revealed British recycling was left to burn or be dumped on beaches and roadsides.
Greenpeace visited 10 sites in the southern city of Adana in March. Investigators found waste including British supermarket packaging in waterways, on beaches and in illegal waste mountains.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicola Sturgeon cabinet reshuffle prioritises Covid and climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/nicola-sturgeon-cabinet-reshuffle-prioritises-covid-and-climate-crises</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/nicola-sturgeon-cabinet-reshuffle-prioritises-covid-and-climate-crises"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:04:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland’s first minister calls joint challenges of pandemic and climate most important since devolution
Nicola Sturgeon has prioritised the Covid recovery and difficult transition to a net zero economy in a significant reshuffle of her cabinet that boosts the roles of younger ministers.
Sturgeon, the first minister, appointed her deputy, John Swinney, to the newly created cabinet post of secretary for Covid recovery, while Michael Matheson, formerly the transport and infrastructure secretary, was given the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell Scotland editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Bearing the brunt’: the suffering of children in the Gaza-Israel conflict – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/bearing-the-brunt-the-suffering-of-children-in-the-gaza-israel-conflict-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/bearing-the-brunt-the-suffering-of-children-in-the-gaza-israel-conflict-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Children in their early teens have lived through four wars, with the fear, loss and trauma that brings 

Her hair is matted with rubble dust. Bare feet poke out from pink tracksuit bottoms. Blood from a head wound streaks over her eye and down her face.
But Suzy Eshkuntana is alive, pulled out of the rubble of her family’s home seven hours after it was hit in an Israeli airstrike in the middle of the night. Her four siblings and her mother were killed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Help, it’s 1,000 trillion degrees in here! The Big Bang artwork that makes scientists cry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/help-its-1000-trillion-degrees-in-here-the-big-bang-artwork-that-makes-scientists-cry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/help-its-1000-trillion-degrees-in-here-the-big-bang-artwork-that-makes-scientists-cry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:45:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What would it have been like to be inside the Big Bang? We meet the ultra-hi-tech art duo who are using light, sound and sub-atomic astro data to recreate the biggest explosion ever
‘Step into the heart of the Big Bang,” says the advert for Halo, a walk-in, 360-degree, audiovisual installation about to open in Brighton. Come off it, I want to retort. You couldn’t “step” into the Big Bang without first travelling 13.8 billion years back in time and then being extremely miniaturised. After all, the universe w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acid test: scientists show how LSD opens doors of perception]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/19/acid-test-scientists-show-how-lsd-opens-doors-of-perception</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/19/acid-test-scientists-show-how-lsd-opens-doors-of-perception"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:43:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study analysing brain scans of people finds psychedelic drug lowers barriers that constrain thoughts
When Aldous Huxley emerged from a mescaline trip that veered from an obsession with the folds in his trousers to wonder at the “miraculous” tubularity of the bamboo legs on his garden chairs, he offered an opinion on how the drug worked.
Writing in The Doors of Perception, his 1954 book that took its name from a William Blake poem, Huxley declared that the psychedelic “lowers the efficiency of the brain as a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Madman … racist, sexist pig’: new book details Obama’s real thoughts on Trump]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/barack-obama-donald-trump-book</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/19/barack-obama-donald-trump-book"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:42:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Democratic ex-president was candid in remarks to donors and advisers, according to Battle for the Soul by Edward-Isaac Dovere
For much of Donald Trump’s presidency, Barack Obama largely abided by the convention that former presidents do not publicly criticize or attack their successors.
 Related: Trump family members got ‘inappropriately close’ to Secret Service agents, book claims 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is the British army not held accountable for its actions? | Neil Mitchell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/why-british-army-not-held-accountable-actions-ballymurphy-massacre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/why-british-army-not-held-accountable-actions-ballymurphy-massacre"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:37:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government’s apology for the Ballymurphy massacre is 50 years too late – this culture of military cover-up needs to change 
In the aftermath of last week’s inquest into the 1971 Ballymurphy massacre, in which a coroner ruled 10 people killed in Belfast during a British army operation were unarmed, innocent civilians, former head of the army Richard Dannatt made a pressing point: “Frankly, these matters should have been investigated much more thoroughly a long time ago.”
Well, why weren’t they? The quest…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Neil Mitchell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340692</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svg-loader-a-different-way-to-work-with-external-svg/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVGs are awesome: they are small, look sharp on any scale, and can be customized without creating a separate file. However, there is something I feel is missing in web standards today: a way to include them as an external …
The post svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shubham Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grenfell inquiry: Tory housing chief says council ‘lacked humanity’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/grenfell-inquiry-fire-chief-warned-council-leader-of-serious-risk-to-residents</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/grenfell-inquiry-fire-chief-warned-council-leader-of-serious-risk-to-residents"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:26:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inquiry also hears that Quentin Marshall ‘was not sympathetic’ to residents’ complaints about refurbishment works
A Tory housing chief with oversight of Grenfell Tower has admitted that the council “lacked humanity” in its dealings with residents before the 2017 fire that killed 72 people.
Quentin Marshall, chair of the Royal Borough of Kensington and Chelsea’s housing scrutiny committee, told the public inquiry into the disaster: “I don’t think we saw the bigger picture. I don’t think we addressed the emot…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Governments achieve target of protecting 17% of land globally]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/governments-achieve-10-year-target-of-protecting-17-percent-land-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/governments-achieve-10-year-target-of-protecting-17-percent-land-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:15:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UN report warns that quantity not matched by quality, with many conserved areas poorly protected, as Germany backs new landscapes fund for developing countries
An area greater than the land mass of Russia has been added to the world’s network of national parks and conservation areas since 2010, amid growing pressure to protect nature.
As of today, about 17% of land and inland water ecosystems and 8% of marine areas are within formal protected areas, with the total coverage increasing by 42% since the beginn…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Black kids were written off’: the scandal of the children sent to ‘dustbin schools’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/19/black-kids-were-written-off-the-scandal-of-the-children-sent-to-dustbin-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/19/black-kids-were-written-off-the-scandal-of-the-children-sent-to-dustbin-schools"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T13:29:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subnormal, a devastating documentary produced by Steve McQueen, reveals how Britain’s education system in the 60s and 70s was stacked against Black pupils – and still is today

Last year, documentary maker Lyttanya Shannon began looking for contributors for a new film on a disturbing period in British history. Her focus was the Black British children who found themselves unfairly removed from mainstream education in the 1960s and 70s. They were sent to what were known as “dustbin schools” – places for those…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Micha Frazer-Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Senior loyalist says NI post-Brexit tensions ‘most dangerous for years’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/senior-loyalist-says-ni-post-brexit-tensions-most-dangerous-for-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/senior-loyalist-says-ni-post-brexit-tensions-most-dangerous-for-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T13:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northern Ireland protocol should be replaced, chair of Loyalist Communities Council tells MPs 
The head of a loyalist group in Northern Ireland with links to former paramilitaries has warned of the prospect of more violence in the region, describing tensions over Brexit as “probably the most dangerous for many years”.
David Campbell, the chair of the Loyalist Communities Council, called for the Northern Ireland protocol to be replaced, echoing the words of new leader of the Democratic Unionist party, Edwin …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arctic training and a Balinese ritual: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/19/arctic-training-and-a-balinese-ritual-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/19/arctic-training-and-a-balinese-ritual-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T13:17:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IOC relies on Olympic athletes to win over Japanese public amid crisis | Andy Bull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/ioc-reliant-on-olympic-athletes-to-win-over-japanese-public-amid-crisis-tokyo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/19/ioc-reliant-on-olympic-athletes-to-win-over-japanese-public-amid-crisis-tokyo"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T13:16:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Games will take place against a backdrop of growing unease from the public due to the pandemic 
A quick look at the “playbook” for the Tokyo Games this summer invites a question about how many of the International Olympic Committee’s own members will notice a significant difference between those four weeks and the 200 others in the Olympic cycle. So they’ll be cut off from all contact with the outside world, confined to business hotels, chauffeur-driven cars and stadiums. This is an organisation, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Bull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple iPad Pro M1 review: stunning screen and so much power]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/apple-ipad-pro-m1-review-screen-power-tablet-display-m1-mac</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/apple-ipad-pro-m1-review-screen-power-tablet-display-m1-mac"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T13:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Super-premium tablet has TV-beating display, M1 chip from the Mac and smart camera for video calls
Apple’s latest iPad Pro gets upgraded with the game-changing M1 processor and a new screen that rivals the very best TVs, let alone tablets and laptops.
The fifth-generation iPad Pro comes in two versions, one costing £749 with an 11in screen and the top dog with a 12.9in screen costing £999. Both have the new M1 chip, but only the larger model – reviewed here – has the stunning new screen.
 Continue reading..…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most Covid patients in East Lancashire hospital had jab, says council leader]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/stop-blaming-vaccine-hesitancy-for-spread-of-india-covid-variant-says-council-leader</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/stop-blaming-vaccine-hesitancy-for-spread-of-india-covid-variant-says-council-leader"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T12:26:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stop blaming vaccine hesitancy for spread of India Covid variant, says Mohammed Khan 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The majority of people in hospital with Covid-19 in East Lancashire have received a vaccine dose, a council leader has said, as ministers were criticised for “blaming” a resurgence of cases on people who had not yet had the jab.
Mohammed Khan, the leader of Blackburn with Darwen council, said six of the nine coronavirus patients in the region’s hospital had re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Halliday North of England correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peaceful coexistence in Israel hasn’t been shattered – it’s always been a myth  | Nimer Sultany]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/peaceful-coexistence-israel-myth-palestinian-denied-rights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/19/peaceful-coexistence-israel-myth-palestinian-denied-rights"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T12:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a Palestinian from within Israel I have long been a second-class citizen, denied basic rights
On Tuesday, in my hometown of Tira, which is inside Israel’s pre-1967 borders, the shops were closed and the streets were empty. A general strike had been declared in protest over Israel’s policies, whether the ethnic cleansing in Sheikh Jarrah, the storming of al-Aqsa mosque, or the onslaught on Gaza.
As the Palestinian death toll continues to rise, commentators lament the shattering of coexistence inside Israe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nimer Sultany</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do we need mega-dropdown hover menus in 2021? Probably not. Let’s explore things to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, alternatives to hover menus and fine details for designing a better UX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We went to the dark side’: horror film shows reality of Mexico’s migrant trail]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/19/we-went-to-the-dark-side-horror-film-shows-reality-of-mexicos-migrant-trail</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/19/we-went-to-the-dark-side-horror-film-shows-reality-of-mexicos-migrant-trail"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mystical realism conveys real-life stories of brutal cartel violence in Fernanda Valadez’s chilling directorial debut

Two teenage boys wave goodbye to their mothers across a field in rural Mexico, leaving home in search of the American dream. The opening moments of the Mexican film-maker Fernanda Valadez’s Identifying Features, available to stream from this week, reflects scenes played out every day across Mexico and Central America, as men, women and children journey north in search of safety and job oppo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nina Lakhani in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS nurses: are you considering leaving your job?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/nhs-nurses-are-you-considering-leaving-your-job</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/nhs-nurses-are-you-considering-leaving-your-job"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T10:50:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from nurses and other healthcare workers who are considering leaving the NHS service
A nurse who cared for Boris Johnson when he was in intensive care with Covid-19 has handed in her resignation, citing “lack of respect” for the NHS and healthcare workers.
We would like to hear from NHS nurses and healthcare workers about how they feel about their jobs following the pandemic and whether they are considering leaving the service.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android 12: everything you need to know about Google’s update]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/android-12-everything-you-need-to-know-about-googles-update</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/android-12-everything-you-need-to-know-about-googles-update"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T10:04:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade is big design overhaul, improves speed and privacy and adds new features to Maps and Photos
Google has announced its big update to Android 12, which will soon roll out in beta to the company’s Pixel devices and those made by third-party manufacturers.
Announced as part of Google’s I/O developer conference in California, Android 12 introduces its biggest visual overhaul since 2014 along with improved performance, a new privacy dashboard and updates for Google Maps and Photos apps.
 Continue reading..…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hard power: Europe’s military drift alarm causes alarm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/hard-power-europes-military-drift-causes-alarm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/hard-power-europes-military-drift-causes-alarm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T10:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critics are asking why, if the EU’s mission is to promote peace, it wants to use public money to fund the supply of weapons to foreign armies
The EU was awarded the Nobel peace prize in 2012 in recognition of “six decades of promoting peace and reconciliation” in Europe. In his acceptance speech in Oslo, the then president of the European Commission, José Manuel Barroso, said the world could “count on our efforts to fight for lasting peace, freedom and justice”.
Yet less than a decade on, the EU is taking t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zach Campbell, Caitlin Chandler and Chris Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pop singer Demi Lovato comes out as non-binary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/pop-singer-demi-lovato-comes-out-as-non-binary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/pop-singer-demi-lovato-comes-out-as-non-binary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T09:37:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lovato will use they and them as pronouns, and says they are ‘still learning & coming into myself’
Demi Lovato has announced they have a non-binary gender identity.
Announcing the news on Twitter, they said:
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Licence approved for one-day Glastonbury event, Equinox, in September]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/licence-approved-for-one-day-glastonbury-festival-in-september</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/licence-approved-for-one-day-glastonbury-festival-in-september"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T09:28:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mendip council give green light to 50,000-capacity show to be called Equinox, with no overnight camping
A licence for a concert at the Glastonbury festival site in September has been approved, paving the way for a one-day event – entitled Equinox – in lieu of the usual five-day June celebration.
Mendip district council, which oversees the festival’s Somerset location, approved the licence after consulting with local residents and authorities.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eurovision 2021: the good, bad and weird songs to look out for]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/eurovision-2021-james-newman-uk-entry-good-bad-weird-songs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/19/eurovision-2021-james-newman-uk-entry-good-bad-weird-songs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T09:14:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amid the German ukuleles, anti-colonial Dutch anthems and Ukrainian folk-techno, can the UK’s James Newman reverse a long run of disappointment?
Future scholars of camp will pen entire counterfactuals about the great cancelled Eurovision of 2020 and what might have been: while the majority of last year’s contestants are back for 2021, they must all perform different songs. It feels especially cruel to Daði Freyr, the Icelandic act who would surely have won with viral hit Think About Things, a charming study…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU to ask UK to respect citizens’ rights after mistreatment scandals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/eu-to-ask-uk-to-respect-citizens-rights-after-mistreatment-scandals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/eu-to-ask-uk-to-respect-citizens-rights-after-mistreatment-scandals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T09:12:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Message to Boris Johnson comes after citizens with UK job interviews say they were locked up 
EU leaders will call on Boris Johnson to respect the rights of their citizens in the wake of scandals over their treatment in the UK, including their detention in removal centres, according to a leaked draft statement seen by the Guardian.
The message to the British prime minister will follow a first discussion of EU-UK relations between the 27 heads of state and government since the ratification of the …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bank of England will not hit panic button yet over rising inflation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/19/bank-of-england-will-not-hit-panic-button-yet-over-rising-inflation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/19/bank-of-england-will-not-hit-panic-button-yet-over-rising-inflation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T08:15:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: it will not be long before UK inflation is above the official 2% target

UK inflation more than doubles as energy prices increase
Business live updates: UK inflation more than doubles to 1.5%
See all our coronavirus coverage

A doubling of the annual inflation rate to 1.5% in April means the UK government’s preferred measure of the cost of living is rising at its fastest rate in more than a year. The lifting of restrictions on the economy mean further increases are nailed on over the coming months…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott Economics editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heads together: the light of hopeful faces – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/gallery/2021/may/19/portrait-of-humanity-1854-media-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/gallery/2021/may/19/portrait-of-humanity-1854-media-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Moroccan teapot menders to Finnish ecologists, these portraits of people from 50 countries are a testament to the human need to connect 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monet’s garden prepares to reopen – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/monets-garden-prepares-to-reopen-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/monets-garden-prepares-to-reopen-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T06:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a closure of more than six months, the gardens at Giverny that inspired Monet’s world-famous paintings of water lilies and other masterpieces reopen on Wednesday
Beneath the scudding clouds and amid the luscious blooms, the gardeners tend the flowerbeds that were the pride and joy of the impressionist painter Claude Monet, with pink and white striped tulips, diaphanous peonies, sky-blue forget-me-nots and myriad other flowers together creating a living work of art.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Leicester. Photographs by François Mori / Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MoD document approves British troops for illegal bombing, charity claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/mod-document-approves-british-troops-for-bombing-charity-claims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/19/mod-document-approves-british-troops-for-bombing-charity-claims"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Directive gives exceptions where troops can engage in countries without parliamentary backing
A previously confidential Ministry of Defence document grants British troops permission to engage in potentially illegal bombing, which has not been approved by parliament, a charity has claimed.
The 2016 chief of defence staff (CDS) directive on so-called “embedded personnel”, released on Tuesday during legal proceedings, outlines exceptions where British troops working in foreign units can engage both in countrie…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis to put millions of British homes at risk of subsiding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/climate-crisis-to-put-millions-of-british-homes-at-risk-of-subsiding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/19/climate-crisis-to-put-millions-of-british-homes-at-risk-of-subsiding"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drier summers mean the ground in vulnerable areas will be more prone to shrink and crack, scientists say
The climate crisis is very likely to put millions of homes at increased risk of subsidence, according to new data from the British Geological Survey (BGS). The hotter and drier summers being driven by global heating mean the ground under houses will shrink and crack, scientists said.
The key areas affected are London, Essex, Kent, and a swathe of land from Oxford up to the Wash. This is because the clay …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kris Hallenga: the woman diagnosed with cancer at 23 who convinced a generation to check their breasts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/kris-hallenga-the-woman-diagnosed-with-cancer-at-23-who-convinced-a-generation-to-check-their-breasts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/kris-hallenga-the-woman-diagnosed-with-cancer-at-23-who-convinced-a-generation-to-check-their-breasts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When she was told she had stage four breast cancer in 2009, Hallenga didn’t even know it could be a danger at her age. Then she started a campaign to save thousands of lives
Eight months before Kris Hallenga was diagnosed with stage four breast cancer that spread to her spine, she went to her GP about a lump. It was 2009, she was 23 years old and, she says, “actually very miserable”, having just come out of a crummy relationship. Living in Beijing, she was working for a travel company, and teaching on the s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confronting hate against east Asians – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/confronting-hate-against-east-asians-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/confronting-hate-against-east-asians-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Asian racism and crimes against the Asian community have amplified with Covid. The photographer Wendy Huynh, whose parents are Chinese immigrants from Vietnam who moved to France to flee communism, has experienced racism in Paris and London. She created a series of portraits celebrating Asian women in London from the creative industry to tackle the issue, and the Guardian talked to some of them about their experiences
For Bonnie Kwok it was a subtle difference. Whenever she used public transport there …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nazia Parveen, photographs by Wendy Huynh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are our cities built for 6ft-tall men? The female architects who fought back]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/why-are-our-cities-built-for-6ft-tall-men-the-female-architects-who-fought-back</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/why-are-our-cities-built-for-6ft-tall-men-the-female-architects-who-fought-back"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fed up living in a world designed by and for men, 80s design activists Matrix declared war on every urban obstacle in their way. And their impact is still being felt today

When Le Corbusier developed his proportional system Le Modulor in the 1940s, the great architect had in mind a handsome British policeman. His system would go on to shape the entire postwar world, dictating everything from the height of a door handle to the scale of a staircase, all governed by the need to make everything as convenient a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Wainwright</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’re hoping for a good season’: Italy prepares to welcome back tourists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/were-hoping-for-a-good-season-italy-prepares-to-welcome-back-tourists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/were-hoping-for-a-good-season-italy-prepares-to-welcome-back-tourists"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T04:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Industry that accounts for 14% of country’s GDP hopes to bounce back as Covid travel restrictions are relaxed 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

If anyone is strategically placed to take note of the people setting foot on the tiny Italian island of Giglio it’s Rosalba Pellegrini. Her bar and pastry shop, Fausto, faces the port, where ferries arrive from Porto Santo Stefano, a town on the Tuscan peninsula of Monte Argentario. A smattering of people, mainly hikers and cyclists, d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida in Giglio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple versus Epic: how the Fortnite app led to a legal showdown - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Apple takes on games developer and Fortnite creator Epic, UK technology editor Alex Hern describes a battle of the tech titans that could reshape the app industry
The video game Fortnite has become a cultural phenomenon in recent years with up to 100 million users a month logging in to play the free online game. They parachute down on to an island with 99 other players and the last one standing is the winner. 
But for users of iPhones and iPads, the wildly popular game has been unavailable ever since it …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Alex Hern; produced by Sami Kent and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break into Ethereum, Crypto, and Web3 as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60a53182906c5207e3a7e588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/breaking-into-ethereum-crypto-web3-as-a-developer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I've been talking about my move into the Web3, Ethereum, and crypto space since making the switch from a traditional web, mobile, and cloud background. Since making that move, a shocking number of people have reached out to me who are also thinking about doing the same.  It's really]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinned Audio WordPress Theme]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/pinned-audio-wordpress-theme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m afraid I have to start this with a whole backstory, as the journey here is the point, not so much the theme.
A fella wrote to me a while back outlining a situation he was in. His company has …
The post Pinned Audio WordPress Theme appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting for the stars: the otherworldly art of astrophotography – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/19/shooting-for-the-stars-the-otherworldly-art-of-astrophotography-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/19/shooting-for-the-stars-the-otherworldly-art-of-astrophotography-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From deep in the bush just outside Bathurst in Australia, Rodney Watters and Niall MacNeill bring the darkness of space into the light.
Using an alchemy of high-speed cameras, telescopes and computer processors, the images created for their new book overcome the multitude of challenges involved in capturing celestial bodies light years away
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodney Watters and Niall MacNeill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian through the ages: one family, seven generations, one newspaper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/18/the-guardian-through-the-ages-one-family-seven-generations-one-newspaper</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/18/the-guardian-through-the-ages-one-family-seven-generations-one-newspaper"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:15:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One reader’s family have been reading the newspaper for 200 years

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

I am sure many families could show that they had read the Guardian for 200 years over seven generations, but here is one example:
1. Jacob Bright and Martha Wood Rochdale, Lancashire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance Development Pricing Guide – Should Freelancers Bill by the Hour?]]></title>
        <id>60a3780f906c5207e3a7db5f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-different-ways-to-charge-for-a-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you offer your services as a freelance developer, you have a major say in how you price your project.  But how do you go about charging for a website project? "Well, I just bill by the hour and send an invoice every week or month." ...I hear you say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding Programs – 101 Ways to Learn to Code for Free]]></title>
        <id>6068f146d5756f080ba9402d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/coding-programs-101-ways-to-learn-to-code-for-free/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T16:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, you can learn to code for free, from the convenience of your own home, and at your own pace. I'm going to show you 101 courses where you can learn computer science and programming for free.  The freeCodeCamp courses are completely free and some of them include a free]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Convert a Keras SavedModel into a Browser-based Web App]]></title>
        <id>609bea6b62ab9107fe5a9f89</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/convert-keras-savedmodel-into-browser-based-webapp/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T16:36:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a Python developer who works with Keras SavedModels, this article is for you.  Perhaps you're not sure how to use SavedModels to leverage the power of machine learning in browser-based web apps. But don't worry – we'll cover all the basic steps you need to get started.  Along with]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redux for Beginners – Learn Redux Basics with Code Examples]]></title>
        <id>609fc4cc62ab9107fe5aac91</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/redux-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T16:18:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Redux can be confusing for beginner React developers to understand. There are a lot of concepts you need to know to use it properly, like reducers, actions, store, pure functions, immutability, and much more. But every React developer should know the basics of how to work with Redux, since industry]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Be a Successful Entrepreneur – A Developer&#x27;s Guide to Startup Strategy and Design]]></title>
        <id>60685767d5756f080ba93df4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/be-a-successful-entrepreneur-developers-guide-to-startup-strategy-and-design/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T16:08:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to freeCodeCamp’s 2018 New Coder Survey, 40.3% of participants want to build a business of their own, either as a freelancer or as an entrepreneur.  If you are in that 40.3%, then this article is for you. If you are in the remaining 59.7%, you]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Neon Text With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340420</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-neon-text-with-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neon text can add a nice, futuristic touch to any website. I’ve always loved the magic of neon signs, and wanted to recreate them using CSS. I thought I’d share some tips on how to do it! In this article, …
The post How to Create Neon Text With CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia O'Dwyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Bolton: have you been affected by the new variant from India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/18/living-in-bolton-have-you-tested-positive-for-coronavirus-during-the-recent-outbreak</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/18/living-in-bolton-have-you-tested-positive-for-coronavirus-during-the-recent-outbreak"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T09:38:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people in Bolton who have tested positive for Covid during the outbreak of a new variant from India
Efforts to tackle an outbreak in Bolton of a new variant first identified in India has led to more than 6,200 people receiving their first vaccination by Sunday evening. People were able to queue at a mass vaccination site in south-west Bolton.
We would like to hear from those living in Bolton on how they have been affected by the new variant first identified in India. We are partic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home sweet Hackney: love, life and local legends in east London – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/18/home-sweet-hackney-love-life-and-local-legends-in-east-london-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/18/home-sweet-hackney-love-life-and-local-legends-in-east-london-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T06:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From bodybuilders in makeshift gyms to octogenarian gardeners, Hackney is home to a diverse group of community-minded people – as these photographs from locals attest
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ecuador: community education during the Covid pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/18/ecuador-community-education-during-the-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/18/ecuador-community-education-during-the-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the pandemic struck Ecuador it turned back the clock for many indigenous and African-Ecuadorean families, forcing them to return to the places they were born and fall back on themselves as in times gone by.
Johis Alarcón is a photographer based in Ecuador. Her work is supported and produced by the Magnum Foundation, a non-profit organisation that expands creativity and diversity in documentary photography, with a grant from the Henry Luce Foundation. 
As Covid-19 ravaged Ecuador’s largest city, Guayaqu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Johis Alarcón. Written by Dan Collyns</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How worrying is the India coronavirus variant for UK plans to unlock this summer?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/18/how-worrying-is-the-india-coronavirus-variant-for-uk-plans-to-unlock-this-summer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/18/how-worrying-is-the-india-coronavirus-variant-for-uk-plans-to-unlock-this-summer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T02:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monday’s change in the rules was supposed to be a moment of celebration – but the new variant spreading in the UK meant it came with a cautionary note. Can the next stage of the government’s ‘irreversible’ plan go ahead?
This time last week, most of us were feeling optimistic about the next step in the government’s “irreversible” plan to end lockdown. Then scientists started to warn that the accelerating spread of the India variant of coronavirus meant that we should proceed carefully – and even consider sl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Nicola Davis; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Hannah Moore  and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard, Nicole Jackson and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty firms produce 55% of world’s plastic waste, report reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/twenty-firms-produce-55-of-worlds-plastic-waste-report-reveals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/twenty-firms-produce-55-of-worlds-plastic-waste-report-reveals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plastic Waste Makers index identifies those driving climate crisis with virgin polymer production
Twenty companies are responsible for producing more than half of all the single-use plastic waste in the world, fuelling the climate crisis and creating an environmental catastrophe, new research reveals.
Among the global businesses responsible for 55% of the world’s plastic packaging waste are both state-owned and multinational corporations, including oil and gas giants and chemical companies, according to a c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML vs JSX – What&#x27;s the Difference?]]></title>
        <id>60a2771762ab9107fe5ab383</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-vs-jsx-whats-the-difference/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HTML vs JSX Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) is the standard language for documents that determine the structure of a web page.  HTML is a very important language in web development. Your code is either in HTML originally or compiles to it so browsers can read it.  JSX, on the other]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Complete Guide to Full Stack Ethereum Development]]></title>
        <id>60a536e1906c5207e3a7e6b5</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/full-stack-ethereum-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you'll learn how to build full stack dApps with React, Ethers.js, Solidity, and Hardhat. You can find the code for this project here. The video course for this tutorial is here. I recently joined Edge & Node as a Developer Relations Engineer and have been diving]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long lunches, tea with the mafia … how reporting Italy has changed over the years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rome correspondent Angela Giuffrida asks predecessor John Hooper how he covered the country in the pre-internet era 

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

Long before even meeting John Hooper, affectionately known among foreign correspondents in Rome as “the Hoops”, I considered him a guide.
In 2018, in preparation for the March general election, I bought his book, The Italians, seeking insight into Italian history,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Short author Michael Lewis on the inside story of America’s failed Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/17/big-short-author-michael-lewis-on-the-inside-story-of-americas-failed-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/17/big-short-author-michael-lewis-on-the-inside-story-of-americas-failed-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The author and journalist Michael Lewis discusses reporting on a group of individuals who tried to alert the US government to the dangers of its inaction as coronavirus cases began to rise at an alarming rate
The author and journalist Michael Lewis has made a career of writing about people who see things coming that most of us don’t. His book The Big Short, which was turned into an Oscar-winning film, followed a group of investors who predicted the collapse of the American housing market in 2007. 
He tells …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Michael Lewis, produced by Courtney Yusuf and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line …
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It’s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about …
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week two]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first of the six stories was reprinted in the Guardian last Friday (7 May). The second is below, with the other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a basic grid inspector 
…
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340573</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2021-design-systems-survey-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T22:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friends at Sparkbox are doing a survey on design systems, as they do each year. Go ahead and fill it out if you please. Here are the results from last year. In both 2019 and 2020, the vibe was …
The post 2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340036</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/advanced-css-animation-using-cubic-bezier/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with complex CSS animations, there is a tendency to create expansive @keyframes with lots of declarations. There are a couple of tricks though that I want to talk about that might help make things easier, while staying in …
The post Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340118</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svgator-3-0-reshapes-the-way-you-create-and-animate-svg-with-extensive-new-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building animations can get complicated, particularly compelling animations where you aren’t just rolling a ball across the screen, but building a scene where many things are moving and changing in concert. When compelling animation is the goal, a timeline GUI …
The post SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['They saw me as mad and needing to be medicated’ | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T10:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, journalist Iman Amrani speaks to Chris, who after being diagnosed with schizophrenia spent a long time in the mental health system. They discuss medication, frustration at the system, and the importance of being listened to and heard. Dr Rufus May, a clinical psychologist, speaks about how he worked with Chris and other patients to show compassion and empathy, and how this can help people with mental health issues navigate society

Watch other episodes of Modern Mascul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Mat Heywood, Kyri Evangelou, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339960</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-disabled-buttons-more-inclusive/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T14:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about disabled buttons. Specifically, let’s get into why we use them and how we can do better than the traditional disabled attribute in HTML (e.g. <button disabled> ) to mark a button as disabled.
There are lots of …
The post Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandrina Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day 11: history and war

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>