<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-18T00:40:48.006Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-18T00:40:48.006Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden expresses support for ceasefire on call with Netanyahu – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/17/joe-biden-covid-relief-bill-child-tax-credit-benefits-liz-cheney-latest-news-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/17/joe-biden-covid-relief-bill-child-tax-credit-benefits-liz-cheney-latest-news-live"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:29:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[White House reported the US president urged Israel ‘to make every effort to ensure the protection of innocent civilians’

Supreme court agrees to consider major rollback of abortion rights
Liz Cheney defiant over Trump as Republican civil war heats up
Joe Biden feels political ground shift as Israel-Gaza conflict rages on

 1.00am BST 
That’s all from me today. Here’s a rundown of the day’s biggest politics stories: 
 12.28am BST 
States are continuing to adjust to the new CDC guidance on masks. 
Earlier to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong and Joan E Greve</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 5,000 migrants reach Spain’s north African enclave Ceuta in a day]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/record-1000-migrants-reach-spains-north-african-enclave-ceuta-in-a-day</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/record-1000-migrants-reach-spains-north-african-enclave-ceuta-in-a-day"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:11:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unprecedented influx comes amid tensions with Morocco over the hospitalisation of Western Sahara’s independence leader in Spain
More than 5,000 migrants, about 1,000 of them presumed to be minors, crossed into Spain’s northern African enclave of Ceuta on Monday, in an unprecedented influx that left Spanish officials scrambling to bolster police presence in the tiny territory.
Ceuta, along with nearby Melilla, has long been a magnet for African migrants hoping to cross into Europe, despite being heavily prot…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashifa Kassam in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty firms produce 55% of world’s plastic waste, report reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/twenty-firms-produce-55-of-worlds-plastic-waste-report-reveals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/twenty-firms-produce-55-of-worlds-plastic-waste-report-reveals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plastic Waste Makers index identifies those driving climate crisis with virgin polymer production
Twenty companies are responsible for producing more than half of all the single-use plastic waste in the world, fuelling the climate crisis and creating an environmental catastrophe, new research reveals.
Among the global businesses responsible for 55% of the world’s plastic packaging waste are both state-owned and multinational corporations, including oil and gas giants and chemical companies, according to a c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK economy could resemble that of Italy by end of 2020s – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/18/uk-economy-could-resemble-italy-by-end-of-2020s-covid-brexit-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/18/uk-economy-could-resemble-italy-by-end-of-2020s-covid-brexit-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thinktank says new strategy needed in face of Covid, Brexit, net zero, automation and demographic change
Britain risks mirroring Italy’s economic woes unless it develops a strategy for tackling the five seismic changes that will shape a decisive decade for the country, a report has warned.
A joint project by the Resolution Foundation thinktank and the London School of Economics said the UK was neither used to nor prepared for the challenges posed by the aftermath of Covid-19, Brexit, the net zero transition…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott Economics editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kiyan Prince’s legacy lives on for Queens Park Rangers in Fifa 21]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/18/kiyan-princes-legacy-lives-on-for-queens-park-rangers-in-fifa-21</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/18/kiyan-princes-legacy-lives-on-for-queens-park-rangers-in-fifa-21"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most promising talent in the QPR academy would have been 30 this year and his life is commemorated in the video game to help provide inspiration to young people
Promotional materials for the latest player to be added to Fifa 21 show Kiyan Prince scoring a goal. He takes a shot with his left foot, over the lunge of a despairing defender, and watches it fly into the roof of the net. Running off in celebration with his arms wide, he shouts in delight. Then he turns and shows his shirt to the crowd: Queens …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ambulance crews in England to use iPads to assess accident and stroke victims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/18/ambulance-crews-in-england-to-use-ipads-to-assess-accident-and-stroke-victims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/18/ambulance-crews-in-england-to-use-ipads-to-assess-accident-and-stroke-victims"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paramedics will send pictures to specialist hospital doctors for rapid diagnosis
Ambulance crews will start using iPads to send photographs of accident and stroke victims to specialist hospital doctors so that they can make rapid diagnoses and save some patients a trip to A&E.
NHS England is giving 30,000 iPads to regional ambulance services to help paramedics decide what care to give and whether to take someone to hospital or treat them at the scene.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK schools voice objections to ‘propping up’ Covid test and trace system, unpaid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/18/uk-schools-voice-objections-to-propping-up-covid-test-and-trace-system-unpaid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/18/uk-schools-voice-objections-to-propping-up-covid-test-and-trace-system-unpaid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T23:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bosses warn of an impending exodus by head teachers if government continues to withhold additional staff and resources

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Schools have spent up to and in excess of 100 hours “propping up” the national Covid test and trace system since the start of the academic year, despite having no additional funding or staff, according to a school leaders’ union.
The National Association of Head Teachers (NAHT), which represents 29,000 UK school leaders, is cal…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza conflict: 200 Palestinians killed in a week, say officials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/israel-gaza-conflict-200-palestinians-killed-in-a-week-say-officials</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/israel-gaza-conflict-200-palestinians-killed-in-a-week-say-officials"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:25:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu signals Israel’s bombardment will continue as Joe Biden issues statement supporting ceasefire
Two hundred Palestinians, including 59 children, have been killed during a week of attacks in Gaza, health officials in the territory have said, as Benjamin Netanyahu signalled Israel’s bombardment would rage on despite mounting global pressure to stop the bloodshed.
After a phone conversation with Netanyahu on Monday afternoon, US president Joe Biden issued a statement for the first time express…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hazem Balousha in Gaza Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Nevers review – not even magical aliens can save this cursed mess]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/the-nevers-review-not-even-magical-aliens-can-save-this-cursed-mess</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/the-nevers-review-not-even-magical-aliens-can-save-this-cursed-mess"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joss Whedon walked away from this romp about women given superpowers by a spaceship, and what was left behind? Sex clubs, serial killers – and silly plot threads flapping in the breeze

The Nevers (Sky Atlantic) is a mess, within and without. Without, there were the massing allegations against its creator Joss Whedon of bullying, verbal and misogynistic abuse and toxicity on his sets (first from Justice League’s Ray Fisher and Buffy the Vampire Slayer’s Charisma Carpenter, supported by others). He departed …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Covid casino’ case collapses as police in Canada accused of stealing watches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/canada-covid-casino-police-stealing-watches-allegation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/canada-covid-casino-police-stealing-watches-allegation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:18:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The owner of a mansion allegedly used for illegal gambling during pandemic will not face charges after police accused of theft and planting evidence
A police investigation into an alleged underground casino operating out of a mansion north of Toronto has fallen apart after officers were accused of stealing two luxury watches and planting evidence.
Police in Ontario said in September they had seized more than $10m in assets, firearms, cash and liquor as part of a months-long investigation into illegal gambli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco in Toronto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fred West: police find ‘possible evidence’ that body of girl is buried in Gloucester cafe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/police-find-possible-evidence-body-of-girl-linked-to-fred-west-is-buried-in-cafe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/police-find-possible-evidence-body-of-girl-linked-to-fred-west-is-buried-in-cafe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:49:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excavation work will go ahead where missing 15-year-old Mary Bastholm worked, police have said
Excavation work will go ahead in a cafe in Gloucester where missing 15-year-old Mary Bastholm worked and the serial killer Fred West was a customer, after “possible evidence” to suggest a body could be buried there, police have said.
Forensic archaeologists have been undertaking exploratory work at the Clean Plate cafe in Southgate Street in connection with the disappearance of the girl who was last seen alive in …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Press Association</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[André Ayew’s moment of class puts Swansea in driving seat against Barnsley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/17/barnsley-swansea-city-championship-play-off-semi-final-first-leg-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/17/barnsley-swansea-city-championship-play-off-semi-final-first-leg-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So much for the theory that form is the prerequisite for promotion via the play-offs. Swansea arrived at Oakwell on their worst run of the season. They had six defeats in 11, Barnsley 13 wins in 19. And so, with a perverse illogicality, the Welsh club have positioned themselves to end their three-year exile in the Football League. Arguably Barnsley’s biggest game since the 2000 Championship play-off final ended in anticlimax, courtesy of André Ayew.
“We have been here before,” said the Swansea manager, Stev…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Jolly at Oakwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML vs JSX – What&#x27;s the Difference?]]></title>
        <id>60a2771762ab9107fe5ab383</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-vs-jsx-whats-the-difference/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HTML vs JSX Hypertext Markup Language (HTML) is the standard language for documents that determine the structure of a web page.  HTML is a very important language in web development. Your code is either in HTML originally or compiles to it so browsers can read it.  JSX, on the other]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Malins and Piutau fire Bristol to big win over Gloucester as fans return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/bristol-gloucester-premiership-rugby-union-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/bristol-gloucester-premiership-rugby-union-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:11:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bristol 39-7 Gloucester
Bears score five tries in bonus point victory

Much has happened in the 14 months since Bristol’s returning supporters last watched their local heroes play live. These days the Bears are clear Premiership leaders and remain on course for a home semi-final but, despite the cheerful presence of 3,128 excited fans, this bizarre contest was a reminder that nothing in rugby can ever be entirely delivered to order.
 Related: Opportunities beckon as Eddie Jones ponders options for summer Te…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson at Ashton Gate</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huddersfield fend off Warrington fightback to deflate returning home fans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/warrington-huddersfield-super-league-rugby-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/warrington-huddersfield-super-league-rugby-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:06:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Warrington 20-26 Huddersfield
Wire recover from 20-0 down but held off in closing stages

Some nights, sport is about much more than the result on the field. Ultimately, this was Huddersfield Giants’ night in terms of the outcome, but really, everyone who was fortunate enough to be in attendance here must have felt like a winner at some stage given how utterly miserable the last 429 days have been as a rugby league supporter, locked out of the game you love.
To truly understand how important a role rugby le…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Bower at the Halliwell Jones Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Pact review – Wales’s Big Little Lies will have you on tenterhooks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/the-pact-review-waless-big-little-lies-will-have-you-on-tenterhooks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/the-pact-review-waless-big-little-lies-will-have-you-on-tenterhooks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T21:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Julie Hesmondhalgh and Eddie Marsan lead a starry cast in the BBC’s dark new whodunnit, with shades of Harlan Coben – and, hopefully, intrigue and scares to the last
I have been burned by enough TV thrillers to be wary of The Pact (BBC One). You know the ones. They are not all on ITV, but most are. They are showy crime dramas, usually stripped across the week, with a strong premise, a story that sets up a puzzle to be solved, only for it all to descend into farce in the final episode as the plot ties itself…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tottenham left reeling after Harry Kane tells club he wants to leave this summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/17/tottenham-left-reeling-after-harry-kane-tells-club-he-wants-to-leave-this-summer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/17/tottenham-left-reeling-after-harry-kane-tells-club-he-wants-to-leave-this-summer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T20:55:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England captain frustated at lack of major honours at Spurs
Striker would prefer to stay in England but would consider Spain

Harry Kane has let it be known to Tottenham Hotspur that he wants to leave the club in the summer. The striker expressed his frustration at the end of last month at a continued inability to achieve his ambition of winning major trophies at Spurs in comments that felt like the first step of an exit strategy.
 Related: Fan protests affected Manchester United performances, Solskjær clai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A dream of belonging: for Indigenous Australians the fabled 'outback' is home | Alexis Wright]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/18/a-dream-of-belonging-for-indigenous-australians-the-fabled-outback-is-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/18/a-dream-of-belonging-for-indigenous-australians-the-fabled-outback-is-home"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T20:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aboriginal people have the skills, refined over thousands of years, to care for this fragile, fire-prone ancient continent

Read more of our Modern Outback series here
Sign up for email notifications from our Modern Outback series

My childhood was spent in Cloncurry, a small town in north-western Queensland once known and locally celebrated as being the hottest in Australia. This was not really true. There were plenty of other places that were scorchingly hot to be found in the country’s remote regions.
I …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Wright</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ofqual: bias against disadvantaged and SEN pupils ‘common’ in assessments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/17/ofqual-bias-against-disadvantaged-and-sen-pupils-common-in-assessments</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/17/ofqual-bias-against-disadvantaged-and-sen-pupils-common-in-assessments"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:35:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Findings by England’s exams regulator add to concerns about government’s summer assessment process
Teacher assessments are often biased against disadvantaged pupils and those with special educational needs (SEN), according to research by England’s exams regulator, Ofqual, that will add to concerns about grades this summer.
The findings were based on a review of existing research on bias in teacher assessment, intended to help inform and improve the quality of guidance for teachers assessing GCSE and A-level…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disingenuous and slippery, Matt Hancock deflects blame for spread of India variant | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/17/covid-coronavirus-disingenuous-slippery-matt-hancock-deflects-blame-spread-india-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/17/covid-coronavirus-disingenuous-slippery-matt-hancock-deflects-blame-spread-india-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:26:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK government can’t learn from its Covid mistakes as it is unable to admit it has made them

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

It was more a question of do as I say, not as I do. “We must be humble,” said Matt Hancock. Not something that comes naturally to Matt, despite him having a lot to be humble about. “We must look at the evidence.” Only it turned out that the health secretary was quite selective about which parts of the evidence he wanted to look at.
Door Matt’s latest…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘This is environmental racism’: activists call on Biden to stop new plastics plants in ‘Cancer Alley’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/st-james-parish-formosa-complex-biden-cancer-alley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/st-james-parish-formosa-complex-biden-cancer-alley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:06:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protest over proposed petrochemical complex in Louisiana is part of 400-mile march led by youth climate group Sunrise Movement
On Monday, groups of climate activists protested against a proposed petrochemical complex an hour away from New Orleans, Louisiana, calling on the Biden administration to revoke the plastics company’s federal permit to start construction.
The demonstration is part of a 400-mile march led by the youth climate group Sunrise Movement, which began last week and traces the path of enviro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Ramirez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GSK’s late entry to the vaccine race will help protect it from aggressive investors | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/17/gsk-vaccine-elliott-management-elon-musk-bitcoin-at-and-t-warnermedia-discovery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/17/gsk-vaccine-elliott-management-elon-musk-bitcoin-at-and-t-warnermedia-discovery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:02:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whatever Elliott Management’s intentions, the UK-based pharmaceutical firm will now be seen as a national asset
GlaxoSmithKline’s progress on Covid vaccines has been slow, frustrating and surprising. More was expected sooner, because the company remains far bigger in the wider vaccine field than, say, AstraZeneca. But there are now tangible signs the pace is improving.
Monday’s encouraging data from a phase 2 trial with French group Sanofi means a protein-based product could appear before the end of this ye…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creature review – dancers twitch and writhe as theatre comes back to life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/17/creature-review-ben-j-riepe-tanztheater-wuppertal-pina-bausch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/17/creature-review-ben-j-riepe-tanztheater-wuppertal-pina-bausch"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Available online
Ben J Riepe and Tanztheater Wuppertal Pina Bausch’s film uses the theme of bodies connecting to tell the story of the past year
On the ground, a robotic mannequin, head bowed sadly, joints twitching. Next to it is a pair of twisted legs, ankles flexing back and forth. You can get a surprising amount of pathos from fibreglass and microchips, it turns out. Elsewhere, two part-animal, part-machine people are attached to cables, screens on their backs like shells. Awkwardly twitching, they’re c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lyndsey Winship</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greenland ice sheet on brink of major tipping point, says study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/greenland-ice-sheet-on-brink-of-major-tipping-point-says-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/greenland-ice-sheet-on-brink-of-major-tipping-point-says-study"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists say ice equivalent to 1-2 metres of sea level rise is probably already doomed to melt
A significant part of the Greenland ice sheet is on the brink of a tipping point, after which accelerated melting would become inevitable even if global heating was halted, according to new research.
Rising temperatures caused by the climate crisis have already seen trillions of tonnes of Greenland’s ice pour into the ocean. Melting its ice sheet completely would eventually raise global sea level by 7 metres.
 C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World is home to 50bn birds, ‘breakthrough’ citizen science research estimates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/world-is-home-to-50bn-birds-breakthrough-citizen-science-research-estimates</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/18/world-is-home-to-50bn-birds-breakthrough-citizen-science-research-estimates"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T19:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[University of NSW study suggests six times as many individual birds as humans but that many species are very rare
There are about 50 billion individual birds in the world, according to new research that uses citizen science observations to try to estimate population numbers for almost 10,000 species.
The paper, led by scientists at the University of New South Wales, suggests there are about six times as many birds on the planet as humans – but that many individual species are very rare.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India variant will be dominant UK Covid strain ‘in next few days’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/uk-cases-of-indian-covid-variant-almost-doubled-in-four-days-says-hancock</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/uk-cases-of-indian-covid-variant-almost-doubled-in-four-days-says-hancock"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists’ warning comes as government comes under pressure to explain border policy

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The Covid variant first detected in India is set to be the dominant strain in the UK within days, experts have said, with the government and health teams struggling to contain cases, which have risen by more than 75% since Thursday.
With the rapid spread of the more transmissible B.1.617.2 variant threatening to reverse moves to ease lockdown, the government f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker, Nicola Davis and Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on Boris Johnson’s coronavirus lockdown easing – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/17/martin-rowson-on-boris-johnsons-coronavirus-lockdown-easing-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/17/martin-rowson-on-boris-johnsons-coronavirus-lockdown-easing-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:55:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millionaires who support taxing the rich protest in front of Jeff Bezos’s homes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/jeff-bezos-protest-patriotic-millionaires</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/jeff-bezos-protest-patriotic-millionaires"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:40:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrations organized by Patriotic Millionaires, whose members earn incomes of over $1m or have assets worth over $5m
A group of millionaires took to the streets on Monday, protesting in front of homes in New York and Washington owned by Jeff Bezos of Amazon, the richest man in the world.
The protest organized by Patriotic Millionaires, a coalition of wealthy individuals who push for progressive policy changes, was staged to mark Tax Day, on which Americans submit their income tax returns to the federal …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coral Murphy Marcos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rock Feilding-Mellen: the Tory councillor forced to resign after Grenfell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/rock-feilding-mellen-tory-councillor-forced-to-resign-after-grenfell</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/rock-feilding-mellen-tory-councillor-forced-to-resign-after-grenfell"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:38:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Profile: since leaving Kensington and Chelsea, Feilding-Mellen has become the director of ‘psychedelic venture studio’ 

Councillor was told about plan to use cheaper cladding

Rock Feilding-Mellen has run a property development company since 2009, and in 2011, at the age of 32, was promoted to a cabinet position at the Conservative stronghold of Kensington and Chelsea council.
Socially Conscious Capital helps obtain planning consent for housing on greenfield sites.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuart Broad feels former England selector Ed Smith ‘didn’t rate me’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/stuart-broad-feels-former-england-selector-ed-smith-didnt-rate-me-cricket</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/stuart-broad-feels-former-england-selector-ed-smith-didnt-rate-me-cricket"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:38:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Veteran pace bowler disappointed with lack of communication
Squad for New Zealand Tests to be announced on Tuesday

Stuart Broad has described his relationship with Ed Smith as a case of working under somebody who did not rate him and said he would accept missing a Test match this summer provided the reasons are communicated properly.
England will name their squad for the upcoming Test series against New Zealand on Tuesday, the first since Smith’s three-year spell as national selector was terminated last mo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grenfell: councillor was told about cheaper cladding plan before fire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/grenfell-inquiry-councillor-was-told-about-plan-to-use-cheaper-cladding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/grenfell-inquiry-councillor-was-told-about-plan-to-use-cheaper-cladding"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:33:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rock Feilding-Mellen had told police he was only made aware of cladding change after 2017 disaster

Rock Feilding-Mellen: the Tory councillor forced to resign after Grenfell

Rock Feilding-Mellen, the Tory councillor in charge of the Grenfell Tower refurbishment, was informed of plans to save money by swapping zinc cladding for aluminium in 2014 but told police he only knew about it after the June 2017 fire, statements released to the public inquiry show.
The switch led to the use of combustible cladding th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It feels really special’: Manchester venues optimistic as doors reopen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/it-feels-really-special-manchester-venues-optimistic-as-doors-reopen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/it-feels-really-special-manchester-venues-optimistic-as-doors-reopen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:27:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spread of the India Covid variant was not enough to dampen a day of reunion

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

On the long march out of lockdown, this was probably the most significant day yet. A day of reopenings and reacquaintances after months of restrictions and rules.
And while the mood in Manchester seemed much sunnier than it has for some time – with museums, galleries, cinemas and music venues opening their doors – there were unmistakable clouds too.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teenage nursery worker on trial in Exeter for sexual assault of children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/teenage-nursery-worker-on-trial-in-exeter-for-sexual-assault-of-children</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/teenage-nursery-worker-on-trial-in-exeter-for-sexual-assault-of-children"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T18:12:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jayden McCarthy, 18, denies charges of rape and sexual assault, despite CCTV footage from the nursery in Devon
A teenage nursery worker sexually assaulted eight young children he was employed to look after, a jury has heard.
Jayden McCarthy allegedly assaulted seven girls and one boy between the ages of two and four over a two-and-a-half-week period at a nursery in Devon. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Covid ethics: easier to enter lockdown than leave it | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/the-guardian-view-on-covid-ethics-easier-to-enter-lockdown-than-leave-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/the-guardian-view-on-covid-ethics-easier-to-enter-lockdown-than-leave-it"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:50:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is a concern that the prime minister opted to ease restrictions without a sure grasp of the facts
The rollout of the vaccine in Britain has seemingly sprung the lock that kept the public indoors during the past pandemic year. For many this is a cause for celebration. Some may have paused, however, and wondered why many scientists appeared reluctant, as coronavirus restrictions eased, to take advantage of the new freedoms. For these experts, the risks are just not worth it. Indoor mixing, potentially with…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on violence against women: focus on the perpetrators | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/the-guardian-view-on-violence-against-women-focus-on-the-perpetrators</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/the-guardian-view-on-violence-against-women-focus-on-the-perpetrators"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:48:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A slew of new proposals from Labour comes at the right time. Confidence in the justice system has been badly shaken 
A shocking series of murders of women in public places, combined with rising levels of domestic violence and a wave of reports of sexual harassment in schools and colleges, have set alarm bells ringing among all those concerned with the safety of women and girls. Protecting women from male violence, including domestic and sexual violence, has long been among feminists’ main goals – along with…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E-scooter hire schemes to be rolled out in London from June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/e-scooter-hire-schemes-to-be-rolled-out-in-london-from-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/e-scooter-hire-schemes-to-be-rolled-out-in-london-from-june"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:47:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To improve safety, speeds will be capped at 12.5mph and the scooters will not work in royal parks
Londoners can legally use e-scooters on public roads next month – but only slowly. E-scooters will be limited to a maximum of 12.5mph, 3mph slower than in the rest of the UK, when rental scheme trials start on 7 June.
The schemes will only operate in a few parts of central, south and west London as the capital prioritises safety. Three operators – Tier, Lime and Dott – have been chosen by Transport for London (…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The DOM Explained for Beginners – How the Document Object Model Works]]></title>
        <id>60a16df162ab9107fe5ab01b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/dom-explained-everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-document-object-model/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I started out as a web developer, people often threw around the term "DOM" in the industry. Every JavaScript tutorial mentioned it, but I didn't know what it meant. Fast forward two years, and now that I know what it's all about, I am going to explain what the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gig economy couriers should be eligible for a pension, says UK regulator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/gig-economy-couriers-should-be-eligible-for-a-pension-says-uk-regulator</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/gig-economy-couriers-should-be-eligible-for-a-pension-says-uk-regulator"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:35:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Companies including Deliveroo and Uber urged to recognise food couriers’ employment rights 
The head of the UK’s pension regulator has called on gig economy companies to recognise the employment rights of those who work for them and set up workplace pensions.
Charles Counsell, the chief executive of the Pensions Regulator, said the government-backed body was already working closely with Uber on a workplace scheme after a supreme court ruling found the ride-hailing group’s private-hire drivers should be clas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frost hopes EU will not ‘react’ if UK suspends Northern Ireland protocol]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/17/uk-proposes-phasing-in-irish-sea-border-checks-on-food-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/17/uk-proposes-phasing-in-irish-sea-border-checks-on-food-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:22:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit minister tells Commons’ select committee that Britain could act unilaterally over border checks

The British government has said it hopes the EU would not take retaliatory measures if it was forced to unilaterally suspend the special Brexit arrangements for Northern Ireland.
Lord Frost told MPs that in the interests of stability and peace, he hoped that the “EU would not make that more difficult by reacting to it”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US supreme court agrees to consider major rollback of abortion rights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/17/abortion-case-supreme-court-threatens-roe-v-wade</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/17/abortion-case-supreme-court-threatens-roe-v-wade"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:20:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Court will take up Mississippi’s bid to enforce a 15-week ban on abortion, setting up a showdown

US politics – live coverage

The US supreme court agreed on Monday to consider a major challenge to reproductive rights, saying it will take up Mississippi’s bid to enforce a ban on almost all abortions after the 15th week of pregnancy.
 Related: ‘It would be glorious’: hopes high for Biden to nominate first Black woman to supreme court 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shareholders urged to vote out Playtech chair over gender imbalance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/shareholders-urged-to-vote-out-playtech-chair-over-gender-imbalance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/shareholders-urged-to-vote-out-playtech-chair-over-gender-imbalance"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investors advised to oust female interim chair in protest against lack of women on board
The female head of gambling software supplier Playtech is facing a possible backlash from shareholders at the company’s annual general meeting over the low number of women on its board.
Glass Lewis, one of the world’s largest and most influential investor advisory services, has recommended that shareholders vote against Claire Milne’s re-election as chair at the AGM in late May, citing its concerns over “lack of board g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill Gates ‘left Microsoft board amid inquiry into relationship with employee’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/bill-gates-microsoft-board-relationship-employee</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/bill-gates-microsoft-board-relationship-employee"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T17:13:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Board members reportedly felt his presence was inappropriate during the investigation into a romantic relationship last year
Board members at Microsoft decided in 2020 it was not appropriate for the tech giant’s co-founder, Bill Gates, to continue sitting on its board as they investigated a romantic relationship with a female employee that was deemed inappropriate, the Wall Street Journal reported.
Microsoft subsequently confirmed the investigation had taken place, and said it had provided support to the fe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Office letter wrongly tells British citizens to apply for settled status]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/immigration-letter-sent-to-long-term-british-citizens-causes-alarm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/immigration-letter-sent-to-long-term-british-citizens-causes-alarm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term citizens alarmed at letter saying they risk losing rights to work and healthcare unless they apply for post-Brexit status
A number of long-term British citizens have expressed alarm at receiving letters from the Home Office telling them they risk losing the right to work, benefits and free healthcare unless they apply for UK immigration status in the next six weeks.
Campaigners said they were concerned that the “scattergun” mailshot, which was sent out to thousands of people instructing them to ap…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid expected to cost Britain £372bn, says National Audit Office]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/covid-expected-to-cost-britain-372bn-says-national-audit-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/covid-expected-to-cost-britain-372bn-says-national-audit-office"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:26:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Almost half of sum was earmarked for business support, including furlough scheme and bounce-back loans

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The government’s bill for tackling Covid-19 has risen by £100bn since the start of the year and now stands at £372bn, according to the independent watchdog that oversees Whitehall spending.
Figures from the National Audit Office highlighted the financial impact of the lockdown imposed to cope with the winter surge in cases of the pandemic and …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Larry Elliott economics editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use the Lottie Library like a Pro – Lottie Resources for Designers and Developers]]></title>
        <id>609f552e62ab9107fe5aaba0</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-lottie-like-a-pro-resources-for-designers-and-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:25:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lottie is a library that helps render Adobe After Effects animations natively on mobile and the web. I like using Lottie for animations in my projects because: Creating an animation from scratch can be time-consuming, andGIF files can be double the size of Lottie JSON files (the files containing the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Massive destruction’: Gaza’s hospitals under strain after Israeli strikes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/israeli-strikes-gaza-health-system-doctors-hospitals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/israeli-strikes-gaza-health-system-doctors-hospitals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deaths of doctors have further hit medical services struggling with damaged facilities and medicine shortages 
In her bed in Gaza City’s Shifa hospital, 25-year-old Aya Aloul recalls the moment her 66-year-old father, Moeen, one of Gaza’s few neurologists, was killed in an Israeli strike, one of two key Palestinian medical staff killed within hours on Sunday.
Covered in wounds and bruises caused by shrapnel and falling masonry, she described the bombing of the family’s home in the Rimal neighbourhood. “I ge…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hazem Balousha in Gaza City and Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Risk of last-minute cancellation ‘chaos’ as UK holidaymakers hoard bookings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/risk-of-last-minute-cancellation-chaos-as-uk-holidaymakers-hoard-bookings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/risk-of-last-minute-cancellation-chaos-as-uk-holidaymakers-hoard-bookings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:18:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Consumers are booking stays at two or more hotels offering fully flexible cancellation, industry says
Many UK holidaymakers are booking stays at two or more hotels with a view to cancelling all but one at the 11th hour, prompting fears among accommodation businesses of last-minute cancellation “chaos”.
Avvio, a hotel technology provider, said its data showed that UK hotel cancellation rates were running at “scarily low” levels as consumers – some of whom would ideally like to travel abroad – hedged their be…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trailer released for Prince Harry and Oprah Winfrey TV series]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/trailer-released-for-prince-harry-and-oprah-winfrey-tv-series</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/trailer-released-for-prince-harry-and-oprah-winfrey-tv-series"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Footage suggests Harry will revisit trauma of his mother’s death in Apple TV+ series on mental health
The Duke and Duchess of Sussex feature in an emotional trailer for Harry’s mental health documentary series with Oprah Winfrey, and footage hints that he will revisit the trauma he experienced after his mother’s death.
The two-minute trailer includes archive film from the 1997 funeral of Diana, Princess of Wales, showing Harry, then 12, standing with his head bowed as his mother’s coffin passes by, alongsid…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Rabbit 2 review – James Corden’s unfunny bunny scampers back]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/17/peter-rabbit-2-review-james-cordens-unfunny-bunny-scampers-back</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/17/peter-rabbit-2-review-james-cordens-unfunny-bunny-scampers-back"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voiced by Corden, Peter tumbles into a life of crime in a part-animated caper that’s occasionally cute but mostly bland
The new Peter Rabbit film is here – as before directed and co-written by Will Gluck and the hero cheekily voiced by James Corden – presenting a U-certificate entertainment that shows rabbits wisecracking and getting up to larks but thankfully uninterested in breeding or sexual congress of any sort.
Beatrix Potter’s creation has returned for a movie sequel that combines live-action humans a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did you solve it? Are you smart enough to opt out of cookies?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/17/did-you-solve-it-are-you-smart-enough-to-opt-out-of-cookies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/17/did-you-solve-it-are-you-smart-enough-to-opt-out-of-cookies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T16:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The solutions to today’s puzzles
Earlier today I set three puzzles from Terms & Conditions Apply, a free online game about website deviousness (that I made with Jonathan Plackett.) The puzzles in the game exaggerate the tricks websites use to extract our data. 
1. Naughty negatives
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Bellos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Carolina: new law makes inmates choose firing squad or electric chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/south-carolina-law-death-row-inmates-firing-squad-electric-chair</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/17/south-carolina-law-death-row-inmates-firing-squad-electric-chair"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Governor Henry McMaster signed law on Friday amid a shortage of lethal injection drugs for death row prisoners 
The governor of South Carolina, Henry McMaster, has quietly signed into law a bill that requires inmates on death row to choose between a firing squad or the electric chair if lethal injection is not available.
The law, signed without ceremony on Friday, comes amid a shortage of lethal injection drugs that has affected the state’s ability to implement capital punishment. South Carolina has not exe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Coral Murphy Marcos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hug refuseniks: the people who won’t embrace the loss of personal space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/hug-refuseniks-the-people-who-wont-embrace-the-loss-of-personal-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/hug-refuseniks-the-people-who-wont-embrace-the-loss-of-personal-space"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:53:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While many are celebrating the return of hugging after more than a year, others would much prefer to maintain their distance
Name: Hug refuseniks.
Age: All ages.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How consumer protection laws are failing to safeguard us | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/17/how-consumer-protection-laws-are-failing-to-safeguard-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/17/how-consumer-protection-laws-are-failing-to-safeguard-us"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iain Ramsay and Ian Arnott respond to George Monbiot’s article on cuts to trading standards and the lack of law enforcement 
George Monbiot is right to draw attention to the absence of enforcement of consumer protection law, and people running into “a wall of unaccountable, opaque bureaucracy” when they attempt to report scams (My friend was the victim of a scam – and cuts mean she can do nothing about it, 12 May). I encountered the same problem when trying to contact trading standards in relation to a nati…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When pubs leave parents out in the cold | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/when-pubs-leave-parents-out-in-the-cold</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/when-pubs-leave-parents-out-in-the-cold"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ‘no children under 10’ policy has left Kate Moores feeling excluded from a return to normal life – and a pint
Grace Dent finishes her review of the Alma in Crystal Palace, London (Feast, 14 May), by stating: “If this is how pubs are coming out of the pandemic, then there’s definitely light at the end of the tunnel.” It’s just a shame that those of us who have become new parents during the last year or so won’t get to enjoy this pub in leafy south London.
The Alma has a “no children under 10” policy, inclu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we loosen restrictions too early, there is a real risk of a third wave in the UK | Devi Sridhar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/third-wave-risk-uk-vaccinated-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/third-wave-risk-uk-vaccinated-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:41:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not enough people are vaccinated against Covid as a new variant spreads, requiring us to remain vigilant for a little longer

Just when it felt like we could begin to relax again, Covid-19 has thrown us yet another curveball. While we’ve been debating in the UK where to go for a holiday and booking long-overdue nights out with friends, the virus has been causing havoc across the world.
The Kent variant, B.1.1.7, found its way into countries such as Taiwan and Singapore; P.1 is causing another wave in Brazil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Devi Sridhar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calorie counts are coming to British menus – and they’re the last thing we need | Rhiannon Lucy Cosslett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/calorie-counts-menus-pandemic-stress</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/calorie-counts-menus-pandemic-stress"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:34:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic should have led to an understanding of how stress affects our eating, but we’re still captured by diet culture
I sort of imagined myself coming out of lockdown like a phoenix rising from the ashes: slim, well-rested, healthy, glowing – my most beautiful self, essentially. Instead, I have wild, almost waist-length hair and a cat on a harness (you can’t choose your destiny, and mine seems to be witch). This past year, people have been very keen to tell us that being alive is enough, and it is, of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhiannon Lucy Cosslett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid has led to record levels of antidepressant use – but withdrawal can be difficult  | David Taylor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/antidepressant-use-up-covid-side-effects-medication</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/antidepressant-use-up-covid-side-effects-medication"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:21:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I know from personal experience that coming off these medications can be horrible. I also researched ways to make it easier

Prof David Taylor is director of pharmacy and pathology at the south London and Maudsley NHS foundation trust

One of the impacts of the Covid lockdowns since March 2020 has been a widespread worsening of mental health, with anxiety and depression the most common symptoms reported. Running parallel to this, the prescription of antidepressants in England has climbed to record levels, a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancelled Philip Roth biography picked up by new publisher amid abuse allegations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/17/cancelled-philip-roth-biography-blake-bailey-skyhorse-publishing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/17/cancelled-philip-roth-biography-blake-bailey-skyhorse-publishing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:18:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blake Bailey’s life of Roth to be republished by Skyhorse Publishing, home to Woody Allen and Roger Stone, next month
A biography of the late novelist Philip Roth that was dropped by its original publisher after sexual abuse claims against its author Blake Bailey has found a new home.
Originally released in April in the US by WW Norton, Bailey’s book had been much-heralded: he had been appointed to the role by Roth, having been the biographer of writers including John Cheever and Richard Yates. But that sam…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we made: My Dad Wrote a Porno]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/how-we-made-my-dad-wrote-a-porno</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/17/how-we-made-my-dad-wrote-a-porno"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘When we played the first episode to Jamie’s parents, his mum left the room’
In 2015, my dad took me aside at a family gathering and said: “I’m writing a book.” He didn’t say what it was about, but a month later he emailed it to me asking for my feedback. When I realised what it was, a pornographic novel, I had to share it with my friends – if only to purge the shame from my body.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Hannah J Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlético Madrid enter The Suárez Zone to tear up script in title drama | Sid Lowe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/17/atletico-madrid-luis-suarez-la-liga-blog-analysis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/17/atletico-madrid-luis-suarez-la-liga-blog-analysis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T15:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Diego Simeone had predicted, it was Luis Suárez who rescued Atlético just as fate looked to inflict another cruel blow
“We’re entering into The Suárez Zone,” Diego Simeone said. Atlético Madrid’s manager knew but even he couldn’t have known it would be quite like this, another story of the absurd in a season built on them. If this was The Suárez Zone, which it was, it was The Twilight Zone too, the implausible unfolding in front of them. With 147 seconds left on the penultimate Sunday there was another t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The beginning of normality’: Algarve welcomes back British tourists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/the-algarve-portugal-welcomes-back-british-tourists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/the-algarve-portugal-welcomes-back-british-tourists"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:56:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployment rose by 70% in the past year in the Portuguese region most reliant on tourism, so locals are delighted to see Kevin Rushby and today’s other arrivals

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The mood at Faro airport was buoyant. Camera operators and photographers jostled to take pictures of smiling tourists, perhaps not as many as hoped, for but more are on the way. João Fernandes, head of the Algarve tourism board, was there, too, greeting arrivals while his staff handed…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rushby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There is no simple explanation for Labour's lost voters | Paula Surridge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/labour-quest-loss-of-voters-local-election-results</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/labour-quest-loss-of-voters-local-election-results"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:54:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local election results in England suggest voting groups are fragmented, rather than the large ‘tribes’ implied by the Brexit vote
With electoral events paused for 12 months, Britain’s pundit class had little to chew over to understand how voter behaviour had been changed by the pandemic, the post-Brexit period and the new leadership of the Labour party.
It was inevitable then that the recent election results would be pored over for clues to the future of British politics. Would “Super Thursday”, as it was d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paula Surridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[India’s Gujarat state braces for ‘monster’ Cyclone Tauktae]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/india-gujarat-state-monster-cyclone-tauktae-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/india-gujarat-state-monster-cyclone-tauktae-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:52:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least 12 people killed as cyclone, billed as worst in 20 years, brushes past coastal states
Indian authorities have moved nearly 150,000 people from their homes in the state of Gujarat to safety and shut ports and an airport as the most powerful cyclone in more than two decades roared up the west coast.
Cyclone Tauktae killed at least 12 people and left a trail of destruction as it brushed past the coastal states of Kerala, Karnataka, Goa and Maharashtra. It is expected to make landfall in Gujarat late o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Ahmedabad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solidity Tutorial – How to Create NFTs with Hardhat]]></title>
        <id>609cb90262ab9107fe5aa026</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/solidity-tutorial-hardhat-nfts/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:39:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm a developer who's mostly been writing JavaScript, so the Solidity development environment was a bit hard to learn.  About four months ago, I switched to Hardhat from Truffle. This cool new kid on the block drastically improved my coding experience. So today I want to share it with my]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indoor hospitality and entertainment venues reopen in England – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/may/17/indoor-hospitality-and-entertainment-venues-reopen-in-england-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/may/17/indoor-hospitality-and-entertainment-venues-reopen-in-england-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:33:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The roadmap for lockdown easing continues as pubs reopen indoors and people can travel abroad – to a select group of countries – for holidays

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arnel Hecimovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden’s silence in the face of Israeli violence is a disgrace | Moustafa Bayoumi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/new-voices-congress-demand-more-than-predictable-deference-to-israel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/new-voices-congress-demand-more-than-predictable-deference-to-israel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:05:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cracks are emerging in the wall that has historically separated any criticism of Israel from American politics – but Joe Biden is still not listening
On Saturday, an Israeli air strike killed 10 people from the same extended family after missiles hit the family’s house in the Shati refugee camp in Gaza. A five-month-old baby, the sole survivor, was pulled out alive from the rubble, having been trapped next to his deceased mother. As I write this, at least 180 Palestinians have been killed in Gaza, including…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Moustafa Bayoumi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sole traders: how sneakers became as collectable as art]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/sole-traders-how-sneakers-became-collectable-art-trainers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/sole-traders-how-sneakers-became-collectable-art-trainers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T13:57:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sale of Kanye West’s 2008 Grammys pair for $1.8m heralded era of investment grade trainers
To most people they just look like a pair of trainers or sneakers, but for Gerome Sapp the Nike Air Yeezy 1 Prototypes represent a watershed moment in design and modern commerce. “If you’re a sneakerhead, you know that sneaker,” says Sapp.
The art market is paying attention, too. The shoes, co-designed by Kanye West and worn by him to the Grammys in 2008, became the most expensive ever sold when Sapp’s company Rares b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lanre Bakare Arts and culture correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Office plan for women’s immigration centre faces legal challenge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/home-office-challenged-over-planned-womens-immigration-detention-centre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/17/home-office-challenged-over-planned-womens-immigration-detention-centre"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T13:42:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners and MPs express concerns at proposals for new detention facility in Durham

A charity is challenging the planned opening of a new immigration detention centre for 80 women in County Durham – the Home Office’s first new detention centre since 2014.
Women for Refugee Women, whose work includes advocating for women in immigration detention, challenges whether the Home Office is complying with equality rules in the development of the new detention centre.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I live in Sheikh Jarrah. For Palestinians, this is not a ‘real estate dispute’ | Lucy Garbett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/palestinians-sheikh-jarrah-jerusalem-city-identity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/17/palestinians-sheikh-jarrah-jerusalem-city-identity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:51:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The threat to our neighbours’ homes is the latest chapter in a long campaign to erase the Palestinian presence in Jerusalem
Sheikh Jarrah today smells of dirty socks and rotting flesh. Israeli police vehicles, known as “skunk trucks”, have been spraying Palestinian homes, shops, restaurants, public spaces and cultural institutions with putrid water at high pressure. The water causes vomiting, stomach pain and skin irritation, and was originally developed by an Israeli company to repel protesters. The stench…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Garbett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competitive pond fishing and a rainbow: Monday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/17/competitive-pond-fishing-and-a-rainbow-mondays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/17/competitive-pond-fishing-and-a-rainbow-mondays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
• This gallery was amended on 17 May 2021 to remove an image that featured antisemitic iconography
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Most people in UK did not work from home in 2020, says ONS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/home-working-doubled-during-uk-covid-pandemic-last-year-mostly-in-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/home-working-doubled-during-uk-covid-pandemic-last-year-mostly-in-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:38:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Uneven impact of Covid laid bare, with affluent London suburbs having highest proportion of home workers 
The proportion of people working from home more than doubled in 2020 during the Covid-19 pandemic, though it remained a minority of overall workers across the UK, according to an official snapshot.
The Office for National Statistics (ONS) said about a quarter of people (25.9%) had worked at home at some point in the week before they responded to officials conducting its annual population survey. It said…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Israel protests in Germany prompt calls for antisemitism crackdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/anti-israel-protests-in-germany-prompt-calls-for-antisemitism-crackdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/anti-israel-protests-in-germany-prompt-calls-for-antisemitism-crackdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:34:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli flags burned as thousands attend demonstrations in Berlin, Cologne and other cities
Politicians in Germany have called for tougher measures against antisemitism after thousands of people attended what became aggressive protests at the weekend in connection with the escalating violence in the Middle East.
In the most violent protest, in the southern Berlin district of Neukölln, demonstrators who had gathered to show solidarity with Palestinians burned Israeli flags, chanted anti-Israel slogans and fl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in  Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomasina Miers’ recipe for chorizo and parsley scotch eggs | The simple fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/17/thomasina-miers-recipe-chorizo-and-parsley-scotch-eggs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/17/thomasina-miers-recipe-chorizo-and-parsley-scotch-eggs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take the classic picnic snack up a notch to ‘epic’
I once co-judged a national street food competition that felt like it was at the forefront of the ensuing street food revolution. The winner, Yianni Papoutsis, ex-technician at the English National Ballet, made the simplest, most delectable burgers and went on to co-found MEATliquor, a roaringly popular burger business. A neighbouring stall sold scotch eggs in every guise imaginable, but it was the chorizo one that really made me weak at the knees. It is th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomasina Miers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Horses: tracks on alert as racecourses open their doors again]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/may/17/talking-horses-tracks-on-alert-as-racecourses-open-their-doors-again-horse-racing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/may/17/talking-horses-tracks-on-alert-as-racecourses-open-their-doors-again-horse-racing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:29:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will those once-a-year racegoers who make up the bulk of the sport’s attendance keep up the racegoing habit?
It was odd to look around the bleak emptiness of the York racecourse on the final day of the Dante meeting on Friday and remember that on John Smith’s Cup day at the track in less than two months’ time, the grandstands could – in theory, at least – be full to bursting point for a card that reliably attracts 40,000 racegoers if the sun is out. The following month, it could welcome around 85,000 more t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we met: ‘He turned up with two bottles of rioja. We hit it off straight away!’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/how-we-met-he-turned-up-with-two-bottles-of-rioja-we-hit-it-off-straight-away</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/how-we-met-he-turned-up-with-two-bottles-of-rioja-we-hit-it-off-straight-away"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T10:33:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro, 53, and Emma, 45, met in 2010 when he was visiting the UK from Spain. Despite the language barrier, they fell in love and now live together in Extremadura with their three dogs
Emma had always pictured herself with a family. But, by 2010, she hadn’t met the right person and was feeling lost. “I was a teacher in Tunbridge Wells at the time,” she says. “I really wanted to be a mum. I was 35, which was my self-imposed ‘deadline’.”
Over the August bank holiday weekend, she went to a friend’s barbecue, wh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lizzie Cernik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-punk band Au Pairs: ‘The Thatcher years gave us plenty of material’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/17/post-punk-band-au-pairs-the-thatcher-years-gave-us-plenty-of-material</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/17/post-punk-band-au-pairs-the-thatcher-years-gave-us-plenty-of-material"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T10:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forty years ago, the Birmingham band released their debut album, and its frank, forthright songs about sex and equality are still pertinent. They explain how music gave their anger a voice
Forty years ago this month, one of the best but often forgotten albums of the 1980s was released: Playing With a Different Sex by Birmingham band Au Pairs. The cover, an Eve Arnold photo showing female militia fighters heading into battle, is a good visual harbinger of the album’s friction-filled songs. Jane Munro’s monst…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Walsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glimmers of hope: the mood at Luton airport as England restarts foreign travel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/glimmers-of-hope-the-mood-at-luton-airport-as-england-restarts-foreign-travel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/glimmers-of-hope-the-mood-at-luton-airport-as-england-restarts-foreign-travel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T09:28:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Rushby tackles an escalator for first time in 15 months as overseas holidays restart for green list countries
Luton airport at 6am on the day that foreign holiday travel begins again. The halls are quiet. Many shops are shuttered. At the easyJet desk the staff seem relieved that things are quieter than expected: the mass brawl last week was a nasty shock. Standing on the escalator to the departure lounge, I suddenly realise why I feel disoriented: I have not been on a moving staircase for 15 months. P…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rushby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My cheapo garden fairy lights do this too’ – Yayoi Kusama: Infinity Mirror Rooms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/japanese-yayoi-kusama-infinity-mirror-rooms-review-tate-modern</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/japanese-yayoi-kusama-infinity-mirror-rooms-review-tate-modern"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T09:18:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tate Modern, London 
The Japanese artist turns her visual hallucinations into a flaring and dimming clockwork universe. But I seem to be immune. Perhaps if I brought a small child or was interested in taking selfies …

All done with lights and looking glasses, Yayoi Kusama’s year-long display of Infinity Mirror Rooms is already booked-out until late October. Viewers must queue and wait, at £10 a head, for two, two-minute dives into Kusama’s universe. Hardly enough time to get your bearings, let alone lose t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Searle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fresh peas, asparagus, wild garlic – Nigel Slater’s revitalising spring recipes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/17/fresh-peas-asparagus-wild-garlic-nigel-slater-revitalising-spring-recipes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/17/fresh-peas-asparagus-wild-garlic-nigel-slater-revitalising-spring-recipes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T07:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Broad beans with new potatoes, and cucumber, chickpea and prawns – spring recipes to encourage the green shoots of recovery
May always feels like the greenest of months. The fizz of new leaves in the gardens, seedlings sprouting on the windowsill and early bunches of asparagus in the shops. The first of the homegrown radishes and tiny soft-leaved lettuces call out for salads by the bowlful: new potatoes with a puree of green peas and rocket; a broad bean salad with yoghurt; and a hollandaise sauce for aspar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nigel Slater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dogs and humans live among the gravestones in Pasay cemetery, Philippines – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/dogs-humans-gravestones-pasay-cemetery-philippines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/17/dogs-humans-gravestones-pasay-cemetery-philippines"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T06:30:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a project for the Lady Freethinker NGO, photographer Aaron ‘Bertie’ Gekoski has teamed up with Ashley Fruno, founder of Pasay Pups, to document the impact of poverty and the Covid-19 pandemic on people and pets living in public cemeteries in Pasay, the Philippines
In the photograph, a skeletal white dog stands on top of a tomb, his spiky vertebrae sharply visible through his ghostly fur. His jutting ribs and pelvic bones match the monotone of grey cemetery aisles and a prominent white cross in the backgr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lex Talamo. Photographs by Aaron Gekoski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Raising a child without a village is doable – but lonely’: readers on the highs and lows of having a lockdown baby]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/raising-a-child-without-a-village-is-doable-but-lonely-readers-on-the-highs-and-lows-of-having-a-lockdown-baby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/17/raising-a-child-without-a-village-is-doable-but-lonely-readers-on-the-highs-and-lows-of-having-a-lockdown-baby"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T06:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bringing a baby into the world can be tough at the best of times, and the pandemic has been far from that. Readers reflect on the pain and joy of new parenthood

I got pregnant right before lockdown in March 2020. I found pregnancy tough – for 14 weeks, I had morning sickness that felt like a constant hangover, and a lot of chronic fatigue throughout. Being able to work from home (and sometimes from my bed) allowed me to keep on top of things and remain as productive as usual. I can’t imagine having to go i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long lunches, tea with the mafia … how reporting Italy has changed over the years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rome correspondent Angela Giuffrida asks predecessor John Hooper how he covered the country in the pre-internet era 
Long before even meeting John Hooper, affectionately known among foreign correspondents in Rome as “the Hoops”, I considered him a guide.
In 2018, in preparation for the March general election, I bought his book, The Italians, seeking insight into Italian history, culture and mindset
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“I am desperate to bring people in again”: small museums in England on reopening]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/small-museums-in-england-on-reopening</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/17/small-museums-in-england-on-reopening"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As indoor attractions welcome visitors back, four museums tells us how they’ll showcase new exhibitions after a particularly tough year
From the new rooftop viewing deck of the Wordsworth museum, the veil of Grasmere looks mottled and spongy on a waterlogged day. The hills are smudged out by an ethereal cloud line that seeps into the fields beyond the four chimneys of Dove Cottage. From up here, it’s clear that the inspiration for Wordsworth’s poetry started right at his front door.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Catastrophic’: Sierra Leone sells rainforest for Chinese harbour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/sierra-leone-sells-rainforest-for-chinese-fishmeal-plant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/sierra-leone-sells-rainforest-for-chinese-fishmeal-plant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial deal with China would be ‘disastrous’ for fishing and protected rainforest, say opponents
A $55m (£39m) deal struck by the government of Sierra Leone with China to build an industrial fishing harbour on 100 hectares (250 acres) of beach and protected rainforest has been criticised as “a catastrophic human and ecological disaster” by conservationists, landowners and rights groups.
The gold and black sands of Black Johnson beach fringe the African nation’s Western Area Peninsula national park, h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karen McVeigh and Kabba Kargbo in Freetown</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mel B on domestic abuse, trauma and recovery: ‘In my mind there was no way out’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/mel-b-on-domestic-abuse-trauma-and-recovery-in-my-mind-there-was-no-way-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/mel-b-on-domestic-abuse-trauma-and-recovery-in-my-mind-there-was-no-way-out"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four years after escaping her marriage, the former Spice Girl talks about confidence, family – and why the pandemic has led to a rise in abusive relationships

Melanie Brown is in her tracksuit talking to me from her Leeds home. Her mother has popped round and is chomping away on an Easter egg she has just found, despite the fact that Brown has made her some “amazing” spicy curry soup for lunch. Her oldest daughter, Phoenix, is going to extreme measures to get her attention. Meanwhile, tiny yorkshire terrie…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK plastics sent for recycling in Turkey dumped and burned, Greenpeace finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/uk-plastics-sent-for-recycling-in-turkey-dumped-and-burned-greenpeace-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/uk-plastics-sent-for-recycling-in-turkey-dumped-and-burned-greenpeace-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Investigation reveals that ‘plastic waste coming from the UK to Turkey is an environmental threat, not an economic opportunity’
Turkey has become the latest destination for British plastic waste, which ends up dumped, burned or left to pollute the ocean, a Greenpeace investigation has found.
More than half of the plastic the British government says is being recycled are sent overseas, often to countries without the necessary infrastructure to do so. The UK exported 688,000 tonnes of discarded plastic packag…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photographers rewrite list of ‘big five’ animals to shoot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/new-big-5-photographers-rewrite-list-of-top-animals-to-shoot-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/17/new-big-5-photographers-rewrite-list-of-top-animals-to-shoot-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Project turns trophy hunters’ hit list into a conservation tool – and reveals the animals we most want to see caught on camera
For trophy hunters, the big five are the toughest, most dangerous animals to kill, but a photography project has turned the meaning of shooting on its head, creating a new list of the five most fantastic creatures to capture on camera.
More than 50,000 people from around the world voted for animals they most liked seeing pictures of as part of the New Big 5 wildlife photography list…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Weston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Everybody is angry’: Modi under fire over India’s Covid second wave]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/everybody-is-angry-modi-under-fire-over-indias-covid-second-wave</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/17/everybody-is-angry-modi-under-fire-over-indias-covid-second-wave"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T04:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From an approval rating of 80% earlier in the year, now tough questions are being asked of PM’s leadership
The missing persons complaint was filed at Parliament Street police station in Delhi as a matter of some urgency: it concerned the “disappearance of Prime Minister Narendra Modi” and 10 of his cabinet ministers during the pandemic.
Nagesh Kariyappa, the general secretary of the Indian national students’ union who filed the report to police on Friday, said he wanted the absence of political leadership w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen in Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Revolution dwells in the heart’: Myanmar’s poets cut down by the military]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/17/revolution-dwells-in-the-heart-myanmars-poets-cut-down-by-the-miltary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/17/revolution-dwells-in-the-heart-myanmars-poets-cut-down-by-the-miltary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Khet Thi, who captured the unflinching determination of the Myanmar public, was the third poet to be killed by the military since the coup
His words captured the unflinching determination of the Myanmar public in the face of military brutality: “They shoot in the head, but they don’t know revolution dwells in the heart.”
The poet Khet Thi was taken from his home in Shwebo, in the Sagaing region, last Saturday. The next day, his wife collected his body from a hospital. His organs had been removed, she told B…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian reporter in Yangon and Rebecca Ratcliffe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Short author Michael Lewis on the inside story of America’s failed Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/17/big-short-author-michael-lewis-on-the-inside-story-of-americas-failed-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/17/big-short-author-michael-lewis-on-the-inside-story-of-americas-failed-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T02:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The author and journalist Michael Lewis discusses reporting on a group of individuals who tried to alert the US government to the dangers of its inaction as coronavirus cases began to rise at an alarming rate
The author and journalist Michael Lewis has made a career of writing about people who see things coming that most of us don’t. His book The Big Short, which was turned into an Oscar-winning film, followed a group of investors who predicted the collapse of the American housing market in 2007. 
He tells …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Michael Lewis, produced by Courtney Yusuf and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: in celebration of youthful freedom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-big-picture-sven-jacobsen-photography-like-birds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-big-picture-sven-jacobsen-photography-like-birds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T06:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Sven Jacobsen’s painterly images, the young become as one with their environment, seemingly without a care in the world
Sven Jacobsen’s photographs ask interesting questions about innocence and bliss. A new book concentrates on images of youthful freedom; teenagers scale fences and climb trees and plunge into lakes, they skateboard and snog and do headstands and backflips and laugh like they will never, ever stop. Any of the pictures might lead advertising campaigns for spring water or blue jeans or perf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue cushion sea stars, short-nosed snakes and sea slugs: 21 days beneath the Timor Sea – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/16/blue-cushion-sea-stars-short-nosed-snakes-and-sea-slugs-21-days-beneath-the-timor-sea-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/16/blue-cushion-sea-stars-short-nosed-snakes-and-sea-slugs-21-days-beneath-the-timor-sea-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T20:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April, documentary photographer and film-maker Conor Ashleigh walked the gangplank of the research vessel Falkor in Darwin to begin a 21-day journey as part of an expedition with the Schmidt Ocean Institute. Having never spent more than a day or two at sea, Ashleigh felt as though he were heading into the unknown. There he discovered intriguing creatures in a seascape of vibrant colours in the pristine waters of Ashmore marine park in the Timor Sea

In the green room: the 2021 Nikon surf photography awar…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Conor Ashleigh/Schmidt Ocean Institute</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When a vinyl record becomes an artist’s canvas – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/15/when-a-vinyl-record-becomes-an-artists-canvas-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/15/when-a-vinyl-record-becomes-an-artists-canvas-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once an album is complete, a test pressing of it is usually made on vinyl. These fragile and extremely rare copies are often kept by musicians as souvenirs, but for a new exhibition called Pressing Matters, 33 test pressings were sent to 33 artists, who were given free rein to use the vinyl and sleeve as a canvas. This week, an auction of their work will be launched and all proceeds will go to mental health charity Music Support
Auction opens 20 May, ends 5 June at heliumlondon.com. On display at Matches, W…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is SendGrid? SMTP Email Newsletter Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>609d63e962ab9107fe5aa2ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-sendgrid-smpt-email-newsletter-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:31:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard of the term SMTP before, and wondered what it is. SMTP is a common method for handling email messages. Today I am going to explain what SMTP is, and how to use an SMTP provider such as SendGrid to send emails from your address. What Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React for Beginners: Complete React Cheatsheet for 2021]]></title>
        <id>609ea83362ab9107fe5aa920</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/react-for-beginners-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the React for Beginners guide. It's designed to teach you all the core React concepts that you need to know to start building React applications in 2021. I created this resource to give you the most complete and beginner-friendly path to learn React from the ground up. By]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Development for Beginners – Learn Basic HTML and CSS to Build Your First Web Page]]></title>
        <id>609e8c2162ab9107fe5aa77d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-development-for-beginners-basic-html-and-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:13:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how websites are built and designed? Do you want to learn the art of web development but you're not that tech savvy – yet? Well, then this tutorial is for you. It's an introduction to Web Development for beginners so you can learn the basics even if]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The therapy has never waned’: Guardian readers on their long relationships with us | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:55:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don Borland on how the paper helped him recover from TB, plus letters from Peter Bird, Elizabeth Jurd, Elizabeth Monger, Graham Head, John Boyle, Andrew Dean, Chas Ball, Tony Meacock, Janet Hulme and Robert Daws

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber. 

In 1953, at the age of 16, I caught tuberculosis. I was in a sanatorium for 18 months. Antibiotics were new and bed rest and lots of fresh air were de rigueur. So I pas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line …
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It’s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about …
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week two]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first of the six stories was reprinted in the Guardian last Friday (7 May). The second is below, with the other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Israel and Palestine on the brink of another war?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, discusses what has prompted the worst unrest in Israel and Palestine since 2014
Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, talks to Rachel Humphreys about the violence that has broken out between Israel and Palestine. In recent weeks there has been a sharp escalation in anger over Israel’s half-century occupation, its ever-deepening military grip over Palestinian life and a wave of evictions and demolitions. In Jerusalem, hundreds of Palesti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Oliver Holmes, produced by Ned Carter Miles and Axel Kacoutié, executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a basic grid inspector 
…
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340573</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2021-design-systems-survey-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T22:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friends at Sparkbox are doing a survey on design systems, as they do each year. Go ahead and fill it out if you please. Here are the results from last year. In both 2019 and 2020, the vibe was …
The post 2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create an Email Newsletter [2021 Tutorial] – Design, Layout, Send]]></title>
        <id>609414f32cd0545b5e943526</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-an-email-newsletter-design-layout-send/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T21:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you manage a large community, chances are you need a way to communicate updates to your members quickly and efficiently. An email newsletter can be a very effective way to do so. In this article, I am going to provide some tips and suggestions for maximizing the impact and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Software Testing? The 10 Most Common Types of Tests Developers Use in Projects]]></title>
        <id>609952396008950828b3ea8d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/types-of-software-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T19:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development and testing go hand in hand. And in the era of agile software development, with quick releases of small iterations, you should do testing more and more frequently.  In order to perform effective testing, you need to know about the different types of testing and when you should]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Tutorial – How to Work with Multiple Checkboxes]]></title>
        <id>609bcc6a62ab9107fe5a9f08</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-work-with-multiple-checkboxes-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T18:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handling multiple checkboxes in React is completely different from how you use regular HTML checkboxes. So in this article, we'll see how to work with multiple checkboxes in React. You will learn: How to use a checkbox as a Controlled Input in ReactHow to use the array map and reduce]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in the UK: how have you been affected by the Covid variant found in India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/13/living-in-the-uk-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-covid-variant-found-in-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/13/living-in-the-uk-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-covid-variant-found-in-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those in the UK who have been affected by a rise in cases of the Covid variant, first discovered in India
Scientists have raised concerns about the dramatic rise in cases of a Covid variant first discovered in India in some areas of the UK, including north-west England and London.
With evidence growing that the B.1.617.2 variant is more transmissible than the ‘Kent variant, which fuelled the UK’s second wave of infections, we want to hear from anyone who has been affected by the n…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340036</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/advanced-css-animation-using-cubic-bezier/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with complex CSS animations, there is a tendency to create expansive @keyframes with lots of declarations. There are a couple of tricks though that I want to talk about that might help make things easier, while staying in …
The post Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340118</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svgator-3-0-reshapes-the-way-you-create-and-animate-svg-with-extensive-new-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building animations can get complicated, particularly compelling animations where you aren’t just rolling a ball across the screen, but building a scene where many things are moving and changing in concert. When compelling animation is the goal, a timeline GUI …
The post SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['They saw me as mad and needing to be medicated’ | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T10:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, journalist Iman Amrani speaks to Chris, who after being diagnosed with schizophrenia spent a long time in the mental health system. They discuss medication, frustration at the system, and the importance of being listened to and heard. Dr Rufus May, a clinical psychologist, speaks about how he worked with Chris and other patients to show compassion and empathy, and how this can help people with mental health issues navigate society

Watch other episodes of Modern Mascul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Mat Heywood, Kyri Evangelou, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is the UK slashing its international aid budget? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s government has blamed the Covid crisis for its decision to cut its international aid budget, but is there more to it?
When David Cameron rose to become Conservative party leader, he set about identifying totemic policies that would show his party was changing. As well as promoting new thinking on the environment, he made an effort to highlight his commitment to overseas aid. When he was prime minister, his government signed a target of spending 0.7% of national income on foreign aid into law…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Patrick Wintour; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339960</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-disabled-buttons-more-inclusive/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T14:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about disabled buttons. Specifically, let’s get into why we use them and how we can do better than the traditional disabled attribute in HTML (e.g. <button disabled> ) to mark a button as disabled.
There are lots of …
The post Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandrina Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Israel: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Israel and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Israel and Hamas, Palestinian militants and Israeli jets have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Israel and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Palestine: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Palestine and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Hamas and Israel, Israeli jets and Palestinian militants have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Palestine and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340359</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-pie-timer-re-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitty reflected on an ancient blog post here on CSS-Tricks on how to make an animated pie timer. The old technique is still clever. The new technique is equally clever and much easier. I particularly like the steps() animation function…
The post CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I could build this during the weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340186</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/joaoqalves/i-could-build-this-during-the-weekend-aa093c5e"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many times have you heard that (or even uttered it under your own breath)? I know I’ve heard it in conversations. I also know I’ve wondered the same thing about a product or two — hey, the idea here …
The post I could build this during the weekend appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Gen CSS: @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339138</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/next-gen-css-container/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is experimenting with @container, a property within the CSS Working Group Containment Level 3 spec being championed by Miriam Suzanne of Oddbird, and a group of engineers across the web platform. @container brings us the ability to …
The post Next Gen CSS: @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Una Kravets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340106</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/distributed-persistent-rendering-dpr/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:33:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like Jamstack, Netlify is coining this term.
If your reaction is: great, a new thing I need to know about and learn, know that while Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) does involve some new things, this is actually a push …
The post Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in the UK: what are your plans on 17 May?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from those in the UK about how they feel and what they plan to do when restrictions are further eased
Hugging and mixing indoors with friends and family will be allowed in England from next week, and also in Scotland with the exception of Moray, which will “very likely” remain under level three restrictions after a surge in cases.
In Wales, up to six people from different households will be able to meet indoors at pubs, cafes and restaurants from Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day nine: economics - inequality, exploitation, unfairness

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>