<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-11T00:31:20.562Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-11T00:31:20.562Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Senators reach agreement on $1tn infrastructure package - live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/10/joe-biden-boris-johnson-uk-g7-covid-coronavirus-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/10/joe-biden-boris-johnson-uk-g7-covid-coronavirus-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T00:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New deal comes after negotiations between Biden and GOP stall
Christopher Wray called the Capitol attack an act of domestic terrorism
US president and first lady meet PM and wife in Cornwall

G7 leaders to call for fresh Covid investigation, leaked memo suggests

 1.15am BST 
 1.07am BST 
Andrew Brown Jr, a Black man who was shot by North Carolina deputies in April, died of a gunshot to the head, a state autopsy confirmed. 
An independent autopsy commissioned by Brown’s family had found the same. But a North Carolina prosecutor said Brown’s death at the hands of officers “while tragic, was justified”. The prosecutor also would not release body-camera video of the confrontation. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh (now) and Vivian Ho (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FBI chief calls Capitol attack domestic terrorism and rejects Trump’s fraud claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/10/capitol-attack-fbi-christopher-wray-congress</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/10/capitol-attack-fbi-christopher-wray-congress"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T23:35:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christopher Wray faces grilling from Democratic lawmakers over lead-up to 6 January insurrection
The FBI director, Christopher Wray, has said that the bureau considers the 6 January Capitol attack an act of “domestic terrorism” and suggested that “serious charges” were still to come in its continuing criminal investigation.
Testifying before Congress on Thursday, the director rubbished Donald Trump’s claims about a stolen presidential election. “We did not find evidence of fraud that could have changed the outcome of the election,” he told lawmakers on the House judiciary committee.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Life review – an ode to precious moments and stage management]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/11/after-life-review-jack-thorne-dorfman-national-theatre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/11/after-life-review-jack-thorne-dorfman-national-theatre"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dorfman, London
Jack Thorne’s adaptation of Hirokazu Kore-eda’s film about dead souls living out eternal memories is charmingly done
The last year has been one awful thing after another. It’s a relief, then, to spend some time thinking of the very best of times. In Jack Thorne’s After Life, adapted from the award-winning 1998 film by Hirokazu Kore-eda, the newly deceased get to pick the one memory they would like to live out for eternity.
Bunny Christie’s set design lines the back wall of the Dorfman from top to toe with filing cabinets. In this co-production with Headlong, the afterlife is not heaven or hell, but a retro, greyscale office. Over the course of the evening, we see a week of work in this bureaucratic limbo, as the dead (the “guided”) worry over which memory to pick, while the official team (the “guides”) work out how best to recreate them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Wyver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: our writers predict the winners, losers and breakout stars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/11/euro-2020-writers-predict-winners-losers-breakout-stars</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/11/euro-2020-writers-predict-winners-losers-breakout-stars"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[France to win, Turkey to spring a surprise and Jude Bellingham to make his mark but Covid disruption is also a worry
Nick Ames France and England, although that eventuality may depend on the latter winning their group and navigating a fiendish last-16 tie against Germany or Portugal.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 23: Hungary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/11/euro-2020-team-guides-part-23-hungary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/11/euro-2020-team-guides-part-23-hungary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The injury-hit Magyars have landed in the Group of Death but will host two of their group games in Budapest
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
This will be a truly unique Euros for Hungarian fans as it is the first major tournament where the team can play at home in a full Puskás Aréna. The new stadium in Budapest has hosted several big games in the past year, such as Champions League games and the European Super Cup, but Hungary’s opening game against Portugal will be the second time they have played there in front of fans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matyas Szeli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers aim to spur domestic tourism with cut-price UK rail pass]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/ministers-aim-to-spur-domestic-tourism-with-cut-price-uk-rail-pass</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/11/ministers-aim-to-spur-domestic-tourism-with-cut-price-uk-rail-pass"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Lottery will also launch £10m voucher scheme for discounts at attractions after summer

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The government has announced plans to kickstart the domestic tourism industry after months of restrictions on travel, socialising and hospitality, including a new rail pass and vouchers for popular attractions.
In a bid to encourage people to holiday at home instead of abroad, an alternative to the “BritRail” pass for foreign visitors will be launched, letting Britons travel across the UK cheaper on certain days of their break, and possibly allowing children to travel free.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson urged to keep English Covid rules in place beyond 21 June]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/boris-johnson-urged-to-keep-english-covid-rules-in-place-beyond-21-june</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/boris-johnson-urged-to-keep-english-covid-rules-in-place-beyond-21-june"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T22:59:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public health expert says social distancing and mask guidance should stay in place for foreseeable future

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Boris Johnson has been urged to pull the plug on the final easing of coronavirus restrictions across England later this month, as he prepares to consider the latest data this weekend.
With just 10 days until the final stage of his roadmap, when all legal limits on social contact could be removed, the prime minister is under growing pressure to err on the side of caution given a surge in cases of the Delta variant, first discovered in India.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dina Asher-Smith continues winning streak with dominant Florence victory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/dina-asher-smith-continues-winning-streak-with-dominant-florence-victory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/dina-asher-smith-continues-winning-streak-with-dominant-florence-victory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T22:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sprinter races home in 22.06sec for second Diamond League win
Laura Muir runs second-best 1500m of career to finish third

First Dina Asher-Smith sent an ominous warning to her Olympic rivals on the track by sauntering to the third-quickest 200m time of her career. Then she did it again with six well-chosen words and a smile: “I definitely have more in me.”
The 25-year-old’s time of 22.06sec in Florence broke a meeting record that had been held for 22 years by Marion Jones. And, for good measure, it was also the second fastest time in the world this year – just 0.03 behind Shaunae Miller-Uibo.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iran sends warship on rare Atlantic mission amid Venezuela speculation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/iran-sends-warship-on-rare-atlantic-mission-amid-venezuela-speculation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/iran-sends-warship-on-rare-atlantic-mission-amid-venezuela-speculation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T21:59:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The destroyer Sahand and the intelligence-gathering vessel Makran departed last month 
An Iranian destroyer and support vessel are now sailing in the Atlantic Ocean on a rare mission far from the Islamic Republic, Iran’s state TV has reported, amid speculation that the ships could be bound for Venezuela. 
The destroyer Sahand and the intelligence-gathering vessel Makran departed last month from Iran’s southern port of Bandar Abbas, said Adm Habibollah Sayyari, Iran’s deputy army chief, on Thursday. He described the mission as the Iranian navy’s longest and most challenging voyage yet, without elaborating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AP</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK to give 100m Covid vaccine doses to poorer countries within a year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/uk-to-give-100m-covid-vaccine-doses-to-poorer-countries-within-a-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/uk-to-give-100m-covid-vaccine-doses-to-poorer-countries-within-a-year"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least 1bn doses due from G7 but campaigners say package does not address structural problems

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The UK will donate 100m surplus coronavirus vaccine doses within the next year to low-income countries as part of at least 1bn doses due from the G7.
The US has promised to buy 500m Pfizer vaccines at a cost of $3bn for distribution to 100 poorer countries, with 200m to be distributed this year, in addition to releasing 80m of its surplus by the end of June.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour and Sarah Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Team GB athletes will not face strict medal targets for Tokyo Olympics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/team-gb-athletes-will-not-face-strict-medal-targets-for-tokyo-olympics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/team-gb-athletes-will-not-face-strict-medal-targets-for-tokyo-olympics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Competition data is missing due to pandemic
Team GB aiming to take 375 athletes to Games

Team GB’s athletes will not face medal targets for the Tokyo Olympics after it was revealed that its experts do not have enough data to make accurate forecasts, because of the Covid pandemic.
Mark England, the British Olympic Association’s chef de mission for Tokyo, was asked whether Team GB’s athletes were capable of exceeding the 67 medals won at the Rio 2016 Games. “We haven’t put a medal target on it – and we won’t, to be honest,” he said. “I don’t think UK Sport will either.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Macron warns Johnson ‘nothing is negotiable’ over Northern Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/macron-warns-johnson-nothing-is-negotiable-over-northern-ireland-protocol</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/macron-warns-johnson-nothing-is-negotiable-over-northern-ireland-protocol"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T20:10:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 summit risks being overshadowed by the bitter standoff over Brexit
The French president last night ramped up the pressure on Boris Johnson over the Northern Ireland protocol by insisting “nothing is negotiable” as the G7 summit of world leaders risked being overshadowed by the bitter standoff over Brexit.
In a defiant intervention as he prepared to travel to the UK, Emmanuel Macron warned Boris Johnson that France is not open to renegotiating any aspect of the protocol – and even appeared to raise questions about whether the UK could be trusted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart, Kim Willsher and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ollie Robinson given time off by Sussex for his ‘mental health and wellbeing’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/ollie-robinson-given-time-off-by-sussex-for-his-mental-health-and-well-being</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/ollie-robinson-given-time-off-by-sussex-for-his-mental-health-and-well-being"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T19:59:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sussex statement: ‘Ollie has made clear the shame he feels’
Rory Burns says England concentrating on winning second Test

Ollie Robinson has pulled out of playing for Sussex this weekend citing the need for a break as the England and Wales Cricket Board continues to deliberate over the offensive teenage tweets that plunged the sport into a crisis.
Robinson, 27, was stood down from the England side taking on New Zealand at Edgbaston this week, with Joe Root side’s fighting back from a collapse on day one of the second Test as Dan Lawrence’s unbeaten 67 took them to 258 for seven.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing NHS waiting times could cost £40bn, leaked No 10 estimates show]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/fixing-nhs-waiting-times-could-cost-40bn-leaked-no-10-estimates-show</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/fixing-nhs-waiting-times-could-cost-40bn-leaked-no-10-estimates-show"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T19:37:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Downing Street thinks spending can wait because public not ‘distressed’ about long delays yet, source says

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Boris Johnson may have to spend up to £40bn to try to repair NHS waiting times and end the long delays being faced by patients, according to unpublished Downing Street estimates.
Calculations for No 10 drawn up by the Cabinet Office make clear that the prime minister may have to commit anywhere between £2bn and £10bn a year for up to four years, on top of core NHS funding, to tackle what is fast becoming a major political headache for the government.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell and Pamela Duncan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Krejcikova saves match point to set up French Open final with Pavlyuchenkova]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/krejcikova-saves-match-point-to-set-up-french-open-final-with-pavlyuchenkova</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/10/krejcikova-saves-match-point-to-set-up-french-open-final-with-pavlyuchenkova"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T19:37:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unseeded Barbora Krejcikova beats Maria Sakkari 7-5, 4-6, 9-7
Anastasia Pavlyuchenkova overcomes Tamara Zidansek 7-5, 6-3

The ball hung high in the sky for what felt like an eternity, offering Barbora Krejcikova all the time in the world to think about how badly things could end. Yet despite making 29 backhand unforced errors on Thursday afternoon, as she stood a point away from losing the biggest singles match of her career when serving at 3-5, 30-40 in the third set, she refused. Krejcikova skipped forward and swiped a nerveless backhand drive volley out of the air to save match point with an angled winner.
Forty-five minutes later, after three hours and 17 minutes of nerves, doubt and tremendous fight, the unseeded Krejcikova finally recovered to defeat Maria Sakkari, the 17th seed, 7-5, 4-6, 9-7 to reach a grand slam singles final for the first time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United have £67m Jadon Sancho bid rejected by Dortmund]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/manchester-united-have-67m-jadon-sancho-bid-rejected-by-borussia-dortmund</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/manchester-united-have-67m-jadon-sancho-bid-rejected-by-borussia-dortmund"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T19:27:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[German club want £77.5m for England winger
United agree terms with Sancho of about £350,000 a week

Manchester United have had an opening bid of £67m for Jadon Sancho turned down by Borussia Dortmund, who are unwilling to lower their asking price for the England winger.
Dortmund want £77.5m (€90m) for Sancho. The Bundesliga club, who are determined to resist Chelsea’s attempts to buy Erling Haaland, will not stand in the 21-year-old’s way if United meet their asking price.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At the Euros, winning teams can start badly. It’s how they respond that matters | Pernille Harder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/10/euros-winning-teams-can-start-badly-how-they-respond-matters-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/10/euros-winning-teams-can-start-badly-how-they-respond-matters-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[France are favourites, but I like the look of Portugal. And the question for England is can they handle the pressure?
In an ideal world you would start a tournament perfectly and go through it winning everything. That’s what every team at the Euros wants to do. It is the pressure and expectation around that desire for perfection that derails so many teams and campaigns, because a loss early on becomes a big deal. But you can lose and progress. I was part of the Denmark team that showed that at the Euros in 2017: we lost to the Netherlands (who finished as champions) in our group but still got out of the group and reached the final.
How you cope with losing early on is important. If you lose a game you can’t let it get too deep, you can’t let the criticism and talk get to you. You have to move on to the next game, develop and improve through the tournament.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pernille Harder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dani Karavan obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/10/dani-karavan-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/10/dani-karavan-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T18:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artist who found fame in the world of environmental sculpture, a new medium that emerged in the 1960s
An environmental piece over 3km long, titled Axe Majeur (1980-ongoing), in the French town of Cergy-Pontoise, north-west of Paris; Passages (1990-94), a memorial to the philosopher Walter Benjamin in Portbou, Spain; Murou Art Forest (1998-2006) in Japan; and Way of Human Rights in Nuremberg, Germany (1989-93), are among the most celebrated works designed by the artist Dani Karavan, who has died aged 90.
Karavan practised various art forms, including painting and drawing, stage-set design and wall reliefs, but it was environmental sculpture, a new medium that emerged in the 1960s and to which he contributed significantly, that brought him fame. He created more than 70 environmental pieces in Israel, Europe and east Asia, some of which became tourist attractions and pilgrimage sites.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dalia Manor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on Joe Biden’s arrival at the G7 talks – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/10/ben-jennings-on-joe-bidens-arrival-at-the-g7-talks-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/10/ben-jennings-on-joe-bidens-arrival-at-the-g7-talks-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings promises No 10 revelations in paid-for newsletter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/dominic-cummings-promises-no-10-revelations-paid-for-newsletter-substack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/dominic-cummings-promises-no-10-revelations-paid-for-newsletter-substack"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T18:25:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM’s former top aide to offer some Substack posts for free and charge for access to extra features such as Q&A sessions
Dominic Cummings is planning to publish a paid-for newsletter in which subscribers can learn about his time inside Downing Street.
Boris Johnson’s former top aide has launched a profile on Substack, a platform that allows people to sign up to newsletter mailing lists.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Addiction treatment harder to get since councils took over, says Tory MP]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/addiction-treatment-harder-to-get-since-councils-took-over-care-says-tory-mp</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/addiction-treatment-harder-to-get-since-councils-took-over-care-says-tory-mp"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T18:01:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shift of responsibility from NHS has led to ‘serious shortcomings’ in service in England, ex-health minister finds
Fewer people with alcohol and drug problems are being treated since responsibility for their care was shifted from the NHS to local councils in England, a former Conservative health minister has found.
Patients’ care has become poorer, specialist detoxification beds are now harder to access and the cost of treatment has spiralled, freedom of information (FoI) requests show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Covid lab-leak theory: act on what we know | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-view-on-the-covid-lab-leak-theory-act-on-what-we-know</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-view-on-the-covid-lab-leak-theory-act-on-what-we-know"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:54:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This pandemic’s precise origins may never be certain. We must address both zoonotic transmission risks and lab security

When something goes terribly wrong, it is human instinct to look for the human hand – perhaps to reassure ourselves that life is not wholly beyond our control. As the flu pandemic reached the US just over a century ago, some blamed German agents. So it wasn’t surprising when people claimed that coronavirus had leaked from – or was even manufactured in – a laboratory in Wuhan, China, where the outbreak began. Nor was it surprising when Donald Trump and his allies promoted the story as they sought to pass the buck for the mounting death toll in the US and embellish the then president’s China-hawk credentials.
It is more striking that the idea is suddenly gaining ground. Last month, Joe Biden ordered his intelligence agencies to intensify their efforts to study Covid’s origins; one reportedly leans towards the lab hypothesis, though others in the US and abroad disagree. Now, a leaked draft communique from the G7 summit in Cornwall has said that leaders will call for a new World Health Organization investigation into the pandemic’s beginnings. More scientists have suggested that the idea should be taken seriously.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on national identity: bravo Gareth Southgate | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-view-on-national-identity-bravo-gareth-southgate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-view-on-national-identity-bravo-gareth-southgate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Nancy Mitford to Euro 2020, ‘Englishness’ can change – and for the better
In some ways, Nancy Mitford’s novel The Pursuit of Love ought not to be as beloved by readers as it is. Its mise-en-scène is so antithetical to the experiences of those growing up today that it should be utterly alienating. And yet it is not. Its wit, its romance and its poignancy still have enormous power. This last aspect – the gentle melancholia that mists the novel – is somewhat stripped away by the recently screened BBC TV adaptation, the arch, stylised aesthetic of which places an ironic distance between the action and the viewer.
But for all the apparent silliness of The Pursuit of Love, it is a serious novel, whose subject is, above all, Englishness. True, this Englishness is a monument to past ideals. It is also an Englishness that is oblivious to any notion of cultural or political distinctiveness in Wales, Scotland or Northern Ireland; like other writers of the time, not least George Orwell, Mitford appears to have collapsed British identity into an idea of England in a way that would be unacceptable today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US drugmaker Regeneron under fire for ‘excessive’ payouts to executives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/us-drugmaker-regeneron-under-fire-for-excessive-payouts-to-executives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/us-drugmaker-regeneron-under-fire-for-excessive-payouts-to-executives"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:48:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advisory groups questioned whether the upfront payouts were in the best interests of shareholders
The US drugmaker Regeneron, whose Covid treatment was hailed as a “cure” by Donald Trump last year, has come under fire from two influential shareholder advisory groups over “excessive” payouts made to its top executives ahead of its annual meeting on Friday.
The investor advisory group Glass Lewis said it was “highly concerned” at the New York-based firm’s decision last year to ditch annual stock options. Instead it will replace them with an upfront five-year grant of performance-restricted stock units worth $130m (£92m) for each of its top two executives – Leonard Schleifer, the Regeneron chief executive, and George Yancopoulos, the chief scientific officer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graduates face highest unemployment rate since austerity era – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/graduates-england-face-highest-unemployment-rate-since-austerity-era-pandemic-job-shortages</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/graduates-england-face-highest-unemployment-rate-since-austerity-era-pandemic-job-shortages"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:16:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department for Education survey finds young people in England hit hardest by job shortages due to pandemic

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Unemployment among recent graduates has risen to levels last seen during the austerity era, with young people worst affected by job shortages due to the pandemic, according to official data.
The unemployment rate for recent graduates in England aged 21 to 30 reached 6.3% in 2020, after it had gradually fallen over nearly a decade since a peak of 6.5% in 2012, in the middle of the coalition government’s austerity drive.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall and Richard Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The city is buzzing again’: Marseille reduces curfew hours after winter lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/10/the-city-is-buzzing-again-marseille-reduces-curfew-hours-after-winter-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/10/the-city-is-buzzing-again-marseille-reduces-curfew-hours-after-winter-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:13:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a Mediterranean city where summer is lived outdoors, residents delight in revelling in the streets once more
In a city as boisterous as Marseille, a summer curfew can be considered something of an affront. Summer is when the Marseillais live outdoors. From May to September, a post-work apéro can easily stretch well into the night. And at the weekend anything goes. As the days became sunnier, France’s second city began to chafe under an early evening curfew that had been in place since October. But on Wednesday there was some respite, with the nightly national curfew moved from 9pm to 11pm.
The city centre squares where the Marseillais come to play – Cours d’Estienne d’Orves, Cours Julien and La Plaine – heaved with revellers delighted to be out beyond sunset. Around the Old Port of Marseille, happy crowds converged on bars, shisha cafes and restaurants. On the corniche, joggers took advantage of the cooler twilight air. The Maghreb-inflected rap for which the city is famous drifted from passing cars.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mary Fitzgerald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are school trips a threat to the security of Britain's borders? | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/are-school-trips-a-threat-to-the-security-of-britains-borders</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/are-school-trips-a-threat-to-the-security-of-britains-borders"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:08:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to new visa rules that could hamper school trips to the UK and make a mockery of the idea of ‘global Britain’
Regarding the point of your article (School trips to UK from EU could halve as Brexit hits cultural exchanges, 4 June), we have a very significant paradox. The UK government talks about “global Britain”, but it seems to completely fail to understand the increasing role of soft power in having a global influence.
To have any truly global role, the world needs to “know” the UK, including its culture, its education, its media, its values, its history, and everything else about the country that has merit. A world where its future leaders have great empathy for the UK is a sine qua non for establishing global Britain.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop and search: how community groups can help build trust in policing | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/10/stop-and-search-how-community-groups-can-help-build-trust-in-policing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/10/stop-and-search-how-community-groups-can-help-build-trust-in-policing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:06:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Bourne says the majority of interactions between the police and public are handled professionally, but mistrust in some communities could be mitigated by local groups
In my role as the deputy chair of the Southwark police independent advisory group (IAG) in London, I have been participating in sessions to view body-worn video and offer feedback. I am pleased to report that the majority of the examples shown to me have included police officers successfully interacting with suspects in a friendly and courteous manner, acting professionally and sometimes with humour.
But on 3 June, I observed a stop and search on a busy main road outside my home and asked myself: “How many plainclothes police officers does it take to stop (in two unmarked cars) a young black moped rider?” Answer: eight. Though the officers were professional, there were too many of them. Was it necessary to handcuff the lad while they searched him? The biker looked terrified. He was innocent. Nothing was found. The eight officers left.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coll: Violin Concerto; Mural, etc review | Andrew Clements's classical album of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/10/coll-violin-concerto-mural-etc-review-on-another-plane-altogether</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/10/coll-violin-concerto-mural-etc-review-on-another-plane-altogether"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patricia Kopatchinskaja/Luxembourg PO/Gustavo Gimeno
(Pentatone)
The violinist has unlocked new expressiveness in the Spanish composer’s music since Gimeno introduced them
The first disc devoted exclusively to orchestral music by Francisco Coll traces a neat trajectory through his development over the last decade and a half. The earliest piece here is Coll’s opus 1, Aqua Cinerea, composed in 2005 when he was 19; the most recent is his Violin Concerto, written for Patricia Kopatchinskaja in 2019. It’s been a hugely impressive development, taking the flair for vivid orchestral colouring and stark, sometimes shocking juxtapositions of imagery that was evident from the start in Coll’s music in ever more distinctive and personal directions, while never forgetting the debt his music owes to tradition, whether modernist or more specifically Spanish.
The nervy, unstable rhythms of Hidd’n Blue, first performed by the London Symphony Orchestra under Coll’s teacher Thomas Adès in 2012, largely continue where Aqua Cinerea left off. But the five-movement Mural, which followed four years later, is much more substantial, almost symphonic attempt to reconcile past and present, to build something fresh from the rubble of musical history, while the Four Iberian Miniatures, for violin and chamber orchestra, lovingly and wittily adopts the rhythms and rawness of Spanish dance from tango to flamenco.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Clements</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fingered for failings he’d forgotten, Matt Hancock wriggles free]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/fingered-for-failings-hed-forgotten-matt-hancock-wriggles-free</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/fingered-for-failings-hed-forgotten-matt-hancock-wriggles-free"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:59:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary off the hook after Dom fails to produce evidence of Covid policy wrongdoings

It wasn’t the seven-hour Netflix mini-series of Dominic Cummings, but it was still a four-hour marathon. It was also something of a mystery. Almost everyone’s recollection of the last year and a half has been of a government playing catchup. Too late to lock down in March 2020, too late to lock down in November 2020, too late to lock down again in January 2021, too late to close the border with India in April 2021 and prevent the Delta variant.
And that’s not to mention the release of untested hospital patients into care homes, shortages of PPE, the billions poured into an – initially at least – inadequate test-and-trace system and 130,000 deaths. Just about the only thing the government got right was its vaccine programme.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tory MP accuses Ofsted of ‘massive failure’ over sexual abuse in schools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/tory-mp-maria-miller-accuses-ofsted-failure-sexual-abuse-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/tory-mp-maria-miller-accuses-ofsted-failure-sexual-abuse-schools"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:47:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maria Miller issues strong criticism after publication of findings five years on from landmark report on scale of problem in England
The Conservative MP Maria Miller has accused Ofsted of a “massive safeguarding failure” after a report by the schools inspectorate showed that sexual harassment and abuse in schools is so commonplace that pupils don’t bother to report it.
Miller was chair of the Commons women and equalities select committee five years ago when it published a landmark report that exposed for the first time the scale of sexual harassment, abuse and violence, endured primarily by girls, in England’s schools.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The DUP’s new leadership continues to rail against the modern world | Susan McKay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/dup-leadership-paul-givan-northern-ireland-edwin-poots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/dup-leadership-paul-givan-northern-ireland-edwin-poots"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:37:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Paul Givan as Northern Ireland first minister and Edwin Poots as leader, the patriarchs are in no mood for compromise
Regardless of politics, the DUP’s Paul Givan might have gained a little bit of everybody’s sympathy on Tuesday when, just hours after being nominated first minister, he had to listen to his dad saying on the BBC that he was afraid his boy might be a bit young and inexperienced for the role. “We just hope and pray that he makes a job of it,” Alan Givan said. However, Givan Jr, who is 39, clearly has the full confidence of his political father figure, Edwin Poots. He started out as Poots’ constituency assistant when he was still a teenager, and has not been seen without a wide grin on his face since Poots became the DUP’s leader a few weeks ago.
Givan Sr was a prison officer; Givan Jr has said that at the age of 16 he had been “captured emotionally” by the Rev Ian Paisley. He has strong tastes – those were the years when Paisley was raving about bitter harvests and apocalypse if the Orange Order was not let walk through the Catholic part of Portadown, and vowing to “smash” the Good Friday agreement, which he depicted as a “partnership with the men of blood”. (The old sectarian warriors who took him literally at the time and killed Catholics to prove it are champing at the bit again these days. Northern Ireland, we are told, is under the “jackboot” of the EU).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Susan McKay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fishmongers’ Hall terrorist Usman Khan was lawfully killed, inquest jury finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/fishmongers-hall-terrorist-usman-khan-lawfully-killed-inquest-jury-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/fishmongers-hall-terrorist-usman-khan-lawfully-killed-inquest-jury-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:35:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Khan was shot dead after fatally stabbing Jack Merritt and Saskia Jones during a prisoner rehabilitation conference in November 2019
Usman Khan, a convicted terrorist, was lawfully killed on London Bridge by armed police after stabbing two people at a prisoner rehabilitation event while wearing a fake suicide belt, an inquest jury has concluded.
The 28-year-old jihadi, originally from Stoke-on-Trent, was shot dead by armed officers outside Fishmongers’ Hall in November 2019. Minutes earlier he had killed Saskia Jones, 23, and Jack Merritt, 25, who were helping to organise the event in the hall, hosted by Learning Together, a prisoner education initiative run by Cambridge University.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Weaver and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global banking regulators call for toughest rules for cryptocurrencies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/10/global-banking-regulators-cryptocurrencies-bitcoin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/10/global-banking-regulators-cryptocurrencies-bitcoin"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Growth of crypto-assets threatens financial stability and could increase risks faced by banks, they warn
Global regulators have said cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin should come with the toughest bank capital rules to avoid putting the wider financial system at risk should their value collapse suddenly.
The Basel Committee on Banking Supervision, which consists of regulators from the world’s leading financial centres, is proposing a “new conservative prudential treatment” for crypto-assets that would force banks to put aside enough capital to cover 100% of potential losses.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sun publisher pays Sir Simon Hughes phone-hacking damages]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/10/sun-publisher-pays-former-mp-simon-hughes-phone-hacking-damages-after-tabloid-outed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/10/sun-publisher-pays-former-mp-simon-hughes-phone-hacking-damages-after-tabloid-outed"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T16:09:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Lib Dem MP claimed he had been ‘victim of unlawful information gathering’ after tabloid outed him
The publisher of the Sun has paid a substantial sum to settle a phone-hacking claim brought by the former Liberal Democrat MP Sir Simon Hughes, who claimed he was illegally targeted by reporters wanting to out his sexuality.
Hughes claimed “he had been the victim of unlawful information gathering by various journalists and executives at the Sun” who were intent on publishing details of his past relationships with men.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We proved in the high court that Michael Gove broke the law. So what happens now? | Jolyon Maugham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/high-court-michael-gove-law-cronyism-covid-contracts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/high-court-michael-gove-law-cronyism-covid-contracts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our legal victory, which proves there has been institutionalised cronyism over Covid contracts, will have real-world effects 

Jolyon Maugham QC is a barrister and director of Good Law Project

Shut out the noise and the story is a simple one.
The pandemic was starting to hit. To manage public health, government needed to influence public behaviour. To influence public behaviour it needed to understand how different health messages would land. To understand how messages would land it needed feedback from focus groups. And getting focus groups meant getting external help.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jolyon Maugham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wife of El Chapo admits helping run Mexican drug cartel in US plea deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/emma-coronel-aispuro-el-chapo-guilty-plea</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/emma-coronel-aispuro-el-chapo-guilty-plea"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:48:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emma Coronel Aispuro pleads guilty to three counts
31-year-old says she conspired in husband’s 2015 prison break

The wife of the Mexican drug kingpin Joaquín “El Chapo” Guzmán has pleaded guilty to charges in the US and admitted that she helped her husband run his multibillion-dollar criminal empire.
Emma Coronel Aispuro, wearing a green jail uniform, appeared in federal court in Washington on Thursday and pleaded guilty to three counts of conspiring to distribute illegal drugs, conspiring to launder money and conspiring to assist the Sinaloa drug cartel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man who slapped Emmanuel Macron gets four-month jail sentence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/man-who-slapped-emmanuel-macron-gets-four-month-jail-sentence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/man-who-slapped-emmanuel-macron-gets-four-month-jail-sentence"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:47:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Court in Valence convicts Damien Tarel on charge of violence against a person invested with public authority
A French court has sentenced a 28-year-old man to four months in prison for slapping France’s president, Emmanuel Macron, in the face.
Damien Tarel was quickly arrested after the swipe that caught Macron’s left cheek with an audible thwack on Tuesday, as the French leader was greeting a crowd.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Valence</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After a year at home, children with disabilities deserve priority vaccination | Frances Ryan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/children-disabilities-priority-vaccination-england-education-shielding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/children-disabilities-priority-vaccination-england-education-shielding"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:46:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Much has been said about pupils in England missing months of education, but little about the plight of those shielding
They disappeared more than a year ago and many are still out of sight. When the pandemic hit, 53,000 under-18s in England with disabilities that made them vulnerable to coronavirus began to shield away at home.
Kept off school long after their classmates went back, and away from friends, they have found their childhoods put on hold. And while the vaccine rollout gave high-risk adults some reprieve in the new year, those aged under 16, who have not been eligible for any vaccine, are still living in limbo.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Frances Ryan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Record number of women in England and Wales had abortions in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/record-number-of-women-in-england-and-wales-had-abortions-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/record-number-of-women-in-england-and-wales-had-abortions-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:46:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increase put down to women being able to seek treatment at home and financial uncertainty
A record number of women in England and Wales had an abortion last year, with the rise particularly among women aged 30 and over.
A total of 209,917 abortions were reported in 2020, with the numbers rising year on year and up from 207,384 in 2019. The largest increases in abortion rates by age were among women aged 30 to 34 with a rise from 16.5 per 1,000 in 2010 to 21.9 in 2020.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Takeaway food and drink litter dominates ocean plastic, study shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/takeaway-food-and-drink-litter-dominates-ocean-plastic-study-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/takeaway-food-and-drink-litter-dominates-ocean-plastic-study-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:41:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just 10 plastic products make up 75% of all items and scientists say the pollution must be stopped at source
Plastic items from takeaway food and drink dominate the litter in the world’s oceans, according to the most comprehensive study to date.
Single-use bags, plastic bottles, food containers and food wrappers are the four most widespread items polluting the seas, making up almost half of the human-made waste, the researchers found. Just 10 plastic products, also including plastic lids and fishing gear, accounted for three-quarters of the litter, due to their widespread use and extremely slow degradation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Navalny backers see cautionary tale in Russian raids on Jehovah’s Witnesses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/navalny-backers-see-cautionary-tale-in-russian-raids-on-jehovahs-witnesses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/navalny-backers-see-cautionary-tale-in-russian-raids-on-jehovahs-witnesses"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:33:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: members of religious group declared extremist in 2017 have faced arrests, surveillance and prison
The decision by a Moscow court to declare Alexei Navalny’s nationwide political organisation as “extremist” adds the group to a list associated with terrorist organisations such as al-Qaida and Islamic State.
But for a guide to how Russia could treat Navalny’s supporters, a better example is the Jehovah’s Witnesses, a non-violent religious group that has felt the full extent of Russia’s law on extremism.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth Moscow correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MEPs back action against European commission over Poland and Hungary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/meps-back-action-against-european-commission-over-rule-of-law-sanctions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/meps-back-action-against-european-commission-over-rule-of-law-sanctions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:33:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European parliament now expected to prepare case over failure to trigger sanctions against Poland and Hungary
MEPs have backed legal proceedings by the European parliament against the European Commission over a failure to trigger financial sanctions against Poland and Hungary for undermining the rule of law.
The parliament’s legal service is now expected to prepare a case to be lodged at the European court of justice later this year, pitting two EU institutions against each other in the EU’s highest court, with only the formality of approval by key committees of the chamber now required.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 leaders depicted in Mount Recyclemore e-waste sculpture]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/mount-recyclemore-g7-leaders-depicted-electronic-waste-sculpture-cornwall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/mount-recyclemore-g7-leaders-depicted-electronic-waste-sculpture-cornwall"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:12:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cornwall art installation created from 20,000 pieces of discarded tech highlights growing threat it poses to environment
The seven giant faces loom above the dunes, gazing sombrely over swathes of bright sea thrift towards the ocean.
Even before the G7 had sat down to begin their Cornish summit, Mount Recyclemore, a sculpture made of discarded electronic waste depicting the visages of the seven leaders, looked bound to be one of the stars of the show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Documentary-maker Marc Isaacs: ‘I like to provoke, but not to be seen’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/10/documentary-maker-marc-isaacs-i-like-to-provoke-but-not-to-be-seen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/10/documentary-maker-marc-isaacs-i-like-to-provoke-but-not-to-be-seen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He counts Louis Theroux as a fan but struggles to find funding for his off-beat drama-doc hybrids. He explains why he uses non-actors to play themselves – and why he filmed his cleaner finding a cat with a defrosted pigeon in its mouth 
While making his first documentary 20 years ago, Marc Isaacs spent two months in the lift of a London tower block, filming the residents coming and going, and asking whimsical questions (“What did you dream about last night?”). That short film, Lift, also featured a fly, which he bought from a pet shop; the insect expired in the final shot. Isaacs hadn’t intended that to symbolise the death of the fly-on-the-wall genre – “It only occurred to me afterwards” – but it fits his philosophy, which spurns any notions of unmediated reality. For two decades, he has prodded, coaxed and intervened, all from behind the camera. “I like to provoke,” he says, “but not to be seen.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Gilbey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince Charles urges businesses to help lead way on climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/prince-charles-urges-businesses-to-help-lead-way-on-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/prince-charles-urges-businesses-to-help-lead-way-on-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prince says private-sector innovation and finance is vital, otherwise ‘we just don’t stand a chance’
Prince Charles has said businesses must lead the way alongside governments in tackling the climate emergency.
Before the start of the G7 summit in Cornwall on Friday, he told a gathering of political and business leaders that private-sector cash and knowhow was essential, and businesses needed strong policy signals from government.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China’s Uyghurs living in a ‘dystopian hellscape’, says Amnesty report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/10/china-uyghur-xinjiang-dystopian-hellscape-says-amnesty-international-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/10/china-uyghur-xinjiang-dystopian-hellscape-says-amnesty-international-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Widespread internment, torture and rights abuses have been claimed by former detainees as Beijing continues a policy of denial 

Amnesty International has collected new evidence of human rights abuses in the Xinjiang region of China, which it says has become a “dystopian hellscape” for hundreds of thousands of Muslims subjected to mass internment and torture.
The human rights organisation has collected more than 50 new accounts from Uyghurs, Kazakhs and other predominantly Muslim ethnic minorities who claim to have been subjected to mass internment and torture in police stations and camps in the region.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who is Patrick Drahi, the billionaire who has become BT’s biggest investor?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/patrick-drahi-billionaire-bt-investor-telecoms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/patrick-drahi-billionaire-bt-investor-telecoms"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moroccan-born telecoms mogul and art lover has surprised investors with £2.2bn swoop on BT
Patrick Drahi has built a $12bn fortune making shrewd bets in telecoms, his latest being the surprise move to become BT’s biggest shareholder. But it was the art lover’s deal to take over Sotheby’s that put him in the media spotlight.
Drahi, the owner of works by Pablo Picasso and Henri Matisse, paid an eye-watering $3.7bn in 2019 for the underperforming auction house, explaining the purchase as an “investment for my family”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slice of life: 10 delicious ways to make the most of watermelon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/slice-of-life-10-delicious-ways-to-make-the-most-of-watermelon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/slice-of-life-10-delicious-ways-to-make-the-most-of-watermelon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:41:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s nothing more refreshing than a chunk of cool, juicy watermelon – but even the smallest fruit generates a lot of leftovers. Here’s how to turn them into quick and easy salads, granita, gazpacho …

I’ve mentioned this before, but waste watermelon is a real problem in my house. On every supermarket trip, my three-year-old sees a watermelon and demands a watermelon, only to eat the daintiest slice of watermelon once he’s home. I am regularly left to consume approximately 98% of a watermelon by myself, and it’s getting boring. So, in a bid to combat this crushing watermelon ennui – and because it happens to be watermelon season – I have collected 10 of the best watermelon recipes on the internet. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341894</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/equal-columns-with-flexbox-its-more-complicated-than-you-might-think/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:34:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As awesome as flexbox is, what it’s doing under the hood is actually a little strange because, by default, it is doing two things at once. It first looks at the content size which is what we would get if by declaring width: max-content on an element. But on top of that, flex-shrink is also doing some work allowing the items to be smaller, but only if needed.
Let’s break those two down and see how they work together.
The post Equal Columns With Flexbox: It’s More Complicated Than You Might Think appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former BrewDog staff accuse craft beer firm of culture of fear]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/brewdog-staff-craft-beer-firm-letter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/brewdog-staff-craft-beer-firm-letter"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:28:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dozens of ex-employees sign open letter claiming they were bullied and treated like objects

BrewDog: from ‘punk’ brewery to beer behemoth

BrewDog, the fast-expanding craft beer firm, has apologised to former employees who accused the company and its co-founder James Watt of fostering a “culture of fear” in which workers were bullied and “treated like objects”.
In an open letter circulated on Twitter, 61 former workers alleged that the Scottish brewer’s dizzyingly rapid growth had involved cutting corners on health and safety, espousing values it did not live by, and creating a “toxic” culture that left staff suffering from mental illness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff and Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/building-a-headless-cms-with-fauna-and-vercel-functions/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:26:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will learn and use headless CMS, Fauna, and Vercel functions to build a blogging platform, Blogify After that, you can easily build any web application using a headless CMS, Fauna and Vercel functions.
The post Building a Headless CMS with Fauna and Vercel Functions appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ikeh Akinyemi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ukraine in talks with Uefa to reverse Euro 2020 shirt decision]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ukraine-talks-with-uefa-reverse-euro-2020-glory-heroes-shirt-decision</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ukraine-talks-with-uefa-reverse-euro-2020-glory-heroes-shirt-decision"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:25:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slogan ‘Glory to the Heroes’ was ordered removed from kit after protests from Russia
Ukraine’s football association said on Thursday it was in talks with Uefa to reverse a decision by the European football governing body to remove a slogan from Ukraine shirts after protests from Russia.
“Ukraine’s football association is in talks with Uefa to keep in place the slogan on its jerseys,” the association’s press service told AFP, after Uefa said the message “Glory to the heroes”, stitched on the inside of the shirt collar, was “clearly political in nature”. The association said that “earlier Uefa had approved the new kit and every element of it, including the slogan”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[America’s richest men pay $0 in income tax. This is wealth supremacy | Robert Reich]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/when-americas-richest-men-pay-0-in-income-tax-this-is-wealth-supremacy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/when-americas-richest-men-pay-0-in-income-tax-this-is-wealth-supremacy"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:18:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The super-rich have bought armies of lobbyists to keep their taxes minuscule and to create tax loopholes large enough to drive their Lamborghinis through
ProPublica’s bombshell report on America’s super-wealthy paying little or nothing in taxes reveals not only their humongous wealth but also how they’ve parlayed that wealth into political power to shrink their taxes to almost nothing.
Jeff Bezos, the richest man in America, reportedly paid no federal income taxes in 2007 and 2011. Elon Musk, the second richest, paid no taxes in 2018. Warren Buffett, often ranking number 3, paid a tax rate of 0.1% between 2014 and 2018.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Reich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edward de Bono obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/10/edward-de-bono-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/10/edward-de-bono-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:12:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author, doctor and inventor of the term lateral thinking who wrote more than 60 books on his original and unorthodox theories
The thinker and writer Edward de Bono, who has died aged 88, once suggested that the Arab-Israeli conflict might be solved with Marmite. During a 1999 lecture to Foreign Office officials, the originator of the term lateral thinking argued that the yeast extract, though proverbially socially divisive, could do what politicians and diplomats had failed for years to achieve. The problem, as he saw it, was that people in the Middle East eat unleavened bread and so lack zinc, which makes them irritable and belligerent. Feeding them Marmite, therefore, would help create peace.
Through his 60-plus books, including The Mechanism of Mind (1969), Six Thinking Hats (1985), How to Have A Beautiful Mind (2004) and Think! Before It’s Too Late (2009), as well as seminars, training courses and a BBC television series, De Bono sought to free us from the tyranny of logic through creative thinking. “What happened was, 2,400 years ago, the Greek Gang of Three, by whom I mean Aristotle, Plato and Socrates, started to think based on analysis, judgment and knowledge,” he said. “At the same time, church people, who ran the schools and universities, wanted logic to prove the heretics wrong. As a result, design and perceptual thinking was never developed.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Jeffries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arizona’s partisan election audit and the Trump-linked donors paying for it | The fight to vote]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/10/arizona-election-ballot-audit-fight-to-vote</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/10/arizona-election-ballot-audit-fight-to-vote"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our investigation found people tied to Trump who fanned election conspiracies were opening their wallets
Happy Thursday,
Ever since Arizona Republicans began their review of 2.1m ballots from the 2020 election, a huge question has loomed over the effort: who exactly is paying for it?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levine in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Parkinson: ‘I dreamed of living with Ingrid Bergman near Barnsley FC’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/michael-parkinson-i-dreamed-of-living-with-ingrid-bergman-near-barnsley-fc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/michael-parkinson-i-dreamed-of-living-with-ingrid-bergman-near-barnsley-fc"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T14:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chatshow presenter and jazz DJ recalls crushes on screen icons, disappointment on the cricket field – and the first time he heard Louis Armstrong
I was born in Cudworth, a mining village near Barnsley. My father worked down Grimethorpe colliery. There’s a great tradition in Yorkshire of brass music and I would listen to the Grimethorpe Colliery Band rehearsing on Sunday mornings above a nearby pub.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Rich Pelley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 overview: group tables, results, fixtures and the knockouts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/10/euro-2020-overview-group-tables-results-fixtures-and-the-knockouts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/10/euro-2020-overview-group-tables-results-fixtures-and-the-knockouts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:55:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your essential, one-stop guide to the latest state of play at Euro 2020, updated throughout the tournament. Note: all times BST
A guide to all 622 players | The lowdown on all the venues
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High risk of autumn Covid surge in Europe despite drop in infections, says WHO]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/risk-of-covid-autumn-surge-is-high-despite-drop-in-infections-in-europe-says-who</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/risk-of-covid-autumn-surge-is-high-despite-drop-in-infections-in-europe-says-who"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:53:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Organisation urges governments to be cautious as societies open up and Delta variant advances 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Covid-19 infections, hospitalisations and deaths are falling fast across Europe, but the risk of a deadly autumn resurgence remains high as societies open up and the more transmissible Delta variant advances, the World Health Organization (WHO) has said.
The warning came as new case numbers continued to plunge in most of the continent, falling in some areas to their lowest levels since August, and multiple governments, including France and Germany, relaxed restrictions further.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley Europe correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corsica trial begins over killing that sparked global feminist campaign]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/corsica-trial-begins-over-killing-julie-douib-that-sparked-global-feminist-campaign</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/corsica-trial-begins-over-killing-julie-douib-that-sparked-global-feminist-campaign"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:30:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bruno Garcia-Cruciani, 44, on trial over fatal shooting of his former partner Julie Douib
A man has gone on trial in Corsica accused of gunning down his former partner in a killing that sparked a global feminist campaign.
The death of Julie Douib in March 2019 highlighted the scale of femicide in France and led to a movement by women to reclaim the streets with marches, demonstrations and the posting of collages.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 security preparations in Cornwall – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/10/g7-security-preparations-in-cornwall-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/10/g7-security-preparations-in-cornwall-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the G7 summit starting on Friday, 5,000 mutual aid officers have arrived in the area from police forces across the UK. They will join 1,500 officers and staff from Devon and Cornwall police being deployed at the event.
More than 100 police dogs will be working at the summit, though no police horses are due to be there
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National Geographic recognizes new Southern Ocean, bringing global total to five]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/new-ocean-global-total-five-national-geographic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/new-ocean-global-total-five-national-geographic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:12:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Organization says the Southern Ocean consists of the waters surrounding Antarctica, out to 60-degrees south latitude
Anyone who thought the world had four oceans will now have to think again, after the National Geographic Society announced it would recognize a new Southern Ocean in Antarctica, bringing the global total to five.
The National Geographic, a non-profit scientific and educational organization whose mapping standards are referenced by many atlases and cartographers, said the Southern Ocean consists of the waters surrounding Antarctica, out to 60-degrees south latitude.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Gabbatt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nailed it: man, 82, builds bench for wife in 30 minutes after council plea ignored]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/nailed-it-man-82-builds-bench-for-wife-in-30-minutes-after-council-plea-ignored</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/nailed-it-man-82-builds-bench-for-wife-in-30-minutes-after-council-plea-ignored"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:11:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Souto took matters into own hands to provide resting place for wife on daily walks in Spanish town
Whatever the rustic bench that sits on a street in the north-west Spanish town of A Estrada may lack in finish and elegance, it more than makes up for in the devotion that went into its creation.
The pale wooden seat was cobbled together after Manuel Souto, an 82-year-old retired lathe operator, decided to find somewhere for his wife to sit and rest on their daily walks. María Souto, who is 79 and has osteoarthritis, walks with a stick and finds her morning exercise increasingly difficult.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The greatest ever songs of the summer – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/the-greatest-ever-songs-of-the-summer-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/the-greatest-ever-songs-of-the-summer-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Don Henley to Drake, we rate the hottest sounds of the season
For a fleeting moment Brooklyn’s the Drums were the skinny jean-sporting indie band du jour. This is their crowning moment, all pogoing bass, petal-soft whistle riffs and a lyric about waking up on a sunny morning and running to the beach. “Oh mama I don’t care about nothing” feels like a very summer 2021 mantra, too.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Cragg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and nature crises: solve both or solve neither, say experts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/climate-and-nature-crises-solve-both-or-solve-neither-say-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/climate-and-nature-crises-solve-both-or-solve-neither-say-experts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Restoring nature boosts biodiversity and ecosystems that can rapidly and cheaply absorb carbon emissions
Humanity must solve the climate and nature crises together or solve neither, according to a report from 50 of the world’s leading scientists.
Global heating and the destruction of wildlife is wreaking increasing damage on the natural world, which humanity depends on for food, water and clean air. Many of the human activities causing the crises are the same and the scientists said increased use of nature as a solution was vital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eurovision winners Måneskin: ‘Cocaine? Damiano barely drinks beer!’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/10/eurovision-winners-maneskin-cocaine-damiano-barely-drinks-beer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/10/eurovision-winners-maneskin-cocaine-damiano-barely-drinks-beer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T13:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Already multiplatinum in their native Italy, the swaggering rock quartet now have two singles in the UK chart. They discuss their rise to success – and that drug-taking allegation
Before their momentous Eurovision victory with Zitti e Buoni, placing Italian rock back on the world stage and earning praise from Simon Le Bon and Miley Cyrus; before a baseless accusation of snorting cocaine almost veered into a full-blown diplomatic crisis; and before their post-win ping-pong tournament became a twee secondary narrative, the Italian band Måneskin had already raised eyebrows in Rotterdam, this year’s host city.
After a rehearsal session ended late, says the bassist, Victoria De Angelis, they were parched – but realised there was no drinking water in their hotel rooms. “We went to the hotel reception, but they said there was no water around,” De Angelis says. “So we made it into the kitchen and took some.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angelica Frey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU tries to loosen Brexit deadlock with colour-coded plan for Swiss-style deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/eu-tries-to-loosen-brexit-deadlock-with-colour-coded-plan-for-swiss-style-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/eu-tries-to-loosen-brexit-deadlock-with-colour-coded-plan-for-swiss-style-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:57:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels lays out options for avoiding checks on food entering Northern Ireland from Great Britain
All Brexit border checks on food, including chilled meats, entering Northern Ireland from Great Britain would be abolished if the UK signed up to a Swiss-style veterinary agreement, the EU has said.
As the escalating row over Northern Ireland threatened to develop into a full-blown trade war, the EU tried to ease tensions with the publication of a new chart on Wednesday night. It gave fresh detail on alternatives to the controversial checks on fresh food, including sausages, after Brexit.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forget incremental change: the left shouldn’t be afraid of thinking big | Ed Miliband]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/thinking-big-labour-politics-radical-vision</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/10/thinking-big-labour-politics-radical-vision"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:56:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s only by setting out a bold, radical vision that Labour will speak to people’s experiences and generate hope

Ed Miliband is a former leader of the Labour party

We have all craved a return to normality during the pandemic. As we emerge from this crisis, it’s tempting to think that big change is the last thing needed right now, and that we should instead be aiming for mere stability. But this analysis ignores the lessons from the events of the last decade. Unrestrained markets produced the financial crisis. A deep sense of our economy failing millions of people led to Brexit. And the effects of Covid-19 have been made significantly worse by the deprivation and inequality that characterise our country.
Each of these crises is a manifestation of underlying political, social and economic problems that have been intensifying for decades. They have each sounded an alarm about the way our economy and society are run, and we must now address their causes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Miliband</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ashcroft daughter-in-law given bail in Belize over officer’s shooting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ashcroft-daughter-in-law-jasmine-hartin-given-bail-in-belize-over-officers-shooting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ashcroft-daughter-in-law-jasmine-hartin-given-bail-in-belize-over-officers-shooting"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:39:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canadian Jasmine Hartin, charged with manslaughter by negligence, freed after eight days behind bars
The daughter-in-law of the Conservative party donor Michael Ashcroft has been released on bail in Belize where she is accused of accidentally shooting dead a senior police officer.
Jasmine Hartin was freed on Wednesday after spending eight days behind bars in Belize’s central prison. She had to surrender her passport and personal documents and cannot leave the country without permission from the supreme court.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New York memorial and a giant sinkhole: Thursday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-new-york-memorial-and-a-giant-sinkhole-thursdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-new-york-memorial-and-a-giant-sinkhole-thursdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:38:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch Marvin's Binoculars, a theatre show about the great outdoors – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/video/2021/jun/10/watch-marvins-binoculars-a-theatre-show-about-the-great-outdoors-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/video/2021/jun/10/watch-marvins-binoculars-a-theatre-show-about-the-great-outdoors-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:35:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Unicorn theatre presents a vibrant new drama about wildlife and friendship designed to encourage children to explore their local green spaces. Directed by Justin Audibert, Marvin’s Binoculars is aimed at audiences aged six to 10. Available until 8 August
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar eclipse 2021: the crescent sun – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-the-crescent-sun-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:27:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From New Jersey to Milton Keynes, skygazers in the northern hemisphere were able to see a partial solar eclipse, witnessing a crescent sun in an eclipsed sunrise in some parts of the world

Solar eclipse 2021: spectacle visible across UK and Ireland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leading authors sound alarm over post-Brexit changes to copyright]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/10/leading-authors-sound-alarm-over-post-brexit-changes-to-copyright</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/10/leading-authors-sound-alarm-over-post-brexit-changes-to-copyright"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T12:27:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Philip Pullman and Kate Mosse among writers warning that changes being considered could flood UK with cheap foreign editions and threaten livelihoods

Bestselling writers including Philip Pullman and Kate Mosse are warning of a “potentially devastating” change to the UK’s copyright laws that could damage authors’ livelihoods by flooding the UK market with cheap foreign editions.
The Intellectual Property Office launched a consultation this week into the UK’s approach to copyright in the wake of Brexit. One option under consideration would see a change to the “copyright exhaustion” rule, which governs when the control of a rights holder over the distribution of their property expires. For example, if a customer buys a book, then the owner of the book’s copyright would not then be able to prevent the customer selling that book to another person in the same territory.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neo-Nazi ex-Ukip member found guilty of terrorism offences]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/dean-morrice-neo-nazi-ex-ukip-member-found-guilty-of-terrorism-offences</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/dean-morrice-neo-nazi-ex-ukip-member-found-guilty-of-terrorism-offences"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:59:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police raid of Dean Morrice’s home found stockpile of chemicals and cache of terrorism manuals
A former Ukip member and British army employee has been found guilty of a range of terror and explosive charges.
Dean Morrice ran a Telegram channel that prosecutors said had “unapologetically, unambiguously pumped out” neo-Nazi propaganda that encouraged the killing of people of colour and Jewish people.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A breathing space’: photo exhibition tells the story of a Cardiff park]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-breathing-space-photo-exhibition-tells-the-story-of-a-cardiff-park</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/10/a-breathing-space-photo-exhibition-tells-the-story-of-a-cardiff-park"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:40:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heath Park adjoins University hospital of Wales, Wales’ biggest hospital, and is used by NHS staff and locals from north Cardiff. Young photographers Tomos Kay and Tom Gower capture some of the park’s regulars. The park has over 10 football pitches, large wooded areas, ponds, a small golf course, tennis courts and a large model railway.
A Park for Our Time outdoor exhibition in Heath Park, Cardiff runs from Friday 11 June to Sunday 13 June
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Photographs: Tomos Kay and Tom Gower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We can’t go back home’: the forgotten victims of Nigeria’s conflict – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/jun/10/we-cant-go-back-home-the-forgotten-victims-of-nigerias-conflict-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/jun/10/we-cant-go-back-home-the-forgotten-victims-of-nigerias-conflict-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:38:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Camped in a half-built royal palace in Anka, in the north-western Zamfara state, displaced families – mostly women and children – just want to escape the upheavals making their lives impossible

Photographs by Siegfried Modola/WFP/Arete
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Azure Data Fundamentals Certification (DP-900) – Pass the Exam With This Free 4.5-Hour Course]]></title>
        <id>60b93afaacb62507dd1d8915</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/azure-data-fundamentals-certification-dp-900-pass-the-exam-with-this-free-4-5-hour-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can learn everything you need to know to earn the Azure Data Fundamentals certification by completing this free 4.5 hour course. What is the Azure Data Fundamentals Certification?The Azure Data Fundamentals Certification is for those seeking a data-related role such as Data Analyst, Data Engineer, or Data]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender-critical views are a protected belief, appeal tribunal rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/10/gender-critical-views-protected-belief-appeal-tribunal-rules-maya-forstater</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/jun/10/gender-critical-views-protected-belief-appeal-tribunal-rules-maya-forstater"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:33:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maya Forstater lost initial legal challenge brought when her contract was not renewed after tweet dispute

The gender-critical views of a researcher who lost her job at a thinktank after tweeting that transgender women could not change their biological sex are a protected philosophical belief under the Equality Act, a judge-led panel has ruled.
Maya Forstater, 47, a tax expert, brought a legal challenge when the Centre for Global Development (CGD), where she was a visiting fellow, did not renew her contract in March 2019 after a dispute over publicising her views on social media.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruben Sergeyev, longtime Guardian fixer in Moscow, dies at 65]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ruben-sergeyev-longtime-guardian-fixer-in-moscow-dies-at-65</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/ruben-sergeyev-longtime-guardian-fixer-in-moscow-dies-at-65"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:29:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former colleagues remember ‘intelligent, playful, constantly curious’ news assistant and friend
Ruben Sergeyev, a longtime consultant and friend to Guardian correspondents in Moscow from the Gorbachev era through to the Putin years, has died of Covid-19 at the age of 65.
He died on Wednesday after being admitted to hospital in Moscow. Sergeyev worked from 1988 until 2014 as a news assistant, fixer, and all-round explainer of Russia during a time of rapid change. He helped a succession of bureau chiefs including Jonathan Steele, David Hearst, James Meek and Miriam Elder.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding and Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England fans, how do you feel when you hear boos as players take a knee?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/england-fans-boos-players-take-a-knee-euro2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/england-fans-boos-players-take-a-knee-euro2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T10:44:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do you think about players taking a knee at Euro 2020, fans booing and Gareth Southgate’s letter to supporters?
England players will be taking a knee before matches at Euro 2020 to show their opposition to racism – a decision that is unpopular with some supporters. There were jeers when players kneeled before their recent friendlies against Austria and Romania at the Riverside Stadium, and there are fears the dispute will rumble on when they meet Croatia in their opening game of Euro 2020 at Wembley on Sunday.
The England manager, Gareth Southgate, has explained in an open letter to fans why England players will be taking a knee. “This idea that some players don’t know what it means to play for England – or don’t care – has become something of a false narrative,” the England manager wrote. “I have a responsibility to the wider community to use my voice, and so do the players. It’s their duty to continue to interact with the public on matters such as equality, inclusivity and racial injustice, while using the power of their voices to help put debates on the table, raise awareness and educate.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solar eclipse 2021: UK skygazers enjoy view of crescent sun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-spectacle-visible-across-uk-ireland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/10/solar-eclipse-2021-spectacle-visible-across-uk-ireland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T10:25:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Skygazers – with appropriate eye protection – could see part of sun obscured on Thursday morning

Solar eclipse 2021: the crescent sun – in pictures

People across the UK were treated to views of a crescent sun on Thursday morning as the moon appeared to partially block out the star.
An annular eclipse – when the sun and moon are in line with the Earth and the moon appears slightly smaller, creating a phenomenon known as the “ring of fire” – was visible on Thursday from places such as Canada, Greenland and northern Russia.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[YouTube no-hoper, a moon called Europa, and firing a billionaire into space – take the Thursday quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T10:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia every Thursday lunchtime – how will you fare?
It is Thursday lunchtime, and once again the summons arrives to pit your wits against our astonishingly named Thursday quiz. Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia with some jokes thrown in. It is just for fun and there are no prizes, but do let us know how you get on in the comments below.
The Thursday quiz, No 7
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of the UK’s best surfing and boarding beaches, chosen by readers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/10/10-uk-best-surfing-and-boarding-beaches-spots-chosen-by-readers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/10/10-uk-best-surfing-and-boarding-beaches-spots-chosen-by-readers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T10:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Big breaks and paddles from the Hebrides to Cornwall, with glorious walks, pubs and campsites once you’ve dried off
Although the south-west may be the most popular choice, the best surfing town in the UK is actually Saltburn-by-the-Sea, in the northernmost corner of Yorkshire. Saltburn is a quaint Victorian seaside resort with a bohemian feel: there is plenty of affordable accommodation, numerous great pubs and fish-and-chip shops, and a 19th-century funicular sea lift connecting the main town with the beach. Saltburn’s waves are clearly defined, the areas surrounding the pier are the most popular spots, and there’s a constant stream of rip-able surf. Saltburn Surf School provides equipment and lessons for all abilities. The town is a real gem. 
Bobby Dickinson
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Father review – Anthony Hopkins superb in unbearably heartbreaking film]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/10/the-father-review-anthony-hopkins-olivia-colman-florian-zeller</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/10/the-father-review-anthony-hopkins-olivia-colman-florian-zeller"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hopkins gives a moving, Oscar-winning turn as a man with dementia in a film full of intelligent performances, disorienting time slips and powerful theatrical effects
“Let me not be mad, not mad, sweet heaven!” says King Lear, a plea which is overwhelmingly sad because it can never be heard by anyone with the power to grant it. Anthony Hopkins, who played Lear in Richard Eyre’s production for the BBC, now delivers another performance as an ailing patriarch with a favourite daughter and nowhere to stay, in a film directed by Florian Zeller, and adapted by Christopher Hampton from Zeller’s own award-winning stage play. There is unbearable heartbreak in this movie, for which Hopkins has become history’s oldest best actor Oscar-winner, and also genuine fear, like something you might experience watching Roman Polanski’s Repulsion or M Night Shyamalan’s The Sixth Sense.
 Related: Florian Zeller on The Father: 'Anthony Hopkins took me in his arms. We knew the miracle had happened' 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More research funding needed to avoid drug-resistant pandemic, warns report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/10/more-research-funding-needed-to-avoid-drug-resistant-pandemic-warns-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/10/more-research-funding-needed-to-avoid-drug-resistant-pandemic-warns-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T09:17:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smaller firms are developing most antibiotics targeting superbugs but often at risk of bankruptcy
Small drugmakers and biotech firms that are developing the bulk of new antibiotics need far more financial support, according to a new report, which warned that without these life-saving medicines there could be a pandemic of drug-resistant infections, worse than Covid-19.
The Access to Medicine Foundation, an Amsterdam-based non-profit group, said small and medium-sized firms, which account for three-quarters of all late-stage antibiotics in development, struggle to secure enough funding and are often at risk of bankruptcy, potentially leaving new medicines stranded on the lab bench.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Line 3: protests over pipeline through tribal lands spark clashes and mass arrests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/line-3-pipeline-arrests-minnesota</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/line-3-pipeline-arrests-minnesota"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T09:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police arrested more than 100 people this week as activists try to block the expansion of the pipeline
Environmental protesters and Native American tribes have joined together to try to block construction efforts that would expand and repair a controversial pipeline called Line 3, which would carry hundreds of thousands of barrels of oil through tribal lands and fragile watersheds in northern Minnesota.
The protesters said they were there as water and land protectors, fighting Enbridge, a Canadian-owned company, and the $9bn upgrade of the pipeline. The action sparked a confrontation with law enforcement officers and raised the prospects of a high-profile fight set to highlight the use of fossil fuels at a time of growing climate crisis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Gammon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Your baby’s heart has stopped’: hell and healing after the stillbirth of my son]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/your-babys-heart-has-stopped-hell-and-healing-after-the-stillbirth-of-my-son</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/10/your-babys-heart-has-stopped-hell-and-healing-after-the-stillbirth-of-my-son"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T09:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2010, Katie Allen was days from giving birth to her second child when she felt his movements slow. She talks about the ordeal – and how she was helped through it
I woke to the barely there contractions of early labour. It was a few days before my due date in my second pregnancy – a pregnancy seemingly without complications. The Moses basket was out and my hospital bag packed; everything was ready for our baby boy. He was kicking as normal.
As the day went on, my contractions remained mild and far apart. I kept to the plan discussed with our midwives: stay at home as long as possible, no rushing to the maternity ward. I took our two-year-old son, Alex, for a walk with a friend and we collected conkers. When I sang Twinkle Twinkle, Little Star at Alex’s bedtime, the baby kicked hard, as he had done most days, as if he recognised the song, knew our routine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katie Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vet who fled Saddam Hussein draws up groundbreaking Kurdistan animals rights bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/vet-who-fled-saddam-hussein-draws-up-landmark-kurdistan-animal-rights-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/vet-who-fled-saddam-hussein-draws-up-landmark-kurdistan-animal-rights-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T06:29:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kurdish vet is behind groundbreaking welfare legislation to be debated by parliament in Iraq’s autonomous region
“The animals are my life,” says Sulaiman Tameer. In one corner of his desk is a statuette of a rearing horse. A watercolour of a donkey hangs behind it. “That one lives with a government minister,” he nods at a photo of a rescued kitten. “But I won’t tell you which one.”
The veterinarian’s office, which shares space with his clinic on a sidestreet in Duhok in the Kurdistan region, in northern Iraq, is where Tameer divides his time between treating animals and campaigning for government action on their rights.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanne Stocker-Kelly in Erbil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve got that sinking feeling over finding insurance for my flat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/ive-got-that-sinking-feeling-over-finding-insurance-for-my-flat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/ive-got-that-sinking-feeling-over-finding-insurance-for-my-flat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T06:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was refused cover because of subsidence, although the last claim was in 2006
We had buildings insurance with LV= until it stopped offering subsidence cover for our flat, on which there had been two subsidence claims in the last 30 years. We therefore took out a policy with NBS, underwritten by Hiscox, but it informed us, shortly before it was due for renewal, it will no longer insure us. We have just over a week to find replacement cover but insurers often won’t take on new customers if their building has a subsidence history.
I was under the impression that companies were required by law to continue to provide cover to existing customers because of this, and it must be affecting many homeowners in north London where subsidence is widespread. The last subsidence claim for our flat was 2006 and nothing has happened since.
VW, London
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Tims</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Father of African cinema’ Ousmane Sembène at work – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/gallery/2021/jun/10/father-of-african-cinema-ousmane-sembene-at-work-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/gallery/2021/jun/10/father-of-african-cinema-ousmane-sembene-at-work-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T05:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A look back at the career of Senegal-born film director Ousmane Sembène as his 1968 film Mandabi is released in the UK for the first time
•Mandabi is released on 11 June in cinemas, and on 28 June on DVD, Blu-Ray and digital platforms.
•Peter Bradshaw on Mandabi: classic about colonialism resonates today
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samba Gadjigo and Jason Silverman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Brazil’s evangelical superstar have her husband killed?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/10/floredelis-did-brazil-evangelical-superstar-have-her-husband-killed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/10/floredelis-did-brazil-evangelical-superstar-have-her-husband-killed"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T05:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flordelis grew up in a Rio favela, but rose to fame after adopting more than 50 children, becoming a hugely successful gospel singer and winning a seat in congress. And now she is on trial for murder
When Flordelis dos Santos de Souza boarded an air force jet from Rio de Janeiro to Brasília on the morning of 1 January 2019, she felt she was witnessing the beginning of a new dawn. Brazil was about to install a far-right religious nationalist, Jair Bolsonaro, as president, and she, a black gospel singer from one of Rio’s most violent and impoverished favelas, had won a seat in parliament, asserting her place among her country’s powerful evangelical elite. At 57, she was a church leader and a social crusader, celebrated for standing up to some of Rio’s most dangerous gangsters and for taking in dozens of children rescued from lives of deprivation and crime. She had devoted her life to building a multimillion-dollar evangelical empire, which had grown to include nine churches. Now she was a politician, too.
At her side was her husband, Anderson do Carmo de Souza, also a preacher, 16 years her junior, who managed her political career. “I want to thank all of you who had faith and gave Flor a place in this movement to change Brazil, isn’t that right love?” Anderson said into a camera as the pair stood on the airport runway, waiting to fly to the capital at the invitation of one of the country’s most powerful politicians, Rodrigo Maia, then speaker of the lower house.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acropolis now: Greeks outraged at concreting of ancient site]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/acropolis-now-greeks-outraged-at-concreting-of-ancient-site</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/10/acropolis-now-greeks-outraged-at-concreting-of-ancient-site"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T04:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Installation of new pathway and lift has been criticised by archaeologists and called ‘a scandal’
When seen through the eyes of Manolis Korres, the architect who has long presided over the restoration of the Parthenon, the Acropolis needs no improvement at all.
In the face of such architectural mastery, he thinks of himself more as a maestro of order, making a monument that has survived explosions, fire, looting and earthquakes more understandable to the public.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The G7 and a crucial moment for the climate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/10/the-g7-and-a-crucial-moment-for-the-climate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T02:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s richest democracies will come together in Britain this week with global heating high on the agenda. Can they match big promises with concrete action? 
The damage wrought by the coronavirus pandemic has been huge, but it pales in comparison to the potential risks associated with the climate crisis. With the world coalescing around the importance of limiting temperature rises to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels, the next 10 years are the last chance to meet that goal - and with the Cop26 summit in Glasgow later this year, the G7 summit in Cornwall this week is the next staging post in a crucial six months to settle on a way forward.
But even as many countries set out significant pledges to do their part, the reality of their policies is often far behind. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s environment correspondent, Fiona Harvey, about what must happen to catch up with those commitments – and what this summit will tell us about the likelihood of making changes that are crucial to averting catastrophe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Fiona Harvey; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Slums of Mumbai to a Rented Apartment – My 30-Year Developer Journey]]></title>
        <id>60b357ad11ffb70827ef9a90</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-journey-into-tech-from-slums-of-mumbai-to-my-own-apartment/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year I tweeted about how I was moving from a Slum where I lived for 29 years to a multi-story rented apartment.  The tech community on Twitter responded with nothing but love. Dan Wahlin posted that he would love to hear more about my story. It's not going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cornucopia of Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340967</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-cornucopia-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know about y’all, but my feeds have been flooded with articles about CSS Container Queries these past few weeks. The buzz about container queries actually started back in December after Miriam Suzanne posted a proposal (picking up on …
The post A Cornucopia of Container Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Skills You Need to Start Freelancing as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60c0ccbed3126007592d5781</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-skills-you-need-to-start-freelancing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's the bottom line: you don't need much to get started as a freelance developer.  The biggest obstacle developers face when they're thinking about getting started is that they tend to overcomplicate things.  Most are intimidated by the sheer number of different paths or skills deemed necessary by various blog]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Bootstrap 5 and SASS by Building a Portfolio Website]]></title>
        <id>60c10a1dd3126007592d5988</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-bootstrap-5-and-sass-by-building-a-portfolio-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap is one of the most popular CSS frameworks and Sass is one of the most popular preprocessors for CSS. We just published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you about Bootstrap 5 and Sass by building a portfolio website. Patrick Muriungi developed this course.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[target=blank]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341916</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/targetblank/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does that make your eye twitch a little bit? Like… it’s a typo. It should be target="_blank" with an underscore to start the value. As in…
<a target="_blank" href="https://codepen.io"Open CodePen in a New Tab
</a
Welp, that’s correct syntax!…
The post target=blank appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your photos and stories of your amazing sheds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/share-your-photos-and-stories-of-your-amazing-sheds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:28:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about the impressive garden sheds you have built and customised
During lockdown some people have taken to sprucing up their sheds, whether it’s to give them a new lease of life or to create a haven away in the garden.
We would like to hear about your amazing sheds, however humble, and what they mean to you. If you have customised yours, what inspired you? What do you use it for?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I fell in the water, but it was worth it!’: Guardian readers on their most extraordinary bird photographs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/i-fell-in-the-water-but-it-was-worth-it-guardian-readers-on-their-most-extraordinary-bird-photographs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/i-fell-in-the-water-but-it-was-worth-it-guardian-readers-on-their-most-extraordinary-bird-photographs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T11:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From friendly Antarctic penguins to the rainbow plumage of a Colombian hummingbird, our readers on their favourite images – and the lengths they went to to capture them.
I took this photo at the end of January in Balloch, Scotland. I have always wanted to take a picture of a male mandarin duck. It is the bird that made me want to start taking photographs. They are beautiful, with so many stunning colours. At the end of January, I had heard via Facebook that there was a pair of them up the road from me. I got up early and drove to Balloch. I had all but given up hope, when all of a sudden I saw the bright orange tail feathers of the duck in between some bushes on the river’s edge. I had to lean on a tree that was in the water to take the pictures. I then fell into the water and tore my trousers, but it was worth it. Paul Fraser, 36, freshwater biologist, Callander, Scotland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I have a smaller penis than my girlfriend’s exes – should I get surgery?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/i-have-a-smaller-penis-than-my-girlfriends-exes-should-i-get-surgery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/i-have-a-smaller-penis-than-my-girlfriends-exes-should-i-get-surgery"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:37:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[She says I’m the best lover she’s ever had. But knowing I’m smaller than previous ones, I can’t stop feeling self-conscious
My girlfriend and I are extremely happy together, but she told me that two of her exes had a bigger penis than me. Depending on the circumstances, my penis is normally about 5.8-6.2in. She said her most recent ex was bigger, at 7in, and the other was maybe an inch longer. I’ve always been self-conscious about it, but this makes me feel worse. For a long time I’ve wanted to get surgery, but she swears that I am the best sexual partner she has had. She also says that she and her most recent ex couldn’t have sex in as many positions, because it would be painful. If I want to get surgery, should I? She says that I’m perfect the way I am and she thinks I’m the perfect size. 
Listen more carefully to your girlfriend. She is telling you that you are “perfect”, but all you hear is “her ex’s penis was bigger”. It is common to use half a story to confirm the negative beliefs one has about one’s self. Work on soothing your male size anxiety and, instead of comparing yourself with others, focus on giving and receiving pleasure. Unfortunately, pornography movies tend to emphasise size and promote the untrue notion that a huge penis automatically produces greater pleasure for a partner. Don’t buy into this rubbish; it is physiologically unsound. An intelligent lover who is willing to learn how to please a partner – without even using his penis – will always be the most appreciated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Stephenson Connolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what lesson did you learn from your summer job?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/tell-us-what-lesson-did-you-learn-from-your-summer-job</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/tell-us-what-lesson-did-you-learn-from-your-summer-job"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T09:48:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from readers about their past and present experiences of summer work 
With a rise in summer job opportunities in some areas and a lack of gap year opportunities due to the pandemic, many young people are planning to use the summer to work and save. 
We would like to hear from readers about their own summer job experiences, past and present. What did it entail? And what lesson did you learn from it?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The interrogation of Matt Hancock - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T02:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two weeks after Dominic Cummings told MPs that the health secretary was a serial liar who lost the trust of No 10, Matt Hancock will face the same committee to defend himself. Heather Stewart explains what is at stake, and what it could mean for the next stage of the pandemic
When Dominic Cummings appeared before MPs to set out his account of what went wrong in the early stages of the Covid pandemic, he attempted a political assassination. But a fortnight later, Matt Hancock, the health secretary, is still limping on. So far, Hancock has been able to bat away questions from journalists, and at the dispatch box, without much trouble, and has retained the support of the prime minister. But a grilling by MPs, who will have much more time and the chance to follow up on their questions, will present him with a far greater challenge.
Hancock’s day of reckoning comes with the 21 June planned unlocking still uncertain, and the number of cases rising again, so his future will have profound consequences for the country. Rachel Humphreys spoke to the Guardian’s political editor, Heather Stewart, about the questions he is likely to face, the light his answers could shed on what went wrong, and why Boris Johnson appears determined to stick with his man — for now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Heather Stewart; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy Your freeCodeCamp Project on AWS – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide to the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>60bfa4d4d3126007592d5160</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-your-freecodecamp-project-on-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T23:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Throughout this post we’ll deploy your freeCodeCamp front end project using various services on AWS like S3, ElasticBeanstalk, and Lambda.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create Your Own Electronics With Arduino - Full Course]]></title>
        <id>60bfd986d3126007592d53a1</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-your-own-electronics-with-arduino-full-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T21:05:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino is an open-source electronics platform based on easy-to-use hardware and software. Arduino boards are able to read inputs - light on a sensor, a finger on a button, or a Twitter message - and turn it into an output - activating a motor, turning on an LED, publishing something]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341982</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/looking-at-wcag-2-5-5-for-better-target-sizes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever experienced the frustration of trying to tap a button on a mobile device only to have it do nothing because the target size is just not large enough **and it’s not picking up on your press? Maybe …
The post Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Todd Libby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Pass Data and Events Between Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b23b8911ffb70827ef954e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pass-data-between-components-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T16:17:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're trying to implement CRUD operations using API endpoints, you might find that it's hard to manage data across multiple components. Or maybe you have a modal, but you want to trigger it from a different component.  Wrapping your head around how to tackle these scenarios can be difficult.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete CSS Grid Tutorial with Cheat Sheet 🎖️]]></title>
        <id>60be6a3cd3126007592d4a03</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/css-grid-tutorial-with-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T16:02:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we're going to learn CSS Grid properties so that you can make your own responsive websites. I'll explain how each of Grid's properties work along with a CheatSheet that covers everything you can do with Grid. Let's go. 🎖️ Table of Contents: CSS Grid Architecture CSS Grid Chart Grid Parent]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341884</id>
        <link href="https://alex.party/posts/2021-05-31-css-trickz-an-experiment-with-netlify-s-on-demand-builders/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress sites have an API by default. Wanna see this site’s most recent posts, with just a specific set of data… in JSON format? Here ya go. Alex Riviere made a joke site using that.
At first, the site …
The post CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The danger – and beauty – of ultrarunning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/08/danger-and-beauty-of-ultrarunning-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/08/danger-and-beauty-of-ultrarunning-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T02:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 21 competitors died during a 100km mountain race in Gansu province, the Chinese government last week suspended all extreme sports. But those who love ultrarunning insist it can be safe – and has changed how they see the world. What keeps them coming back?
To most people, the horror of 21 lives being lost during a race across 100km in a Chinese mountain range will have been amplified by how obscure the sport seems to outsiders. But ultrarunning has boomed in popularity in recent years, with the number of finishers around the world rising from 120,000 to more than 600,000 in a decade. Now there are concerns that in China and beyond, a proliferation of new races has created a risk that safety rules will not always be enforced, and with it a chance that some of the most obsessive participants will discard vital protective equipment in the interests of gaining an advantage over their rivals.
Rachel Humphreys talks to Outside magazine’s Will Ford about the tragedy in China, and whether the decision of the government there to ban all extreme sports is the right response. And she hears from the author and ultrarunner Adharanand Finn about the extraordinary appeal of this brutally difficult feat of endurance – and how any analysis of its dangers must sit alongside an understanding of its power to change its devotees’ lives in profound ways.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Adharanand Finn and Will Ford; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Stack Development with Next.js and Supabase – The Complete Guide]]></title>
        <id>60bbd28eacb62507dd1d99fb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-complete-guide-to-full-stack-development-with-supabas/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:33:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to build full stack serverless apps with Supabase and Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenCV and Python for Computer Vision and AI]]></title>
        <id>60be863cd3126007592d4c36</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opencv-and-python-for-computer-vision-and-ai/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a popular Python library for real-time computer vision. We just released a new OpenCV course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. This course comes directly from the creators of OpenCV and is the perfect course for beginners.  You will learn how to use OpenCV for Computer Vision and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK parents and teachers: what is currently happening in your school?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T09:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear what the situation is like in UK schools from the parental and teaching point of view

We’re keen to hear from parents, teachers and school leaders across the UK about the situation in schools.
Whether it’s exam preparations, the management of social distancing protocols, the provision of wraparound care or school closures due to rising infections in communities, we’d like to hear about it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: your complete guide to all 622 players]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/04/euro-2020-complete-guide-to-all-622-players-ratings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/04/euro-2020-complete-guide-to-all-622-players-ratings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:08:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about all the players, including pets, hobbies and heroes. Click on the circular player picture for a full profile 

If you like this interactive, and would like to support our journalism, you can make a contribution from as little as £1. It only takes a minute. Thank you. 

 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Christenson and Steven Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>