<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-21T00:38:40.562Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-21T00:38:40.562Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden speaks on the Israel-Gaza ceasefire saying it will begin in less than two hours - live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/20/us-politics-live-israel-joe-biden-bernie-sanders-covid-coronavirus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/20/us-politics-live-israel-joe-biden-bernie-sanders-covid-coronavirus"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:56:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I send my condolences to all families, Israeli and Palestinian,’ the president said
President says: ‘We cannot be complicit. We have to speak out’
Senate to act on Capitol commission bill ‘very soon’, Schumer says
Bernie Sanders brings resolution to halt arms sales to Israel

 12.56am BST 
– Joan E Greve and Maanvi Singh
 12.21am BST 
New Yorkers could win up to $5m from the New York state lottery if they get vaccinated against Covid-19 at a state-run clinic, Governor Andrew Cuomo announced on Thursday.
Th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh in Oakland (now) and Joan E Greve (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel approves Gaza ceasefire to halt 11-day conflict]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/israels-security-cabinet-approves-gaza-ceasefire-reports</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/israels-security-cabinet-approves-gaza-ceasefire-reports"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:15:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Netanyahu’s office announces ‘mutual and simultaneous’ truce to begin within hours
Israeli and Palestinian militants have agreed to a ceasefire ending an 11-day conflict which has cost more than 230 lives in Gaza and 12 in Israel, after days of international pressure to stop the bloodshed.
The ceasefire came into effect at 2am local time on Friday, after Israeli prime minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s office announced late on Thursday that the cabinet had unanimously approved the “mutual and unconditional” ceas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU deal on Covid passes to open travel – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2021/may/20/coronavirus-live-news-tokyo-olympics-will-be-safe-says-ioc-vaccines-make-nine-people-billionaires</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2021/may/20/coronavirus-live-news-tokyo-olympics-will-be-safe-says-ioc-vaccines-make-nine-people-billionaires"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:09:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This blog is now closed. 

See all our coronavirus coverage

 12.09am BST 
This blog is now closed. 
 11.40pm BST 
Our full story on New York’s lottery incentive: 
New Yorkers could win up to $5m from the New York state lottery if they get vaccinated against Covid-19 at a state-run clinic, Governor Andrew Cuomo announced on Thursday.
 Related: New York governor announces $5m Covid vaccine lottery incentive  
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell (now); Yohannes Lowe, Rachel Hall, Martin Belam and Helen Sullivan (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expansion of English airports could threaten climate commitments – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/expansion-of-english-airports-could-threaten-climate-commitments-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/expansion-of-english-airports-could-threaten-climate-commitments-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impact on climate of expansion plans at regional airports has been underestimated, report finds
The climate impact of expansion plans at regional airports in England has been dramatically underestimated and would threaten the UK’s legally binding commitments, according to a report published ahead of a key summit later this year.
The study from the New Economics Foundation (NEF) calculated that proposals to expand four airports in England will lead to an increase in emissions up to eight times higher than pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK asylum seekers at ‘unprecedented’ risk of suicide amid deportation threat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-asylum-seekers-at-unprecedented-risk-of-suicide-amid-deportation-threat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-asylum-seekers-at-unprecedented-risk-of-suicide-amid-deportation-threat"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One-third of detainees at immigration centre who had crossed Channel on constant suicide watch
The Home Office’s rush to deport asylum seekers who had crossed the Channel in small boats last year led to “unprecedented levels” of those at risk of suicide, a watchdog has found.
During the period between the end of July to December 2020, when the Home Office was operating a programme of “compressed” charter flights, one-third of the detainees at Brook House immigration removal centre near Gatwick were placed o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Diana inquiry: a piercing exposé | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-diana-inquiry-a-piercing-expose</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-diana-inquiry-a-piercing-expose"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Dyson’s report reveals BBC breaches of journalistic ethics and inadequate editorial scrutiny
The BBC, the media, and even the Britain described in Lord Dyson’s report on Martin Bashir’s 1995 Panorama interview with Diana, Princess of Wales, may seem in some respects to belong to a bygone era. Most of those involved have departed the public stage, while the princess herself has been dead for nearly a quarter of a century. No one under 30 is likely to have a direct memory of a broadcast that took place w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Premier League: 10 things to look out for on the final day of the season]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/21/premier-league-10-things-to-look-out-for-on-the-final-day-of-the-season</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/21/premier-league-10-things-to-look-out-for-on-the-final-day-of-the-season"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea and Liverpool aim to seal their Champions League places as Sergio Agüero bids farewell to the Etihad Stadium
If Harry Kane really is making his Tottenham swansong at the King Power Stadium, he will have wished it could come with stakes rather higher than a fraught battle to cling on to seventh place. The emotions will be inescapable and the motivation to provide one last star turn presumably huge. Winning at such a difficult venue would be bittersweet for Kane and Spurs, given how costly the collaps…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames, Paul Doyle and Barry Glendenning</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[6.5m households in UK plan to buy an electric car by 2030]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/21/65m-households-uk-electric-car</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/21/65m-households-uk-electric-car"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ofgem data points to consumer shift as ban on sale of new petrol and diesel vehicles approaches
One in four UK households intend to buy an electric car in the next five years, as a ban on the sale of new petrol and diesel vehicles in 2030 approaches, according to research.
More than 6.5m households plan to buy an electric vehicle or plug-in hybrid, research by the energy watchdog Ofgem has found. This equates to 24%, or nearly one in four, of all energy households.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn CSS!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340933</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/learn/css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:51:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ooo look at this mighty SEO flex from Google: Learn CSS! Well deserved — this is great content. Twenty-three chapters taking you through all the fundamentals of CSS with extra content, like relevant podcasts, interactive examples, and even quizzes to …
The post Learn CSS! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adam Gemili ‘would take a knee’ in Tokyo and warns IOC over protest ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/adam-gemili-warns-ioc-tokyo-olympics-taking-knee-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/adam-gemili-warns-ioc-tokyo-olympics-taking-knee-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British sprinter critical of Olympic podium protest regulations
‘If they ban an athlete for protesting, all hell will break loose’

Adam Gemili has vowed to take a knee in support of Black Lives Matter if he wins an Olympic medal in Tokyo – and warned the IOC that “all hell will break loose” if it tries to ban athletes from protesting on the podium.
The British sprinter also accused the International Olympic Committee of double standards for hailing athletes who made Black Power salutes at the Mexico Games …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Are Lady Parts review – give it up for TV’s fearless Muslim riot grrrls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/we-are-lady-parts-review-give-it-up-for-tvs-fearless-muslim-riot-grrrls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/we-are-lady-parts-review-give-it-up-for-tvs-fearless-muslim-riot-grrrls"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Channel 4’s sweet, silly sitcom offers something we’ve never seen before on mainstream television: Muslim women being themselves, and rocking out to rowdy punk anthems 
Amina Hussain. 26. Capricorn. Finishing a PhD in microbiology. Prone to excessive sweating, secret American folk-guitar-playing in her wardrobe, and husband-finding. Desperately seeking a nice Muslim boy with eyebrows you can hang on to. No, strike that! What she wants is to join an all-female, Muslim, post-punk band called Lady Parts. Truly…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chitra Ramaswamy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subnormal: A British Scandal review – the racist nightmare that scarred black children for life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/subnormal-a-british-scandal-review-racist-nightmare-steve-mcqueen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/subnormal-a-british-scandal-review-racist-nightmare-steve-mcqueen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lyttanya Shannon’s film is a devastating look at the kids unfairly deemed ‘educationally subnormal’ in the 60s and 70s – and their lasting trauma
Those who saw Small Axe, Steve McQueen’s masterful series of standalone dramas, will no doubt remember the powerful final episode. Education told the story of a 12-year-old boy, Kingsley, who has trouble reading and is sent to a “special school”. It wass part of an unofficial segregation policy in the 1960s, which saw hundreds of black children labelled “education…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ford inspired by Foxes’ FA Cup victory as Leicester Tigers tackle Montpellier | Gerard Meagher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/rugby-union-european-challenge-cup-leicester-tigers-montpellier-george-ford</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/rugby-union-european-challenge-cup-leicester-tigers-montpellier-george-ford"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester fly-half George Ford is determined to end his team’s barren trophy run in the European Challenge Cup final
It says a lot about the decline of Leicester Tigers that George Ford struggles to remember how old he was the last time they won a major trophy. 
It was the last of their 10 Premiership titles in 2013 – for the record, he was 20 – and, barring a negligible Anglo-Welsh Cup in 2017, the subsequent eight years have been barren. In the interim Leicester City have been crowned Premier League champ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Are Here review – 1969 moon landings spark musical midlife adventure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/20/you-are-here-review-southwark-playhouse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/20/you-are-here-review-southwark-playhouse"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Southwark Playhouse, London
Wendi Peters seizes the role of a suburbanite who is inspired by the lunar broadcast to embark on a spontaneous trip
Two men walked on the moon in the summer of 1969. Ten more followed in their footsteps over the next three years. All giant leaps for man – but what did it mean for womankind? You Are Here, given its UK premiere by the new musical-theatre company the Grey Area, imagines the moon’s pull on a suburban Chicagoan, Diana.
Her Sunday nights have usually been spent with h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Wiegand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince William slams BBC ‘deceit’ over Diana interview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/bbc-martin-bashir-used-deceitful-behaviour-to-secure-diana-interview-report-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/bbc-martin-bashir-used-deceitful-behaviour-to-secure-diana-interview-report-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harry also criticises media practices after damning report into Martin Bashir Panorama programme
Princess Diana’s sons have slammed the BBC over the Martin Bashir Panorama interview with their mother, saying the corporation’s failures contributed to the fear she felt in her final years and was part of a “culture of exploitation and unethical practices that ultimately took her life”.
In a blistering statement, Prince William said that BBC leaders had failed Diana, Princess of Wales, with their “woeful incomp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney and Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Girl, 11, smeared blue slime on would-be kidnapper to help police identify him]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/20/florida-girl-attempted-kidnapping-blue-slime</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/20/florida-girl-attempted-kidnapping-blue-slime"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T20:59:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alyssa Bonal, who was attacked on Tuesday, said she learned about evidence from the TV show Law & Order: Special Victims Unit
An 11-year-old girl in Florida had the presence of mind to smear the blue slime she had been playing with on the arms of an attempted kidnapper, who threatened her with a knife and dragged her toward his van, so police could identify him.
Alyssa Bonal, of Pensacola, said she learned the importance of evidence from her favorite TV show, the long-running detective series Law & Order: S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea bounce back from Barcelona defeat with FA Cup win over Everton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/chelsea-everton-womens-fa-cup-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/chelsea-everton-womens-fa-cup-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T20:20:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A wet and windy Kingsmeadow proved the backdrop to the final act of the women’s season as, fittingly, Chelsea finished the campaign on a high.
Although Everton made them work hard at times, goals from Guro Reiten, Sam Kerr and Drew Spence ensured Emma Hayes’s side booked their place in the last eight of the FA Cup. It may seem strange to break for the summer immediately after a rescheduled fifth-round tie but Covid-prompted postponements have dictated that the competition’s latest edition straddles two seas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louise Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US PGA: Corey Conners takes overnight lead with Brooks Koepka in contention]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/brooks-koepka-plays-through-aftermath-of-injury-to-take-share-of-us-pga-lead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/brooks-koepka-plays-through-aftermath-of-injury-to-take-share-of-us-pga-lead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T20:07:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conners hits 67 to lead chasing pack by two shots
Koepka among contenders after recent injury woes

Those taking interest in Brooks Koepka’s preview press conference at this US PGA Championship may have sensed an unwitting stumble into an episode of Grey’s Anatomy. Some 16 out of 17 questions posed to Koepka related in some way or other to matters of injury.
Therein lies the reason it has been easy to forget Koepka’s one-time – and recent – specialism on these platforms. Fitness woes, apparently prolonged b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray at Kiawah Island</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[El Salvador: dozens of bodies found at ex-cop’s house investigated as femicides]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/el-salvador-mass-grave-ex-detectives-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/el-salvador-mass-grave-ex-detectives-house"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:59:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clandestine cemetery in Chalchuapa is believed to contain as many as 40 bodies – most of them thought to be women
Authorities in El Salvador are excavating a clandestine cemetery at the house of a former detective which is believed to contain as many as 40 bodies – most of them thought to be women.
The remains of at least 24 people have been recovered so far at the house in the municipality of Chalchuapa, about 48 miles (78km) north-west of the capital, San Salvador. Exhuming the bodies could take another m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in San Salvador</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trust is key to BBC’s survival – so it must learn from Martin Bashir scandal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/trust-key-to-bbc-survival-martin-bashir-scandal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/trust-key-to-bbc-survival-martin-bashir-scandal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: a revered public service broadcaster cannot be seen to have an ‘end justifies the means’ mentality 
Lord Dyson’s report into how the BBC obtained and then investigated Martin Bashir’s groundbreaking interview is devastating: its star journalist lied, the BBC’s own investigation was “woefully inadequate” and then the BBC covered up this appalling behaviour for 26 years.
The 127-page report goes into excruciating detail of how senior executives – one of whom went on to become the director general – …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jane Martinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England under pressure to reschedule or cancel fifth Test against India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/england-under-pressure-to-reschedule-or-cancel-fifth-test-against-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/england-under-pressure-to-reschedule-or-cancel-fifth-test-against-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:24:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[September match could clash with plans for restarted IPL
ECB says schedule is ‘long agreed’, expected to resist changes

English cricket’s relationship with India faces a potential fork in the road following an informal request to move the fifth Test in September to the start of the series – or even cancel it altogether – in order to complete the Indian Premier League.
The IPL was suspended on 4 May amid an outbreak of Covid-19 among the franchises. But with the 31 IPL games still to be played worth an esti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular 11 Tutorial: Code a Project from Scratch]]></title>
        <id>60a6b3ab906c5207e3a7f5fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/angular-11-tutorial-code-a-project-from-scratch/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angular is one of the most popular web frameworks. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create an Angular 11 project from scratch. It uses a public API to create a game database website. You will gain a great foundation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No 10 plays down reports of cabinet rift over post-Brexit Australia trade deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/no-10-plays-down-reports-of-cabinet-rift-over-post-brexit-australia-trade-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/no-10-plays-down-reports-of-cabinet-rift-over-post-brexit-australia-trade-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:10:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Downing Street hints at support for plan to slash import tariffs despite concerns over impact on British farming
Downing Street has played down reports of a cabinet rift over the UK’s future trading relationship with Australia, as trade secretary Liz Truss pushes to secure a deal before the G7 summit next month.
Truss is keen to throw open the UK market to Australian farmers, by slashing import tariffs on goods such as beef, lamb and sugar; while some of her cabinet colleagues, including Michael Gove, are a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on the government’s UK rail industry reform plan – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/20/steve-bell-on-the-governments-uk-rail-industry-reform-plan-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/20/steve-bell-on-the-governments-uk-rail-industry-reform-plan-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayne Mardle: ‘I wanted to be a clown. No one wants that any more’ | Jonathan Liew]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/wayne-mardle-i-wanted-to-be-a-clown-no-one-wants-that-any-more</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/20/wayne-mardle-i-wanted-to-be-a-clown-no-one-wants-that-any-more"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The flamboyant player turned pundit on the ‘terrible’ attitude that held him back, his coaching school, and social media abuse 
A couple of months ago, Wayne Mardle was filming a celebrity episode of the ITV gameshow Bullseye when he was gripped by a strange and unfamiliar sensation. You might think that, as a former professional darts player and now one of the sport’s most recognisable commentators, performing on television is the last thing that would faze him. But as he prepared to go on stage in tandem …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Liew</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rail reforms will surely reroute Trainline’s profit margins to head south]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/20/rail-reforms-will-surely-reroute-trainlines-profit-margins-to-head-south</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/20/rail-reforms-will-surely-reroute-trainlines-profit-margins-to-head-south"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before Thursday’s white paper Trainline’s ability to continue extracting 5% commissions on ticket sales seemed assured
Farewell, Trainline, you made a handful of executives, backed by the private barons of KKR, very rich, but now Grant Shapps, the transport secretary, has your number.
That, at least, is a possible reading of the ticketing shake-up within the rail reforms that will create Great British Railways. The new “fat controller” body will launch its own website and app to sell tickets, which looks a …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confirmed cases of India variant in UK rise 160% in a week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/confirmed-cases-of-india-variant-in-england-rise-160-in-a-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/confirmed-cases-of-india-variant-in-england-rise-160-in-a-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T18:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Latest figures from PHE come as another new variant is designated ‘under investigation’

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The number of confirmed cases in the UK of the Covid variant of concern that was first detected in India has risen more than 160% in the past week, data shows, and another new variant has been designated as “under investigation”.
Data from Public Health England (PHE) shows there have now been 3,424 confirmed cases of the B.1.617.2 variant in the UK, up from …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shares in alt-milk maker Oatly surge on US stock market debut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/shares-alt-milk-maker-oatly-us-stock-market-debut-investors-alternative</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/shares-alt-milk-maker-oatly-us-stock-market-debut-investors-alternative"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T18:16:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Swedish firm valued at $13bn as investors bet on soaring demand for plant-based food alternatives
Shares in Oatly have surged by 30% on the company’s US stock market debut, valuing the alt-milk maker at $13bn (£9.2bn), as investors bet runaway demand from consumers for plant-based food alternatives will continue.
Oatly is using the money from the initial public offering to expand its global network of factories, enabling it to quadruple production from 350m litres of oat milk a year to 1.4bn in two years. I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Student shot dead in Blackburn ‘in wrong place at wrong time,’ court told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/student-shot-dead-in-blackburn-in-wrong-place-at-wrong-time-court-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/student-shot-dead-in-blackburn-in-wrong-place-at-wrong-time-court-told"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T18:04:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aya Hachem was killed in drive-by shooting after dispute between tyre firm owners, jury hears
A student who was shot dead in the street amid a dispute between two neighbours in Blackburn was “in the wrong place at the wrong time”, a court has heard.
Aya Hachem, a 19-year-old law student, was a killed in a drive-by shooting on 17 May last year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carlos Ghosn ordered to repay £4.3m to Nissan and Mitsubishi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/carlos-ghosn-ordered-to-repay-43m-to-nissan-and-mitsubishi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/carlos-ghosn-ordered-to-repay-43m-to-nissan-and-mitsubishi"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T18:01:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fugitive businessman loses wrongful dismissal claim as Dutch court finds he did not have valid contract
Carlos Ghosn, the fugitive automotive executive, has been ordered to repay £4.3m to Nissan and Mitsubishi by a Dutch court after he failed in the first step in a legal claim.
Ghosn led the Japanese carmaker Nissan and France’s Renault in an alliance, before falling from grace spectacularly. At the end of 2018 he was arrested by prosecutors in Tokyo, charged with concealing his income, but fled to Lebanon …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brother of Manchester arena attackers asks for immunity to take part in public inquiry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/brother-of-manchester-arena-attackers-ask-for-immunity-to-take-part-in-public-inquiry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/brother-of-manchester-arena-attackers-ask-for-immunity-to-take-part-in-public-inquiry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:59:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ismail Abedi wants promise from attorney general his answers will not ‘land him in the dock’
The elder brother of the Manchester Arena bombers has asked for immunity from prosecution in return for answering questions at the public inquiry into the terror attack.
Ismail Abedi wants a promise from the attorney general that if he were to give evidence his answers will not “land him in the dock”, his solicitor, Jeremy Hawthorn, told the hearing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK-Australia trade deal: what are the key issues?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/uk-australia-trade-deal-what-are-the-key-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/uk-australia-trade-deal-what-are-the-key-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:57:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explainer: the post-Brexit deal could reduce meat prices in the UK – bad news for British agriculture
The prospect of a tariff-free trade deal with Australia has alarmed British farmers and some MPs, including Conservatives. A lot is at stake in what would be the first post-Brexit major trade deal. Here we look at the key issues.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Second bite is one that broke the bones’: Alaska man describes bear mauling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/20/alaska-bear-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/20/alaska-bear-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:49:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Allen Minish was surveying land when he locked eyes with a brown bear in an encounter that left him with a crushed jaw and deep cuts

Warning: contains image of injuries sustained in the attack

Allen Minish was alone and surveying land for a real estate agent in a wooded, remote part of Alaska, putting some numbers into his GPS unit when he looked up and saw a large brown bear walking about 30ft (10 meters) away.
“I saw him and he saw me at the same time,” Minish said by phone on Wednesday from his hospita…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the US and Israel: time for change | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/the-guardian-view-on-the-us-and-israel-time-for-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/the-guardian-view-on-the-us-and-israel-time-for-change"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:48:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden’s approach to this conflict is as expected. But the views of his party and the public are changing

One of the grimmest aspects of the conflict that has unfolded over recent days is its sheer familiarity, especially to those living through it. Even the youngest have faced this violence too many times before: the Norwegian Refugee Council reported that 11 of the children killed by Israeli airstrikes in Gaza over the past week were participating in its psychosocial programme to help them deal with t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concern about potential fare rises as government unveils rail changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/concern-about-potential-fare-rises-as-government-unveils-rail-reform</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/concern-about-potential-fare-rises-as-government-unveils-rail-reform"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:46:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grant Shapps says Great British Railways will be simpler and will ‘bring down overall costs’
A Great British Railways will mean a simpler, more efficient system for the industry and passengers, the government has pledged – but job cuts and fare rises have not been ruled out as ministers said they would bear down on costs.
The transport secretary, Grant Shapps, said the changes announced in a white paper on Thursday would “make the railways easier to use by simplifying fares and ticketing, providing more con…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Natural England to get 47% funding increase amid ‘green recovery’ plans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/natural-england-to-get-47-funding-increase-amid-green-recovery-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/natural-england-to-get-47-funding-increase-amid-green-recovery-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:37:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservation watchdog given boost after decade of funding cuts that left it at ‘crisis point’
Natural England, the government’s conservation watchdog, is to receive a 47% increase in government funding this year as its role expands to support a “green recovery” and provide environmental scrutiny of the government’s controversial “Project Speed”.
The dramatic funding increase is a boost for wildlife protection and monitoring after a decade of deep cuts which left the agency at “crisis point” and its chairman…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image released of cellar being searched in Fred West investigation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/image-released-of-cellar-being-searched-in-fred-west-investigation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/image-released-of-cellar-being-searched-in-fred-west-investigation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:37:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police excavating part of Gloucester cafe’s basement in search for remains of 15-year-old Mary Bastholm
Police have released an image and footage of a cellar where the body of a possible victim of the serial killer Fred West may be buried.
Officers are excavating six “voids” in the basement floor of the Clean Plate cafe in Gloucester as part of an investigation into the disappearance of 15-year-old Mary Bastholm more than half a century ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU parliament ‘freezes’ China trade deal over sanctions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/eu-parliament-freezes-china-trade-deal-over-sanctions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/eu-parliament-freezes-china-trade-deal-over-sanctions"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tit-for-tat sanctions over Beijing’s treatment of Uyghurs puts halt on investment agreement 
The European parliament has voted overwhelmingly to “freeze” any consideration of a massive investment deal with China, following recent tit-for-tat sanctions over Beijing’s treatment of its Uyghur population in Xinjiang province.
According to the resolution, the parliament, which must ratify the deal, “demands that China lift the sanctions before parliament can deal with the Comprehensive Agreement on Investment (C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni China affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s nothing ‘great’ about this new British Railways revamp | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/great-british-railways-ministers-rail-system-train-companies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/great-british-railways-ministers-rail-system-train-companies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:14:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers will not get the rail system back on track until they allow individual train companies to manage their assets
No enemy of Tory policy is as savage as a Johnson Tory. Enter Grant Shapps, transport secretary. His proposed reincarnation of British Railways (ridiculously with “Great” attached) ends one of the major failures of modern British government. He accuses the botched Conservative privatisation of British Rail in 1993 of leading to “fragmentation, confusion and overcomplication”. In truth what…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Modern C++ by Building an Audio Plugin]]></title>
        <id>60a694ab906c5207e3a7f544</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-modern-cpp-by-building-an-audio-plugin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of C++ courses teach you how to build toy projects with no real-world application. But it can often be more helpful to write programs people would actually use. We just released a 5-hour C++ course that will teach you how to write modern C++ code by building an]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renovation of parliamentary flats cost nearly £700,000 of public money]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/renovation-of-parliamentary-flats-cost-nearly-700000-of-public-money</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/renovation-of-parliamentary-flats-cost-nearly-700000-of-public-money"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:08:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emails released under FoI show officials were initially given a budget of £280,000
A secret plan to renovate five “grace and favour” flats on the parliamentary estate for senior House of Commons staff has cost nearly £700,000 of public money, the Guardian can reveal.
Emails released under the Freedom of Information Act show that officials were initially given a budget of £280,000 for the refurbishment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How is the UK government planning to change the rail network?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/how-is-the-uk-government-planning-to-reform-the-rail-network</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/how-is-the-uk-government-planning-to-reform-the-rail-network"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers say Great British Railways will mean a simpler, more accountable system, but how will it work? 
The long-awaited review of Britain’s rail industry has been published by the government, with the creation of a new Great British Railways promising a simpler, more accountable system.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s beef exports to UK ‘could rise tenfold’ on free-trade deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/australia-beef-exports-uk-free-trade-deal-farmers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/australia-beef-exports-uk-free-trade-deal-farmers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:02:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Head of Australian agricultural firm predicts sales surge as UK farmers warn they will struggle to compete
Australia’s biggest cattle farmer has predicted that the nation’s beef exports to the UK could rise as much as tenfold if the two countries strike a free-trade deal.
Boris Johnson is determined to push through a free-trade deal with Australia, despite warnings from the National Farmers’ Union over the “irreversible damage” such a deal would do to UK agriculture. It was discussed by ministers at a cabin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Declining birthrates will the take strain off our planet | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/declining-birthrates-will-take-the-strain-off-our-planet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/declining-birthrates-will-take-the-strain-off-our-planet"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to a Guardian editorial that suggested a demographic crisis is looming in Europe
I must take issue with your editorial that seems to suggest that declining birthrates need to be reversed (The Guardian view on declining birthrates: there may be trouble ahead, 16 May).
With climate change and environmental destruction accelerating worldwide, and the obvious reluctance of politicians to spell out to their electorates the economic, lifestyle and societal changes required to tackle this, natural …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We need public and affordable workspaces | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/we-need-public-and-affordable-spaces-workspaces</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/20/we-need-public-and-affordable-spaces-workspaces"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:36:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RL Symonds offers a solution to the future of working from home, while Malcolm Mckay says consumers have been forgotten by businesses
I agree with your editorial (The Guardian view on working from home: a new social divide, 18 May), but you do not explore the alternative. Someone might be managing international conferences from a laptop in their kitchen, while their partner works downstairs. Two jobs for multinationals run from a small house with two children at home in lockdown – and a dog. Since Covid, th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Both sides in Israel-Gaza conflict lay groundwork for victory narratives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/both-sides-in-israel-gaza-conflict-lay-groundwork-for-victory-narratives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/both-sides-in-israel-gaza-conflict-lay-groundwork-for-victory-narratives"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:35:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: flare-up regarded by some as example of domestic politics driving violent escalation
As a ceasefire begins between Israel and Palestinian fighters in Gaza, the longtime foes are poised to turn their attention away from military action and on to constructing competing narratives of victory.
Already, the groundwork is being laid. Unnamed Israeli defence officials are being quoted in local media as saying they are satisfied with the damage inflicted. And a militant source in Gaza said: “For us, the b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pro-Palestine movement is broad but it can’t be a home to antisemitism | Keith Kahn-Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/pro-palestine-movement-antisemitism-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/pro-palestine-movement-antisemitism-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:25:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Antisemitic incidents in London on the same weekend as protests underline the need for an honest reckoning 
Last Sunday saw one of the most dramatic antisemitic incidents in the UK in recent years. A convoy of cars, flying Palestinian flags, drove through Jewish neighbourhoods in north London and their occupants were filmed shouting antisemitic and misogynistic threats (aimed at Jews, not just Israelis).
An upsurge in violence in Israel-Palestine is always accompanied by an upsurge in antisemitic incidents …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Kahn-Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is not rail renationalisation, Shapps protests – even though it is | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/this-is-not-rail-renationalisation-shapps-protests-even-though-it-is</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/20/this-is-not-rail-renationalisation-shapps-protests-even-though-it-is"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:23:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was the transport secretary’s big day, so let’s forget about ideology – and don’t ask about ticket prices
Methinks he doth protest too much. “This is not renationalisation,” the transport secretary, Grant Shapps, had said in his statement to the Commons on the overhaul of the rail network. Yet you couldn’t help thinking that many of the proposals being put forward were all but that in name. Something to which the Tories would have raised countless objections had they been put forward by the Labour party.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Rosen condemns ‘loathsome and antisemitic’ manipulated image]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/20/michael-rosen-condemns-loathsome-and-antisemitic-manipulated-image</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/20/michael-rosen-condemns-loathsome-and-antisemitic-manipulated-image"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:17:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria University is investigating one of its staff for sharing a doctored image of Jeremy Corbyn reading an antisemitic text, placed over Rosen’s We’re Going on a Bear Hunt
Northumbria University is urgently investigating one of its academics after a doctored image was shared from his Twitter account showing Jeremy Corbyn reading from the notorious antisemitic forgery The Protocols of the Learned Elders of Zion. The title had been superimposed on the Michael Rosen book We’re Going on a Bear Hunt, whic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Art students seek to take university to court over ‘heartbreaking’ clear-out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/20/art-students-seek-to-take-university-to-court-over-heartbreaking-clear-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/20/art-students-seek-to-take-university-to-court-over-heartbreaking-clear-out"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:14:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Royal College of Art offers compensation for work and materials damaged or lost in studio tidy
The conceptual artist Farvash Razavi had planned to use the colour-changing inks she spent two years developing with scientists for an intricate installation at her master’s graduation show. That is, until she found her delicate pieces shattered in a box after her university, the Royal College of Art (RCA), cleared out her studio over the summer. 
Razavi’s sculpture, which explored censorship and belonging through…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animal rights charities criticise the Offspring over video of chimp in strip club]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/animal-rights-charities-criticise-the-offspring-chimps-music-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/animal-rights-charities-criticise-the-offspring-chimps-music-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:06:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peta and Save the Chimps issue statements criticising US punk band, describing scenes featuring chimpanzees as ‘animal exploitation at its worst’
Animal rights charities have criticised chart-topping Californian punk band the Offspring for using chimpanzees to act like humans – including in a strip club – in their latest music video.
Save the Chimps, a Florida-based sanctuary for chimpanzees that have been involved in scientific research, the entertainment industry and elsewhere, described the video as “ani…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Lives Matter photographer becomes Southbank Centre chair]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/20/black-lives-matter-photographer-misan-harriman-becomes-southbank-centre-chair</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/20/black-lives-matter-photographer-misan-harriman-becomes-southbank-centre-chair"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Misan Harriman, who only took up photography four years ago, now leads Britain’s largest art centre
A former City headhunter turned photographer who took one of the defining pictures from last year’s Black Lives Matter protests in London has been appointed chair of Britain’s largest arts centre.
Misan Harriman is to succeed Susan Gilchrist as chair of trustees at the Southbank Centre, it was announced on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Brown Arts correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Boris Johnson really going to sacrifice arts degrees for the Conservative cause? | Gaby Hinsliff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/boris-johnson-arts-degrees-conservative-funds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/boris-johnson-arts-degrees-conservative-funds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cutting subsidies and tuition fees are part of broader and more audacious attack on England’s liberal institutions
Imagining the future is never easy. But for teenagers in a pandemic, struggling to get a feel for university life from “virtual open days” now being conducted strictly via Zoom, it’s perhaps uniquely tough. This year’s lower sixth, only too aware of a harsh jobs market out there, are more anxious than ever about getting their decisions right.
Is university even worth it? Should they follow thei…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaby Hinsliff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Borrowdale Banksy’ mystery over stone artworks in Lake District]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/borrowdale-banksy-mystery-over-stone-artworks-in-lake-district</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/borrowdale-banksy-mystery-over-stone-artworks-in-lake-district"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:44:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stone structures appear at three locations, courtesy of ‘talented, patient,’ unknown artist
Lake District landscapes have inspired artists for centuries, from Beatrix Potter to Taylor Swift, and now it seems another has been stirred by the views after a number of stone artworks appeared in the area, courtesy of an unknown artist whom locals are referring to as the “Borrowdale Banksy”.
Two structures have been photographed so far, one on Castle Crag and another a three-hour walk east on Raven Crag. According…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK civil servants given just days to prepare £2.9bn aid cuts in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/uk-civil-servants-given-just-days-to-prepare-29bn-aid-cuts-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/uk-civil-servants-given-just-days-to-prepare-29bn-aid-cuts-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:40:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cuts were agreed on the basis of a forecast shown five days later to be too pessimistic, report finds
UK civil servants were given five to seven working days to prepare 30% cuts in the overseas aid budget last summer, including a £730m cut to bilateral aid that it later emerged was unnecessary.
The cuts were agreed in July 2020 on the basis of a single forecast reduction in the size of the UK economy, which was shown to be too pessimistic five days after the cuts package was signed off.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanish aid volunteer abused online for hugging Senegalese migrant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/spanish-aid-volunteer-luna-reyes-abused-online-for-hugging-african-migrant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/spanish-aid-volunteer-luna-reyes-abused-online-for-hugging-african-migrant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:32:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Luna Reyes targeted by far-right supporters after footage of gesture goes viral
The image captured the raw humanity of the moment: a Red Cross volunteer tenderly consoling a Senegalese man moments after he stepped foot in Spain’s north African enclave of Ceuta.
Hours after the footage went viral, however, Luna Reyes set her social media accounts to private after she was targeted by a torrent of abuse from supporters of Spain’s far-right Vox party and others incensed by the unprecedented arrival of 8,000 mig…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashifa Kassam in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pedestrian casualties higher among BAME people and in poor areas, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/pedestrian-casualties-england-wales-higher-among-bame-people-and-in-poor-areas-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/pedestrian-casualties-england-wales-higher-among-bame-people-and-in-poor-areas-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:27:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: BAME people in poorer areas of England and Wales three times more likely to be injured or die than white people in richer districts
People living in deprived areas and those from minority ethnic backgrounds are notably more likely to be killed or injured as pedestrians on the roads, according to a new study.
The research, using 10 years of casualties reported to the police across England and Wales, found black, Asian and minority ethnic (BAME) pedestrians living in poorer areas were more than thr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of breast implant victims will get payouts after court ruling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/pay-compensation-to-victims-of-defective-breast-implants-rules-paris-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/pay-compensation-to-victims-of-defective-breast-implants-rules-paris-court"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:27:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Case in Paris was brought by 2,700 women over implants made by French company and certified as safe by German firm
Thousands of victims of the PIP breast implant scandal, including 540 British women, will receive compensation after a Paris appeals court ruling.
The case in Paris was brought by 2,700 women who said they had suffered long-term health effects after receiving implants manufactured by a French firm which were filled with cheap, industrial-grade silicone not cleared for human use.
 Continue readi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Topping</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Started with Version Control Using Git]]></title>
        <id>60a4b5c7906c5207e3a7e2bb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/get-started-with-version-control-and-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, you'll learn what version control is and how you can contribute to open-source projects using Git.  We'll get through the fundamentals of Git and I'll give you the knowledge that is indispensable for any web developer. What is Git?Git is a version control software which lets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The ‘peaceful coexistence’ of my city of Jaffa is falling apart in front of my eyes | Asaf Ronel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/peaceful-coexistence-jaffa-falling-apart-israeli-police</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/peaceful-coexistence-jaffa-falling-apart-israeli-police"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:17:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This ancient city has been turned into a battleground, and the Israeli police are doing nothing to ease tensions
Jaffa is one of the oldest cities in the world. It was the metropolis of Palestine, until it was conquered by Israel in 1948 – most of its Palestinian population then became refugees, and the city was absorbed into Tel Aviv one year later.
For decades the city was simply seen as the backyard of Tel Aviv. But in recent years, Israeli Jews like me started discovering its charms, and a process of ge…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Asaf Ronel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn JavaScript - A Free 7-hour Interactive Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60a36742906c5207e3a7da6e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-javascript-interactive-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last four months, I have recorded what is probably the most interactive JavaScript course that has ever been created. The reason I have done this is because I often see new coders fall into the same pitfalls again and again when trying to learn JavaScript, with the most]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Color me confused: Lil Yachty's nail paints are doing a lot of mental gymnastics | Harron Walker]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/20/lil-yachty-nail-paints-nail-polish-branding-unisex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/20/lil-yachty-nail-paints-nail-polish-branding-unisex"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:49:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rapper said his new line is all about ‘breaking down the barriers’ but taking something traditionally feminine and giving it a new name is very silly
After months of hype, Lil Yachty is finally about to release his much-anticipated line of nail polishes – sorry, nail paints. Nail polishes are for girls, but nail paints? That’s for boys.
Anyway, as I was saying, the Georgia-born rapper – whose latest mixtape, Michigan Boy Boat, came out in April – will debut said line of nail paints this coming Friday. T…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harron Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicolas Sarkozy on trial for alleged illegal campaign financing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/france-nicolas-sarkozy-trial-alleged-campaign-financing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/france-nicolas-sarkozy-trial-alleged-campaign-financing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:29:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former president of France, already convicted of corruption, faces accusation of overspending 
The former French president Nicolas Sarkozy has gone on trial for the alleged illegal campaign financing of the massive, showman-style political rallies he staged during his failed re-election bid in 2012.
Sarkozy, president for one term from 2007 to 2012, was not present for the opening of the trial in Paris on Thursday but will take the stand next month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angelique Chrisafis in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘You can’t block the M5’: police prepare for mass protests at Cornwall G7 summit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/you-cant-block-the-m5-police-prepare-for-mass-protests-at-cornwall-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/20/you-cant-block-the-m5-police-prepare-for-mass-protests-at-cornwall-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:29:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local force says it has identified more than 30 groups planning some kind of action during event

Activists are expected to disrupt next month’s G7 summit in Cornwall by blocking main roads into the county, trying to obstruct convoys carrying world leaders and perhaps even targeting a cruise ship that will be anchored off the coast as extra accommodation for police officers.
Devon and Cornwall police are preparing for thousands of protesters to head to the far south-west of Britain for the 11-13 June event,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boko Haram leader tried to kill himself during clash with rivals, officials claim]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/boko-haram-leader-abubakar-shekau-nigeria-forest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/boko-haram-leader-abubakar-shekau-nigeria-forest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:28:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abubakar Shekau dead or seriously wounded after clashes in forest, Nigerian authorities say
Intelligence officials in Nigeria have claimed the leader of Boko Haram is dead or seriously wounded after trying to kill himself to avoid capture during clashes with a rival extremist faction.
There is no confirmation of the claims, and Nigeria’s intelligence services and military have reported Abubakar Shekau’s death many times before.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke in Johannesburg and Emmanuel Akinwotu in Lagos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340715</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/can-we-create-a-resize-hack-with-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you follow new developments in CSS, you’ve likely heard of the impending arrival of container queries. We’re going to look at the basics here, but if you’d like another look, check out Una’s “Next Gen CSS: @container” article. …
The post Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jhey Tompkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blaming the unvaccinated for Covid's spread won't help stop the virus | Gabriel Scally]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/unvaccinated-covid-patients-bolton-matt-hancock-virus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/unvaccinated-covid-patients-bolton-matt-hancock-virus"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:21:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pointing the finger at people who haven’t yet had the jab, as Matt Hancock did this week, just diverts attention from government failures

This week in the House of Commons, Matt Hancock referred three times to a group of patients in Bolton hospital being treated for Covid-19. He seemed particularly keen to point out that of these 19 patients, the majority were eligible for a vaccine but “had chosen not yet to have it”.
Hancock’s use of this information raises several important questions. How did the health…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriel Scally</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fit-content and fit-content()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340897</id>
        <link href="https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2021/04/fitcontent_and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s some hardcore deep-dive CSS nerdery from PPK. If you can wrap your mind around min-content (the smallest an element can be based on the content it contains) and max-content (the largest the content of an element can push it) …
The post fit-content and fit-content() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zack Snyder: ‘I don’t have a rightwing political agenda. People see what they want to see’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/20/zack-snyder-i-dont-have-a-rightwing-political-agenda-people-see-what-they-want-to-see</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/20/zack-snyder-i-dont-have-a-rightwing-political-agenda-people-see-what-they-want-to-see"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As his latest film Army of the Dead hits Netflix, the Justice League director takes time to answer questions from fans and collaborators
Luca, Zack Snyder’s chow-labrador cross, is going bananas. It’s early morning in rural Pasadena and the air is filled with growls. When a bear ambled past the other day, Luca didn’t bat an eyelid. But the appearance of the gardener (who apparently comes every day) means he needs considerable restraint.
So it was while wrestling this “big, muscly, silly dog” that Snyder ans…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Catherine Shoard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Bygraves obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/mark-bygraves-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/mark-bygraves-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T13:38:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friend and former colleague Mark Bygraves, who has died aged 62, was the loudest person at the Guardian – by a long way. Mark, a picture editor who worked with us for 28 years, was also probably the funniest, toughest, filthiest, sweariest, bluntest, warmest, loyalest (if he liked you), smartest, and rudest man at the Guardian. It’s impossible to do Mark justice in a family newspaper.
Mark was born in south London to Bill, a printer maintenance worker at the News of the World, and Eileen (nee Latuske), a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nurses know exactly why Boris Johnson’s nurse quit – we are running on empty | Anonymous]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/nurses-jenny-mcgee-quit-better-paid-resignation-boris-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/20/nurses-jenny-mcgee-quit-better-paid-resignation-boris-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T13:32:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jenny McGee’s resignation makes it clear how shoddily we have been treated by this government
I’ve never treated anybody famous. But then, as a nurse, you treat everybody the same – without fear or favour.
Jenny McGee might have looked after Boris Johnson when he was gravely ill with Covid-19, but that’s the only difference I can see between her and nearly every nurse I know. Do your job, give your all, come back again tomorrow. Until you can’t.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anonymous</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vampires, naked apes and free booze! The 20 wildest Eurovision performances ever]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/the-20-wildest-eurovision-performances-ever</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/20/the-20-wildest-eurovision-performances-ever"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T13:20:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Baffling stunts and bizarre lyrics are de rigueur at europop’s premier competition – so it takes quite something to make this list
At Eurovision, you have three minutes to impress the world. While an unforgettable song and stonking vocals are key to getting douze points, how else can you make your performance stand out? With bewildering stunts, surreal lyrics and distracting props, of course! With the biggest event in europop returning this week, let’s revisit some of the weirdest performances over the year…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Bryan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue sky, green sea and red tape: diving in the Algarve after lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/20/diving-in-the-algarve-after-lockdown-lagos-rushby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/20/diving-in-the-algarve-after-lockdown-lagos-rushby"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T12:10:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a few days of spectacular diving near Lagos fresh in the memory, Kevin Rushby had to tackle the last few hurdles of Covid paperwork to return home

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Part One. The End. I’m standing at the head of the check-in queue for my easyJet flight back to the UK from Portugal. I’ve just been told that I have not got the correct documents. The receptionist does not know, but I am diving down a warren of holes, very dark holes of memory, all containing a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rushby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ceuta influx highlights fragility of EU’s approach to migration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/ceuta-influx-highlights-fragility-of-eus-approach-to-migration</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/ceuta-influx-highlights-fragility-of-eus-approach-to-migration"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T12:01:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arrival of thousands of migrants in Spanish enclave is just latest example of issue that affects whole of ‘Fortress Europe’
On the outskirts of the Spanish city of Ceuta, a warehouse has been hastily transformed into a makeshift shelter for young people, their actions watched over by hired security. Days after joining an unprecedented influx of 8,000 migrants into Spain, the fate of these minors who arrived alone has become a thorny issue, stretching far beyond the north African enclave.
“It’s important to …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashifa Kassam in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Plant’s teenage obsessions: ‘Stourbridge was our Beverly Hills’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/robert-plants-teenage-obsessions-stourbridge-was-our-beverly-hills</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/robert-plants-teenage-obsessions-stourbridge-was-our-beverly-hills"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Led Zeppelin frontman turned podcaster reflects on jazz beatniks reading Camus, the primeval power of Ike & Tina Turner, and taking Muddy Waters’s spot on Alexis Korner’s couch
I was an only child until I was 11, so my childhood was spent in this blissful otherworldly state, cycling with my dad through the Welsh borders, visiting castles and churches. Just 30 to 40 miles from the Black Country, everything would change: the landscape, language, folklore and the remoteness of spirits. As a teenager, I spe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Dave Simpson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A sea rescue and drive-in opera: Thursday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/20/a-sea-rescue-and-drive-in-opera-thursdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/20/a-sea-rescue-and-drive-in-opera-thursdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:34:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world

 Warning: contains images that some may find disturbing
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harry Kane claims Spurs could be wise to sell and he will decide own future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/harry-kane-says-spurs-could-be-ready-to-sell-and-he-will-decide-own-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/harry-kane-says-spurs-could-be-ready-to-sell-and-he-will-decide-own-future"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:33:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Striker wants ‘good honest conversation’ with the club
‘Ultimately it’s going to be down to me and how I feel’

Harry Kane has suggested that Daniel Levy may be wise to sell him this summer because his value is at its peak, and the Tottenham striker has mentioned £100m as a potentially acceptable figure. Kane, who is determined to get a move away – most likely to Manchester City – also feels he should not be held against his will after giving his all for Spurs since joining as an 11-year-old.
“As players, y…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis behind drastic drop in Arctic wildlife populations – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Native shorebirds and caribou among species at risk as survival strategies are upended
A drastic drop in caribou and shorebird populations is a reflection of the dire changes unfolding on the Arctic tundra, according to a new report from the Arctic Council. 
The terrestrial Arctic spans approximately 2.7m sq miles (7m sq km), marked by extreme cold, drought, strong winds and seasonal darkness. Species living in this environment have adapted to thrive in the harsh conditions. But the climate crisis has upend…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Dickie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It sounded like 80,000’: how it felt to have fans back in Premier League]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/it-sounded-like-80000-how-it-felt-to-have-fans-back-in-premier-league-grounds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/20/it-sounded-like-80000-how-it-felt-to-have-fans-back-in-premier-league-grounds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the return of supporters to top-flight grounds, our reporters reflect on the impact at the matches they attended
The Amex’s reopening could not have gone more perfectly to script. Brighton’s comeback sparked wild celebrations in all four stands but the atmosphere had been electric from the first whistle. Everyone present seemed desperate to make up for lost time and there was barely a pause for breath even when, having heartily booed Riyad Mahrez seconds before he created the opener, they saw Manchest…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snoring, slugs and sarcoptic mange: is it safe for cats and dogs to sleep on our beds?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/snoring-slugs-and-sarcoptic-mange-is-it-safe-for-cats-and-dogs-to-sleep-on-our-beds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/snoring-slugs-and-sarcoptic-mange-is-it-safe-for-cats-and-dogs-to-sleep-on-our-beds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dogs can carry bacteria and parasites, while cats smuggle in gory ‘presents’. So is it best to lock them out of the bedroom?

Vomiting on the bed. Snoring. The shedding of hair. The stealing of sheets. The passing of wind. Night-time face-licking. A higher-than-average chance of catching sarcoptic mange …
If I could sit my dog down and quietly explain the risks associated with him sharing the bed with us, this is the list I would read to him. But I know he wouldn’t listen. Oz, our young lurcher, would only …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jules Howard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naturalist Jane Goodall wins 2021 Templeton prize for life’s work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/20/naturalist-jane-goodall-wins-2021-templeton-prize-for-lifes-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/20/naturalist-jane-goodall-wins-2021-templeton-prize-for-lifes-work"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prize recognises primatologist’s contribution to work on animal intelligence and humanity
The naturalist Jane Goodall has been announced as the 2021 winner of the Templeton prize in recognition of her life’s work on animal intelligence and humanity.
Goodall, 87, built her global reputation on her groundbreaking studies of chimpanzees in Tanzania in the 1960s. Her foundation, the Jane Goodall Institute, works with local communities as well as providing safe habitats for chimpanzees and gorillas, and its educ…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you attended a large-scale test event in England?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from the people who attended these events about their experiences
In April, the government launched their scheme to pilot large-scale events in England to test their safety before restrictions are eased on mass gatherings.
The majority of rules on social contact are set to be removed by 21 June, but this is dependent on cases, deaths and hospital admissions continuing to fall.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dogs can better detect Covid in humans than lateral flow tests, finds study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/dogs-can-better-detect-covid-in-humans-than-lateral-flow-tests-finds-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/dogs-can-better-detect-covid-in-humans-than-lateral-flow-tests-finds-study"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:20:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French trial shows dogs were able to detect presence of coronavirus with 97% accuracy

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Dogs are better at detecting Covid-19 in humans than many fast lateral flow tests (LFTs), according to a French study which could see canines more widely deployed for mass virus screening in crowded places including airports.
The trial, conducted in March and April by France’s national veterinary school and the clinical research unit of Paris’s Necker-Cochin h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venus, Victoria and a very lucky pussycat – take the Thursday quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/20/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia every Thursday lunchtime – how will you fare?
It is Thursday lunchtime and you know the drill – it is time for our exciting weekly quiz, newly christened “the Thursday quiz” after literally seconds of discussion in the office.
Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia, laced with a few weird facts and some jokes – and this week there is a hint of Eurovision in the air. It is just for fun and there are no prizes, but do let u…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘People die in less than a week’: Covid wave catches Argentina off-guard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/argentina-covid-coronavirus-cases-deaths-hospitals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/argentina-covid-coronavirus-cases-deaths-hospitals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cases have risen from a daily total of about 5,000 in early March to a record 35,000 this week amid relaxed restrictions and a low vaccination rate
It is 1am, and intensive care doctor Vanina Edul is trying vainly to remember the names of all the Covid patients who have died on her watch.
The 47-year-old physician still remembers the first patient she saw die of Covid last year. “He was 60, and we were surprised because that was young for that long-ago time. We thought only old people died. How wrong we wer…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Uki Goñi in Buenos Aires</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you been affected by the India Covid variant?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:28:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking to speak with people who have been impacted by the India variant of Covid-19 in the UK 
We are looking to speak with people in the UK and elsewhere who have been affected by the B.1.617.2 variant that originated in India.
Have you tested positive for the variant? Are you in an area where there is surge testing? How is the vaccination programme progressing where you are?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black actors speak out on hair mistreatment: ‘I was told they didn’t have the budget’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/20/black-actors-hair-mistreatment-hollywood</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/20/black-actors-hair-mistreatment-hollywood"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T09:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lamorne Morris says he was told to do his own hair while Meagan Good recalls a pressing comb ‘basically burning’ her
Hollywood figures are calling for more diversity in hair and makeup departments on sets, after Black actors came forward about their experiences of racism including being told there was no budget to cut hair of their type.
Camille Friend, a top stylist who has worked on Black Panther, Tenet and Captain Marvel, said hair stylists who don’t know how to work with Black hair should not be working…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An avenue to other worlds: Auditorial, a new idea for accessible storytelling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/auditorial-new-idea-accessible-storytelling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/20/auditorial-new-idea-accessible-storytelling"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T07:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has launched an experimental feature format on World Accessibility Awareness Day, in partnership with Google and the Royal National Institute of Blind People
Audio storytelling is an avenue into other worlds. So when the Guardian was approached to take part in an experimental project to make journalism more accessible to low-vision and blind users, it felt like an opportunity we couldn’t turn down. Audio has always been about making stories more accessible, and this was an opportunity to push t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Sanderson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Power of Black Identity – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/power-of-black-identity-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/power-of-black-identity-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T07:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karis Beaumont has been announced as the inaugural winner of the photography competition The Power of Black Identity, in partnership with Nikon. Beaumont will have her Bumpkin Files project showcased at The Power Of_ festival at Lambeth town hall, London in June
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who moved my cheese? The silent battle between vegetarians and vegans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/20/who-moved-my-cheese-the-silent-battle-between-vegetarians-and-vegans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/20/who-moved-my-cheese-the-silent-battle-between-vegetarians-and-vegans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T07:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When there’s only space for one meat-free option on the menu, chefs often now ditch dairy for vegan alternatives. Is this the end of veggie dining?
The recent explosion in vegan food has not been without pushback. Mainly from bolshily indignant meat-eaters who take it as a personal affront. But could a far more peaceable group, vegetarians, also be finding all that vegan energy a bit, well, irritating?
Anecdotally, their beef (now seitan) is that the current zeitgeisty cool surrounding plant-based food is i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tony Naylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Divine, Pacino, Jagger … and me: 50 years of Albert Watson’s portraits – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/divine-pacino-jagger-photographer-albert-watson-gallery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/20/divine-pacino-jagger-photographer-albert-watson-gallery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The legendary photographer’s new book features inspiring images and insider tips – such as remembering to order in a subject’s favourite coffee
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mafia mussel: the fight to save a mollusc from the mob]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/mafia-date-mussels-fight-to-save-mollusc-from-naples-mob-camorra</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/mafia-date-mussels-fight-to-save-mollusc-from-naples-mob-camorra"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T05:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As poaching of date mussels wrecks Naples’ reefs, police joined biologists to find the gangs behind it
After a three-year investigation into two organised crime groups in Italy’s Campania region that included wire taps, surveillance and nearly 100 suspects, police cracked down with a dozen arrests in March – not for offences linked to drugs or prostitution, but for the illegal harvesting of a small mollusc.
Known as date mussels, Lithophaga lithophaga are cigar-shaped shellfish that make their homes inside …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agostino Petroni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A united nations of crime’: how Marbella became a magnet for gangsters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/may/20/a-united-nations-of-how-marbella-became-a-magnet-for-gangsters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/may/20/a-united-nations-of-how-marbella-became-a-magnet-for-gangsters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T05:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new international crime organisations have made Marbella their centre of operations. And as violence rises, the police lag far behind
One morning last autumn, a dozen or so locals were eating breakfast at a cafe under a clear Marbella sky, in front of the offices of the Special Organised Crime Response Unit (Greco), on the Costa del Sol. The property is nondescript – an unobtrusive building in a working-class neighbourhood – and only someone with a sharp eye for detail might notice the two security came…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nacho Carretero and Arturo Lezcano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate disasters ‘caused more internal displacement than war’ in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/20/climate-disasters-caused-more-internal-displacement-than-war-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T04:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Refugee organisation says 30m new displacements last year were due to floods, storms or wildfires
Intense storms and flooding triggered three times more displacements than violent conflicts did last year, as the number of people internally displaced worldwide hit the highest level on record.
There were at least 55 million internally displaced people (IDPs) by the end of last year, according to figures published by the Norwegian Refugee Council’s Internal Displacement Monitoring Centre (IDMC).
 Continue read…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saeed Kamali Dehghan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rio de Janeiro’s deadliest police raid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T02:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Latin American correspondent Tom Phillips visits Jacarezinho, one of Rio’s biggest favelas, the day after police carried out the deadliest raid in the city’s history
Anushka Asthana talks to Tom Phillips about the police raid in Jacarezinho favela, in the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro. On 6 May police stormed the favela, targeting one of the city’s largest drug gangs, known as Red Command. Twenty-seven men were shot dead by police and one police officer was killed. Police, politicians and some p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Tom Phillips, produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340731</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Public Beta of the Notion API dropped! Woot! Here’s their guide. I’ve been a Notion user and fan for a long time, for both personal and professional team use. They even sponsored a few videos around here a …
The post Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Selectors to Style Your Web Page]]></title>
        <id>60a341f5906c5207e3a7da61</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-css-selectors-to-style-webpage/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS selectors are one of the most important parts of CSS. They give you the ability to target HTML elements on your web page that you want to style. Without CSS selectors, you wouldn't be able to style your page to look how you want. Thankfully CSS selectors have been]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Web3? The Decentralized Internet of the Future Explained]]></title>
        <id>60a42386906c5207e3a7dfe2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet is going through a paradigm shift. Learn the differences between Web2 and Web3, and why many developers and companies are shifting their approach in building apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Optimize for Change in Software Development]]></title>
        <id>60a469ec906c5207e3a7e1b9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-optimize-for-change-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine that you work at Magic Money Corp, which runs on just three lines of JavaScript: let input = { step1: 'collect underpants' } doStuff(input)  profit(input) // $$$!!! Now imagine that something's wrong with doStuff and you need to take it down for maintenance. What happens if you temporarily comment out the second]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you an amateur investor affected by the crash of cryptocurrencies?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/tell-us-are-you-an-amateur-investor-affected-by-the-crash-of-cryptocurrencies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/19/tell-us-are-you-an-amateur-investor-affected-by-the-crash-of-cryptocurrencies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:10:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of cryptos are losing value after China signalled a Bitcoin crackdown. We’d like to hear from small investors – what will you do next?
Amid a sudden crash of cryptocurrencies including Bitcoin, Ethereum, Dogecoin and Cardano, we’d like to hear from amateur investors on how they feel about this latest bout of extreme market volatility affecting alt coins.
Whether you have invested a lot or a little in cryptos, we’re keen to hear what you’ll do next, whether you’ll hold or sell, whether you’ve lost m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate change could make overwinter ‘zombie’ fires more common]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/19/climate-change-could-make-overwinter-zombie-fires-more-common"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:01:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study finds burn area from fires that survive winter varies depending on warmth of summers
In the boreal forests of the far northern hemisphere, where the climate is warming faster than almost anywhere else, some wildfires are surviving winter snows and picking up again in spring.
Now scientists from the Netherlands and Alaska have figured out how to calculate the scope of those “zombie fires” that smoulder year-round in the peaty soil.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two young boys in the heart of LA gangland: Merrick Morton’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/two-young-boys-heart-of-la-gangland-merrick-mortons-best-photograph-drive-by</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/two-young-boys-heart-of-la-gangland-merrick-mortons-best-photograph-drive-by"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:51:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’ve taken shots of people pointing their guns at me – and one gang wanted to be photographed doing a drive-by shooting. I refused’
I’ve been shooting street gangs in Los Angeles since the early 80s. For whatever reason, I always seemed to gravitate towards the gangs with the potential for violence. A contact in the LA county probation department helped me get started. He took me to some of the people on his caseload and, from there, I started to drive around the neighbourhoods with my photographs, stoppin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU citizens: how have you been affected by the ‘hostile environment’ policy?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/eu-citizens-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-hostile-environment-policy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/19/eu-citizens-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-hostile-environment-policy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T15:25:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from EU citizens who have encountered issues at the UK border and other difficulties related to the policy
Following Brexit, some EU citizens have been caught up in the UK’s “hostile environment” policy and have reported being held in airport detention rooms and sent to immigration removal centres.
We would like to hear from EU citizens about how they have been affected by the “hostile environment” policy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340692</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svg-loader-a-different-way-to-work-with-external-svg/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVGs are awesome: they are small, look sharp on any scale, and can be customized without creating a separate file. However, there is something I feel is missing in web standards today: a way to include them as an external …
The post svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shubham Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel-Palestine crisis explained: why has the violence escalated again? – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/19/israel-palestine-crisis-explained-why-has-the-violence-escalated-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/19/israel-palestine-crisis-explained-why-has-the-violence-escalated-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:23:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent Oliver Holmes examines the series of combustible events that coincided to trigger the worst violence in Israel and Gaza since 2014

Israel-Gaza conflict: 200 Palestinians killed in a week, say officials

Who’s to blame for reigniting the Israel-Palestine conflict? | Simon Tisdall
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes, Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do we need mega-dropdown hover menus in 2021? Probably not. Let’s explore things to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, alternatives to hover menus and fine details for designing a better UX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heads together: the light of hopeful faces – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/gallery/2021/may/19/portrait-of-humanity-1854-media-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/gallery/2021/may/19/portrait-of-humanity-1854-media-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Moroccan teapot menders to Finnish ecologists, these portraits of people from 50 countries are a testament to the human need to connect 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kris Hallenga: the woman diagnosed with cancer at 23 who convinced a generation to check their breasts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/kris-hallenga-the-woman-diagnosed-with-cancer-at-23-who-convinced-a-generation-to-check-their-breasts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/19/kris-hallenga-the-woman-diagnosed-with-cancer-at-23-who-convinced-a-generation-to-check-their-breasts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When she was told she had stage four breast cancer in 2009, Hallenga didn’t even know it could be a danger at her age. Then she started a campaign to save thousands of lives
Eight months before Kris Hallenga was diagnosed with stage four breast cancer that spread to her spine, she went to her GP about a lump. It was 2009, she was 23 years old and, she says, “actually very miserable”, having just come out of a crummy relationship. Living in Beijing, she was working for a travel company, and teaching on the s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confronting hate against east Asians – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/confronting-hate-against-east-asians-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/19/confronting-hate-against-east-asians-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Asian racism and crimes against the Asian community have amplified with Covid. The photographer Wendy Huynh, whose parents are Chinese immigrants from Vietnam who moved to France to flee communism, has experienced racism in Paris and London. She created a series of portraits celebrating Asian women in London from the creative industry to tackle the issue, and the Guardian talked to some of them about their experiences
For Bonnie Kwok it was a subtle difference. Whenever she used public transport there …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nazia Parveen, photographs by Wendy Huynh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple versus Epic: how the Fortnite app led to a legal showdown - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Apple takes on games developer and Fortnite creator Epic, UK technology editor Alex Hern describes a battle of the tech titans that could reshape the app industry
The video game Fortnite has become a cultural phenomenon in recent years with up to 100 million users a month logging in to play the free online game. They parachute down on to an island with 99 other players and the last one standing is the winner. 
But for users of iPhones and iPads, the wildly popular game has been unavailable ever since it …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Alex Hern; produced by Sami Kent and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break into Ethereum, Crypto, and Web3 as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60a53182906c5207e3a7e588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/breaking-into-ethereum-crypto-web3-as-a-developer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I've been talking about my move into the Web3, Ethereum, and crypto space since making the switch from a traditional web, mobile, and cloud background. Since making that move, a shocking number of people have reached out to me who are also thinking about doing the same.  It's really]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinned Audio WordPress Theme]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/pinned-audio-wordpress-theme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m afraid I have to start this with a whole backstory, as the journey here is the point, not so much the theme.
A fella wrote to me a while back outlining a situation he was in. His company has …
The post Pinned Audio WordPress Theme appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian through the ages: one family, seven generations, one newspaper]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/18/the-guardian-through-the-ages-one-family-seven-generations-one-newspaper</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/18/the-guardian-through-the-ages-one-family-seven-generations-one-newspaper"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:15:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One reader’s family have been reading the newspaper for 200 years

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

I am sure many families could show that they had read the Guardian for 200 years over seven generations, but here is one example:
1. Jacob Bright and Martha Wood Rochdale, Lancashire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance Development Pricing Guide – Should Freelancers Bill by the Hour?]]></title>
        <id>60a3780f906c5207e3a7db5f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-different-ways-to-charge-for-a-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you offer your services as a freelance developer, you have a major say in how you price your project.  But how do you go about charging for a website project? "Well, I just bill by the hour and send an invoice every week or month." ...I hear you say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding Programs – 101 Ways to Learn to Code for Free]]></title>
        <id>6068f146d5756f080ba9402d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/coding-programs-101-ways-to-learn-to-code-for-free/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T16:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, you can learn to code for free, from the convenience of your own home, and at your own pace. I'm going to show you 101 courses where you can learn computer science and programming for free.  The freeCodeCamp courses are completely free and some of them include a free]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Neon Text With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340420</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-neon-text-with-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neon text can add a nice, futuristic touch to any website. I’ve always loved the magic of neon signs, and wanted to recreate them using CSS. I thought I’d share some tips on how to do it! In this article, …
The post How to Create Neon Text With CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia O'Dwyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How worrying is the India coronavirus variant for UK plans to unlock this summer?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/18/how-worrying-is-the-india-coronavirus-variant-for-uk-plans-to-unlock-this-summer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/18/how-worrying-is-the-india-coronavirus-variant-for-uk-plans-to-unlock-this-summer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T02:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monday’s change in the rules was supposed to be a moment of celebration – but the new variant spreading in the UK meant it came with a cautionary note. Can the next stage of the government’s ‘irreversible’ plan go ahead?
This time last week, most of us were feeling optimistic about the next step in the government’s “irreversible” plan to end lockdown. Then scientists started to warn that the accelerating spread of the India variant of coronavirus meant that we should proceed carefully – and even consider sl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Nicola Davis; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Hannah Moore  and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard, Nicole Jackson and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long lunches, tea with the mafia … how reporting Italy has changed over the years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/17/guardian-200-john-hooper-my-predecessor-as-rome-correspondent-and-my-guide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T05:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rome correspondent Angela Giuffrida asks predecessor John Hooper how he covered the country in the pre-internet era 

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

Long before even meeting John Hooper, affectionately known among foreign correspondents in Rome as “the Hoops”, I considered him a guide.
In 2018, in preparation for the March general election, I bought his book, The Italians, seeking insight into Italian history,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line …
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It’s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about …
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a basic grid inspector 
…
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. 

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>