<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-23T00:43:08.101Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-23T00:43:08.101Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Mickelson holds narrow lead going into final round of US PGA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/phil-mickelson-holds-narrow-lead-going-into-final-round-of-us-pga</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/23/phil-mickelson-holds-narrow-lead-going-into-final-round-of-us-pga"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T23:27:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five-times major winner rolls back the years
Brooks Koepka and Louis Oosthuizen in contention

We spent much of Saturday awaiting the moment whereby Phil Mickelson peeled back his sunglasses to reveal an alter ego. Or Phil Mickelson in his pomp. Just weeks short of his 51st birthday, 16 years after the one and only time he has lifted the Wanamaker Trophy, Mickelson was making a mockery of the US PGA Championship. In what is typically a tame and non-tribal environment, Mickelson was vociferously roared on fr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray at Kiawah Island</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eurovision 2021: Måneskin triumphs for Italy in Rotterdam]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/eurovision-2021-maneskin-triumphs-for-italy-in-rotterdam</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/eurovision-2021-maneskin-triumphs-for-italy-in-rotterdam"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T23:20:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contest returns for its 65th edition after being postponed last year due to the coronavirus pandemic
Måneskin, representing Italy, have won the 65th Eurovision song contest, which was held in Rotterdam on Saturday night. Their entry, Zitti e buoni, scored 524 points in the grand final, which was broadcast across Europe and around the globe.
The UK’s entry, Embers, sung by James Newman, finished last, failing to win a single point. It was the only Eurovision act to receive 0 after the juries of all 39 countr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DRC orders evacuation of Goma after Nyiragongo volcano erupts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/nyiragongo-volcano-erupts-in-eastern-congo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/nyiragongo-volcano-erupts-in-eastern-congo"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T22:57:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of people in eastern city head towards border with Rwanda after red fumes fill sky and power was cut

The government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo has ordered the evacuation of Goma after the eruption of the Mount Nyiragongo volcano overlooking the eastern city of nearly 2 million people.
Even before the official announcement on Saturday, thousands of people had started filling the streets and carrying what they could as they headed out of the border city.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We love: fashion fixes for the week ahead – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T22:55:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sustainable sportswear brand PlayerLayer joins forces with the Jamaican Rugby League team, & Other Stories launches kidswear, and a new wardrobe rental service for men
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s get shorty: 15 of the best smart men’s shorts – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/lets-get-shorty-15-of-the-best-smart-mens-shorts-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/lets-get-shorty-15-of-the-best-smart-mens-shorts-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T22:50:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pair of plain tailored shorts is the foundation for countless summer looks. Choose warm colours and wear them under a loose, open shirt 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throw shade: 10 of the best oversized sunglasses – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/throw-shade-10-of-the-best-oversized-sunglasses-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/22/throw-shade-10-of-the-best-oversized-sunglasses-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T22:45:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Channel your inner fashion icon this summer in a pair of new oversized sunglasses
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bevan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate activists protest against BP sponsorship at British Museum]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/climate-activists-protest-against-bp-sponsorship-at-british-museum</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/climate-activists-protest-against-bp-sponsorship-at-british-museum"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T21:48:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A demonstration also took place at the Science Museum in London where Shell is a sponsor
Dozens of protesters, dressed in orange and green flowing costumes to represent the burning environment, gathered at the British Museum on Saturday while youth activists staged a separate demonstration at the Science Museum. Both events aimed to pressure the institutions to sever ties with oil corporations.
The theatrical activist group BP or not BP staged a protest at the British Museum in response to the oil company’s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anthony Joshua ordered to defend his WBO title against Oleksandr Usyk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/anthony-joshua-ordered-to-defend-his-wbo-title-against-oleksandr-usyk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/anthony-joshua-ordered-to-defend-his-wbo-title-against-oleksandr-usyk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T21:04:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed fight with Tyson Fury appears unlikely
Fury turns to second rematch with Deontay Wilder

Anthony Joshua has been ordered to defend his WBO heavyweight title against mandatory challenger Oleksandr Usyk after the collapse of the Briton’s fight against domestic rival Tyson Fury.
Fury announced earlier this week he would take on Joshua in Saudi Arabia on 14 August, only to be informed hours later by a United States arbitrator that he was contractually obliged to fight Deontay Wilder for a third time.
 …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A ticking time bomb’: Timor-Leste begins to reckon with alleged Catholic church sex abuse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/a-ticking-time-bomb-timor-leste-begins-to-reckon-with-alleged-catholic-church-sex-abuse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/a-ticking-time-bomb-timor-leste-begins-to-reckon-with-alleged-catholic-church-sex-abuse"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T21:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The trial of defrocked priest Richard Daschbach, charged with sexual abuse of 14 girls, is dividing the small, deeply Catholic country
Lita grew up in a poor family in a hamlet surrounded by the spectacular mountains of Oecusse in Timor-Leste. When she was 11 years old she went to live in Topu Honis shelter home, in the mountainous, forest-encircled village of Kutet.
The shelter was run by Richard Daschbach, a now-defrocked 84-year-old US priest who founded the facility in 1992.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zevonia Vieira in Dili and Tjitske Lingsma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rick Santorum axed by CNN over racist remarks on Native Americans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/cnn-rick-santorum-axed-native-americans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/cnn-rick-santorum-axed-native-americans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T20:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Republican senator’s April comments prompted outrage
Santorum said he misspoke but did not apologize for remarks

CNN has dropped former Republican US senator Rick Santorum as a senior political commentator after racist remarks he made about Native Americans at an event in April.
News of Santorum’s termination was first reported by HuffPost. A CNN spokesperson confirmed to the Guardian that the network has parted ways with Santorum. No further comment on the firing was provided, though an anonymous CNN e…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Aratani in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children with Covid: why are some countries seeing more cases – and deaths?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/children-with-covid-why-are-some-countries-seeing-more-cases-and-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/23/children-with-covid-why-are-some-countries-seeing-more-cases-and-deaths"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T20:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The perceived wisdom has been that children do not suffer severely from the virus. Yet they are now in Brazil, Indonesia and India
Emergency physician and leading epidemiologist in Brazil, Dr Fatima Marinho, is seeing symptoms of Covid-19 in children that starkly contrast with the message that has been relayed globally throughout the pandemic that children do not appear to suffer severely from the virus.
Severe muscle aches, diarrhoea, coughing, abdominal pain and hospitalisation – all of these are happenin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Davey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘There’s so much freedom out here’: life in the outback offers thrills, but population dwindles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/23/theres-so-much-freedom-out-here-life-in-the-outback-offers-thrills-but-population-dwindles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/may/23/theres-so-much-freedom-out-here-life-in-the-outback-offers-thrills-but-population-dwindles"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T20:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just 266 people live in Barcoo shire, an area that covers almost 62,000 sq km. They’re bonded by strong community ties, forged through hardship

Read more of our Modern Outback series here
Sign up for email notifications from our Modern Outback series

In March last year Doreen Pitman was mustering cattle on her 70,000-acre property in central west Queensland when the motorbike she was riding hit a wheel rut.
The grazier, now 62, was knocked unconscious as she hit the ground. “It might have only been a coup…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denise Cullen  Photographs: David Maurice Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Inconceivable’: why has Australia’s history been left to rot?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/inconceivable-why-has-australias-history-been-left-to-rot</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/23/inconceivable-why-has-australias-history-been-left-to-rot"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T20:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Historians are aghast that the National Archives have had to resort to crowdfunding to protect irreplaceable historical records
Historians are calling it an international embarrassment for Australia and saying it is “inconceivable that it has come to this”, as they preemptively mourn the loss of “irreplaceable national history”.
The National Archives of Australia doesn’t often make headlines, but when it does, it’s rarely good news.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elias Visontay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’ll intervene to restore trust in the BBC’ warn ministers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/well-intervene-to-restore-trust-in-the-bbc-warn-ministers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/well-intervene-to-restore-trust-in-the-bbc-warn-ministers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T20:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next year’s review of the corporation will be ‘beefed up’ as Dyson report into Diana interview sees ex-boss Lord Hall resign post 
Ministers pledged on Saturday to intervene to restore trust in the BBC by conducting a wider-than-anticipated review of its operations next year, as recriminations grew over its controversial Panorama interview in 1995 with Diana, Princess of Wales.
The fallout from an independent report by Lord Justice Dyson into the programme 26 years ago prompted the dramatic resignation on S…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm and Vanessa Thorpe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings claims ministers backed herd immunity against Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/22/dominic-cummings-claims-ministers-backed-herd-immunity-against-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/22/dominic-cummings-claims-ministers-backed-herd-immunity-against-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T19:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PM’s ex-adviser says if ‘competent’ people had been in charge at least two lockdowns could have been avoided
Dominic Cummings has launched an extraordinary new attempt to destroy the government’s credibility over Covid-19, claiming that ministers had backed a policy of “herd immunity” then lied about having done so.
In an astonishing series of tweets on Saturday just days before he is due to appear before a Commons inquiry, the prime minister’s former adviser in effect accused the health secretary, Matt Han…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hornchurch sink Hereford to claim unlikely FA Trophy win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/22/hereford-hornchurch-fa-trophy-final-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/22/hereford-hornchurch-fa-trophy-final-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T19:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hereford 1-3 Hornchurch
Seventh-tier side come from behind to win at Wembley

Hornchurch, from the seventh-tier Isthmian Premier Division, collected the 2020-21 FA Trophy after coming from behind to stun favourites Hereford with three late goals at Wembley.
Tom Owen-Evans opened the scoring for National League North side Hereford after 13 minutes with a deflected effort but Charlie Ruff equalised with a quarter of an hour to go, heading home after a long throw-in had been flicked on to the bar.
 Continue re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Observer Sport and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ever Given owner says Suez canal authority at fault ship’s grounding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/ever-given-owner-says-suez-canal-authority-at-fault-for-grounding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/ever-given-owner-says-suez-canal-authority-at-fault-for-grounding"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T19:36:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawyers for Shoei Kisen tell court container ship was wrongly allowed to enter waterway amid bad weather

The owner of a container ship that blocked the Suez canal in March says the canal authority was at fault over its grounding as it disputes the vessel’s detention and a compensation claim, a lawyer representing the owner said on Saturday.
The Ever Given, one of the world’s largest container ships, became jammed across the canal in high winds on 23 March, and remained grounded for six days, blocking traff…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technical fault blights Glastonbury streamed event Live at Worthy Farm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/technical-fault-ruins-glastonbury-streamed-event-live-at-worthy-farm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/technical-fault-ruins-glastonbury-streamed-event-live-at-worthy-farm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T19:19:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ticketholders were initially unable to access online concert due to faulty access codes but it will be shown again
In the digital equivalent of a washed-out festival, Glastonbury’s much-anticipated livestreamed event, Live at Worthy Farm, has left fans disappointed after many ticketholders were unable to access the stream.
Hopeful viewers – many of whom had created Glastonbury-themed parties in anticipation – had spent £20 for tickets to access the event, featuring performances by Coldplay, Damon Albarn, Ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Faith in false nines makes for compelling poacher-free Champions League final | Jonathan Wilson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/22/faith-false-nines-makes-for-striker-free-champions-league-final-manchester-city-chelsea</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/may/22/faith-false-nines-makes-for-striker-free-champions-league-final-manchester-city-chelsea"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T19:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pep Guardiola and Thomas Tuchel prioritise dropping deep, pulling wide, aiding the collective and protecting possession
Manchester City’s leading Premier League goalscorer this season is Ilkay Gündogan with 13. Jorginho tops Chelsea’s scoring chart with seven, followed by Tammy Abraham, Mason Mount and Timo Werner who are all on six. And yet these are the two sides who will contest next week’s Champions League final.
Among elite clubs over the past decade there has been a clear tension between those who foc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pfizer and AstraZeneca ‘highly effective’ against India Covid variant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/pfizer-and-astrazeneca-highly-effective-against-india-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/pfizer-and-astrazeneca-highly-effective-against-india-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T18:28:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Public Health England study has revealed the vaccines can be up to 88% effective after a second dose 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Both the Pfizer and AstraZeneca jabs are highly effective at protecting people from the strain of the Covid-19 virus first found in India, a study by Public Health England (PHE) has found.
The analysis, carried out between 5 April and 16 May, found the Pfizer vaccine was 88% effective against symptomatic disease from the India variant two wee…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Juan Cruz Mallía fires Toulouse past 14-man La Rochelle to win Champions Cup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/la-rochelle-toulouse-champions-cup-final-rugby-union-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/22/la-rochelle-toulouse-champions-cup-final-rugby-union-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T18:19:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[La Rochelle 17-22 Toulouse
Mallía’s try settles all-French final after Botia sees red

Past all-French European finals have failed to produce the finest foie gras and, until the latter stages, this one also struggled to deliver. In Toulouse, however, they will care little about the modest fare and rejoice instead in a final scoreline that makes them the most decorated champions in the tournament’s history.
For lengthy periods this was a niggly, ill-tempered slugging contest which only belatedly clicked up i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson at Twickenham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No 10 ‘tried to block’ data on spread of new Covid variant in English schools]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/no-10-tried-to-block-data-on-spread-of-new-covid-variant-in-english-schools</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/no-10-tried-to-block-data-on-spread-of-new-covid-variant-in-english-schools"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T18:19:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists, unions and teachers concerned after data cut from Public Health England report ahead of shift on face masks
Downing Street leaned on Public Health England not to publish crucial data on the spread of the new Covid variant in schools, documents seen by the Observer have suggested. Scientists, union officials and teachers said that the lack of transparency was “deeply worrying”.
The focus of their anger concerns the pre-print of a PHE report that included a page of data on the spread of the India …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carole Cadwalladr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlético Madrid clinch La Liga title after Luis Suárez seals win at Real Valladolid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/22/real-valladolid-atletico-madrid-la-liga-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/22/real-valladolid-atletico-madrid-la-liga-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:58:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Atlético Madrid’s captain, Koke, says they are destined to suffer but they are champions. The 3,000 fans gathered in the car park outside the José Zorrilla stadium exploded as Diego Simeone’s side offered another exhibition in survival. They came from behind to win 2-1 for the second time in a week and take the title at the end of a season of twists to the last. Top since week 12, Atlético hung on to a lead they had first taken in November.
Their opponents, Valladolid, could not. They had fought here, but r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe at José Zorrilla Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t recognise our own city: Israeli barrage redraws the map of Gaza]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/we-dont-recognise-our-own-city-israeli-barrage-redraws-the-map-of-gaza</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/we-dont-recognise-our-own-city-israeli-barrage-redraws-the-map-of-gaza"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:41:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A ceasefire is finally in force, but traumatised families have little hope as they recall collapsing buildings and deaths of loved ones
As they emerge from hiding, people living in Gaza City have had to adapt their memories. So deformed is this small place on the coast that a mental map of its roads and landmarks from two weeks ago is largely useless today. Shortcuts to avoid traffic may no longer work, as craters dot back streets and rubble blocks roads. Locally famous high-rises no longer exist.
Eleven da…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes and Hazem Balousha in Gaza City</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greek firefighters tackle major forest fire in conservation area near Athens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/greek-firefighters-tackle-major-forest-fire-in-conservation-area-near-athens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/greek-firefighters-tackle-major-forest-fire-in-conservation-area-near-athens"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:31:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts warn of a ‘huge ecological disaster’ after blaze in the Geraneia mountains

Hundreds of firefighters battled Greece’s first major forest fire of the summer on Saturday, as experts warned of a “huge ecological disaster” in a nature conservation area near Athens.
The fire, which broke out late on Wednesday in the Geraneia mountains 55 miles (90km) west of the capital, is “one of the biggest in the past 20 to 30 years, and has come early in the season”, fire chief Stefanos Kolokouris told ANT1 televisi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram photo seems to show Princess Latifa in Dubai mall]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/instagram-photo-seems-to-show-princess-latifa-in-dubai-mall</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/instagram-photo-seems-to-show-princess-latifa-in-dubai-mall"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:13:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image believed to be of 35-year-old who fled father Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum in 2018
Sheikha Latifa bint Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum of Dubai, whose plight has captivated the world since a daring attempt at escaping her father across the Indian Ocean, appears to have been photographed in public for the first time in years.
In a picture posted to Instagram two days ago by both former Royal Navy member Sioned Taylor and another user, Princess Latifa is seated with two women at a cafe table in …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mateo García Elizondo: ‘I get a little bored by having to talk about my grandfather’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/mateo-garcia-elizondo-i-get-a-little-bored-by-having-to-talk-about-my-grandfather</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/mateo-garcia-elizondo-i-get-a-little-bored-by-having-to-talk-about-my-grandfather"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The writer – and grandson of Gabriel García Márquez – on Mexican folklore, his early love of horror and learning to live with the family’s literary legacy
Mateo García Elizondo, a 34-year-old writer from Mexico, may come from literary stock – his paternal grandfather is Colombian heavyweight Gabriel García Márquez and his maternal grandfather is Mexican literary giant Salvador Elizondo – but he is carving his own path at the forefront of a burgeoning scene in Spanish language literature. He has published a …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson cooks up a trade deal – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/22/boris-johnson-cooks-up-a-trade-deal-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/22/boris-johnson-cooks-up-a-trade-deal-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The prime minister and his sous chef, Brexit, pop another shrimp on the barbie

You can buy your own print of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ballot rigging is so last year. There are now new ways of buying votes | Nick Cohen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/ballot-rigging-is-so-last-year-new-ways-of-buying-votes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/ballot-rigging-is-so-last-year-new-ways-of-buying-votes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T17:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Politicians no longer use their own money as bribes; they use yours instead
Bribery has always been the main concern of opponents of political corruption. The virtually non-existent threat of fake voters turning up at ballot stations and pretending to be legitimate citizens is as nothing when set against the crooked politician’s promise to buy your vote. Since parliament passed the Corrupt and Illegal Practices Prevention Act in 1883, the UK has not seen as concerted an attempt to rig elections as the venal…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police make four arrests after violence in Swansea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/police-arrest-people-after-violence-swansea-mayhill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/police-arrest-people-after-violence-swansea-mayhill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:45:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three men and boy aged 16 in custody in connection with riot in Mayhill area on Thursday night

Three men and a 16-year-old boy have been arrested in connection with violence on the streets of Swansea.
Cars were set on fire and missiles were thrown at police after a vigil in the Mayhill area on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Steinbeck’s estate urged to let the world read his shunned werewolf novel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/john-steinbecks-estate-urged-to-let-the-world-read-his-shunned-werewolf-novel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/john-steinbecks-estate-urged-to-let-the-world-read-his-shunned-werewolf-novel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:15:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rejected and hidden away since 1930, an early murder mystery by the Nobel-winning author is ‘an incredible find’ 
Years before becoming one of America’s most celebrated authors, John Steinbeck wrote at least three novels which were never published. Two of them were destroyed by the young writer as he struggled to make his name, but a third – a full-length mystery werewolf story entitled Murder at Full Moon – has survived unseen in an archive ever since being rejected for publication in 1930.
Now a British a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dalya Alberge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t let Middle East violence fuel hatred on the streets of Britain | Afzal Khan and Alex Sobel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/dont-let-middle-east-violence-fuel-hatred-on-the-streets-of-britain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/dont-let-middle-east-violence-fuel-hatred-on-the-streets-of-britain"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An open letter to Britain’s Muslim and Jewish communities

Labour MPs Afzal Khan and Alex Sobel

Islam and Judaism have a long shared and complex history. The Qu’ran and the Tanakh speak of our common patriarch, Abraham/Ibrahim, whose sons Ishmael and Isaac forged separate paths to the establishment of each faith. This neat, if simplistic, analogy of two siblings parting ways is at the heart of our collective past.
All over the world, we have lived together for more than a thousand years. And today, we find…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Afzal Khan and Alex Sobel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: Manchester Arena Bomb: Stories of Hope; Jackie Weaver Has the Authority; Today]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/manchester-arena-bomb-stories-of-hope-review-jackie-weaver-has-the-authority-podcast-amol-rajan-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/manchester-arena-bomb-stories-of-hope-review-jackie-weaver-has-the-authority-podcast-amol-rajan-today"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A meeting between two survivors of the 2017 Manchester bomb attack makes for unmissable listening; Jackie Weaver has a new podcast; and Amol Rajan is a Today natural
Manchester Arena Bomb: Stories of Hope (BBC Radio Manchester) | BBC Sounds 
Jackie Weaver Has the Authority | audioboom.com 
Today (BBC Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
By far the most gripping audio I heard last week came from BBC Radio Manchester, which has made a podcast series about the bombing of the Ariana Grande concert in 2017: Manchester Arena Bo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Painting the memories evoked by motorways – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/22/painting-the-memories-evoked-by-motorways-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/22/painting-the-memories-evoked-by-motorways-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Jen Orpin’s father had a stroke in September 2015, the Manchester-based artist became very familiar with the journey to Surrey to visit him in hospital: M56, M6, M42, M40, M25. After he died, driving down these motorways evoked visceral feelings, which she has captured in a series of paintings. “I’ve had so many conversations with people recently,” she says, “about childhood memories and nostalgic feelings attached to a special bit of road or a bridge they used to go under, passing a tower or service …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billie Piper: From vulnerable teen pop star to director of an ‘anti-romcom’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/billie-piper-from-vulnerable-teen-pop-star-to-director-of-an-anti-romcom</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/billie-piper-from-vulnerable-teen-pop-star-to-director-of-an-anti-romcom"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The characters she plays do not match her own life, the actress insists, but it’s hard not to see parallels with her own journey
Billie Piper has occupied a near continual, if shifting, position in the public imagination for almost a quarter of a century. That’s a notable achievement by any reckoning of a performer’s career, but it’s also rather alarming, given that she’s still only 38.
Having started out as 15-year-old chart sensation, she walked away from the pop music treadmill, enjoyed a boozy marriage …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Anthony</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s legacy could be the concreting over of England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/22/boris-johnsons-legacy-could-be-the-concreting-over-of-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/22/boris-johnsons-legacy-could-be-the-concreting-over-of-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T16:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping the housing market spinning has become top priority for a government focused on wealth creation based on property
When we consider the likely effects of Boris Johnson’s administration over the next three years, and possibly beyond, it is easy to believe his achievements will be near or less than zero.
Looking back to his time as mayor of London, he wasted most of his first term dealing with arguments among his close lieutenants before procrastinating about which of his limited set of manifesto pledg…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Myanmar junta leader says Aung San Suu Kyi will soon appear in court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/myanmar-junta-leader-says-aung-san-suu-kyi-will-soon-appear-in-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/myanmar-junta-leader-says-aung-san-suu-kyi-will-soon-appear-in-court"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:59:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In first interview since February coup, Min Aung Hlaing says deposed leader is in good health
 Myanmar’s junta leader, Min Aung Hlaing, has said deposed leader Aung San Suu Kyi is healthy at home and will appear in court in a few days, in his first interview since overthrowing her in a coup in February.
The coup has plunged the south-east Asian country into chaos. An ethnic armed group opposed to the ruling junta attacked a military post in a north-western jade-mining town while other violent incidents were…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decorative ceramics – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/gallery/2021/may/22/decorative-ceramics-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/gallery/2021/may/22/decorative-ceramics-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vases, vessels and bowls to brighten up your shelves 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ronald Greene punched and dragged by police before his death, video shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/ronald-greene-death-louisiana-police-officers-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/ronald-greene-death-louisiana-police-officers-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greene, 49, died after confrontation with officers in 2019
Louisiana police initially refused to release bodycam footage

Two years after Ronald Greene, a 49-year-old Black man, died after a confrontation with white police officers in May 2019, the Louisiana police department released footage of the incident.
Louisiana state police had refused to publicly release footage from the incident, which they claimed culminated in Greene dying from crashing into a tree and injuring his head.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Aratani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical physicist Chiara Marletto: ‘The universal constructor could revolutionise civilisation’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/22/theoretical-physicist-chiara-marletto-the-universal-constructor-could-revolutionise-civilisation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/22/theoretical-physicist-chiara-marletto-the-universal-constructor-could-revolutionise-civilisation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The scientist on why studying elementary particles is only one way of explaining phenomena, how the 3D printer could change the world, and her optimism about women in science
Chiara Marletto is a research fellow at Wolfson College, University of Oxford. Her research is in theoretical physics – especially quantum computation, thermodynamics and information theory. Her broader interests include theoretical biology, epistemology and Italian literature. The Science of Can and Can’t: A Physicist’s Journey Throug…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Anthony</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Art by the sea: a coastal home rich in treasures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/handcrafted-wooden-furniture-and-midcentury-classics-in-a-st-leonards-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/handcrafted-wooden-furniture-and-midcentury-classics-in-a-st-leonards-home"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handcrafted wooden furniture lives in harmony with midcentury classics in this St Leonards home
Nearly everything in Beatrice Ancillon’s home is for sale. The reason is that she buys instinctively for ODE, or Objéts de Epoch, the 20th-century design store she owns in Hastings, never simply what she thinks her clients will buy and, invariably, some of those pieces found their way to her home. She lives in a split-level flat in nearby St Leonards, which she shares with her husband, John Alfredo Harris, an art…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carolyn Asome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If Apple is the only outfit capable of defending our privacy, it really is time to worry | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/if-apple-is-the-only-organisation-capable-of-defending-our-privacy-it-really-is-time-to-worry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/if-apple-is-the-only-organisation-capable-of-defending-our-privacy-it-really-is-time-to-worry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A giant private company is doing the work governments should be doing on regulation of user data. That’s not a good thing 
A few weeks ago, Apple dropped its long-promised bombshell on the data-tracking industry. The latest version (14.5) of iOS – the operating system of the iPhone – included a provision that required app users explicitly to confirm that they wished to be tracked across the internet in their online activities. At the heart of the switch is a code known as “the identifier for advertisers” or…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put out to pasture? Britain’s farmers fear surge of imports from Australia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/22/put-out-to-pasture-britains-farmers-fear-surge-of-imports-from-australia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/22/put-out-to-pasture-britains-farmers-fear-surge-of-imports-from-australia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T15:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A trade deal could expose UK agriculture to the economic power of the southern hemisphere’s giant livestock ranches
On a rain-lashed and windswept day in the Welsh valleys, Jonathan Huntley is almost at the end of the busiest six weeks of the year on his hillside farm. Lambing season is over, following the arrival of 1,400 newborns, and one of his 60 suckling cows is calving.
Huntley, 53, farms sheep and cattle in the same 500 acres as his father before him, and he and his wife Tracey hope their 22-year-old…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands gather in London for Palestine solidarity march]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/thousands-gather-in-london-for-palestine-solidarity-march</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/thousands-gather-in-london-for-palestine-solidarity-march"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:40:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protests also taking place in other UK cities, including Bristol, Peterborough and Nottingham
Thousands of protesters have gathered in central London in solidarity with the people of Palestine.
Organisers estimated that more than 180,000 people were in Hyde Park for pro-Palestinian protests on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters in London mark anniversary of George Floyd death]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/anti-racism-protesters-gather-in-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/anti-racism-protesters-gather-in-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:15:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-racism demonstration outside the US embassy one of a number taking place across UK 

Anti-racism protesters have called for “justice” as they gathered in south-west London to commemorate almost a year since the death of George Floyd.
About a dozen campaigners from Stand Up To Racism held placards and chanted outside the US embassy in Nine Elms on Saturday morning.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My New York Year review – a leaden take on the literary life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/22/my-new-york-year-review-joanna-rakoff-margaret-qualley-sigourney-weaver-jd-salinger</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/22/my-new-york-year-review-joanna-rakoff-margaret-qualley-sigourney-weaver-jd-salinger"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sigourney Weaver and Margaret Qualley are squandered in this adaptation of Joanna Rakoff’s memoir of her year working with JD Salinger
There are Farrow & Ball paint charts with more inherent drama than My New York Year, an enervating adaptation of Joanna Rakoff’s 2014 memoir, My Salinger Year. Philippe Falardeau (Monsieur Lazhar) directs and Margaret Qualley stars as aspiring writer Joanna, who finds work assisting grande dame literary agent Margaret (Sigourney Weaver). Margaret’s main client is JD Salinger…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wendy Ide</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If anyone can really turn back time, Cher can | Rebecca Nicholson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/if-anyone-can-truly-turn-back-time-cher-can</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/if-anyone-can-truly-turn-back-time-cher-can"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even an authorised film of the singer’s life is bound to eclipse the rest of the crop of musical biopics
Cher is the latest music star to get the biopic treatment. “Ok Universal is Doing Biopic” she tweeted, in her inimitable style, adding that the producers of both Mamma Mia!s are involved (and I hope that whoever plays Cher gets to re-enact that helicopter arrival).
It will be written by her friend Eric Roth, of Forrest Gump and A Star Is Born fame. Naturally, she included her favourite emoji, the ghost, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On my radar: Heather Phillipson’s cultural highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/22/on-my-radar-heather-phillipson-cultural-highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/22/on-my-radar-heather-phillipson-cultural-highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The artist, whose latest work is currently gracing Tate Britain’s Duveen Galleries, on the joy of weather forecasts, a gripping memoir, and the greatness of Theaster Gates
Born in 1978 in London, award-winning artist and poet Heather Phillipson completed a PhD in fine art practice at Middlesex University in 2007. Her work encompasses digital media, music and sculpture, and she has published five volumes of poetry. Her sculpture The End, which depicts a cherry-topped swirl of whipped cream and transmits a li…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Phillipson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A trip to the dump is one of my great pleasures in life – and I’m not alone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/trip-to-the-dump-great-pleasures-in-life-not-alone</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/trip-to-the-dump-great-pleasures-in-life-not-alone"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T14:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything has its place at the dump, no matter how abject or broken. No wonder there were queues when it reopened after lockdown
A couple of miles from my home, down on the other side of the motorway, in a semi-industrial scrubland of building-supply merchants, gearbox specialists and a mysterious warehouse called Limbs and Things, lies the Household Waste Recycle Centre. At least, the council calls it the “HWRC”; everyone else calls it the dump. I have visited this enchanted acre seven or eight times this…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Godwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands of work-related Covid deaths go unreported in UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/thousands-of-work-related-covid-deaths-go-unreported-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/thousands-of-work-related-covid-deaths-go-unreported-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T13:33:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unsafe workplaces could still put lives at risk, unions warn

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Businesses could be significantly under-reporting the number of work-related Covid deaths to the government’s safety watchdog, new research suggests.
Forthcoming analysis by the TUC shows employers have notified the Health and Safety Executive of 387 work-related Covid deaths since April 2020 even though the Office for National Statistics has identified 15,263 people of working age wh…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Wall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former BBC boss Lord Hall resigns from National Gallery after Diana row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/ex-bbc-director-general-lord-hall-resigns-as-national-gallery-chair-martin-bashir-diana-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/22/ex-bbc-director-general-lord-hall-resigns-as-national-gallery-chair-martin-bashir-diana-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T13:18:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As controversy rages over Panorama interview, Tony Hall says continuing in role ‘would be a distraction’ 

Tony Hall has resigned as chairman of the National Gallery amid the controversy over the BBC Panorama interview with Diana, Princess of Wales, in 1995.
The corporation’s former director general was severely criticised in Lord Dyson’s report for overseeing a flawed and “woefully ineffective” internal investigation into how Martin Bashir obtained the interview.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeffrey Epstein prison guards spared jail time in deal with US prosecutors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/jeffrey-epstein-prison-guards-manhattan-prosecutors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/jeffrey-epstein-prison-guards-manhattan-prosecutors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T13:07:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pair accused of sleeping and browsing the internet instead of monitoring Epstein on night he died admitted falsifying records
The two Bureau of Prisons workers tasked with guarding Jeffrey Epstein the night he killed himself in a New York jail have admitted they falsified records, but they will skirt any time behind bars under a deal with federal prosecutors, authorities said Friday.
 Related: Trump Hotel raised prices to deter QAnon conspiracists, police files show 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daisy Haggard: ‘I love getting older. I care less about what people think’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/this-much-i-know-daisy-haggard-i-love-getting-older-i-care-less-about-what-people-think</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/this-much-i-know-daisy-haggard-i-love-getting-older-i-care-less-about-what-people-think"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor, 43, on hiding from her children in bed, hanging out with Matt LeBlanc and her love of Wotsits
I do all my writing in bed. Not due to decadence, but because it’s the place I can hide from my children most effectively.
My recent Bafta nomination genuinely came as a huge shock. I assumed it was Breeders that had been shortlisted, not me [for female performance in a comedy programme]. When I finally clicked, I blurted out, “Good God!” I don’t think I’ll win, but if by some miracle I did, my kids woul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Hogan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Resurrection: Bugzy Malone review – highs and lows that catch you off guard]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/the-resurrection-bugzy-malone-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/the-resurrection-bugzy-malone-review"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(B Somebody)
After two brushes with death last year, the Manchester rapper has a lot to process on his starkly honest second album 
Hip-hop has no shortage of redemption narratives. Bugzy Malone’s is ongoing. As recently as last year, the Manchester MC was charged with two counts of wounding – this, after many years spent boxing, rapping, then acting in Guy Ritchie movies in a largely successful effort to put a difficult past behind him. The 30-year-old still carries sufficient ferocity to have guested on t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kitty Empire</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot vax summer? Dating apps encourage vaccination]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/22/hot-vax-summer-dating-apps-encourage-vaccination</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/22/hot-vax-summer-dating-apps-encourage-vaccination"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T12:16:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tinder and OKCupid team up with The White House to make vaccinations ‘attractive’
Dating Apps are attempting to make getting vaccinations “sexy” in a new partnership with the White House.
Tinder, Hinge and OkCupid are amongst the dating apps that are part of the initiative, which will allow users to see if their potential dates are either fully vaccinated, not yet vaccinated or ‘prefer not to disclose’.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top pupils rejected by universities in A-levels fiasco fallout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/22/top-pupils-rejected-by-universities-in-a-levels-fiasco-fallout</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/22/top-pupils-rejected-by-universities-in-a-levels-fiasco-fallout"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T12:01:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talented students in UK missing out on the best courses as colleges clear last year’s deferrals and panic about being oversubscribed
With predicted A-level grades of A*, A*, A, and national awards for swimming, 17-year-old state-school student Eve Leleux could have expected a string of top university offers in an ordinary year. Instead, with elite universities panicking about being overloaded with high-grade students this summer, she has had no offers to study her chosen course of dentistry.
She is not alon…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fazackerley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jane Rogers on writing Mr Wroe’s Virgins: ‘I was wildly ambitious, and had a chip on my shoulder’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/jane-rogers-on-writing-mr-wroes-virgins-i-was-wildly-ambitious-and-had-a-chip-on-my-shoulder</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/22/jane-rogers-on-writing-mr-wroes-virgins-i-was-wildly-ambitious-and-had-a-chip-on-my-shoulder"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T12:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to take on the very male literary world of the 1980s, Rogers turned to areas in which women could find meaning outside motherhood: work, religion, love
When I started work on Mr Wroe’s Virgins I was 35. I was wildly ambitious, and had a chip on my shoulder. Faber had published my first three novels and all had found critical favour. But I was broke and my sales were poor, and I was spiky about the literary world, which seemed to me to consist mainly of men, mainly in London.
Two conversations from t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jane Rogers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two dead and eight injured, one critically, in Minneapolis shooting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/at-least-two-dead-in-minneapolis-shooting</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/at-least-two-dead-in-minneapolis-shooting"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T11:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say two men in a crowd near a nightclub got into an argument, pulled out guns and started firing
 Two people were killed and eight more were wounded, one seriously, in a shooting in downtown Minneapolis early on Saturday.
Police spokesperson John Elder said the gunfire stemmed from two men in a crowd who got into an argument near the Monarch nightclub, pulled out guns and started shooting, KMSP-TV reported.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How genetic sequencing is helping scientists find the next Covid variant | Manon Ragonnet-Cronin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/how-genetic-sequencing-is-helping-scientists-find-the-next-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/how-genetic-sequencing-is-helping-scientists-find-the-next-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new Global Pandemic Radar is a welcome step towards comprehensive sequencing of the Covid-19 genome
“Nun’s office Tivoli safe!” When I was a child, we used to play a game where several of us whispered a message to one another in sequence. The fun of the game is when errors pop up along the way – and the final listener announces with glee something quite different from the original message.
As Covid-19 spreads through a population, it undergoes similar changes, or “mutations”. Every time a new virus is b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manon Ragonnet-Cronin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jewish Americans are at a turning point with Israel | Arielle Angel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/jewish-americans-israel-palestine-arielle-angel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/jewish-americans-israel-palestine-arielle-angel"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I felt alone as a Jew attending a Palestine solidarity rally in 2014. I don’t feel alone any more
On Nakba Day, 15 May, amid the outbreak of war in Israel/Palestine, I attended a rally in Bay Ridge in Brooklyn, to commemorate the expulsion of more than 700,000 Palestinians from the new Israeli state in 1948, and to protest against the oppression of the Palestinian people in the land between the river and the sea. From the signs I saw as part of that crowd – “This Jew will not stand by” or “Another Jew for a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arielle Angel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bob Dylan at 80: in praise of a mighty and unbowed singer-songwriter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/bob-dylan-at-80-in-praise-of-a-mighty-and-unbowed-singer-songwriter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/bob-dylan-at-80-in-praise-of-a-mighty-and-unbowed-singer-songwriter"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prolific, resilient and endlessly creative … as Dylan celebrates his 80th birthday, Edward Docx assesses his artistic contribution to the human story

Beyond Mr Tambourine Man: 80 Bob Dylan songs everyone should know  

Astonishingly, Bob Dylan turns 80 on Monday. For millions of people like me, this is a moment to celebrate. We’re insane, of course. We listen to him every day like other people pray. We’ve been to hundreds of the live shows – witnessed the transcendent moments and stood there loyally throug…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Docx</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One year on, how George Floyd’s murder has changed the world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/george-floyd-murder-change-across-world-blm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/22/george-floyd-murder-change-across-world-blm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The killing of Floyd by a white officer reflected a common history of violence against Black people that united protesters in a renewed global movement
George Floyd’s murder felt like everything was the same and nothing was the same, said Miski Noor, an activist in Minneapolis, where Floyd was killed by a white police officer a year ago on 25 May.
“How many times have we seen Black death go viral?” asked Noor, the co-founder of Black Visions, which advocates for abolition, an approach to public safety that …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deborah Douglas, Angelique Chrisafis and Aamna Mohdin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How centuries of racist images came down in one year – a visual guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/22/racist-statues-monuments-removed-us-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/22/racist-statues-monuments-removed-us-world"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:00:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Black Lives Matter protests after George Floyd’s death forced leaders to re-examine the images in our everyday lives – in the US and beyond
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alvin Chang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the scenes at Glastonbury’s Live at Worthy Farm – photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/behind-the-scenes-at-glastonburys-live-at-worthy-farm-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/22/behind-the-scenes-at-glastonburys-live-at-worthy-farm-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T10:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We joined Wolf Alice, Michael Kiwanuka, Haim, Jorja Smith, the Mutoid Waste Company and others as they made the film that replaces the Glastonbury festival this year
When I drove into the Glastonbury site last Sunday afternoon, the woman on accreditation asked if I knew my way around the site. In theory, yes, but not without its traditional landmarks – over five normal days at the festival, you navigate by stages, food stalls and flags. (“I’m four metres in front and five metres to the left of the Bob Marle…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Levene (photography), essay by Laura Snapes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meera Sodha’s vegan recipe for walnut-stuffed aubergines | The new vegan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/22/meera-sodha-vegan-recipe-walnut-stuffed-aubergines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/22/meera-sodha-vegan-recipe-walnut-stuffed-aubergines"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T09:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tangy, garlicky sauce given texture and crunch by breadcrumbs and walnuts, spiked with spice, and melded with creamy baked aubergine
The aubergine has an air of mystery to it until it hits the oven. Various food writers over time have argued over whether it should be salted to remove any bitterness (it shouldn’t) and whether it needs drenching in oil to cook (it doesn’t), but, when cooked in the oven, there’s only one way the aubergine will go, and that is creamy – and, because of that, a baked aubergine …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meera Sodha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris Lees: ‘It drives me crazy when people introduce me as a trans activist’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/paris-lees-drives-me-crazy-when-people-introduce-me-as-a-trans-activist</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/22/paris-lees-drives-me-crazy-when-people-introduce-me-as-a-trans-activist"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T09:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[She survived a troubled youth – and a spell in prison – to forge a new life for herself as a writer and campaigner. Now, despite the pain of revisiting those years, she’s telling her story in full
Paris Lees always knew she would write the story of her life. She knew it when she was a teenager in Hucknall, just north of Nottingham, getting beaten up in alleyways, imagining that her bullies would get to read about her in the paper. She knew when she told her auntie Rachael that when she was older, her life w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 'free speech' law will make university debate harder, not easier | David Renton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/the-free-speech-law-will-make-university-debate-harder-not-easier</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/the-free-speech-law-will-make-university-debate-harder-not-easier"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T09:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Under the proposed bill, any lecture, seminar or guest speech could end up in a lawsuit
The government has published its higher education (freedom of speech) bill. Under it, universities will have a new duty to secure freedom of speech for staff members, students and visiting speakers. Anyone (“a person”) will be able to sue (“bring civil proceedings”) where they believe that a university or student union has failed to protect free speech. An official with the Orwellian title of “director for freedom of spe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Renton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sing about war and cluck like a chicken: tips from the pros on how to win Eurovision]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/eurovision-tips-from-the-pros-on-how-to-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/22/eurovision-tips-from-the-pros-on-how-to-win"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T09:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After an enforced hiatus, the contest is back. As the hopefuls don their sequins, here’s how to succeed at the gloriously OTT pop jamboree
To some, it’s a cultural cringefest. To others, it’s the World Cup of music. But no matter your spin, the Eurovision Song Contest remains one of the world’s most-watched television programmes, with the last edition, in 2019, attracting more than 180 million viewers. Founded in 1956, it has inspired and outlasted countless reality singing franchises owing to its mix of bi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>William Lee Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s nothing guilty about the pleasure I get from TV shows by women, for women | Hadley Freeman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/nothing-guilty-about-the-pleasure-i-get-from-tv-shows-by-women-for-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/22/nothing-guilty-about-the-pleasure-i-get-from-tv-shows-by-women-for-women"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T08:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Male reactions to Nancy Mitford’s The Pursuit Of Love aren’t just about sexism. They’re also about fear
Tomorrow night, the final part of the latest adaptation of Nancy Mitford’s The Pursuit Of Love will screen on the BBC, but it is imperative you do not watch it. Or, if you do, you absolutely must hate everything about it: the characters, the author, the author’s family and – most of all – everyone who enjoys any and especially all of the above. A man has decreed it must be so: “I demand an end to the glor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadley Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kathleen Stock: taboo around gender identity has chilling effect on academics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/22/kathleen-stock-taboo-around-gender-identity-chilling-effect-on-academics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/22/kathleen-stock-taboo-around-gender-identity-chilling-effect-on-academics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T07:15:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Culture of silencing any challenge to prevailing ideology is damaging academic freedom, says professor
The press release that accompanies Prof Kathleen Stock’s new book says she wants to see a future in which trans rights activists and gender-critical feminists collaborate to achieve some of their political aims. But she concedes that this currently seems fanciful. As far as she is concerned, the book, Material Girls, sets out her stall – and she knows a lot of people will find it distasteful.
Stock, a prof…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Moorhead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Rashford: ‘Whenever I hear “no”, I ask myself: why not?’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/22/marcus-rashford-whenever-i-hear-no-i-ask-myself-why-not</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/22/marcus-rashford-whenever-i-hear-no-i-ask-myself-why-not"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T07:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year the football star twice fought Boris Johnson on food poverty – and won 2-0. Now he has a new goal: helping the 383,000 British kids who have never owned a book
Imagine being Marcus Rashford. You’re just going about your business, playing football for Manchester United and England, being an everyday sporting superstar. Then you put out a Twitter thread suggesting that the country’s poorest children need to be supported better in the pandemic, and it’s the government’s responsibility to help them. A…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK animal rights group blockades four McDonald’s depots]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/animal-rights-protesters-blockade-four-mcdonalds-distribution-centres-in-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/animal-rights-protesters-blockade-four-mcdonalds-distribution-centres-in-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activists plan 24-hour protest in attempt to get company to turn fully plant-based by 2025
Animal rights protesters have set up blockades at four McDonald’s distribution centres across Britain, which they say will affect about 1,300 restaurants.
Activists from Animal Rebellion used trucks and bamboo structures to blockade distribution sites at Hemel Hempstead, Basingstoke, Coventry and Heywood in Greater Manchester from about 4.30am on Saturday, the group said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Morgan’s son says Priti Patel has added to family’s agony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/daniel-morgans-son-says-priti-patel-has-added-to-familys-agony</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/22/daniel-morgans-son-says-priti-patel-has-added-to-familys-agony"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home secretary urged to ‘bring our torture to an end’ by allowing publication of report into police and media corruption

Opinion: our father was murdered, yet we have no closure after 34 years – only anger and grief
The son of the murdered private detective Daniel Morgan has said the home secretary has exacerbated the 34 years of agony for his family by blocking the publication of the report into the role police and media corruption played in shielding his killers.
Breaking a public silence of over three d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sewage samples being tested across England to monitor Covid variants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/sewage-samples-being-tested-across-england-to-monitor-covid-variants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/22/sewage-samples-being-tested-across-england-to-monitor-covid-variants"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wastewater analysis programme will aim to detect variants early and identify need for surge testing

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Sewage samples are being tested to determine which Covid-19 variants are most prevalent across regions accounting for two-thirds of England’s population.
The Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) said the programme had helped identify the need for surge testing in areas such as Bristol and Luton. On Wednesday, the health secretary, Matt Han…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gaza damage and Glasgow raids: human rights this fortnight in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/22/gaza-damage-and-glasgow-raids-human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/22/gaza-damage-and-glasgow-raids-human-rights-this-fortnight-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A roundup of the coverage on struggles for human rights and freedoms, from Myanmar to Peru
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US journalist Barrett Brown arrested in the UK on incitement offences]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/us-journalist-barrett-brown-arrested-incitement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/us-journalist-barrett-brown-arrested-incitement"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He had been in Britain since November and intended to claim asylum on the basis that he had been persecuted in the US for his journalism
The American journalist Barrett Brown has been arrested and detained in the UK for allegedly overstaying his visa and for alleged public order and incitement offences relating to his role in holding a protest banner which said: “Kill Cops.”
Police arrested Brown on Monday at a canal boat moored in east London, where he had been living for several months with a British woma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Gayle in London</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If Dominic Cummings has proof he didn’t go to Durham twice, he could show it now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/22/if-dominic-cummings-has-proof-he-didnt-go-to-durham-twice-he-could-show-it-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/22/if-dominic-cummings-has-proof-he-didnt-go-to-durham-twice-he-could-show-it-now"/>
        <updated>2021-05-22T06:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: a year after the Guardian’s original story, much about Johnson’s adviser’s trip north remains unclear

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

When the Guardian and the Mirror revealed that Dominic Cummings had travelled to Durham and Barnard Castle during the first lockdown, our stories were dismissed by Downing Street as a “stream of false allegations by campaigning newspapers”.
Two days later, in the Downing Street rose garden, Cummings admitted they were true and prompte…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Weaver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/21/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/21/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:32:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The conflict in Gaza and Israel, migrants on the border between Morocco and Spain’s north African enclave of Ceuta, a volcano in Iceland, and Covid vaccinations in the Amazon: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the richest getting richer: fix a broken economic system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-richest-getting-richer-fix-a-broken-economic-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-the-richest-getting-richer-fix-a-broken-economic-system"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:16:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government activism is needed to deal with the baleful and growing levels of inequality in society
The Sunday Times rich list provides a useful social X-ray of Britain. It is a journalistic tool that looks inside high society without damaging its subjects. However, the findings of the latest survey – that the richest have got even richer – have been released when many people have endured a Covid year of hardship, loss and boredom. A preview released on Friday reveals that there are now 24 more billionaires …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on cryptoart: caution is necessary | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-cryptoart-caution-necessary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/21/the-guardian-view-on-cryptoart-caution-necessary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T17:15:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Non-fungible tokens are all the rage in the art market, but the environmental impact is huge
NFTs – non-fungible tokens – are being grandly hyped in the art market. There were headlines globally when a digital artwork by Beeple (real name Mike Winkelmann) was sold by Christie’s in March for $69.3m, along with an NFT – effectively a token proving ownership, which is stored on a blockchain. Blockchains, unalterable and unhackable “digital ledgers” that are also used to store the ownership records of cryptocur…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why ID card plans are likely to pass this time | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/why-id-card-plans-are-likely-to-pass-this-time</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/21/why-id-card-plans-are-likely-to-pass-this-time"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:56:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jem Whitely, Mike Cushman, Martin Willey and Eleanor Martindale respond to Simon Jenkins’ article about the government’s plans for voter identity checks
Simon Jenkins is right (Johnson’s voter ID checks are not about electoral fraud, they’re about power, 18 May), but also wrong. This is not mainly about “regulation and surveillance of daily life”, it’s about voter suppression, and for the Tories it’s so much the better if, like so many of their policies, it disproportionately impacts ethnic minorities. Beca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whining and dining: keep kids out of pubs | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/whining-and-dining-keep-kids-out-of-pubs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/21/whining-and-dining-keep-kids-out-of-pubs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:54:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers defend a London pub’s decision to ban entry on children under 10
Following Grace Dent’s review (14 May) of the Alma in Crystal Palace, London, you published a letter (When pubs leave parents out in the cold, theguardian.com, 17 May) contesting the pub’s seemingly “bizarre” ban on children under the age of 10. I feel compelled to provide a counter point of view.
As a woman who has chosen not to have children, a choice many others know is something we are judged for almost on a daily basis – “you’ll c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From bats to hornbills: Whitley award winners – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/21/from-bats-to-hornbills-whitley-award-winners-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/21/from-bats-to-hornbills-whitley-award-winners-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:50:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Whitley Fund for Nature has announced this year’s winners of its annual awards, which support conservation work across the global south. More details at www.whitleyaward.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The JavaScript Array Handbook – JS Array Methods Explained with Examples]]></title>
        <id>6098ce302cd0545b5e944d0b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-javascript-array-handbook/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In programming, an array is a collection of elements or items. Arrays store data as elements and retrieve them back when you need them.  The array data structure is widely used in all programming languages that support it. In this handbook, I'll teach you all about arrays in JavaScript. You'll]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richest nations agree to end support for coal production overseas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/richest-nations-agree-to-end-support-for-coal-production-overseas"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 countries reaffirm commitment to limit global heating to 1.5C after nearly two days of wrangling
The world’s richest nations have agreed to end their financial support for coal development overseas, in a major step towards phasing out the dirtiest fossil fuel.
After nearly two days of wrangling at a meeting of the G7 environment and energy ministers, hosted virtually by the UK on Thursday and Friday, all reaffirmed their commitment to limiting global heating to 1.5C, and committed to phasing out coal and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May gales help Britain set record for wind power generation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/may-gales-help-britain-set-record-for-wind-power-generation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/21/may-gales-help-britain-set-record-for-wind-power-generation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:15:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In early hours of Friday, windfarm turbines provided nearly two-thirds of Britain’s electricity
Powerful gusts of wind sweeping across Britain have helped the country reach a new all-time high for electricity generated from wind turbines.
A new record was set in the early hours of Friday for the share of wind power in the generation mix, with wind providing nearly two-thirds of Britain’s electricity, according to provisional data from National Grid.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Kollewe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Black fungus’ disease linked to Covid spreads across India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/mucormycosis-black-fungus-disease-linked-covid-spreads-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/21/mucormycosis-black-fungus-disease-linked-covid-spreads-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T12:59:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[7,200 mucormycosis cases reported, usually in patients with diabetes or compromised immune systems

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

States across India have begun declaring a “black fungus” epidemic as cases of the fatal rare infection shoot up in patients recovering from Covid-19.
The fungal disease, called mucormycosis, has a 50% mortality rate. It affects patients initially in the nose but the fungus can then spread into the brain, and can often only be treated by major sur…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen in Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG) From Scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK citizens: have you experienced any issues at EU border control?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/21/uk-citizens-have-you-experienced-any-issues-at-eu-border-control"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T09:31:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from UK citizens who have encountered issues when travelling to other countries in Europe

Following reports that some EU citizens have been sent to immigration removal centres and held in airport detention rooms, we would like to hear from UK citizens about any issues they have faced at border control when travelling to Europe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life inside Gaza during 11 days of bombardment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/21/life-inside-gaza"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian journalist Hazem Balousha describes living in, and reporting from, Gaza, under heavy bombardment until a ceasefire began on Friday, while historian Rashid Khalidi discusses the history of the Palestinian struggle for statehood
Anushka Asthana talks to Hazem Balousha, a Guardian correspondent who lives in Gaza. He describes living in, and reporting from, the strip, which was under heavy bombardment from last Monday until the agreement of a ceasefire, beginning early on Friday morning. The latest con…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hazem Balousha and Rashid Khalidi, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn CSS!]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340933</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/learn/css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T21:51:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ooo look at this mighty SEO flex from Google: Learn CSS! Well deserved — this is great content. Twenty-three chapters taking you through all the fundamentals of CSS with extra content, like relevant podcasts, interactive examples, and even quizzes to …
The post Learn CSS! appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angular 11 Tutorial: Code a Project from Scratch]]></title>
        <id>60a6b3ab906c5207e3a7f5fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/angular-11-tutorial-code-a-project-from-scratch/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T19:14:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angular is one of the most popular web frameworks. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create an Angular 11 project from scratch. It uses a public API to create a game database website. You will gain a great foundation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Modern C++ by Building an Audio Plugin]]></title>
        <id>60a694ab906c5207e3a7f544</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-modern-cpp-by-building-an-audio-plugin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T17:12:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of C++ courses teach you how to build toy projects with no real-world application. But it can often be more helpful to write programs people would actually use. We just released a 5-hour C++ course that will teach you how to write modern C++ code by building an]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Started with Version Control Using Git]]></title>
        <id>60a4b5c7906c5207e3a7e2bb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/get-started-with-version-control-and-git/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T15:20:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, you'll learn what version control is and how you can contribute to open-source projects using Git.  We'll get through the fundamentals of Git and I'll give you the knowledge that is indispensable for any web developer. What is Git?Git is a version control software which lets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn JavaScript - A Free 7-hour Interactive Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>60a36742906c5207e3a7da6e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-javascript-interactive-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last four months, I have recorded what is probably the most interactive JavaScript course that has ever been created. The reason I have done this is because I often see new coders fall into the same pitfalls again and again when trying to learn JavaScript, with the most]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340715</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/can-we-create-a-resize-hack-with-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:24:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you follow new developments in CSS, you’ve likely heard of the impending arrival of container queries. We’re going to look at the basics here, but if you’d like another look, check out Una’s “Next Gen CSS: @container” article. …
The post Can We Create a “Resize Hack” With Container Queries? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jhey Tompkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fit-content and fit-content()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340897</id>
        <link href="https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2021/04/fitcontent_and.html"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s some hardcore deep-dive CSS nerdery from PPK. If you can wrap your mind around min-content (the smallest an element can be based on the content it contains) and max-content (the largest the content of an element can push it) …
The post fit-content and fit-content() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate crisis behind drastic drop in Arctic wildlife populations – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/20/climate-crisis-drastic-drop-arctic-wildlife-populations-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Native shorebirds and caribou among species at risk as survival strategies are upended
A drastic drop in caribou and shorebird populations is a reflection of the dire changes unfolding on the Arctic tundra, according to a new report from the Arctic Council. 
The terrestrial Arctic spans approximately 2.7m sq miles (7m sq km), marked by extreme cold, drought, strong winds and seasonal darkness. Species living in this environment have adapted to thrive in the harsh conditions. But the climate crisis has upend…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gloria Dickie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you attended a large-scale test event in England?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-attended-a-large-scale-test-event-in-england"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:45:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from the people who attended these events about their experiences
In April, the government launched their scheme to pilot large-scale events in England to test their safety before restrictions are eased on mass gatherings.
The majority of rules on social contact are set to be removed by 21 June, but this is dependent on cases, deaths and hospital admissions continuing to fall.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your favourite memories from the Glastonbury festival]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/20/share-your-favourite-memories-from-the-glastonbury-festival"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:25:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the festival gearing up for the Live at Worthy Farm live stream this weekend, we want to hear your most cherished moments from past years
One year off, we could handle. After all, Glastonbury often has a fallow year to let the land, and the workers, have a bit of a rest. But two cancellations of the festival in a row is really quite depressing, leaving us and thousands of ticket holders dolefully marking out June 2022 in the diaries for the next possible trip.
But as well as September’s planned one-day…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rio de Janeiro’s deadliest police raid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/audio/2021/may/20/inside-jacarezinho-favela-after-rio-de-janeiros-deadliest-police-raid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T02:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Latin American correspondent Tom Phillips visits Jacarezinho, one of Rio’s biggest favelas, the day after police carried out the deadliest raid in the city’s history
Anushka Asthana talks to Tom Phillips about the police raid in Jacarezinho favela, in the Brazilian city of Rio de Janeiro. On 6 May police stormed the favela, targeting one of the city’s largest drug gangs, known as Red Command. Twenty-seven men were shot dead by police and one police officer was killed. Police, politicians and some p…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Tom Phillips, produced by Rose de Larrabeiti and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340731</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/notion-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:18:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Public Beta of the Notion API dropped! Woot! Here’s their guide. I’ve been a Notion user and fan for a long time, for both personal and professional team use. They even sponsored a few videos around here a …
The post Notion API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use CSS Selectors to Style Your Web Page]]></title>
        <id>60a341f5906c5207e3a7da61</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-css-selectors-to-style-webpage/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T23:17:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS selectors are one of the most important parts of CSS. They give you the ability to target HTML elements on your web page that you want to style. Without CSS selectors, you wouldn't be able to style your page to look how you want. Thankfully CSS selectors have been]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Web3? The Decentralized Internet of the Future Explained]]></title>
        <id>60a42386906c5207e3a7dfe2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-web3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T21:09:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The internet is going through a paradigm shift. Learn the differences between Web2 and Web3, and why many developers and companies are shifting their approach in building apps.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Optimize for Change in Software Development]]></title>
        <id>60a469ec906c5207e3a7e1b9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-optimize-for-change-software-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T17:30:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine that you work at Magic Money Corp, which runs on just three lines of JavaScript: let input = { step1: 'collect underpants' } doStuff(input)  profit(input) // $$$!!! Now imagine that something's wrong with doStuff and you need to take it down for maintenance. What happens if you temporarily comment out the second]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340692</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svg-loader-a-different-way-to-work-with-external-svg/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T14:28:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SVGs are awesome: they are small, look sharp on any scale, and can be customized without creating a separate file. However, there is something I feel is missing in web standards today: a way to include them as an external …
The post svg-loader: A Different Way to Work With External SVG appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shubham Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple versus Epic: how the Fortnite app led to a legal showdown - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/19/apple-versus-epic-how-the-fortnite-app-led-to-a-legal-showdown-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Apple takes on games developer and Fortnite creator Epic, UK technology editor Alex Hern describes a battle of the tech titans that could reshape the app industry
The video game Fortnite has become a cultural phenomenon in recent years with up to 100 million users a month logging in to play the free online game. They parachute down on to an island with 99 other players and the last one standing is the winner. 
But for users of iPhones and iPads, the wildly popular game has been unavailable ever since it …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Alex Hern; produced by Sami Kent and Iain Chambers; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break into Ethereum, Crypto, and Web3 as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60a53182906c5207e3a7e588</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/breaking-into-ethereum-crypto-web3-as-a-developer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T21:04:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I've been talking about my move into the Web3, Ethereum, and crypto space since making the switch from a traditional web, mobile, and cloud background. Since making that move, a shocking number of people have reached out to me who are also thinking about doing the same.  It's really]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinned Audio WordPress Theme]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340613</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/pinned-audio-wordpress-theme/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m afraid I have to start this with a whole backstory, as the journey here is the point, not so much the theme.
A fella wrote to me a while back outlining a situation he was in. His company has …
The post Pinned Audio WordPress Theme appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freelance Development Pricing Guide – Should Freelancers Bill by the Hour?]]></title>
        <id>60a3780f906c5207e3a7db5f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-different-ways-to-charge-for-a-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T17:12:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you offer your services as a freelance developer, you have a major say in how you price your project.  But how do you go about charging for a website project? "Well, I just bill by the hour and send an invoice every week or month." ...I hear you say.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Neon Text With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340420</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-neon-text-with-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T14:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neon text can add a nice, futuristic touch to any website. I’ve always loved the magic of neon signs, and wanted to recreate them using CSS. I thought I’d share some tips on how to do it! In this article, …
The post How to Create Neon Text With CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia O'Dwyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340716</id>
        <link href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T22:38:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Addy Osmani on images in HTML:
The humble <img> element has gained some superpowers over the years. Given how central it is to image optimization on the web, let’s catch up on what it can do and how it can 
…
The post The Humble `img` Element And Core Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Love Letter to HTML & CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339522</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-love-letter-to-html-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I see you. In the back there, behind JavaScript and React and PHP and all those “real” programming languages, I see you. And I appreciate you.
The post A Love Letter to HTML & CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ashley Kolodziej</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euismod]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340594</id>
        <link href="https://www.euismod.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T14:27:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An interactive tool for learning grid syntax from Etesam Ansari. In the Learn section, it teaches you some concepts (involving multiple bits of the grid syntax) then gives you a task to complete by filling out the right syntax. I’m …
The post Euismod appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>