<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-27T00:34:34.980Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-27T00:34:34.980Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Praying for a miracle’: the desperate search for scores missing in condo collapse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/condo-collapse-surfside-search</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/condo-collapse-surfside-search"/>
        <updated>2021-06-27T00:12:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rescue crews digging into unstable rubble have been hampered by storms and fires in the mound of debris
Death came swiftly to residents of Champlain Towers South. Grandparents, parents and children were sleeping in their beds when their 12-storey condominium building collapsed into a heap of smouldering rubble.
Survivors described a sound like thunder, followed by complete destruction of dozens of apartments in the oceanside south Florida block. The collapse took barely 10 seconds but was captured on grim security camera footage from a neighboring building that quickly began streaming on news websites across the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Croatia’s Ivan Perisic tests positive for Covid and will miss Spain tie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/27/croatias-ivan-perisic-tests-positive-for-covid-and-will-miss-spain-tie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/27/croatias-ivan-perisic-tests-positive-for-covid-and-will-miss-spain-tie"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T23:51:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winger’s self-isolation rules him out of Euro 2020 match
All other Croatia players and staff tested negative

Ivan Perisic has tested positive for Covid-19, the Croatian Football Federation announced on Saturday evening.
The Internazionale winger scored in the 3-1 win over Scotland on Tuesday that secured a place in the last 16 as runners-up to England in Group D. The 32-year-old will now spend 10 days in self-isolation, and so will not be available for Monday’s match against Spain in Copenhagen.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hipgnosis’s back-catalogue spending pays off in pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/27/hipgnosis-music-streaming-old-songs-beyonce-blondie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/27/hipgnosis-music-streaming-old-songs-beyonce-blondie"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T23:05:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The firm’s strength in old songs has seen revenues up by two-thirds after streaming saw a huge boost in lockdown
If there was a soundtrack to the annual results for Hipgnosis next week, Hey Big Spender would be perfect. In a deal-making flurry aimed at capitalising on a surge in music listening during the pandemic, the music rights owner has over the past year spent $1bn (£710m) on evergreen hit songs, buying the rights to 84 song catalogues by artists ranging from Neil Young to Shakira.
Its entire catalogue, which also includes songs by Beyoncé, Blondie, Barry Manilow and more, is worth $2.2bn following that spree.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make a splash: 21 of the best swimsuits – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/26/make-a-splash-21-of-the-best-swimsuits-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/26/make-a-splash-21-of-the-best-swimsuits-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T22:50:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Take the plunge this summer with our pick of the best women’s swimwear
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hope Lawrie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sajid Javid steps back into the cabinet to steer UK out of pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/sajid-javid-steps-back-into-the-cabinet-to-steer-uk-out-of-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/sajid-javid-steps-back-into-the-cabinet-to-steer-uk-out-of-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T22:15:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incoming secretary of state faces daunting task while mastering his new position in the Department of Health as quickly as possible
Sajid Javid may have already served in two of the most testing offices of state, as chancellor of the exchequer and home secretary. But on Saturday he walked into what is now arguably the biggest and most challenging of all: the job of health secretary.
Not only does Javid have to steer the country out of what will hopefully be the final stages of the pandemic, ensuring we reach the end of what Boris Johnson has called the “irreversible road to freedom”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blow to Johnson’s authority as his health minister loses all support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/blow-to-johnson-authority-as-health-secretary-loses-all-support</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/blow-to-johnson-authority-as-health-secretary-loses-all-support"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:44:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From his local Tory party to senior NHS figures, pressure on Matt Hancock mounted until he was unable to carry on
When Matt Hancock drove to see Boris Johnson at Chequers to tell him he was resigning on Saturday, it wasn’t just an admission that he had run out of supporters after admitting his infamous clinch with an aide breached Covid guidelines. It was also a rare moment when the prime minister’s legendary ability to defy political gravity appeared to falter.
Even by Saturday afternoon, when Tory MPs had begun to make their feelings known, Hancock’s own local paper had condemned him and senior figures in the NHS had concluded Hancock had lost all credibility, Downing Street stuck to its initial conclusion that the matter of the health secretary’s conduct was closed. The tactic, after all, had a good record of success. Be it the home secretary Priti Patel over bullying claims, education secretary Gavin Williamson over botched exams, or communities secretary Robert Jenrick over a Tory donor’s property deal, Johnson resolutely ignored demands for sackings. The regular use of the tactic had led Whitehall insiders and some Tory MPs to wonder what levers were still in place to hold faltering ministers accountable.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italy find something extra from Matteo Pessina to see off Austria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/italy-austria-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/italy-austria-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:40:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Federico Chiesa walked out on to the Wembley pitch with six minutes of normal time remaining and this tight, fretful last-16 tie still goalless. The story of the game to that point had been a finely wrought defensive performance from Austria, who showed great resolve against a team most expected to simply blow them away.
The final whistle came as a relief to Italy’s players, who fell into an angsty-looking huddle around their manager. Roberto Mancini’s message was clear even from the sidelines. Take a breath, reset the throttle. And Italy did find another gear.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay at Wembley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donald Trump returns to campaign trail with rally targeting Ohio Republican]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/donald-trump-campaign-rally-ohio-republican-new-york-investigation-rudy-giuliani</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/donald-trump-campaign-rally-ohio-republican-new-york-investigation-rudy-giuliani"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:26:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As New York legal troubles mount, ex-president hints at 2024 run and targets those who voted for impeachment

The Constitution of Knowledge: defending truth from Trump

Donald Trump was set to return to the campaign trail with a rally in Ohio on Saturday night, campaigning against a Republican who voted for his impeachment and trailing his own candidacy for president in 2024.
 Related: Trump Organization could face criminal charges in New York next week 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three arrested and three officers injured at anti-lockdown protests in London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/three-arrested-and-three-officers-injured-at-anti-lockdown-protests-in-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/three-arrested-and-three-officers-injured-at-anti-lockdown-protests-in-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:15:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of tennis balls, some bearing messages, launched at the Houses of Parliament to chants of ‘shame on you’
Police arrested three people and three officers were injured during anti-lockdown protests on Saturday that saw thousands descend on central London and hundreds of tennis balls launched at the Houses of Parliament.
The Metropolitan police said three people were arrested at the protests – for breach of the peace and assault on police, plus one was already wanted for a previous assault – and three officers suffered minor injuries.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dina Asher-Smith books Olympic place with 100m trials victory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/dina-asher-smith-books-olympic-place-with-100m-trials-victory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/dina-asher-smith-books-olympic-place-with-100m-trials-victory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:12:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sprinter ‘in really, really good shape’ after 10.97 run
Mo Farah not finished, insists coach Gary Lough

Dina Asher-Smith destroyed her opponents – and sent the clock dizzy – as she booked her place at the Olympics next month with victory in the British 100m trials in Manchester.
As Asher-Smith crossed the line the clock initially showed a time of 10.71sec – which would have been the second-fastest time in the world this year. No wonder the crowd gasped in stunned awe – only for the time to be revised up to 10.97 about 30 seconds later.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle at Manchester Regional Arena</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conor Murray named Lions captain after Alun Wyn Jones ruled out by injury]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/lions-japan-match-report-alun-wyn-jones</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/lions-japan-match-report-alun-wyn-jones"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T21:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British & Irish Lions 28-10 Japan
Beard replaces Jones in squad; Navidi replaces Tipuric

The Ireland scrum-half Conor Murray has been named as Warren Gatland’s surprise choice as the new British & Irish Lions captain after Alun Wyn Jones was ruled out with a dislocated shoulder on a disastrous day for the tourists. Justin Tipuric has also been withdrawn with a shoulder injury with the Lions plunged into disarray before flying to South Africa on Sunday.
Murray’s appointment as the new tour captain comes from left field, with Gatland overlooking Maro Itoje, Owen Farrell and Ken Owens as potential replacements for Jones, but the 32-year-old Irishman can be considered a safe pair of hands, having started all three Tests in New Zealand four years ago. In a position in which Gatland does not have great depth, Murray is also one of few players who seem assured of their Test spot at this early stage, though it must be said he was not among the Lions’ best performers in the comfortable four-try victory over Japan on Saturday. His captaincy experience is also limited.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher at BT Murrayfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[White House seeks to put infrastructure deal back on track after Biden blunder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/biden-infrastructure-deal-republicans-white-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/biden-infrastructure-deal-republicans-white-house"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:45:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The president said he wouldn’t sign bill unless it was accompanied by an even bigger package covering Democratic priorities
The White House scrambled to put Joe Biden’s bipartisan infrastructure deal back on track on Saturday, after Republican senators balked at his surprise demand to pair the nearly $1tn plan with an even bigger investment package covering progressive policy priorities, a demand the president made on Thursday even while hailing the deal.
 Related: How Mitch McConnell has unified Republicans as a red wall against Biden’s agenda  
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Bale walks out of interview when asked about Wales future]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/gareth-bale-walks-out-of-interview-when-asked-about-wales-future</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/gareth-bale-walks-out-of-interview-when-asked-about-wales-future"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:10:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wales knocked out of Euro 2020 4-0 by Denmark
Manager Robert Page said questioning ‘insensitive’

Gareth Bale cast doubt on his Wales future by walking out of an interview when asked whether a last-16 European Championship defeat to Denmark would be his last international game. Bale has repeatedly avoided discussing his future, citing a reluctance to cause “chaos”, and last month twice declined to dispel speculation he would retire after this tournament.
Robert Page, the interim Wales manager, said the line of questioning was “insensitive” and insisted his captain had done the right thing by cutting short the pitchside interview. “I know you were asked yesterday if this was going to be your last game for Wales and you said you wanted at least another one,” was as far as the BBC reporter got, referencing the pre-match press conference, before Bale rolled his eyes and walked off camera.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at the Johan Cruyff Arena</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comeback kings Harlequins crowned as most extraordinary champions yet | Michael Aylwin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/26/comeback-kings-harlequins-crowned-as-most-extraordinary-champions-yet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/26/comeback-kings-harlequins-crowned-as-most-extraordinary-champions-yet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:05:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This season’s Premiership winners battled back from the brink time and time again before vanquishing Exeter in a hectic final
It goes without saying this was an epic. Another. And in this era of the comeback, who should be crowned as the English champions but a team that had seemed in pieces only a few months ago, their coach gone, their form ruined? Harlequins became English rugby’s unlikeliest champions – not the first to prevail from fourth place, perhaps, but undoubtedly the first to have found themselves in such seemingly hopeless positions throughout this season, right up to last weekend and the 28-0 deficit that needs no introduction.
Where is Paul Gustard now? Well, polishing some unlikely silverware of his own, actually, as defence coach of Benetton Treviso, newly crowned champions of the Rainbow Cup. But this gong is of rather more substance. Did Gustard lay the foundations, or was this turnaround all the more remarkable for the ruins he left behind?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Aylwin at Twickenham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Unnecessarily cruel’: how Australia’s closed border is forcing migrants to leave permanently]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/27/unnecessarily-cruel-how-australias-closed-border-is-forcing-migrants-to-leave-permanently</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/27/unnecessarily-cruel-how-australias-closed-border-is-forcing-migrants-to-leave-permanently"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent arrivals find themselves choosing between their fairytale life in Australia and desperation to see family

Covid travel restrictions in Australia
NSW Covid restrictions; NSW exposure sites and cases map
Vaccine rollout tracker; Download the free Guardian app; Get our morning email briefing

“We need to decide how long we can live like this,” says Jennie Edeleanu.
Fifteen months after the coronavirus pandemic brought international travel to a standstill, Australia’s progressive tightening of its borders is forcing newly arrived migrants such as Jennie and her fiance, Steen Reed, to consider leaving permanently. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elias Visontay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You’ve been warmed: 10 slow-bake recipes to keep you home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/27/youve-been-warmed-10-slow-bake-recipes-to-keep-you-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/27/youve-been-warmed-10-slow-bake-recipes-to-keep-you-home"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the cold weather takes hold, leverage the heat of your oven to stay cosy while cooking up a feast


With more of us spending time indoors during winter and while working from home, your oven can double up on duties: making dinner and warming your kitchen in the process. You don’t need a slow cooker when your oven can do all the work for you, from tender confit vegetables to a rich and luxurious custard.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Waldegrave</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’ve seen too many bodies’: Jakarta gravediggers chart Indonesia’s Covid battle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/27/ive-seen-too-many-bodies-jakarta-gravediggers-chart-indonesias-covid-battle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/27/ive-seen-too-many-bodies-jakarta-gravediggers-chart-indonesias-covid-battle"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workers like Darsiman sometimes work 16-hour days in the mud to handle the coffins brought out from a line of waiting ambulances

See all our coronavirus coverage

It is only noon and the grave diggers at Rorotan cemetery have buried 23 bodies of Covid-19 patients since they started work at 7am.
At least two excavators are on standby because the hard soil in the area makes it difficult to dig with just shovels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gemma Holliani Cahya in Jakarta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Mexico: five dead after hot air balloon crash in Albuquerque]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/new-mexico-hot-air-balloon-crash-albuquerque</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/new-mexico-hot-air-balloon-crash-albuquerque"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T19:51:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four dead at the scene and one dies in hospital after balloon blown into power lines by wind catches fire
Five people died after a hot air balloon hit power lines in New Mexico’s largest city on Saturday, police said.
The crash happened around 7am on Albuquerque’s west side, police spokesman Gilbert Gallegos said. No identities were immediately released but fire officials said three males, including the pilot, and two females died.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Albuquerque, New Mexico</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock resigns as health secretary after day of humiliation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/matt-hancock-resigns-after-questions-over-relationship-with-aide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/matt-hancock-resigns-after-questions-over-relationship-with-aide"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T19:10:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-chancellor Sajid Javid is made health secretary but Boris Johnson’s authority suffers blow from resignation
Matt Hancock has resigned as health secretary after Tory MPs, ministers and grassroots Conservatives defied Boris Johnson and demanded he be dismissed from the government.
The minister fell on his sword after a day that began with senior Tories observing a deliberate silence over Hancock’s future – seemingly to test public opinion in their constituencies – before many later broke ranks to insist he had to go.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm, Michael Savage and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate must combat Germany’s agents of chaos – but first, pick a shape | Jonathan Wilson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/26/gareth-southgate-must-combat-germanys-agents-of-chaos-but-first-pick-a-shape</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/26/gareth-southgate-must-combat-germanys-agents-of-chaos-but-first-pick-a-shape"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T19:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to counter Joshua Kimmich and Robin Gosens is one of a string of conundrums the England manager must solve
Nothing in football is ever straightforward. There are few rights and few wrongs; almost everything is contingent. But even within that context, England’s game against Germany on Tuesday is hard to pin down. There are few certainties for either side; rather this is two swarms of questions buzzing into each other.
At least with Germany, there is relative certainty about the shape. Joachim Löw has vacillated between a back three and a back four since the World Cup debacle before finally settling on a 3-4-3, in which the real strength is the attacking prowess of the wing-backs, Joshua Kimmich and Robin Gosens. Other than replacing the injured Thomas Müller with Leroy Sané, Löw stuck with the same personnel for all three group games, so it seems reasonable to assume there will not be major changes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Observer view on Matt Hancock’s resignation | Observer editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/the-observer-view-on-the-matt-hancock-affair</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/the-observer-view-on-the-matt-hancock-affair"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T18:37:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A rotten culture of impunity pervades the Tory party, where blind loyalty counts for more than integrity and competence
‘There must be no actual or perceived conflicts of interest. The precious principles of public life – integrity, objectivity, accountability, transparency, honesty and leadership in the public interest – must be honoured at all times.” So reads Boris Johnson’s foreword to the ministerial code, written almost two years ago. Yet Matt Hancock, who resigned as health secretary yesterday evening, is only the latest minister to disrespect the citizens of this country by flouting this code.
Health secretary Matt Hancock’s private affairs are his own business, but he has made his intimate relationship with his old friend, adviser and paid director of the Department of Health a public matter. First, as he has openly admitted, he has broken the Covid regulations he was responsible for. Members of the public who were unable to hug loved ones before they died, who missed funerals and who went months without seeing newborn grandchildren will be justified in feeling furious at a minister breaking the rules to engage in an affair. Hancock has also said that public figures in far less high-profile positions were right to resign for breaking the regulations. His hypocrisy undermines faith in the government’s approach to public health during a pandemic. This alone was enough to prompt his immediate resignation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Observer editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hurricane Lane blows past Lone Eagle to deny Dettori in Irish Derby thriller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/irish-derby-report-hurricane-lane-lone-eagle-frankie-dettori</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/irish-derby-report-hurricane-lane-lone-eagle-frankie-dettori"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T18:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[William Buick pips Frankie Dettori at the Curragh
Aidan O’Brien favourite High Definition is well beaten

Hurricane Lane denied Lone Eagle in the final stages in a thrilling finale as British raiders dominated the Irish Derby at the Curragh.
Frankie Dettori looked to have stolen the Classic on Martyn Meade’s Lone Eagle, shooting three lengths clear of a melee in behind with two furlongs to run. Hurricane Lane looked to be right in trouble, but once straightened out by William Buick he made up ground relentlessly, eventually prevailing by a neck.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dawid Malan answers critics and helps England to T20 sweep over Sri Lanka]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/dawid-malan-answers-critics-and-helps-england-to-t20-whitewash-of-sri-lanka</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/dawid-malan-answers-critics-and-helps-england-to-t20-whitewash-of-sri-lanka"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T18:09:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Third T20i: England 180-6: Sri Lanka 91
England complete clean sweep with 89-run win

This series had already been decided before a ball had been bowled yet the final match in Southampton did offer Dawid Malan an opportunity to remind everyone why he is still the No 1-ranked batsman in international Twenty20 cricket.
The 33-year-old had come into this dead rubber under pressure after a run of one half-century in seven previous innings, including scores of seven and four during England’s pair of victories in the opening two matches in Cardiff earlier in the week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Stocks at the Ageas Bowl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK students want tuition fees refunded as they face third year online]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/uk-students-want-tuition-fees-refunded-as-they-face-third-year-online</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/uk-students-want-tuition-fees-refunded-as-they-face-third-year-online"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T18:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Universities are still waiting for clarity on social-distancing rules before deciding on mix of teaching, Observer survey finds

Coronavirus – latest updates

See all our coronavirus coverage

Students are facing a third successive year of online learning, after an Observer analysis suggested that most universities are planning to offer a mix of in-person seminars and online lectures when term begins again this autumn.
It prompted fresh calls for students to be refunded at least part of the fees they are charged each year if they are mostly taught online. The exact blend of teaching will depend on social distancing rules and whether young people are double-vaccinated in time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our politics of nostalgia is a sure sign of present-day decay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/our-politics-of-nostalgia-is-a-sure-sign-of-present-day-decay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/our-politics-of-nostalgia-is-a-sure-sign-of-present-day-decay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T18:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Both the left and right are obsessed by a lost golden age. A confident Britain would look to the future
The belief that the past was better than the present, and the only way forward is back, can be found in the corners of any society at any time. But when nostalgia grows to dominate Britain and much of the west it is as sure a symptom of decay as the stink of dry rot.
Every step of Britain’s decline has been accompanied by the sound of sighs for a lost country. To confine myself only to the past few weeks, we had Boris Johnson ordering a new royal yacht “to display the UK’s burgeoning status as a great, independent maritime trading nation”, a £200m attempt to feign 19th-century splendour that covers up the impoverishing consequences of Brexit on the UK’s real trade. After that, we had ministers promoting a well-meant but equally deceitful patriotic song that declared: “We are Britain/ And we have one dream/ To unite all people/ In one great team.” The yearning for a united country would be less pitiable if the same ministers had not partitioned the United Kingdom by putting a trade border down the Irish Sea and were not now driving Scots into the arms of separatists, who are no slouches when it comes to myth-making themselves.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denmark end Wales’ Euro 2020 dreams as Dolberg double caps dominant win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/wales-denmark-euro-2020-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/wales-denmark-euro-2020-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:55:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was exactly the kind of party Denmark had mapped out. On an Amsterdam evening when the locals turned out to send their love to Christian Eriksen, another former Ajax prodigy propelled Denmark into the quarter-finals of the European Championship.
Twenty-nine years to the day since Denmark won Euro 92 Kasper Dolberg scored twice, the first a delicious effort from outside the box, to help dispatch Wales with relative ease before Joakim Mæhle and Martin Braithwaite sealed victory late on.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at the Johan Cruyff Arena</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Le Pen looks to Provence for last hope of victory in French regional elections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/le-pen-looks-to-provence-for-last-hope-of-victory-in-french-regional-elections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/le-pen-looks-to-provence-for-last-hope-of-victory-in-french-regional-elections"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:40:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poll on knife-edge as parties form alliances in a bid to defeat far-right RN party
At the 17th-century town hall in the Provençal city of Arles, a large tricolour flapped vigorously outside the open window of the mayor’s office last week, animated perhaps by what locals call the mistralet, a gentle summer version of the strong wind that blows through the Rhône valley.
The world heritage city – the largest commune in metropolitan France – has been marked by foreign influence throughout its history: the Romans conquered it in 123BC, leaving the magnificent arena, theatre, necropolis and aqueduct; much later came the artists, Dutchman Vincent Van Gogh and Spanish-born Pablo Picasso among them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Arles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for action after women in Covid quarantine report harassment by guards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/call-for-action-after-women-in-covid-quarantine-report-harassment-by-guards</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/call-for-action-after-women-in-covid-quarantine-report-harassment-by-guards"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:28:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow home secretary Nick Thomas-Symonds says ministers must urgently investigate alleged behaviour of G4S security staff


Ministers must take action over allegations that people quarantining in hotels have been sexually harassed by security guards, the shadow home secretary has said.
Nick Thomas-Symonds made the comments after BBC News reported that four women had come forward to say they had been harassed by guards working for the outsourcing firm G4S during their stays in Covid quarantine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Younger and more diverse: TV’s team of pundits now reflect their game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/younger-and-more-diverse-tvs-team-of-pundits-now-reflect-their-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/26/younger-and-more-diverse-tvs-team-of-pundits-now-reflect-their-game"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:17:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Line-up of presenters, which includes female and black ex-players, mirrors football’s changing makeup
England’s footballers have come a long way since they were embarrassed by losing to Iceland in 2016. And so have the broadcasters.
The rosters of presenters, analysts and commentators at ITV and the BBC are markedly more diverse than they were five years ago. Of the 23 people that ITV announced as part of its on-air team for the tournament in France then, only two were women – Jacqui Oatley and Eni Aluko – and five were from ethnic minorities. This time, the team of 31 includes seven women and 14 people of colour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rumaan Alam: ‘Our cultural response to a crisis was to go shopping’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/rumaan-alam-leave-the-world-behind-covid-crisis-shopping</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/rumaan-alam-leave-the-world-behind-covid-crisis-shopping"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The author of the apocalyptic novel Leave the World Behind reflects on its parallels with the Covid pandemic, the genius of Lorrie Moore and why he is looking forward to letting his kids run feral outside
Rumaan Alam was born in 1977 and raised in Washington DC. He is the author of three novels, the latest of which, Leave the World Behind, got rave reviews when it came out in hardback last year. The story of two families, one white, one black, thrust together in a Long Island holiday home amid apocalyptic events, it was described by the Observer as “simply breathtaking… as terrifying and prescient as Cormac McCarthy’s The Road”. Now out in paperback, it is being turned into a film by Sam Esmail (Mr Robot) starring Julia Roberts and Denzel Washington. Alam lives in Brooklyn with his husband, David Land, a photographer, and their two adopted sons.
A lot of reviewers called your book “prescient”, given that you wrote it before the pandemic. What’s your take on that?
I’d never even heard the word coronavirus prior to February 2020. On a very basic level, the book dramatises being trapped in at home and not having enough information – and it happened to be published into a reality in which many readers felt that they were trapped in their homes and didn’t have enough information. So it’s a strange resonance. I think it’s connected to other books that are talking about some of the same things – about the individual relationship to anxiety over the climate, the absurdity of the contemporary moment, our warped relationship to technology. People are thinking and talking about this stuff so it makes sense that there will be books about it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Killian Fox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raves from the grave: lost 90s subculture is back in the spotlight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/26/raves-from-the-grave-lost-90s-subculture-is-back-in-the-spotlight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/26/raves-from-the-grave-lost-90s-subculture-is-back-in-the-spotlight"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Driven by a ‘groundswell’ of young devotees and fortysomething nostalgia, a series of events is celebrating the youth movement
It is perhaps one of the most ignored subcultures in modern British history, but rave music and the free party movement of the early 90s is coming back into focus.
Over the next few months, a series of films, exhibitions, memoirs and podcasts will reappraise free parties and the crackdown on them by John Major’s government, as well as their modern echoes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uefa VIPs get a quarantine-free pass to Wembley – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/26/uefa-vips-get-a-quarantine-free-pass-to-wembley-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/26/uefa-vips-get-a-quarantine-free-pass-to-wembley-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite the Delta variant, football officials – and Matt Hancock – get free rein
• You can order your own copy of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong needs law to tackle ‘hostility against the police’, says force’s new chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/hong-kong-needs-law-to-tackle-hostility-against-the-police-says-forces-new-chief</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/hong-kong-needs-law-to-tackle-hostility-against-the-police-says-forces-new-chief"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T16:41:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raymond Siu blames protests on ‘fake news’ – but critics fear the label will be used to muzzle dissent
Hong Kong’s new police chief has called for a “fake news” law to tackle “hostility against the police”, in what analysts see as an indication of the next phase of the crackdown on free speech in the former British overseas territory.
“I understand that there are residents who are still hostile against us,” Raymond Siu, 55, said at his first media briefing since taking office on Friday. “In this regard, I told my colleagues that many of these torn relationships and hostility against the police are due to fake news.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni China affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If only Stonehenge were of use in the culture wars, then it might be protected | Catherine Bennett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/if-only-stonehenge-any-use-culture-wars-might-be-protected</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/if-only-stonehenge-any-use-culture-wars-might-be-protected"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T16:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government likes heritage when it helps in a fight. Otherwise, it just doesn’t care
Thankfully, as the prime minister once reminded us, “there are international conventions in place that prevent the destruction of cultural heritage”. At specific risk (from Donald Trump’s threats) at the time were 52 of Iran’s major cultural sites, 24 of them world heritage listed. Theoretically protecting them in 2020 was the 1954 Hague convention for the protection, in the event of armed conflict, of cultural assets: “Movable or immovable property of great importance to the cultural heritage of every people.” Places, for instance, such as Stonehenge.
In peacetime, however, alterations that might be resented as “adverse and irreversible” if inflicted on a great monument by a foreign power may be completed by a national government with consequences hardly more serious – for a leadership that routinely courts both – than international condemnation and contempt.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Catherine Bennett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Donavon Smallwood: ‘What’s it like to be a black person in nature?’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/26/donavon-smallwood-photographs-black-nature-central-park-langour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/26/donavon-smallwood-photographs-black-nature-central-park-langour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The self-taught 27-year-old discusses Languor, a prize-winning series of portraits shot in Central Park over the past year
Since he was seven years old, Donavon Smallwood had lived in the same apartment in Harlem close to the northern tip of Central Park. As a teenager, he hung out there with his friends and, later, as he became interested in photography, he would often wander through the park with his camera looking for hidden places where the clamour of the city seemed a world away. “So many urban communities don’t have any nature spaces,” he says, “so I was lucky to have one close by.”
In 2019, he had “a vague idea for a project about walking and looking”, a flaneur’s take on the park as a place in which to lose oneself. Throughout the spring and summer of 2020, while New York was in lockdown, he photographed in and around the wooded north-western corner of the park, where ravines, glades and manmade waterfalls give the impression of a natural wilderness. Often, on his way there and back, he encountered the same people, locals mainly, for whom the park was a place to escape the constrictions of the Covid pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean O’Hagan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: 606; Mitchell on Meetings; Instant Genius; Conflict of Interest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/26/606-5-live-review-mitchell-on-meetings-instant-genius-conflict-of-interest-iwm-syria-carey-mulligan-waad-al-kateab</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/26/606-5-live-review-mitchell-on-meetings-instant-genius-conflict-of-interest-iwm-syria-carey-mulligan-waad-al-kateab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The moaniest of football phone-in shows doesn’t disappoint; David Mitchell rails to perfection; and Carey Mulligan hears first-hand about the war in Syria
606 (BBC 5 live) | BBC Sounds
Mitchell on Meetings (BBC Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The mystery of the Georgian papier-mache horse – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/26/the-mystery-of-the-georgian-papier-mache-horse-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/26/the-mystery-of-the-georgian-papier-mache-horse-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T16:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vija Skangale, a curator, grew up in Tbilisi, Georgia, in the 1980s, and now lives in London. One day, looking through childhood photos, she found an image of her four-year-old self atop a papier-mache horse at the local zoo. “All my Tbilisi friends have a similar photo,” she says, “but I knew nothing about the photographer.” So she posted on social media and was overwhelmed by the response. “People shared their own pictures and I connected with the photographer’s grandson.” She discovered that the pictures, roughly dating from 1960 to 2013, were taken by local photographer Victor Sukiasov, who had destroyed his archive before he died. This haunted Skangale: “I decided to honour his legacy, even though he didn’t think what he did was meaningful.” She set up a digital archive so that anyone can upload their own Sukiasov portrait with his prop horse. “Thousands have sat for him and will have memories triggered by looking at his work. I think collective memory is important.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Democrats cite Ku Klux Klan Act in suits over ‘Trump Train’ Texas bus incident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/trump-train-texas-bus-lawsuit-kkk-act-democrats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/26/trump-train-texas-bus-lawsuit-kkk-act-democrats"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:40:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawsuits claim Trump supporters conspired to intimidate and harass Biden-Harris campaigners
A convoy of Trump supporters that swarmed a Biden-Harris campaign bus on a Texas highway last October violated the Ku Klux Klan Act of 1871, which prohibits violent election intimidation, two new lawsuits allege.
 Related: Donald Trump returns to campaign trail with rally targeting Ohio Republican 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Bekiempis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds of thousands of EU citizens ‘scrabbling’ to attain post-Brexit status before deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/hundreds-of-thousands-of-eu-citizens-scrabbling-to-attain-post-brexit-status-before-deadline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/hundreds-of-thousands-of-eu-citizens-scrabbling-to-attain-post-brexit-status-before-deadline"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:39:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure grows for UK to extend Wednesday’s settlement-scheme cut-off date as backlog of applications grows and helplines crash
EU citizens are struggling to apply for post-Brexit settled status as the Home Office reaches “breaking point” coping with a last-minute surge in applications.
With three days before the deadline of the EU settlement scheme this Wednesday, campaigners say late applicants are being stuck in online queues as others find it impossible to access advice on the government helpline.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Townsend</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tour de France: Julian Alaphilippe takes opening stage marred by big crashes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/tour-de-france-stage-one-report-julian-alaphilippe-chris-froome</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/26/tour-de-france-stage-one-report-julian-alaphilippe-chris-froome"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:22:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French rider wins and takes yellow jersey in Landerneau
Chris Froome among riders hurt in crash 8km from line

In a chaotic and bloody finish to stage one of the Tour de France, Julian Alaphilippe of France took the yellow jersey, as the four-times champion Chris Froome struggled to get back on to his bike after being caught in a high-speed crash, shortly before the final climb to the Côte de la Fosse aux Loups.
Alaphilippe’s searing acceleration shredded a front group still recovering from the aftermath of two crashes. Despite being among the fallers in the first crash, the world road champion opened a significant gap on his rivals and held on to his advantage to seal both the stage win and the overall lead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Whittle in Landerneau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Mr Westwood: Vivienne is ‘eccentric, serious and genuine’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/26/being-mr-westwood-vivienne-is-eccentric-serious-and-genuine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/26/being-mr-westwood-vivienne-is-eccentric-serious-and-genuine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:05:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though 25 years apart in age, their ideas are locked in sync. Andreas Kronthaler, husband of the couture queen, reveals his plans for the maverick fashion house
On 21 March 2020, days before Britain’s initial lockdown, Vivienne Westwood shared her first isolation address to the nation. Royalty, of sorts, she delivered it in her trademark fashion: she spoke of saving the planet and her new manifesto, while donning couture – and surrounded by curiosities – in her south London home.
These impassioned speeches became a year-long weekly occurrence. Westwood offered anti-racism, anti-capitalism, and a stern rebuke of the arms trade; in wig, blue dress and floral-print platforms, she spoke of the need to rescue the oceans, while standing in her tiled bathtub.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Segalov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call of the coast: an Australian stylist’s California dream home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/call-of-the-coast-an-australian-stylists-california-dream-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/call-of-the-coast-an-australian-stylists-california-dream-home"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years in New York, a move to Laguna Beach for a nature-lover was like coming home
Marcus Hay still clearly recalls the moment he decided to move to Laguna Beach in California. He was having lunch with his partner in a restaurant overlooking the ocean. “Everybody looked so happy and the sun was shining,” he says. “We were in our black clothes from New York and stood out like sore thumbs. But we said to ourselves: ‘This could be our future.’ After being in Manhattan for 13 years, I was ready for a sea change.”
For the Australian stylist, whose clients include American homeware brands such as CB2, West Elm and Williams Sonoma, it was also something of a throwback to his childhood. “When I grew up in Sydney, I lived right on the beach,” he says. “I used to spend a lot of my childhood fascinated with rock pools.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Executive pay: big names that fell foul of shareholders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/executive-pay-big-names-that-fell-foul-of-shareholders</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/executive-pay-big-names-that-fell-foul-of-shareholders"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From supermarket group Morrisons to mining giant Rio Tinto, investors have voted against boardroom payouts in the pandemic
The personal and financial sacrifices of many during the pandemic have cast a harsh light on executive pay excesses. Shareholders have delivered stinging rebukes to some of the UK’s best-known companies for failing to match the national mood.
The High Pay Centre, a campaign group, thinks big pay packets in the time of coronavirus could result in political pressure to give worker representatives a say on bosses’ pay.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green groups’ fury at loophole in new North Sea oil test]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/green-groups-fury-at-loophole-in-new-north-sea-oil-test</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/green-groups-fury-at-loophole-in-new-north-sea-oil-test"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Projects that could produce more than 1.7bn barrels will not have to go through the government’s ‘checkpoint’, data reveals
Prospective oil projects in the North Sea with the capacity to produce more than a billion barrels will avoid a new test designed to assess their impact on the climate crisis, the Observer has learned.
In a development that has angered environmental campaigners, it has emerged that proposed new developments representing some 1.7bn barrels of oil will not have to undergo the forthcoming “climate compatibility checkpoint”, designed to determine whether they are consistent with the government’s climate commitments.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Church of England should recognise same-sex weddings, says bishop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/church-of-england-should-recognise-same-sex-marriage-says-bishop</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/church-of-england-should-recognise-same-sex-marriage-says-bishop"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Bayes, bishop of Liverpool, pushes for ‘gender-neutral marriage canon’ and church ceremonies
A senior bishop has said the Church of England should recognise marriage between people of the same sex and allow such ceremonies in church, a move that would break with centuries of Christian teaching.
Paul Bayes, the bishop of Liverpool, called for a “gender-neutral marriage canon” in a controversial and hard-hitting speech on Saturday, making him the most senior figure in the C of E to explicitly back a change in church law and teaching.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On my radar: Simon Russell Beale’s cultural highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/26/on-my-radar-simon-russell-beale-cultural-highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/26/on-my-radar-simon-russell-beale-cultural-highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor on a lockdown-saving classical podcast, the power of William Blake, and the book that got him back into cooking
The actor Simon Russell Beale was born in Penang, Malaysia, in 1961 and studied English at Cambridge University. He began his career with the Royal Shakespeare Company; since then his extensive theatre roles have won him three Laurence Olivier awards and a Tony for Tom Stoppard’s Jumpers on Broadway in 2004. His film work includes Orlando, The Deep Blue Sea and The Death of Stalin, for which he received a British Independent Film award for best supporting actor. He is playing Johann Sebastian Bach in Nicholas Hytner’s production of Nina Raine’s Bach & Sons at the Bridge theatre, London, until 11 September.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘People aren’t looking for just a model’: meet the amazing Ryan Zaman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/26/people-arent-looking-for-just-a-model-meet-the-amazing-ryan-zaman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/26/people-arent-looking-for-just-a-model-meet-the-amazing-ryan-zaman"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When he caught the eye of the fashion world, he couldn’t believe his luck. Now Ryan Zaman is modelling alongside Kate Moss – and promoting the rights of disabled people
When he was five years old, Ryan Zaman walked in a fashion show at his primary school. The catwalk was made from gym mats laid out in a T, and the front row was populated not by Wintours and Kardashians but by rapt parents on tiny chairs. Zaman’s mum shot a video and it should be issued with an “extreme cuteness” advisory. At the end, a teacher with a microphone buttonholes Zaman and asks, “Are you famous?”
“Yeah,” he replies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Lewis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rob Delaney is going to prove that love is all about animal attraction | Rebecca Nicholson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/rob-delaney-is-going-to-prove-love-is-all-about-animal-attraction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/rob-delaney-is-going-to-prove-love-is-all-about-animal-attraction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The comedian is hosting a TV show where contestants go on blind dates while dressed as sharks and pandas
The TV dating show exists in a cultural landscape that encourages love-seeking participants to get married to each other without ever having met, to see if that works out, to get married having spoken to each other only through frosted glass, to see if that works out, to spend a long hot summer in a house full of attractive young people while being literally paid to resist having sex, to see if that works out, and to go on a date having seen the person only in the buff, from the genitals up, before ever having heard a word they have to say. You know, to see if that works out.
Now, joining these innovations, is Sexy Beasts. The very funny Rob Delaney has signed on to narrate not one but two seasons of this new Netflix dating show that has cocked an eye at love and thought, hmm, what love needs is to take a few lessons from The Masked Singer. “Take it off! Take it off!” would have a different meaning here.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[School meals at risk due to shortage of UK lorry drivers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/school-meals-at-risk-due-to-shortage-of-uk-lorry-drivers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/school-meals-at-risk-due-to-shortage-of-uk-lorry-drivers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T13:05:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loss of 100,000 hauliers as a result of Covid and Brexit could leave cooks relying on emergency standby ingredients
School meals could be disrupted for the remainder of this term by delays and shortages of food supplies across the country as a result of a dearth of lorry drivers in the UK.
The warning came as industry representatives told Boris Johnson that the driver shortage – exacerbated by Brexit and the pandemic – was causing a “crisis” in the food supply chain.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carlo Rovelli: ‘My work in physics is endlessly creative’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/this-much-i-know-carlo-rovelli-my-work-in-physics-is-endlessly-creative</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/this-much-i-know-carlo-rovelli-my-work-in-physics-is-endlessly-creative"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T13:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The scientist, 65, talks about quantum gravity, LSD, free love, escaping a bear and his lifetime in radical politics
Verona was a beautiful place to grow up, but the town was close-minded and provincial. Dad, a gentle and hard-working man, ran a business. Mum was intelligent and bored – a lethal combination. They encouraged my independence from a young age, which I took too far. At 14, I ran away from home and headed to France, to find like-minded, free-thinking young people.
I took my first acid in Paris aged 16, then hitchhiked across Europe. One night I slept in a small boat I found moored by a pier on the Danube. Lying down to rest underneath the immense, starry sky was the first time I felt true happiness.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Segalov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why pick a holiday in Gibraltar? ‘We couldn’t go anywhere else’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/why-pick-a-holiday-in-gibraltar-we-couldnt-go-anywhere-else</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/why-pick-a-holiday-in-gibraltar-we-couldnt-go-anywhere-else"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T13:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prized green-list status attracts younger British tourists to the Rock for the first time as vacation choices remain slim
If the residents of Apes’ Den are pleased to see a larger than usual number of Britons snapping them, cooing over them or, indeed, edging gingerly away from them, they give little indication of it.
It is not much of a stretch to suggest that the social, political and economic ramifications of the current pandemic have been wholly lost on the crag-haunting, tourist-attracting Barbary macaques as they lounge around their lair high above the busy streets and marinas of Gibraltar.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Gibraltar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Jeffrey Donaldson endorsed to lead DUP after majority vote]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/sir-jeffrey-donaldson-endorsed-to-lead-dup</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/26/sir-jeffrey-donaldson-endorsed-to-lead-dup"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T12:44:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lagan Valley MP to take over after resignation of Edwin Poots and vows to ‘right the wrong’ of NI protocol
Sir Jeffrey Donaldson has been formally endorsed as the new leader of the Democratic Unionist party (DUP), vowing to “right the wrong” of the Northern Ireland protocol. 
The Lagan Valley MP was the only person to put their name forward after successive revolts among party members deposed both Edwin Poots, who lasted 21 days in post, and his predecessor, Arlene Foster.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[12 arrested in raids on Extinction Rebellion sites in London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/26/12-arrested-raids-extinction-rebellion-london-protest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/26/12-arrested-raids-extinction-rebellion-london-protest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T11:41:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police seize equipment from three premises before what officers expect will be busy weekend of protests
Police in London have raided a warehouse used by Extinction Rebellion, as well as an arts centre that was exhibiting some of the structures used in the demonstrations that blockaded newspaper printing plants last year.
The Met is under increased scrutiny as the group plans further protests against the owners of the UK’s press outlets this weekend, alongside supporters of the Black Lives Matter campaign against racial injustice.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can the British countryside cope this summer?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/can-the-british-countryside-cope-this-summer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/can-the-british-countryside-cope-this-summer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T11:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the first lockdown, farmer James Rebanks was astonished by a visitor-free Lake District. Ahead of a super-season of domestic tourism, he wonders if there’s a better way
Last March, I stood in the middle of the A66 between Penrith and Keswick and gawped at what had become a ghost road. It is one of the main routes in and out of the Lake District, where I’ve lived all my life, and usually roars with traffic. But there wasn’t a vehicle for miles. I just stared, stunned by the silence. The sun was shining in a deep-blue sky, the birds were singing, but it felt apocalyptic, as if I were the only person left in the world.
In those first weeks of lockdown, the whole landscape came to seem radically different. The shores of the lakes were abandoned, even on sunny days; the car parks were empty; the footpaths and fells silent. It felt wrong to enjoy this time that was terrible for so many people, but, in truth, many of us did. The 19 million visitors a year to the Lakes are an accepted fact of our day-to-day lives, and I never imagined they would not be here. Now I could see what it might be like to live without them all around us, something perhaps a lot of rural people had long wanted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Rebanks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Zinovieff, British composer and synth pioneer, dies aged 88]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/26/peter-zinovieff-british-composer-and-synth-pioneer-dies-aged-88</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/26/peter-zinovieff-british-composer-and-synth-pioneer-dies-aged-88"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T11:13:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Beatles, Pink Floyd and Kraftwerk all used Zinovieff’s EMS synthesisers 
Peter Zinovieff, a hugely influential figure in British music whose early synthesisers helped to change the sound of pop, has died aged 88. He had suffered a fall at home earlier this month.
With its marketing slogan “think of a sound – now make it”, his company Electronic Music Studios (EMS) was one of the first to bring synthesisers out of studios and to the public. With products such as the portable VCS3 and Synthi A, EMS customers – including David Bowie, Kraftwerk, the Who, Tangerine Dream and Pink Floyd – were often taught to use the instruments by Zinovieff. Paul McCartney was a visitor to his studio, and Zinovieff also taught Ringo Starr to use the VCS3.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The service is appalling’: drivers face holdups as DVLA fails to send licences]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/26/uk-drivers-dvla-licences-delays</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/26/uk-drivers-dvla-licences-delays"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T11:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers say their lives have been put on hold because of delays at the government agency
Diane Black-Ware is getting desperate. She was due to receive her new driving licence in January, and its non-arrival has left her spending £50 a day on taxis to get to her job in a rural caravan park. Since the start of the year, her taxed and insured car has been left unused at her Penrith home.
“If DVLA doesn’t send me my licence soon I’m going to have to give up my job as I can’t go on like this,” she says. “I’m so desperate that I called them 97 times in a single day last week and was still unable to get through. It is inexcusable how DVLA are treating people.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miles Brignall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helicopter carrying Colombian president and senior officials hit by gunfire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/helicopter-carrying-colombian-president-and-senior-officials-hit-by-gunfire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/helicopter-carrying-colombian-president-and-senior-officials-hit-by-gunfire"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T10:53:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iván Duque says ‘cowardly’ attack will not stop him tackling drug trafficking, terrorism and organised crime
Colombia’s president, Iván Duque, said a helicopter carrying him and several senior officials came under fire in the southern Catatumbo region bordering Venezuela, in a rare instance of a direct attack on a presidential aircraft.
Duque said everyone on board the helicopter was safe, including the defense minister, Diego Molano; the interior minister, Daniel Palacios and the governor of Norte de Santander state, Silvano Serrano. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘At first I thought, this is crazy’: the real-life plan to use novels to predict the next war]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/project-cassandra-plan-to-use-novels-to-predict-next-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/project-cassandra-plan-to-use-novels-to-predict-next-war"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T10:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three years ago, a small group of academics at a German university launched an unprecedented collaboration with the military – using novels to try to pinpoint the world’s next conflicts. Are they on to something?
As the car with the blacked-out windows came to a halt in a sidestreet near Tübingen’s botanical gardens, keen-eyed passersby may have noticed something unusual about its numberplate. In Germany, the first few letters usually denote the municipality where a vehicle is registered. The letter Y, however, is reserved for members of the armed forces.
Military men are a rare, not to say unwelcome, sight in Tübingen. A picturesque 15th-century university town that brought forth great German minds including the philosopher Hegel and the poet Friedrich Hölderlin, it is also a modern stronghold of the German Green party, thanks to its left-leaning academic population. In 2018, there was growing resistance on campus against plans to establish Europe’s leading artificial intelligence research hub in the surrounding area: the involvement of arms manufacturers in Tübingen’s “cyber valley”, argued students who occupied a lecture hall that year, brought shame to the university’s intellectual tradition.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teenager stabbed to death in Sydenham, south-east London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/teenager-stabbed-death-sydenham-south-london-murder</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/teenager-stabbed-death-sydenham-south-london-murder"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T09:44:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mother of 19-year-old victim visits scene as murder inquiry gets under way into killing on Friday evening
Police have launched a murder investigation after a teenager was stabbed to death in south-east London.
Officers were called to a street in Sydenham at 9.30pm on Friday but the 19-year-old man died at the scene.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I burst into tears. Then went back to my desk’: when dream jobs become nightmares]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/26/burst-into-tears-then-went-back-to-desk-dream-jobs-nightmare</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/26/burst-into-tears-then-went-back-to-desk-dream-jobs-nightmare"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T09:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creative industries are notorious for toxic workplaces run by ‘talented genius’ bosses. Will anything change when we return to the office? 
I was on the receiving end of more than a few tantrums during the five years I worked in advertising, but by far the most memorable was the day a senior creative executive threw a book across the room in the middle of one of his regular tirades.
I was an account manager in my early 20s, working at a leading ad agency. My colleague levelled a stream of expletives at me, tossed the book and stormed out, curious heads popping out of other offices to gawp at my misfortune as he continued to rant.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Otegha Uwagba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[People have told me I’m on the wrong side of history, but I still want to be their friend | Hadley Freeman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/people-have-told-me-i-am-on-the-wrong-side-of-history-but-i-still-want-to-be-their-friend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/people-have-told-me-i-am-on-the-wrong-side-of-history-but-i-still-want-to-be-their-friend"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T08:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t drop people I disagree with from my life – but for many liberals, differences of opinion have become unacceptable
It’s rare to see a woman really let her anger glitter, unhindered by any fear of accusations of hysteria or worse, so what a blast of delicious fire Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie has given us. Her essay It Is Obscene, published online last week, is ostensibly about two former students of hers who denounced her on social media after she gave an interview to Channel 4 in 2017 in which, when asked if she thought trans women were women, Adichie made the tautological but now highly controversial reply, “Trans women are trans women.” Instead of just calling her, one of Adichie’s students “went on social media to put on a public performance,” she wrote. The other tweeted that people should “pick up machetes to protect us from transphobes like Adichie”, and still assumed Adichie would endorse her book.
Really, the essay is about a strong current in modern culture. “There are many social media-savvy people who are choking on sanctimony and lacking in compassion... People who demand that you denounce your friends for flimsy reasons in order to remain a member of the chosen puritan class,” Adichie writes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadley Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stories to save the world: the new wave of climate fiction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/stories-to-save-the-world-the-new-wave-of-climate-fiction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/26/stories-to-save-the-world-the-new-wave-of-climate-fiction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T08:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now more than ever, novelists are facing up to the unthinkable: the climate crisis. Claire Armitstead talks to Margaret Atwood, Amitav Ghosh and more about the new cli-fi
In September 2017, David Simon, creator of The Wire, tweeted a photograph of golfers calmly lining up their putts on an Oregon course as wildfires raged in the background. “In the pantheon of visual metaphors for America today, this is the money shot,” he wrote of the picture, which was taken by an amateur photographer who spotted the photo-op as she was about to skydive out of a plane. Everything about this story – the image, the circumstances – seems stranger than fiction.
A year before Simon’s tweet, in a landmark polemic, The Great Derangement: Climate Change and the Unthinkable, Indian novelist Amitav Ghosh had questioned why so few writers – himself included – were tackling the world’s most pressing issue in their fiction. But now, as extreme weather swirls around the globe, melting glaciers, burning forests, flooding districts and annihilating species, the climate emergency has brought the unimaginable into our daily lives and literature. A survivor in Jessie Greengrass’s haunting new novel The High House sums it up: “The whole complicated system of modernity which had held us up, away from the earth, was crumbling … and we were becoming again what we had used to be: cold, and frightened of the weather, and frightened of the dark. Somehow while we had all been busy, while we had been doing those small things which added up to living, the future had slipped into the present.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Armitstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic was meant to change work, but what have we got so far? Free pizza | Josie Cox]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/pandemic-change-work-free-pizza-corporate-perks-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/pandemic-change-work-free-pizza-corporate-perks-office"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T08:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The corporate world is turning to novelty perks to get us back to the office in an attempt to postpone the moment of reckoning
Earlier this month in lower Manhattan’s financial district, food carts lined what is otherwise a usually sterile stretch of pavement. Vendors doled out free burritos and ice cream to the mingling sun-kissed bankers – folks who had begrudgingly traipsed back to their physical desks after a year of remote working, following the stern orders of moneyed overlords.
Free lunch is entry-level when it comes to corporate perks, a trusted staple many businesses have fallen back on as a means of convincing workers to resume their pre-pandemic working habits and arduous commutes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josie Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I had threats to my life’: how mob attacks on social media are silencing UK teachers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/i-had-threats-to-my-life-how-mob-attacks-on-social-media-are-silencing-uk-teachers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/26/i-had-threats-to-my-life-how-mob-attacks-on-social-media-are-silencing-uk-teachers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A British offshoot of a Trump-supporting network is among those targeting educators they regard as ‘woke’
When Gemma Parker, a secondary school teacher, tweeted about teaching students about racism earlier this year, she wasn’t prepared for the flood of abuse she unleashed. A rightwing activist group flagged her as a dangerous teacher, and within hours she had been labelled a “Nazi sympathiser” and a “child abuser”, as thousands of people waded in to attack her.
“I was teaching a class and I kept getting calls from friends asking if I was all right. When I finally checked there were thousands of responses.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Fazackerley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I spy: are smart doorbells creating a global surveillance network?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/i-spy-are-smart-doorbells-creating-a-global-surveillance-network</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/i-spy-are-smart-doorbells-creating-a-global-surveillance-network"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They were sold as gadgets that meant you would never miss a delivery. But now doorbell cameras – from Amazon’s Ring to Google’s Nest – are recording our every move
I have got a new doorbell. It’s brilliant. It should be; it cost £89. It’s a Ring video doorbell; you’ll have seen them around. There are others available, made by other companies, with other four-letter names such as Nest and Arlo. When someone rings my doorbell, I’m alerted on my smartphone. I can see who is there, and speak to them.
My phone is ringing! C major first inversion chord, arpeggiated, repeated, for the musically trained – you’ll recognise it if you’ve heard it. It’s a delivery. Amazon, as it happens; Amazon acquired Ring in 2018, reportedly for more than $1bn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Wollaston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grasshopper bred in captivity returns to East Anglia marshes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/26/grasshopper-bred-in-captivity-returns-to-east-anglia-marshes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/26/grasshopper-bred-in-captivity-returns-to-east-anglia-marshes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Citizen zookeepers release endangered large marsh grasshopper in former strongholds
Britain’s largest grasshopper is being bred in captivity by citizen zookeepers and returned to marshes across East Anglia in a move to revive the endangered species.
The large marsh grasshopper, an elusive green insect that can appear in a striking pink-and-yellow form, is too isolated in fragments of wetland to hop back to its former strongholds.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nice recommends mental health support for those badly affected by acne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/26/nice-recommends-mental-health-support-for-those-badly-affected-by-acne</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/26/nice-recommends-mental-health-support-for-those-badly-affected-by-acne"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guidance advises clinicians to consider referrals for those with history of conditions such as severe depression and anxiety
For the first time ever, the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (Nice) has recommended mental health support for people severely affected by their acne.
The final guidance, the first by Nice to address the common skin condition, offers recommendations on therapies such as antibiotics and oral contraceptives (for women) and advises clinicians to consider referrals to mental health services, in particular for those with a history of severe depression or anxiety, body dysmorphic disorder, suicidal ideation and self-harm.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant horses’ heads and 10-metre sculptures: massive art to see right now]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/26/giant-horses-heads-and-10-metre-sculptures-massive-art-to-see-right-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/26/giant-horses-heads-and-10-metre-sculptures-massive-art-to-see-right-now"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a year of squinting at art in books, online or as NFTs, it’s now time to immerse yourself in the UK’s most colossal artworks

Modern Toss on Big Art

One aspect of art you really cannot get at home – not by looking at it online or even in the most XXL of art books, and especially not with the screenlocked world of non-fungible token artworks – is the sheer, sensual thrill of bigness. It is time to think big, see big and feel big.
 Related: The Guide: Staying In – sign up for our home entertainment tips 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recipe for inflation: how Brexit and Covid made tinned tomatoes a lot dearer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/recipe-for-inflation-how-brexit-and-covid-made-tinned-tomatoes-a-lot-dearer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/26/recipe-for-inflation-how-brexit-and-covid-made-tinned-tomatoes-a-lot-dearer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Combine the pandemic with rising raw material costs, stir in a labour shortage, a twist of Brexit, add a pinch of poor weather and voila …
Tinned tomatoes are a taken-for-granted store cupboard staple, relied upon by Britons to whip up home cooked favourites such as spaghetti bolognese. But the price could soon make you take notice, amid warnings of higher shopping bills, set against a backdrop of soaring global food prices.
From the packaging to the transportation and the energy used in manufacturing, nearly all aspects of the production of this popular ingredient now cost more. The crushed tomatoes alone are 30% dearer than a year ago, at €0.48 per kilo. The same pressures are driving the prices of many foods higher, meaning Britons will probably face bigger bills for groceries or meals out this autumn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire at martial arts school in China kills 18 children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/fire-at-marital-arts-school-in-china-kills-18-boarding-students</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/fire-at-marital-arts-school-in-china-kills-18-boarding-students"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T06:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local media say victims of the fire in central China were boarding pupils aged between seven and 16
At least 18 people have been killed and 16 injured after a fire broke out at a martial arts school in central China, according to the local government.
Official state news agency Xinhua reported that all victims were boarding pupils, while local media said they were aged between seven and 16.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Oxford vaccine: the trials and tribulations of a world-saving jab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/the-oxford-vaccine-the-trials-and-tribulations-of-a-world-saving-jab</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/the-oxford-vaccine-the-trials-and-tribulations-of-a-world-saving-jab"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T06:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amid bemusement from scientists at the deluge of often undeserved criticism, the Guardian pieces together the story behind the vaccine’s successes and failures

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

In January 2020, when most of the world slept soundly in ignorance of the pandemic coming its way, a group of scientists at Oxford University got to work on a vaccine to save the planet. They wanted it to be highly effective, cheap, and easy to use in even the poorest countries.
Prof Sarah Gilbert, Prof Andrew Pollard and others pulled it off. With speed crucial, they designed it and launched into trials before bringing in a business partner. The giant Anglo-Swedish pharmaceutical company AstraZeneca would manufacture it, license it around the world – and not make a profit until the pandemic was over.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley Health editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Actor Rafe Spall talks about his weight struggles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/26/actor-rafe-spall-talks-about-his-weight-struggles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/26/actor-rafe-spall-talks-about-his-weight-struggles"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T06:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor addresses pressures facing men and women in entertainment industry in Guardian podcast
The actor Rafe Spall has spoken candidly about his struggles with his weight throughout his acting career, and the pressures of losing weight to look like a “normal guy”.
Speaking on an upcoming episode of the Guardian podcast Comfort Eating with Grace Dent, the actor, who has appeared in films including Men in Black: International and Just Mercy, spoke about a recent “big-profile” job he did for television where his weight became a concern for production staff.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US and France warn Iran time is running out to return to nuclear deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/us-and-france-warn-iran-time-is-running-out-to-return-to-nuclear-deal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/us-and-france-warn-iran-time-is-running-out-to-return-to-nuclear-deal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T03:27:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On a visit to Paris, US secretary of state Antony Blinken says deal is at risk if Tehran fails to make concessions
The United States and France have warned Iran that time is running out to return to a nuclear deal, voicing fear that Tehran’s sensitive development program could advance if talks drag on.
On the first high-level visit to Paris by president Joe Biden’s administration, secretary of state Antony Blinken and his French hosts saluted a new spirit of cooperation after four years of turbulence under Donald Trump.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Car bomb injures 13 UN peacekeepers in Mali]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/car-bomb-injures-13-un-peacekeepers-in-mali</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/26/car-bomb-injures-13-un-peacekeepers-in-mali"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T01:31:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attack occurs in Gao region where insurgents linked to al-Qaida and Islamic State are active
Thirteen UN peacekeepers have been wounded in northern Mali by a car bomb, the UN mission said, while Mali’s army said six of its soldiers were killed in a separate attack in the centre of the country.
The attack on Friday in the north targeted a temporary base set up by the peacekeepers near the village of Ichagara in the Gao region, where Islamist insurgents linked to al-Qaida and Islamic State are active.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suspected tornado damages homes in east London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/suspected-tornado-damages-homes-in-east-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/26/suspected-tornado-damages-homes-in-east-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T23:39:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Garden walls torn down and dustbins sent flying hundreds of metres through the air, but no injuries reported


A suspected tornado has damaged homes, torn down garden walls and sent dustbins flying hundreds of metres through the air in east London.
Footage posted on social media showed havoc caused by strong winds, which left tiles strewn around roads in and around Hulse Avenue, about half a mile from Barking tube station.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Derek Chauvin sentenced to 22.5 years in prison for murder of George Floyd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/25/derek-chauvin-george-floyd-murder-sentencing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/25/derek-chauvin-george-floyd-murder-sentencing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T21:10:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four members of the Floyd family, including his seven-year-old daughter Gianna, gave statements before the sentencing
Derek Chauvin, the former Minneapolis police officer who murdered George Floyd, has been sentenced to 22 years and six months for second-degree murder, closing one chapter of a case that thrust the issue of race and American policing back into the global spotlight.
 Related: Protests erupt in Minneapolis over man fatally shot by deputies 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frenchwoman guilty of murdering stepfather after years of abuse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/woman-who-killed-stepfather-after-years-of-abuse-in-france-found-guilty</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/woman-who-killed-stepfather-after-years-of-abuse-in-france-found-guilty"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T19:29:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valérie Bacot, raped aged 12 by Daniel Polette who later became her husband, is spared  more time in jail
A French woman who killed her stepfather, who raped her at the age of 12 and later became her husband, has been convicted of premeditated murder but spared any more time in prison.
Valérie Bacot was subject to more than 20 years of violence at the hands of Daniel Polette, with whom she had four children. The court heard she shot and killed him after he began prostituting her to strangers, fearing that he was about to begin abusing their teenage daughter.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/twenty-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/twenty-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:55:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protests in the West Bank, summer solstice at Stonehenge, Juneteenth in Galveston and the election in Ethiopia: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Property Brain Twisters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342718</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-property-brain-twisters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:39:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am part of that 82% that got the answer to Lea Verou's quiz wrong. Stephen Shaw posted a similar quiz as well and it's a fun exercise sharpen your CSS chops.
The post Custom Property Brain Twisters appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on work-life balance: a step in the right direction | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/25/the-guardian-view-on-work-life-balance-a-step-in-the-right-direction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/25/the-guardian-view-on-work-life-balance-a-step-in-the-right-direction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:39:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Selectively muting phone messages will help draw necessary boundaries between work and home 
“A man perfects himself by working,” wrote Thomas Carlyle in 1843, and though we might rightly have jettisoned other views he held (history as a parade of great men, for instance), we have not only taken this to heart, but expanded work’s dominion. “Work,” wrote Joanna Biggs in All Day Long: A Portrait of Britain at Work, is too often “how we give our lives meaning when religion, party politics and community fall away”.
At the same time, we are increasingly aware that work cannot be everything. The phrase “work-life balance” is problematic, not least because it assumes life only happens when work stops, but its ubiquity nevertheless draws attention to its frequent absence. The pandemic has exacerbated the trend: if you didn’t lose your job, you were quite likely to be working all hours instead. Goldman Sachs juniors rebelling against 18-hour shifts, and MPs warning this month that burnout in the NHS has reached dangerous levels, are only the most obvious outbreaks of a lurking malaise. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘They’re all lawyers’: Labour voters look elsewhere in Batley byelection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/25/theyre-all-lawyers-labour-voters-look-elsewhere-in-batley-byelection</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/25/theyre-all-lawyers-labour-voters-look-elsewhere-in-batley-byelection"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:06:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some blame local problems on Labour-led council and say party does not represent working class
“My brother was a miner, my dad was a builder, my mam was a barmaid who worked in mills, I was a nurse – you’re not going to vote anybody but Labour, are you?”
Cheryl Rowan, 62, is just the type of voter that the Labour party is desperately trying to hold on to in next week’s byelection in Batley and Spen, and in their former northern heartlands more generally. She lives in one of a small row of council houses in Heckmondwike, a town formerly known for manufacturing blankets as part of West Yorkshire’s heavy woollen district. That industry is long gone.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The grotesque subsidies given to second home owners | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/25/the-grotesque-subsidies-given-to-second-home-owners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/25/the-grotesque-subsidies-given-to-second-home-owners"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T15:58:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to an article by George Monbiot and a recent letter and editorial on housing inequality
George Monbiot is absolutely right (Second homes are a gross injustice, yet the UK government encourages them, 23 June). A housing crisis that has been brewing for decades has been hugely exacerbated in tourist areas by the likes of Airbnb, and further compounded by the ludicrous subsidies, incentives and tax breaks made available to second home owners by successive governments. Owners of two (or more) properties are clearly in a relatively comfortable financial position; there can be no justification – financial or moral – for the grotesque package of government handouts and subsidies outlined by Monbiot.
It has taken years of health warnings and significant tax rises to bring about a significant drop in the number of cigarette smokers. As a first step, rather like the health warnings on a packet of cigarettes, every document/brochure relating to the sale/purchase of a second home should, alongside the usual aspirational guff, be required to carry a prominent strapline quoting Monbiot: “a luxury that deprives other people of a necessity”.
Phil Murray
Linlithgow, West Lothian
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joni Mitchell kept me going through lion country | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/joni-mitchell-kept-me-going-through-lion-country</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/joni-mitchell-kept-me-going-through-lion-country"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T15:50:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ruth Borthwick on how singing songs from Ladies of the Canyon and Blue sustained her courage on a dangerous trip
Singing songs by Joni Mitchell, whose album Blue turned 50 this week (Joni Mitchell’s Blue: my favourite song – by James Taylor, Carole King, Graham Nash, David Crosby and more, 22 June), kept me going as I trekked through lion country in Uganda in 1981. As a solo traveller, I had been frustrated by my attempts to visit safari parks in Kenya – no pedestrians allowed. But people told me about Chobe, a reserve on the Nile in Uganda; once fashionable with chic Europeans, it was now down on its luck after Idi Amin’s disastrous regime. After hitching through dusty and dangerous country, I reached the derelict gates to find that there was no transport and I would have to walk the five miles through the bush to get to the lodge and a bed for the night.
I summoned up my courage and prayed a that lion wouldn’t consider me tasty as I warbled my way through Ladies of the Canyon and Blue. The horizon eventually filled with the sea that was the Nile, half-submerged hippos glistening in the shallows. This was one river I didn’t wish to skate away on.
Ruth Borthwick
Prestwood, Buckinghamshire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anywhere but Westminster: 10 years in 10 minutes – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a decade of reports from all over the UK, the Guardian's flagship video series has won this year's Orwell prize for political journalism. Here, John Harris and John Domokos collect the highlights of their journey and ask viewers a simple question: where should they go next?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris and Noah Payne-Frank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cancel Pending API Requests to Show Correct Data]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342911</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-cancel-pending-api-requests-to-show-correct-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently had to create a widget in React that fetches data from multiple API endpoints. As the user clicks around, new data is fetched and marshalled into the UI. But it caused some problems.
One problem quickly became evident: …
The post How to Cancel Pending API Requests to Show Correct Data appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Georgi Nikoloff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The pressure is unbearable’: final days of Hong Kong’s Apple Daily]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/final-days-hong-kong-apple-daily-pressure-unbearable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/final-days-hong-kong-apple-daily-pressure-unbearable"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:21:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newspaper’s closure shows how pro-democracy movement and press freedom are being crushed
On Wednesday morning, the Apple Daily reporter Angel Kwan was at a government press conference for the Hong Kong census when her phone started buzzing with notifications. Six days earlier, hundreds of police had raided her workplace, arrested her bosses and seized dozens of computers. On Monday, the company board had said it would have to shut the paper unless authorities unfroze its finances.
As she stood holding her microphone towards the government official, Kwan did not dare look at her phone and the news it heralded: Apple Daily was shutting down. Today.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating A Multi-Author Blog With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains how we can connect different types of content in a Next.js application. With this technique, we can add any kind of one-to-one, one-to-many, or even many-to-many relationship to our projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Dom Habersack)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in wildlife – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/jun/25/the-week-in-wildlife-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/jun/25/the-week-in-wildlife-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T11:00:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best of this week’s wildlife pictures, including a newborn fallow deer fawn and an elephant in the room
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Compiled by Joanna Ruck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your area’s exciting green projects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/tell-us-about-your-areas-exciting-green-projects</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/tell-us-about-your-areas-exciting-green-projects"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:40:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear about interesting green initiatives of all shapes and sizes around the country
Does your city, town or village have exciting environmental plans that are aimed at creating jobs and improving lives? Perhaps you already have flourishing green initiatives? Should we be jumping on a train/bicycle to come and see them? 
There has been lots of talk about a green recovery – but what does it actually look like? What are communities already doing to boost their own local green economy, and to create sustainable jobs? We would like to find out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Run A UX Audit For A Major EdTech Platform (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article is a case study of how a UX audit affects a UI. It explains how a famous educational platform can be analyzed edX against Jakob Nielsen’s usability guidelines. To get started, Mark Lankmiller shares all of the criteria and metrics he used for his UX audit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mark Lankmilier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In strictness and in health: the new Covid rules for weddings and wakes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/all-in-all-together/2021/jun/25/in-strictness-and-in-health-the-new-covid-rules-for-weddings-and-wakes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/all-in-all-together/2021/jun/25/in-strictness-and-in-health-the-new-covid-rules-for-weddings-and-wakes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T09:32:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For many of life’s major celebrations and ceremonies, Covid restrictions were relaxed on 21 June in England. From the first dance to saying goodbye to loved ones, what do the new rules mean for you?
There’s no denying that weddings are joyful, but they also come freighted with a list of unwritten rules, which guests should obey but often breach.
Of course, during the pandemic, weddings and other significant life events, from civil partnerships to funerals, baptisms, barmitzvahs and batmitzvahs, have been governed by another, tougher but necessary, set of guidelines: downsized guest numbers, hand sanitisation after exchanging rings, fathers walking their daughters down the aisle 1 metre apart.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Koch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yellowstone: report reveals extent of climate threat to oldest US national park]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/25/yellowstone-national-park-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T08:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say temperatures, already the highest in the past 20,000 years, could increase by up to 10F by 2100
Yellowstone, established in 1872, is famous around the globe for good reason: it’s the oldest national park in the United States and one of the most popular.
But a new report issued this week shows how Yellowstone’s near pristine environment, with attractions like the Old Faithful geyser and herds of bison, is under threat from global heating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharine Gammon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: how are you affected by the recent changes to the UK travel list?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/tell-us-how-are-you-affected-by-the-recent-changes-to-the-uk-travel-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/25/tell-us-how-are-you-affected-by-the-recent-changes-to-the-uk-travel-list"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T08:02:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those living in Malta, Madeira and the Balearic islands, as well as travellers about the changes
The government has announced that Malta, Madeira and the Balearic islands have been added to the UK green travel list meaning that travellers do not need to quarantine when returning from these countries.
At the moment, people who travel to amber list countries have to quarantine on return, however on Tuesday the health secretary said ministers are planning to allow quarantine-free travel to amber-list countries for people in England who have been fully vaccinated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How trans kids' rights are under attack in the US – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T07:39:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the first day of Pride month, the governor of Florida signed a law banning transgender girls from joining girls’ sports teams in schools and colleges. It was just one of 13 anti-trans bills conservative lawmakers in the US passed this year – and one of more than 110 proposed bills, many of which also target access to gender-affirming healthcare. This is by far the largest number filed in a single year in US history.
Guardian LA correspondent, Sam Levin, and Prof Jules Gill-Peterson, a historian and expert on trans kids, examine how this legislative attack has escalated and how the presence of trans kids in America is not a new phenomenon

Mapping the anti-trans laws sweeping America: ‘A war on 100 fronts’

In the US, the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255. In the UK and Ireland, Samaritans can be contacted on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org or jo@samaritans.ie. In Australia, the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami building collapse: rescue operation under way – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/jun/25/miami-building-collapse-rescue-operation-under-way-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/jun/25/miami-building-collapse-rescue-operation-under-way-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T07:38:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dozens still unaccounted for after part of a beachfront condominium block collapses in Surfside

One dead as rescue crews say 99 unaccounted for
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moscow’s record heatwave – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/25/moscows-record-heatwave-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/25/moscows-record-heatwave-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T06:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moscow has been hit by a heatwave this week, with temperatures reaching a 120-year record high due to the effects of the climate emergency, Russia’s weather service has said
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new Brexit crisis for Northern Ireland’s unionists - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/25/the-new-brexit-crisis-for-northern-irelands-unionists-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/25/the-new-brexit-crisis-for-northern-irelands-unionists-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T02:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From a leadership fiasco to the ‘sausage wars’, the Democratic Unionist party’s stance on Brexit has forced it to contend with a new – perhaps even existential – set of problems. What will they mean for the region’s future?
When the Democratic Unionist party decided to support Brexit, many warned that the decision could have profound consequences for Northern Ireland’s position within the UK. Five years on, new customs arrangements and an Irish Sea border mean trade flows with the Republic of Ireland are growing – even as imports from Great Britain are slowing. And some on the unionist side fear that bit by bit, the argument for a united Ireland is gaining ground.
Now the region has found itself in the grip of a so-called ‘sausage war’ over chilled processed meats. At the same time, the DUP is about to install its third leader in a month, a crisis at the top that has exacerbated fears that the party could face electoral annihilation. Anushka Asthana speaks to the Guardian’s Ireland correspondent, Rory Carroll, and the Brexit correspondent, Lisa O’Carroll, about a seismic moment for Northern Ireland – and what a political crisis for Stormont’s leading unionist party could mean for the region’s future.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rory Carroll and Lisa O'Carroll; produced by Courtney Yusufand Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2021 Martin Kantor portrait prize finalists – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/the-2021-martin-kantor-portrait-prize-finalists-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/25/the-2021-martin-kantor-portrait-prize-finalists-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T23:43:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The finalists of the third Martin Kantor portrait prize have been announced. All finalists will be exhibited as part of the 2021 Ballarat International Foto Biennale, showcasing their portraits of culturally significant Australians
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears and her battle for freedom: what we know so far – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears has spoken out publicly for the first time against the controversial legal arrangement that has stripped her of independence for 13 years – and handed control of her estate, career and aspects of her personal life to her father, Jamie Spears, who also at times had authority over her medical and mental health treatment. 

The 39-year-old delivered an emotional speech to a Los Angeles court on Wednesday 23 June, saying she has been forced to work against her will, and that the conservatorship has blocked her from getting married and from having her IUD birth control removed so she could try to have another child. She added: 'I just want my life back.'
Her allegations were detailed and disturbing, and will fuel the growing #FreeBritney movement, as Guardian US correspondent Sam Levin explains.

‘Denied a baby’: key claims from Britney Spears testimony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Common React Mistakes You Might Be Making – And How to Fix Them]]></title>
        <id>60d3ee396e1a1407b6b0b6ef</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/common-react-mistakes-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:01:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's go over the most common mistakes you might be making in your React code right now, plus how to fix them. If you want to create amazing React applications, it's essential to avoid many common errors along the way. In this article, we'll not only cover how to fix]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenTelemetry to Understand Software Performance]]></title>
        <id>60d4b5e96e1a1407b6b0bac4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opentelemetry/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T16:50:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you want good performance in your application, you need to collect data to figure out where to make improvements. That's where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemetry offers a single set of APIs and libraries that standardize how you collect and transfer telemetry data. OpenTelemetry provides a specification for instrumentation so]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chapter 9: Community]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342818</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/chapter-9-community/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April of 2009, Yahoo! shut down GeoCities. Practically overnight, the once beloved service had its signup page replaced with a vague message announcing its closure.
We have decided to discontinue the process of allowing new customers to sign up 
…
The post Chapter 9: Community appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Hoffmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rise Of Design Thinking As A Problem Solving Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the dynamic and unpredictable environments in which we work, even the most carefully crafted solutions can have a short shelf life. When we accept that our work is impermanent and our problem-solving abilities are limited, our goal can shift from delivering full solutions to developing tools that empower our users to adaptively design for themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Josh Singer)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top insurers join Prince Charles to fight climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/top-insurers-join-prince-charles-to-fight-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/24/top-insurers-join-prince-charles-to-fight-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T13:52:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taskforce led by Lloyd’s of London plans to expand coverage of greener projects and help countries facing extreme risk
Chief executives from the UK’s largest insurers have joined forces with the Prince of Wales to launch a sector-wide taskforce aimed at tackling the climate crisis.
The Sustainable Market Initiative Insurance Taskforce – comprising bosses from 17 firms including Legal & General, Allianz, Hiscox and Axa – has pledged to support the transition to a less carbon-intensive economy by expanding insurance coverage for projects such as offshore windfarms, and partnering with governments to provide better disaster protection cover in countries facing serious risks like extreme weather caused by global heating.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How meme stars of the early internet are striking it rich with NFTs - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/24/how-meme-stars-early-internet-striking-it-rich-nfts-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of non-fungible tokens has given rise to massive windfalls for those behind early virals. Sirin Kale and Alex Hern explain all
On 28 May 2016 the photographer Jeff McCurry was taking pictures of a 17-year-old western lowland gorilla called Harambe in Cincinnati zoo when a child entered the enclosure. The zookeepers reacted by shooting the gorilla dead. The child was unhurt. What was a local story suddenly became a global phenomenon due to the combination of social media and McCurry’s picture. Harambe’s image was everywhere. But, despite his photo being shared billions of times, McCurry did not see much of a financial benefit. Now advances in technology have given the world non-fungible tokens (NFTs) – and McCurry has a way of finally cashing in on his famous image.
The Guardian’s technology editor, Alex Hern, tells Rachel Humphreys that this year’s craze for NFTs follows in the wake of speculation on cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin. Now similar technology means unique images, film clips, animations and even poems are being bought and sold online for increasingly large sums.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Alex Hern; produced by Alex Atack, Ned Carter Miles and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Data Analysis? How to Visualize Data with Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib &amp; Seaborn Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>605abca5687d62084bf6b7cd</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/exploratory-data-analysis-with-numpy-pandas-matplotlib-seaborn/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T00:11:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data Analysis is the process of exploring, investigating, and gathering insights from data using statistical measures and visualizations.  The objective of data analysis is to develop an understanding of data by uncovering trends, relationships, and patterns. Data analysis is both a science and an art. On the one hand it]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microservices Architecture – Explained in Plain English]]></title>
        <id>6072ffd4d5756f080ba98b27</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/microservices-architecture-for-humans/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:52:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few years, microservices have gone from an overhyped buzzword to something you should understand as a software engineer.  According to an O'Reilly developer survey in 2020:  61% of companies have been using microservices in the last year29% say at least half of their company systems are built]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343076</id>
        <link href="https://www.bram.us/2021/06/21/tablesng-improvements-to-table-rendering-in-chromium/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T21:37:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I blogged “Making Tables With Sticky Header and Footers Got a Bit Easier” recently, I mentioned that the “stickiness” improvement was just one of the features that got better for <table>s in Chrome as part of the TablesNG upgrade…
The post TablesNG — Improvements to table rendering in Chromium appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342750</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-performant-next-gen-images-in-css-with-image-set/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T19:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS image-set() function has been supported in Chromium-based browsers since 2012 and in Safari since version 6. Support recently landed in Firefox 88. Let’s dive in and see what we can and can’t do today with image-set().…
The post Using Performant Next-Gen Images in CSS with image-set appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create a REST API with .NET 5 and  C#]]></title>
        <id>60d36eb66e1a1407b6b0b16d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-a-rest-api-with-dot-net-5-and-c-sharp/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T18:08:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[.NET is a popular software framework developed by Microsoft. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create a REST API end-to-end from scratch using the latest .NET 5 innovations and Visual Studio Code. The course uses the C# programming language.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create a Great Technical Course]]></title>
        <id>60a406bd906c5207e3a7dfcb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-a-great-technical-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T17:19:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article you will learn how to create a great technical video course. I run the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel where we post technical courses from a variety of contributors. Video courses that follow the guidelines in this article are often a good fit for freeCodeCamp's channel. How to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Weak declaration”]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342669</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/weak-declaration/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:27:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK looks at aspect-ratio, a CSS property for layout that, for the most part, does exactly what you would think it does. It’s getting more interesting as it’s behind a flag in Firefox and Safari now, so we’ll have …
The post “Weak declaration” appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experience of having periods during menopause]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/23/share-your-experience-of-having-periods-during-menopause"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re interested to hear how women going through menopause experience their menstrual cycles and periods
An estimated 13 million women in the UK are living with menopause, with 4.5 million of them making up the fastest-growing demographic in the workplace.
We’d like to hear how women experience their periods leading up to and during this time of hormonal change, and how this might be affecting their lives. How are you coping with period changes at work? How are your home and social lives affected?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Online Workshops (July-October 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frontend and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run [online workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automating Screen Reader Testing On macOS Using Auto VO]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated testing is an important part of any software project, including testing for accessibility. There are already tools for linting and integration testing accessibility, but what about end-to-end testing with real assistive technology? Since I hadn’t seen this before, I set out to build Auto VO, a driver for the VoiceOver screen reader.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cameron Cundiff)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logical Fallacies – Definition and Fallacy Examples]]></title>
        <id>607f5fafdd38b9088c2bd0c9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/logical-fallacies-definition-fallacy-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T04:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're debating someone, you want to use all the resources at your disposal to convince them you're right. And that's great – but you should be careful that you don't end up using a logical fallacy to help you make your point. What is a Logical Fallacy?A logical fallacy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police corruption and the unsolved murder of Daniel Morgan – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/23/police-corruption-unsolved-murder-daniel-morgan-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/23/police-corruption-unsolved-murder-daniel-morgan-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The brutal murder of a private investigator in 1987 has become the UK’s most investigated killing – but 34 years later it remains unsolved and mired in new official findings of police corruption
On 10 March 1987, a 37-year-old private investigator named Daniel Morgan was found dead in a south London pub car park with an axe embedded in his head. Despite the arrests of several men, the initial investigation did not lead to any charges and the murder has gone unsolved amid allegations of police corruption. 
The Metropolitan police have previously accepted that corrupt officers shielded the killers. But a new panel inquiry concluded last week that the crime was probably “solvable” had it not been undermined. The force was described as “institutionally corrupt” and its commissioner, Cressida Dick, personally censured for obstruction by an independent inquiry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Duncan Campbell and Alistair Morgan; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[inherit, initial, unset, revert]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342930</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/inherit-initial-unset-revert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:20:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are four keywords that are valid values for any CSS property (see the title). Of those, day to day, I’d say I see the inherit used the most. Perhaps because it’s been around the longest (I think?) but also …
The post inherit, initial, unset, revert appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Scraping with PHP – How to Crawl Web Pages Using Open Source Tools]]></title>
        <id>60d2323d6e1a1407b6b0ac4f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-scraping-with-php-crawl-web-pages/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T21:11:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web scraping lets you collect data from web pages across the internet. It's also called web crawling or web data extraction.  PHP is a widely used back-end scripting language for creating dynamic websites and web applications. And you can implement a web scraper using plain PHP code.  But since we]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Async/Await to Write Better JavaScript Code]]></title>
        <id>60cac8ff4dc1a607ed7b4592</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-async-await-write-better-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:24:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a special syntax you can use in JavaScript that makes working with promises easier. It's called “async/await", and it’s surprisingly straightforward to understand and use.  In this article, we'll discuss:  What are asynchronus functions? How promises work in JavaScript Async/Await basics How to use]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use TypeScript and MongoDB to Build a 100 Days of Code Discord Bot]]></title>
        <id>60c13e71d3126007592d5be2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-a-100-days-of-code-bot-for-discord-using-typescript-and-mongodb/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T16:20:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 100 Days of Code challenge is very popular among new coders and developers looking to level up their skills. It's so popular that our Discord server has an entire channel dedicated to it.  By popular demand, we recently built a Discord bot that helps people track their progress in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Custom Elements in Svelte]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342634</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-custom-elements-in-svelte/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:37:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte fully supports custom elements (e.g. <my-component>) without any custom configuration or wrapper components and has a perfect score on Custom Elements Everywhere. However, there are still a few quirks you need to watch out for, especially around …
The post Using Custom Elements in Svelte appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Rich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342925</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/if-were-gonna-criticize-utility-class-frameworks-lets-be-fair-about-it/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m not here to raise a shield protecting CSS utility frameworks. I don’t even particularly like the approach, myself, and nothing is above fair criticism. But fair is a key word there. I can’t tell you how many times I’ve …
The post If we’re gonna criticize utility-class frameworks, let’s be fair about it appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing With Code: A Modern Approach To Design (Development Challenges)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of innovation in both tools and processes, the struggle between design and development is still real. This article focuses on the best practices for improving the design to development processes and how cutting-edge solutions, such as UXPin powered by Merge technology, can help in facilitating the change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342887</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/new-responsive/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T21:22:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Una is calling it the new responsive. A nod to the era we were most certainly in, the era of responsive design. Where responsive design was fluid grids, flexible media, and media queries, the new responsive is those things …
The post Are we in a new era of web design? What do we call it? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342448</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-create-css-charts-with-interesting-shapes-glyphs-and-emoji/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:32:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s forego the usual circles and bars we typically see used in charts for more eccentric shapes. With online presentations more and more common today, a quick way to spruce up your web slides and make them stand out is …
The post How to Create CSS Charts With Interesting Shapes, Glyphs and Emoji appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image To Text Conversion With React And Tesseract.js (OCR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have to process data manually because it is served through images or scanned documents? An image-to-text conversion makes it possible to extract text from images to automate the processing of texts on images, videos, and scanned documents. In this article, we look at how to convert an image to text with React and Tesseract.js(OCR), preprocess images, and deal with the limitations of Tesseract (OCR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ayobami Ogundiran)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341511</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-the-outline-property-as-a-collapsable-border/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T20:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The outline property in CSS draws a line around the outside of an element. This is quite similar to the border property, the main exception being that outline isn’t a part of the box model. It is often used for …
The post Using the `outline` Property as a Collapsable Border appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carter Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342326</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography-2/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:44:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I studied the fonts of the top 1000 websites. Here’s what I learned. — Michael Li brings the data. San-serif has total dominance. “[…] it is rare to go below 10px or above 24px.” And poor <h5> always being the 
…
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341948</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/perfect-tooltips-with-css-clipping-and-masking/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clipping and masking have been around for a while now in CSS and even have pretty decent browser support. I recently worked on a project that needed to use a clipping technique for tooltips showing above links in text.
Those …
The post Perfect Tooltips With CSS Clipping and Masking appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Louis Hoebregts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342257</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/start-serving-optimized-images-in-vue/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:38:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have become extremely important to the effectiveness of websites. They speak a 1000 words, attract attention, and stimulate emotions.
However, web performance is also a growing problem for most websites. And images are at the heart of many web …
The post Start Serving Optimized Images in Vue appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>ImageEngine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: have you re-thought your wedding dress during the pandemic?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/15/tell-us-have-you-re-thought-your-wedding-dress-during-the-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/15/tell-us-have-you-re-thought-your-wedding-dress-during-the-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T13:25:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear if you have changed your mind about your wedding attire during the pandemic 
For couples who decided to get married during the last 18 months, wedding plans have often had to be altered. Pandemic restrictions sparked a rise in pared-back micro-weddings and virtual ceremonies. Perhaps unsurprisingly, this has also has an impact on the day’s dress code, with many brides (in particular) opting for a more relaxed look over a formal wedding dress.
With this in mind, we’d love to hear from those who re-thought their wedding attire during the pandemic. Perhaps you decided to go for a cocktail dress, rather than a floor-skimming evening gown? Or maybe you decided not to wear a dress at all? Tell us about it, and share your photos, here.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flying cars? Electric jets? Five things you need to know about the future of transport]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/smarter-science/2021/jun/03/flying-cars-electric-jets-five-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-future-of-transport</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/smarter-science/2021/jun/03/flying-cars-electric-jets-five-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-future-of-transport"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T09:20:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may still sound like the stuff of science fiction, but some of the biggest companies in the world are investing hugely in previously fanciful transport technologies

From 2030, new petrol and diesel vehicles will be banned in Britain – a sure sign that we’re on the threshold of a transport revolution. But what exactly will this revolution look like? With estimates that the market for autonomous vehicles could be worth almost £42bn in just over a decade, the future of transport looks to be anything but boring. Here are five things you need to know …
Driverless cars take to the roads
While fully autonomous vehicles (where the driver could, in theory, watch a film while the vehicle takes the controls) are still a way off, the first driverless cars – with automated lane-keeping systems that allow drivers to safely take their hands off the wheel – could be on Britain’s roads this year. In Japan, Toyota is building its own smart city, which will function in part as a giant testing facility for autonomous vehicles. Meanwhile, in the US, Waymo – which grew out of Google’s self-driving car project – is trialling driverless “robotaxi” services for the public in parts of Phoenix. The road to the driverless future may still be a little bumpy, but it is showing signs of smoothing out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Waugh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>