<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-28T00:57:26.193Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-28T00:57:26.193Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.9.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchin criticizes Republican opposition to 6 January commission: ‘There’s no excuse’ – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/27/joe-biden-republicans-covid-coronavirus-us-politics-latest-updates</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/may/27/joe-biden-republicans-covid-coronavirus-us-politics-latest-updates"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T00:02:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senator says: ‘They do not believe the truth will set you free’

McConnell dismisses commission as ‘extraneous’
Republicans introduce nearly $1tn infrastructure plan
Democrats’ push for voting rights law faces tortuous path
Sign up to receive First Thing – our daily briefing by email

 1.02am BST 
We’re wrapping up our live US politics coverage for the night, with key political developments still unfolding, including an expected vote on the creation of a bipartisan commission to investigate Trump supporters’ invasion of the Capitol on 6 January. 
An updated summary of today’s key news: 
 12.19am BST 
Federal prosecutors in New York are investigating whether Ukrainian officials attempted to interfere in the 2020 presidential election to undermine Biden and help Trump, including by using Rudolph Giuliani, the president’s personal lawyer, to spread misinformation, the New York Times reported, citing unnamed sources “with knowledge of the matter”. 
NYT SCOOP: Federal prosecutors are investigating whether Ukrainian officials helped orchestrate a wide-ranging plan to meddle in the 2020 campaign, including using Giuliani to spread misleading claims about Biden and tilt the election in Trump’s favor.https://t.co/7QHFvugPcb
SCOOP: RUDY GIULIANI signed an agreement with ANDRII ARTEMENKO in Nov. 2019 to locate witnesses to defend TRUMP.
One of those witnesses, accused "active Russian agent" ANDRIY DERKACH, later hired Artemenko's company to lobby in DC. https://t.co/Rw2ATZ7VOp https://t.co/IWgEa1HXnY
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lois Beckett in Los Angeles (now) and Joan E Greve (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bank transfer scammers steal £700,000 a day from UK victims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/28/bank-transfer-scammers-steal-700000-a-day-from-uk-victims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/28/bank-transfer-scammers-steal-700000-a-day-from-uk-victims"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T23:01:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Consumer body Which? criticises ‘unfair and inconsistent’ bank reimbursement policies
More than £700,000 is lost to bank transfer scams every day, which works out at £491 a minute, according to research by the consumer body Which?
It claimed the banking industry’s approach to reimbursing victims of this type of fraud was “unfair and inconsistent,” with less than half of losses being returned to those affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the pipeline: networks to warm UK homes using surplus heat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/28/in-the-pipeline-networks-to-warm-uk-homes-using-surplus-heat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/28/in-the-pipeline-networks-to-warm-uk-homes-using-surplus-heat"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T23:01:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government plans to spend £45m on citywide systems and other technologies to reduce carbon output
Tens of thousands of homes, offices and hospitals could soon be warmed with surplus heat from factories, incinerator plants and even disused mine shafts under plans by the government to fund low-carbon heating.
The government will spend £30m to help set up heat networks across cities including London, Glasgow and Manchester and a further £14.6m to develop other low-carbon technologies that can heat and cool buildings without fossil fuels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose Energy correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site in Syria could be world’s oldest war memorial, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/28/site-in-syria-could-be-worlds-oldest-war-memorial-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/28/site-in-syria-could-be-worlds-oldest-war-memorial-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T23:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Archaeologists say White Monument in Tal Banat was tribute to war dead of 3rd millennium BC
A burial mound in northern Syria has been identified by researchers as perhaps the world’s oldest known war memorial.
The site, known as the White Monument, in the town of Tal Banat had previously been thought to be an ancient mass grave of enemy fighters. However, a report published in the journal Antiquity on Friday suggests it was a memorial for the community’s battle dead from the 3rd millennium BC.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Chulov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Rashford and Barack Obama share ‘surreal’ Zoom conversation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/28/marcus-rashford-and-barack-obama-share-zoom-conversation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/28/marcus-rashford-and-barack-obama-share-zoom-conversation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T23:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United striker and ex-president discuss youth
‘When president Obama speaks, all you want to do is listen’

Marcus Rashford has spoken with former US president Barack Obama to discuss the power young people can have to make change in society.
Rashford, the Manchester United and England striker, met virtually with the 44th president of the United States in a Zoom conversation organised by Penguin Books.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Number of smokers has reached all-time high of 1.1 billion, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/27/number-of-smokers-has-reached-all-time-high-of-11-billion-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/27/number-of-smokers-has-reached-all-time-high-of-11-billion-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T22:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Governments told to focus on stopping young from taking up habit that killed 8 million people in 2019
Smoking killed almost 8 million people in 2019 and the number of smokers rose as the habit was picked up by young people around the world, according to new research.
A study published in the Lancet on Thursday said efforts to curb the habit had been outstripped by population growth with 150 million more people smoking in the nine years from 1990, reaching an all-time high of 1.1 billion.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaamil Ahmed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indoor gigs could be staged without raising Covid risk, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/indoor-gigs-could-be-staged-without-raising-covid-risk-study-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/indoor-gigs-could-be-staged-without-raising-covid-risk-study-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T22:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No new cases recorded after controlled event in Spain that allowed singing and dancing with no social distancing

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Early evidence suggests indoor music events can take place without increasing the risk of coronavirus transmission. 
The first randomised controlled trial to assess the impact of comprehensive Covid-19 safety measures at a live indoor concert, held in Spain, reported no cases of virus transmission.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Midsummer Night’s Dream review – the Globe’s giddy return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/27/a-midsummer-nights-dream-review-shakespeare-globe-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/27/a-midsummer-nights-dream-review-shakespeare-globe-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T22:15:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shakespeare’s Globe, London
Goody-bag props, party-hatted fairies and a donkey-shaped piñata sweeten the bard’s dark comedy in a revival of Sean Holmes’s vibrant 2019 production
A donkey-shaped piñata dangles above the stage. It’s a decent metaphor for this play’s colourful, sweet-centred festivities amid destruction. A Midsummer Night’s Dream chimes with lockdown nightmares of confinement and separated lovers, the discombobulation of a world turned upside down and climate chaos. But the Globe throws a party instead, reviving Sean Holmes’s ebullient 2019 Dream, vibrantly designed by Jean Chan, as the venue reopens for the first time since the pandemic hit.
Nicholas Hytner, Dominic Hill and Joe Hill-Gibbins have all recently drawn out the play’s more troubling aspects; here we have bright bursts of dance, brass musicians (from Hackney Colliery Band) who are partial to blasts of Jimi Hendrix, and goody-bag props including bubble guns, water pistols and starry headbands. It’s a fun night, lovably silly with some smart surprises, but doesn’t spin that difficult, delicate web required to let this enchanting play do more than amuse.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Wiegand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill Cosby parole petition denied after he refuses therapy for sexual offenders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/bill-cosby-parole-pennsylvania</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/bill-cosby-parole-pennsylvania"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T22:15:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Comedian, 83, rejects therapy program for violent predators
Cosby sentenced to up to 10 years in prison for sexual assault

The Pennsylvania parole board has turned down comedian Bill Cosby’s petition to be released from a 10-year prison sentence for aggravated indecent assault, citing his refusal to participate in a therapy program for sexually violent predators.
Laura Treaster, a spokeswoman for the state parole board, confirmed the decision, which was made on 11 May and first reported on Thursday by Nicole Weisensee Egan, author of the book Chasing Cosby, on her Facebook page.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Lives Matter co-founder to step down as foundation’s executive director]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/black-lives-matter-cofounder-patrisse-cullors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/black-lives-matter-cofounder-patrisse-cullors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T22:10:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patrisse Cullors has recently faced attacks from a far-right group and criticism from other Black organizers
A co-founder of Black Lives Matter announced Thursday that she is stepping down as the executive director of the movement’s foundation following what she has called a smear campaign from a far-right group and recent criticism from other Black organizers.
Patrisse Cullors, who has been at the helm of the Black Lives Matter Global Network Foundation for nearly six years, said she is leaving to focus on other projects, including the upcoming release of her second book and a multi-year TV development deal with Warner Bros. Her last day with the foundation is Friday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Are We Feeding Our Kids? review – junk food exposé will leave you queasy]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/27/what-are-we-feeding-our-kids-review-a-junk-food-expose-that-will-leave-you-feeling-queasy-bbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/27/what-are-we-feeding-our-kids-review-a-junk-food-expose-that-will-leave-you-feeling-queasy-bbc"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T21:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One half of TV’s twin doctor duo, Chris van Tulleken, gorges on ultra-processed, sugar-and-salt-filled foods to find out whether profits are being put before our families’ health 
Maybe we will come to measure out the pandemic in Tulleken time. The identical twin brothers – and practising doctors – Chris and Alexander (Xand) van Tulleken have had a busy year; they have rarely been off our screens for long. Respectively, they are a virologist at University College hospital, London, and an experienced public health doctor with years of experience on the frontline of disaster zones. The pair would doubtless have been commissioned to educate us on Covid – even if Xand hadn’t caught the virus and brought a personal view to the gig (Surviving the Virus: My Brother and Me). Their series Operation Ouch, and other online contributions, helped parents desperately trying to home school, in between fending off unemployment, sourcing supermarket deliveries and caring for shielding parents.
Alone or together, the Van Tullekens are very good at what they do. They turn potentially dark, heavy subjects – primarily, but not always, medical – into lighter, brighter fare, still informed by their in-depth knowledge, but delivered without ego and accessible to a mass audience. In What Are We Feeding Our Kids? (BBC One), we have Chris as a solo act, looking into the health effects – particularly for children – of our increasing consumption of ultra-processed food. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Tacoma police officers charged in killing of Manuel Ellis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/manuel-ellis-tacoma-three-officers-charged-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/manuel-ellis-tacoma-three-officers-charged-death"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:58:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Decision came more than a year after Pierce county medical examiner’s office ruled Black father of two’s death a homicide

The Washington state attorney general’s office has filed felony charges against three police officers in the killing of Manuel Ellis, a 33-year-old Black father of two, who, moments before his death, called out: “I can’t breathe.”
This is the first time the office has filed criminal charges against police officers for unlawful use of deadly force.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hallie Golden in Seattle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s £11bn school repair bill goes back to Michael Gove cuts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/27/englands-11bn-school-repair-bill-goes-back-to-michael-gove-cuts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/27/englands-11bn-school-repair-bill-goes-back-to-michael-gove-cuts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:15:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: bill is a result of austerity cuts and decisions made by the coalition education secretary

Report: repair bill for schools in England doubles to over £11bn

The £11bn worth of repairs for England’s schools, identified by the Department for Education’s own report, is the accumulated bill that goes back to the decision by Michael Gove to axe an ambitious programme of rebuilding.
The Blair government’s £55bn Building Schools for the Future plan – the biggest programme of its kind since the Victorian era – was a victim of the austerity budgets introduced by the coalition government after 2010, with Gove’s contribution being the abrupt cancellation of building works that were already approved and about to break ground. Some did eventually go ahead, mainly for Gove’s new academies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colombia politician tells protesters hurt by police to ‘stop crying over one eye’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/27/colombia-protests-paola-holguin-stop-crying-one-eye</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/27/colombia-protests-paola-holguin-stop-crying-one-eye"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:15:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least 43 protesters have been killed by police and 46 people have suffered eye injuries 
After a month of protests in which 46 people have suffered eye injuries from police teargas rounds and rubber bullets, a Colombian politician has prompted outrage by saying that supporters of the anti-poverty demonstrations should “stop crying over one eye”.
“Don’t fool Colombians and don’t fool the international community and stop crying over one eye,” said Paola Holguín, a senator from the ruling Centro Democrático party, to opposition politicians during a virtual floor speech on Wednesday afternoon.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels in Bogotá</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hancock faces calls to explain Covid test failings at care homes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/matt-hancock-not-all-patients-sent-care-homes-tested-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/matt-hancock-not-all-patients-sent-care-homes-tested-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:08:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary claims it ‘wasn’t possible’ to test all patients sent to care homes at outset of pandemic

Dominic Cummings’ key accusations against Matt Hancock
See all our coronavirus coverage

Matt Hancock is under mounting pressure to explain why the government failed to protect care home residents at the outset of the Covid pandemic, as he sought to salvage his reputation after Dominic Cummings accused him of lying.
The health secretary claimed for the first time it “wasn’t possible” to test all care home residents for Covid before they were discharged from hospital last March, because the testing capacity was not yet available.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Repair bill for schools in England doubles to over £11bn, finds survey]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/27/repair-bill-for-schools-in-england-doubles-to-over-11bn-finds-survey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/27/repair-bill-for-schools-in-england-doubles-to-over-11bn-finds-survey"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:05:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report by Department for Education took four years to produce and finds widespread problems

Analysis: school repair bill goes back to Michael Gove cuts

Schools in England face a repair bill of more than £11bn, nearly double some previous estimates, according to a long-awaited national survey completed by the government.
The survey confirmed years of complaints by teachers and parents of crumbling buildings and leaking facilities, in some cases riddled with asbestos, and of “temporary” cabins that remain in use despite exceeding their lifespan.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Adams Education editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How did a green, newbie hedge fund out-play Exxon so comprehensively? | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/27/how-did-a-green-newbie-hedge-fund-out-play-exxon-so-comprehensively</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/may/27/how-did-a-green-newbie-hedge-fund-out-play-exxon-so-comprehensively"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:02:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The day Big Oil discovered that the makeup of its board could be changed against its will
In the short history of shareholder activism, the humiliation of the board of ExxonMobil on Wednesday takes some beating. The directors were comprehensively out-played by an environmentally minded hedge fund formed only six months ago that arrived with a stake of only 0.02%.
Despite emerging almost from nowhere, Engine No. 1, the upstart fund, succeeded in persuading other shareholders to vote two of its four candidates on to the board; a third newcomer could follow when the “too close to call” tallies are finally counted. The campaigning achievement is remarkable.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on the Dominic Cummings row over Covid and care homes – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/27/steve-bell-on-the-cummings-row-on-covid-and-care-homes-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/27/steve-bell-on-the-cummings-row-on-covid-and-care-homes-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Tuchel: inside the mind of an obsessive with the winning touch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/thomas-tuchel-chelsea-inside-the-mind-of-an-obsessive-with-the-winning-touch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/thomas-tuchel-chelsea-inside-the-mind-of-an-obsessive-with-the-winning-touch"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T19:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes Chelsea’s manager so successful? We find out from people who have known him since his school days
Christian Heidel laughs as he remembers a story that sums up Thomas Tuchel’s obsessive attention to detail. “We were in a training camp in Austria and had a match against Olympiakos,” Mainz’s sporting director says. “Thomas was looking closely at the lawn. He was measuring the height, sniffing the grass. He was so thrilled about this pitch that he wanted me to transfer the groundsman to Mainz. The next day the groundsman called me and said: ‘I heard that we’re going to have some talks about a contract.’ The deal didn’t happen but it shows what a perfectionist he is.”
Heidel, who gave Tuchel his break when he put him in charge of Mainz’s first team in 2009, is not the first person to marvel at the Chelsea manager’s quest for perfection. Hans Komm, who taught PE at the German’s Simpert-Kraemer high school, remembers a gifted sportsman who possessed a surprisingly bright tactical mind for a teenager.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock enjoys some Tory TLC and a new-found job security | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/matt-hancock-insists-he-never-lied-which-is-almost-certainly-a-lie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/matt-hancock-insists-he-never-lied-which-is-almost-certainly-a-lie"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:51:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It could have been a much trickier day for the health secretary, but now he, Tory MPs and the PM are all in this together 
Through a glass darkly. Wasn’t it ironic, said the Conservative William Wragg, that so many Labour MPs who had previously dismissed Dominic Cummings as a Herod were now hailing the prime minister’s former chief adviser as some kind of prophet? Er, maybe ... But it was also noticeable how many Tories, who had once seen Dom as some kind of terrifying, omnipotent genius, were now so quick to denounce him as a fraud. After all, without Cummings there would probably have been no Brexit and no 80-seat majority in the 2019 election.
After Matt Hancock was accused of being a serial liar who should have been sacked on many occasions, Thursday’s urgent question from his Labour shadow, Jon Ashworth, could have made for a tricky hour for the health secretary. Instead it was something of a breeze as Matt was love-bombed by a succession of Tory MPs – the government benches were almost (socially distanced) full, while the opposition benches were nearly empty – who had little interest in mistakes that might have been made in the past. It wasn’t the best of looks when tens of thousands of people may have died unnecessarily, but you couldn’t fault their loyalty.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘House of One’: Berlin lays first stone for multi-faith worship centre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/berlin-lays-first-stone-for-multi-faith-house-of-one-worship-centre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/berlin-lays-first-stone-for-multi-faith-house-of-one-worship-centre"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:50:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Construction begins on project that will unite Muslims, Jews and Christians under one roof
Muslims, Jews and Christians are to be united for worship under one roof in Berlin in a groundbreaking project called ‘House of One’.
The cornerstone of the multi-denominational temple was laid in the German capital on Thursday with supporters saying they hoped it would forge greater understanding between the three religions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Labour MP George Galloway joins Batley and Spen byelection race]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/ex-labour-mp-george-galloway-joins-batley-and-spen-byelection-race</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/ex-labour-mp-george-galloway-joins-batley-and-spen-byelection-race"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:48:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Entry of Brexiter, who was expelled from Labour in 2003, may help the Conservatives take the seat 
George Galloway is to contest the upcoming Batley and Spen byelection in a move that could make it harder for Labour to hold the seat.
After the party’s defeat to the Tories in the recent Hartlepool byelection, Labour had been regarded as facing a tough battle to hold Batley and Spen when voters go to the polls on 1 July.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JD Group paid its boss £6m after government support of £100m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/27/jd-group-paid-boss-6m-government-support-pandemic-peter-cowgill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/27/jd-group-paid-boss-6m-government-support-pandemic-peter-cowgill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:40:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Cowgill took a voluntary 75% cut in basic pay during the pandemic but banked a special bonus 
The boss of JD Group, Peter Cowgill, has been handed almost £6m in bonuses since February last year despite the company accepting more than £100m in government support.
The owner of JD Sports, Millets and Black Leisure, and a string of overseas sportswear chains, accepted £86.1m in furlough payments for staff and an estimated £38m in business rates relief last year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiger Woods: rehab from crash ‘more painful than anything I have experienced’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/tiger-woods-rehab-car-crash-golf-return</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/tiger-woods-rehab-car-crash-golf-return"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:40:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Golfer is recovering from serious injuries sustained in February
45-year-old does not answer question on possible return to golf

Tiger Woods has spoken about the grueling recovery process from the car crash earlier this year that left him with serious leg injuries.
One police officer who attended the Los Angeles crash in February said Woods was “lucky to be alive” after his car hit a tree at 75mph.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-quarters of new UK Covid cases could be India variant, says Hancock]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/uk-covid-cases-india-variant-matt-hancock-three-quarters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/uk-covid-cases-india-variant-matt-hancock-three-quarters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:35:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reported cases of variant reach almost 7,000, as it becomes dominant in Britain

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Up to three-quarters of new UK Covid cases are now thought to be caused by the variant first detected in India, the health secretary has said.
The variant of concern, known as B.1.617.2, has been linked to a rise in cases in hotspots around the country. Data released on Thursday by Public Health England (PHE) shows 6,959 cases have been confirmed so far in the UK, up from 3,424 the week before.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recruiters urged to clamp down on exploitation via ‘umbrella companies’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/27/recruiters-urged-to-clamp-down-on-exploitation-via-umbrella-companies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/27/recruiters-urged-to-clamp-down-on-exploitation-via-umbrella-companies"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:27:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs, unions and lobby groups say firms, though legal, are used to pay workers at arm’s length
Recruiters must clamp down on tax abuse and exploitation of workers via umbrella companies, the industry’s lobby group has told its members, amid growing pressure for regulation of temporary labour.
So-called umbrella companies, used by recruiters and employers to pay temporary workers, have attracted growing scrutiny from MPs and unions following reports of abuses across the industry and investigations by the Guardian and the BBC that raised concerns about agencies supplying the NHS test-and-trace scheme.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voters weigh up Cummings’ revelations before crucial byelections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/voters-weigh-up-cummings-revelations-before-crucial-byelections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/voters-weigh-up-cummings-revelations-before-crucial-byelections"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:19:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wednesday’s vitriolic complaints about ministers’ incompetence don’t seem to be helping Labour in Chesham and Amersham or Batley and Spen
“He’s sulking, isn’t he?” said Steve Jowett, 63, when asked about Dominic Cummings’ explosive revelations in Westminster on Wednesday. A driver waiting to start his shift at Heckmondwike bus station, West Yorkshire, neither Jowett nor his colleague Trevor Lewis, 55, had much sympathy for the prime minister’s former adviser.
“But, if it’s true, there’s got to be an investigation, because there’s a lot of families up and down the country that won’t be happy,” Lewis added.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Wolfe-Robinson and Kevin Rawlinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trayvon Martin family lawyer Natalie Jackson announces run for Congress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/natalie-jackson-congress-replace-val-demings-florida</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/natalie-jackson-congress-replace-val-demings-florida"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:13:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Florida attorney who has received endorsements from Benjamin Crump and Philonise Floyd is running to replace Val Demings
Natalie Jackson, a prominent Florida attorney whose clients include Trayvon Martin’s family, is running to replace Representative Val Demings in Congress next year.
Just days into her campaign for the Orlando-based House seat, Jackson has already garnered endorsements from two powerful civil rights champions: attorney Benjamin Crump and Philonise Floyd, George Floyd’s brother.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Villarreal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PM refused Trump’s call to bomb Iraq after legal advice, Cummings claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/pm-refused-trump-call-bomb-iraq-legal-advice-cummings-claims</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/pm-refused-trump-call-bomb-iraq-legal-advice-cummings-claims"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:05:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s former chief aide described ‘completely surreal day’ in his testimony to MPs on Wednesday
Boris Johnson rejected a call from Donald Trump’s White House to participate in airstrikes in Iraq last March after an intervention by the UK government’s top legal officer, according to Dominic Cummings.
The reasoning behind the attorney general’s advice was not spelled out by the prime minister’s former chief aide during his seven-hour testimony on Wednesday, although a human rights group said the US strikes were illegal under international law.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zinedine Zidane’s departure from Real Madrid seems to suit both parties | Sid Lowe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/zinedine-zidane-departure-real-madrid-seems-to-suit-both-parties</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/zinedine-zidane-departure-real-madrid-seems-to-suit-both-parties"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was the manager’s decision to leave the Santiago Bernabéu and the club have chosen to quickly turn the page
“One day I’m in, one day I’m out, then I’m a bit in, then we draw or lose and I’m out again,” Zinedine Zidane said. That was early February and it is also part of the reason why, almost four months later, he really is out. On Thursday morning, around 10.30, the Real Madrid manager drove into Valdebebas. By the time he drove back out two hours later, he was officially the former Real Madrid manager. Again. He had told some players the night before, around the time footage appeared of the Santiago Bernabéu on fire.
The statement from the club confirming his departure was released just after midday. It was polite without being especially effusive and only 102 words long. There are no plans for a press conference or a farewell; the club’s media chose to turn the page, the statement followed by studied silence. The only player Zidane could say goodbye to in person was Lucas Vázquez, undergoing his rehabilitation at Valdebebas.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sid Lowe in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conjuring: The Devil Made Me Do It review – slick threequel magics up scares]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/the-conjuring-the-devil-made-me-do-it-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/the-conjuring-the-devil-made-me-do-it-review"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest tale involving the real-life paranormal investigator couple is a handsomely made, if often overly self-serious, addition to the popular franchise
As Warner Brothers still tries to repair the ungodly mess that is the DC cinematic universe (a scrappy hack job of false starts, recasts, cursed sets and confusing timelines), the studio has strangely found more sustained success and structural consistency with another interlinked set of movies from a genre not traditionally associated with this form of brash expansion. With The Conjuring franchise, Warners has turned a sleeper hit into a series of seven and a half films over eight years, totalling almost $2bn at the global box office, unprecedented for the horror genre and as creaky as the films might have gotten, it’s an impressive and revealing case study on how to turn very little into a lot.
 Related: A Quiet Place Part II review – Emily Blunt horror is something to scream about 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve Machine Learning Model Performance by Combining Categorical Features]]></title>
        <id>60af931811ffb70827ef85d3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-machine-learning-model-performance-by-combining-categorical-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're training a machine learning model, you can have some features in your dataset that represent categorical values. Categorical features are types of data that you can divide into groups. There are three common categorical data types: Ordinal – a set of values in ascending or descending order. Example: rating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Former NFL player to take charge of GB Wheelchair Rugby in Tokyo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/jason-brisbane-appointed-to-lead-great-britain-wheelchair-rugby-paralympic-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/jason-brisbane-appointed-to-lead-great-britain-wheelchair-rugby-paralympic-games"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:52:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jason Brisbane is a former American football linebacker 
Team ranked fourth in world with hopes of Paralympic medal

A former American football linebacker is to take charge of Great Britain Wheelchair Rugby, in what those within the sport hope will be a year of Paralympic success. Jason Brisbane will become one of the few black people to hold a senior management role in UK sport when he takes up his position in July.
Brisbane will replace David Pond as chief executive. Pond has overseen substantial growth in the sport over the past decade, and an international team ranked fourth in the world with hopes of a medal in Tokyo later this summer, should the Paralympic Games go ahead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of avoidable Covid deaths: is Cummings right?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/avoidable-deaths-covid-dominic-cummings-right-scientists-agree</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/avoidable-deaths-covid-dominic-cummings-right-scientists-agree"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:47:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Scientists agree with the former adviser’s claim, with one calling the estimate ‘conservative’

Coronavirus – latest updates

See all our coronavirus coverage

One of the most shocking allegations made by Boris Johnson’s former chief adviser Dominic Cummings during Wednesday’s joint parliamentary committee hearing was his claim that “tens of thousands of people died who didn’t need to die”, because of the way the government handled the Covid pandemic.
His claims have some support from scientists, who have estimated that the toll from government delays could be as high as 33,000 lives.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Covid inquiry: time to bring it on | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/the-guardian-view-on-the-covid-inquiry-time-to-bring-it-on</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/the-guardian-view-on-the-covid-inquiry-time-to-bring-it-on"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:38:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings’ charges have strengthened the case for the official public inquiry into coronavirus to be brought forward from next year
Faced with Dominic Cummings’ fusillade against Boris Johnson’s handling of the coronavirus pandemic, the government on Thursday circled the wagons. As a short-term expedient, it made grubby tactical sense. The Conservative party believes public feeling is on its side because of the vaccination programme. Mr Cummings is mistrusted because of the Barnard Castle debacle. The former Downing Street adviser has not yet published the documents that may corroborate his claims. This added up to a window of opportunity for ministers to dismiss the allegations as false or unsubstantiated, and for Tory MPs to put on a display of unity behind the health secretary, Matt Hancock.
It was not, though, a morally dignified exercise, especially in the light of Mr Cummings’ grave claims that tens of thousands of British people died unnecessarily because of the government’s failures and that Mr Johnson is not fit to be prime minister. In political terms, it may not be a sustainable position either. The charges levelled on Thursday by Labour’s Jonathan Ashworth were substantive and serious. Fourteen months ago, Mr Hancock promised a protective shield around care homes; yet 30,000 care home residents died. He promised extensive supplies of personal protective equipment; yet up to 8,700 patients and 850 health workers died after contracting the virus in hospitals. These shocking facts are not going to go away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Hillsborough: unjust to the bitter end | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/the-guardian-view-on-hillsborough-unjust-to-the-bitter-end</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/the-guardian-view-on-hillsborough-unjust-to-the-bitter-end"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The families’ determination made them a beacon for other campaigners. But while they forced the truth into the open, the courts let them down
The families of the 96 people unlawfully killed at Hillsborough as a result of gross negligence by the police fought for justice for more than three decades. The collapse of the trial of two former police officers and a solicitor, after a judge ruled that the men had no case to answer, marks a cruel end to one of the bravest and longest-lasting of all British justice campaigns. The institutions that between them make up the policing and legal system should be deeply ashamed. First, Hillsborough’s victims and survivors were blamed. Now, they have been let down yet again.
There have been many individual and organisational failures over the years, beginning with inadequate planning by the police and others for the FA Cup semi-final in Sheffield on 15 April 1989. The media, specifically the Sun newspaper which joined in with police efforts to smear the victims, 37 of whom were teenagers, are implicated in some of these.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lisa Shaw death: BBC presenter had blood clots after AstraZeneca jab, family says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/bbc-presenter-lisa-shaw-died-of-blood-clot-after-astrazeneca-jab-family-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/bbc-presenter-lisa-shaw-died-of-blood-clot-after-astrazeneca-jab-family-says"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:36:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio Newcastle broadcaster had severe headaches a week after vaccine and fell seriously ill days later, relatives say
The award-winning BBC radio presenter Lisa Shaw died in hospital after suffering blood clots following her AstraZeneca vaccination, her family has said.
The 44-year-old, who was a well-known broadcaster in the north-east of England and had worked for BBC Radio Newcastle since 2015, developed severe headaches a week after having the jab and fell seriously ill a few days later, relatives said in a statement.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forthcoming. insightful, eloquent: Naomi Osaka’s media snub is a big loss for tennis | Tumaini Carayol]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/naomi-osaka-media-snub-big-loss-tennis-french-open</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/naomi-osaka-media-snub-big-loss-tennis-french-open"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:31:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The grand slam winner is one of the sport’s most engaging characters and her silence will be keenly felt at the French Open
Towards the end of last season, not long after players had returned from lockdown, the Frenchman Gaël Monfils continued to embrace his newfound hobby on the streaming website Twitch. After retiring from a match in October, he decided to skip his mandatory post-match press duties in favour of inviting French journalists to conduct the press conference online for his fans.
The journalists were left with a choice – attend the press conference on terms dictated by Monfils or potentially miss out. In the end, those who did attend discussed with him his biggest news of the year: he was shutting down his season.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN to launch inquiry into ‘systematic discrimination’ in Israel and Palestine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/un-rights-body-debates-systematic-discrimination-in-israel-and-palestine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/un-rights-body-debates-systematic-discrimination-in-israel-and-palestine"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UN rights chief says Israel attacks on Gaza could constitute war crimes and accuses Hamas of firing indiscriminate rockets
The UN’s main human rights body will launch an investigation into “systematic discrimination and repression” in Israel and Palestine, with the aim of identifying what it said were the root causes of recent Gaza bloodshed.
The proposal for unprecedented levels of scrutiny of alleged abuses, called at the request of Muslim states, was passed by the 47-member UN human rights council on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ECHR criticises Italian court for referring to ‘red underwear’ in rape case]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/27/echr-criticises-italian-court-for-referring-to-red-underwear-in-case</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/27/echr-criticises-italian-court-for-referring-to-red-underwear-in-case"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:21:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Human rights court says language used was unjustifiable and orders €12,000 payment to woman
The European court of human rights has condemned an Italian court for “reproducing sexist stereotypes” after it referred to a woman’s red underwear and bisexuality as signs of her “ambivalent attitude towards sex” when acquitting six men accused of gang-rape.
The case dates back to 2008, when the woman, a student, 22 at the time, claimed she had been raped by seven men in Florence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida in Rome</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dominic Cummings’ tell-all told us what we already knew about the Tories | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/dominic-cummings-tell-all-told-us-what-we-already-knew-about-the-tories</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/dominic-cummings-tell-all-told-us-what-we-already-knew-about-the-tories"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers on the former No 10 adviser’s revelations about the incompetence of the government in handling the Covid crisis

It is astonishing that it has taken so long for self-styled superbrain Dominic Cummings to figure out that the man he put into No 10 is “unfit for the job” (Report, 26 May). The rest of us have been painfully aware of this for many years, and never more so than over the last 18 months. While Cummings’ testimony was full of sanctimonious bile and he is not known for his honesty, as long as Boris Johnson refuses to initiate a timely public inquiry this may be the best opportunity we get to see behind the curtain and reveal the mishandling of the pandemic by this “confederacy of dunces” led by Johnson and Cummings.
Jane Barrett
Buxton, Derbyshire
 Related: Renewed anguish over my husband’s death from hospital-acquired Covid | Letter 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grave error of an obit published too soon | Brief letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/grave-error-of-an-obit-published-too-soon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/grave-error-of-an-obit-published-too-soon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:12:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obituaries | Australia camel trek | Guardian website | Hillsborough disaster | Pub signs | Other lives
When the Guardian archive was first made available online, my mother and I took the opportunity to look up some ancestors. One obituary we discovered was that of the Rev John Aldis (6 December 1900). We were a little confused: hadn’t he lived a few years longer? Still, we were delighted to discover the obituary. Even better was to find a correction in the next edition – the obituary had been published in error; the death had been of his son (also the Rev John Aldis). The Rev John Aldis Sr lived until 1907, dying at the age of 99, but I have no record if the obituary was republished.
Ingrid Warren
Oxford
• It was inspiring to see wonderful images of Sophie Matterson’s ongoing and hugely impressive walk (Outback camel trek: one woman’s 5,000km journey across Australia, 25 May) and I wish her well. However, it’s remarkable that the image captions did not once reference the pioneering Robyn Davidson, who made just such a journey and wrote about it in her award-winning book Tracks (1980). This is mentioned not to diminish Matterson’s achievement but rather to create a lineage of women’s achievements in their own terms. Memory is central to this process and amplifies, rather than reduces, what follows.
Gareth Evans
London
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viktor Orbán to become second EU leader hosted at No 10 after Brexit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/hungary-viktor-orban-to-become-second-eu-leader-hosted-at-no-10</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/hungary-viktor-orban-to-become-second-eu-leader-hosted-at-no-10"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson to welcome the Hungarian prime minister, a fierce critic of Joe Biden and ally of China
Boris Johnson will welcome his Hungarian counterpart, Viktor Orbán, a fierce critic of Joe Biden and an ally of China, to No 10 on Friday, only the second EU leader the UK prime minister has greeted since the the country left the bloc.
Orbán is hoping to prove to Hungarian voters ahead of next year’s elections that he can forge influential alliances and that the departure of his governing Fidesz party from the European People’s party centre-right grouping does not usher in an era of political isolation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We read The Very Hungry Caterpillar weekly’: readers’ tributes to Eric Carle]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/27/we-read-the-very-hungry-caterpillar-weekly-readers-tributes-to-eric-carle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/27/we-read-the-very-hungry-caterpillar-weekly-readers-tributes-to-eric-carle"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:28:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers share what the celebrated children’s author and illustrator’s work meant to them

Report: Eric Carle, author and illustrator, dies at 91
Obituary: Eric Carle

Eric Carle, children’s author and illustrator of The Very Hungry Caterpillar and many other children’s books, has died at the age of 91. Here, readers share their memories of what the celebrated author’s work means to them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sanctions are imposed by the sanctimonious, and achieve nothing | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/sanctions-achieve-nothing-belarus-lukashenko</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/sanctions-achieve-nothing-belarus-lukashenko"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:19:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The west can disapprove all it likes of leaders like Belarus’s Lukashenko, but only engagement will change anything
What should we do about Belarus? It is becoming the North Korea of Europe, its opposition leader in exile, Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, told the European parliament this week. But it must be the wrong question. The question is not what should we do, but what can we do?
European and American politicians reach for economic sanctions as they used to reach for gunboats or bombers. But gunboats meant results. You soon knew if anything had changed. Sanctions are like papal edicts, signals of moral superiority supposedly cost-free to the signaller.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russia refuses to allow European planes to land in Moscow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/world-aviation-body-to-launch-inquiry-into-belarus-hijacking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/world-aviation-body-to-launch-inquiry-into-belarus-hijacking"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:16:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Retaliation over Belarus airspace row results in cancellation of flights from French and Austrian carriers
Russia has retaliated against a ban on carriers entering Belarus’s airspace by refusing to grant permission to European planes flying to Moscow.
In an apparent escalation by the Kremlin, Russian aviation authorities forced Austrian Airlines to cancel its flight from Vienna to the Russian capital. Air France also cancelled its Paris-Moscow flight for the second day in a row, after it was denied permission on Wednesday to land in Russia.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels and Luke Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester United plan moves for Sancho, Rice, Kane and Pau Torres]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/manchester-united-eye-moves-for-sancho-rice-kane-and-pau-torres</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/manchester-united-eye-moves-for-sancho-rice-kane-and-pau-torres"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T16:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ole Gunnar Solskjær keen to strengthen squad
Jadon Sancho the most likely to arrive at Old Trafford

Ole Gunnar Solskjær wants to strengthen Manchester United in the centre-back, midfield, wide attacker and No 9 positions, with Pau Torres, Declan Rice, Jadon Sancho and Harry Kane among his preferred targets.
Although the manager is conscious that adding four major signings is unlikely given an estimated total cost of more than £300m and the availability of any particular player, he is intent at least on pursuing one in each of his identified areas to bolster a squad that requires an upgrade in quality and depth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astronomers create largest map of the universe’s dark matter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/27/astronomers-create-largest-map-universe-dark-matter-einstein</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/27/astronomers-create-largest-map-universe-dark-matter-einstein"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:30:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International team reveal vast cosmic voids over the Earth’s skies that could challenge Einstein
We can’t see it, barely understand it, but know that it exists because of the powerful influence it exerts on space.
Dark matter makes up about 27% of the universe, and its gravitational force is enough to mesh entire galaxies together in a structure known as the cosmic web. Now, scientists have created the largest ever map of this mysterious substance – and it could imply that there’s something wrong with Einstein’s theory of relativity.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The UK’s forced adoption scandal was state-sanctioned abuse | Gaby Hinsliff]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/uk-forced-adoption-state-sanctioned-abuse-unmarried-mothers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/uk-forced-adoption-state-sanctioned-abuse-unmarried-mothers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:17:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unmarried mothers were treated with contempt by authorities in the mid-20th century. The same goes for people deemed not to matter today
When Ann Keen gave birth, the midwives refused to give her anything for the pain. That way, they told her, she would remember it and learn not to be so wicked again. To be treated like an animal in labour, denied the most basic compassion and respect, was simply part of the punishment she had supposedly earned for getting pregnant out of wedlock aged 17. The hospital discharged her without any follow-up care, as if the birth had never happened. But the most grievous part of the story is that she also went home without her baby.
For Keen is one of a still unknown number of unmarried British women coerced into handing over their newborns for adoption between the 1950s and the late 1970s, who are now seeking an apology from Boris Johnson on behalf of the governments of the day. But perhaps just as importantly, they want it acknowledged that they didn’t give their children up willingly. Some were told that if they loved their babies they would want them raised by respectable married couples, not under the shadow of illegitimacy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaby Hinsliff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three men jailed over 2017 Catalonia terror attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/three-men-jailed-over-2017-catalonia-terror-attacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/three-men-jailed-over-2017-catalonia-terror-attacks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohamed Houli Chemlal, Driss Oukabir and Said Ben Iazza jailed over attacks that left 16 people dead and 140 wounded
Three men have been jailed for between eight and 53 years after being found guilty of assisting the perpetrators of the 2017 terror attacks in Catalonia, which left 16 people dead and 140 wounded.
The men who carried out the atrocities – Spain’s worst terror attack since the Madrid train bombings in March 2004 – used a van to knock down pedestrians on Barcelona’s La Rambla boulevard on 17 August 2017 and then staged another assault the following day in the Catalan coastal town of Cambrils.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make a Bouncing Basketball in Unity with Materials and Textures 🏀]]></title>
        <id>60a325c6906c5207e3a7da25</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-a-basketball-in-unity-with-materials-and-textures/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll teach you how to make a basketball using materials and textures in Unity. You can extend this micro-concept to create any kind of ball like a football, tennis ball, or snooker balls.  That said, these techniques aren't just limited to creating round 3D objects like balls.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second to nun: why Call the Midwife’s medical miracles are a joke]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/27/why-call-the-midwife-medical-miracles-are-a-joke</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/27/why-call-the-midwife-medical-miracles-are-a-joke"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:12:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sheer number of rare conditions Dr Turner and the midwives of Nonnatus House diagnose would warrant a Nobel prize – and are making the series as silly as Midsomer Murders
If television were the real world, no one would want to live in the global homicide hotspot of Midsomer. Every woman, though, would beg to be a patient at Nonnatus House clinic in Poplar, East London, because the standard of healthcare is so extraordinary.
So far in season 10 of Call the Midwife, which concludes on Sunday, Dr Patrick Turner (Stephen McGann) and his team of midwives have diagnosed a case of gestational diabetes, a condition little understood at the dramatised time of 1966, and a very rare enzyme disorder, phenylketonuria.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Lawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investing 0.1% of global GDP could avoid breakdown of ecosystems, says UN report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/nature-financial-value-investing-global-gdp-avoid-breakdown-ecosystems-un-report-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/nature-financial-value-investing-global-gdp-avoid-breakdown-ecosystems-un-report-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature’s financial value must be considered to avoid ‘irreversible’ degradation to biodiversity and land
The world needs to quadruple its annual investment in nature if the climate, biodiversity and land degradation crises are to be tackled by the middle of the century, according to a new UN report.
Investing just 0.1% of global GDP every year in restorative agriculture, forests, pollution management and protected areas to close a $4.1tn (£2.9tn) financial gap by 2050 could avoid the breakdown of natural ecosystem “services” such as clean water, food and flood protection, the report said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model behind ‘hands off my hijab’ post is named Vogue Scandinavia editor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/27/model-hands-off-my-hijab-post-vogue-scandinavia-editor-rawdah-mohamed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/27/model-hands-off-my-hijab-post-vogue-scandinavia-editor-rawdah-mohamed"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:44:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rawdah Mohamed’s Instagram image opposing a proposed hijab ban in France went viral in April
Rawdah Mohamed, the Somali-Norwegian model whose protest against a proposed ban on the hijab in France went viral, has been announced as editor of the soon-to-be-launched Vogue Scandinavia.
Mohamed will become the first hijab-wearing editor of colour at a fashion magazine in the west.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Priya Elan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Covid come from a Wuhan lab? What we know so far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/did-covid-come-from-a-wuhan-lab-what-we-know-so-far</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/did-covid-come-from-a-wuhan-lab-what-we-know-so-far"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:13:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To China’s fury, Joe Biden has ordered a review of rival theories about lab leaks and animal hosts

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

President Joe Biden has ordered US intelligence agencies to conduct a 90-day review of what is known about the origins of Covid-19 and whether it could have escaped from a laboratory in Wuhan. So what does this mean for the lab leak theory?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fred West: family of suspected victim are ‘sad’ remains not found]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/27/fred-west-inquiry-no-human-remains-found-at-gloucester-cafe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/27/fred-west-inquiry-no-human-remains-found-at-gloucester-cafe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:11:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Family of Mary Bastholm, who disappeared in 1968, were hoping to get closure to put her to rest
The family of a teenager suspected to have been a victim of the serial killer Fred West have expressed sadness that her remains have not been found after the basement of a Gloucester cafe was excavated by police.
Relatives of 15-year-old Mary Bastholm, who vanished in 1968, said they still hoped the mystery of what happened to her will one day be solved.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switzerland walks out of seven-year treaty talks with EU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/switzerland-walks-out-of-seven-year-treaty-talks-with-eu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/27/switzerland-walks-out-of-seven-year-treaty-talks-with-eu"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:02:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Swiss say terms unacceptable despite Brussels’ claims they are better than those offered to UK
Switzerland has walked out of talks on a closer trading relationship with the European Union despite being offered better terms than the UK in key areas, EU officials have claimed.
On Wednesday the country’s foreign minister, Ignazio Cassis, pulled the plug on long-running discussions with the EU, saying that Berne’s conditions were “not met”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s not like you were in a war, love’: the ignorance surrounding an MP with PTSD | Rhiannon Lucy Cosslett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/war-ptsd-nadia-whittome-mp-diagnosis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/war-ptsd-nadia-whittome-mp-diagnosis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The vitriolic reaction to Nadia Whittome’s diagnosis shows how far we are from understanding trauma
At the beginning of the pandemic, I reread Mrs Dalloway. I wasn’t the only one – something about the novel seemed to resonate; as Evan Kindley noted in the New Yorker last April, the spectre of Spanish flu hangs subtly but perceptibly over it. I had first read it as a student – probably, on reflection, mere months before a terrible thing would happen to me, during which I expected I would die. This event changed the configuration of my mind and, in myriad unforeseeable ways, my entire life. It also, it turns out, changed the way in which I’d read Mrs Dalloway. Its portrayal of a shell-shocked mind, which I had noted but not fully appreciated before, seems all the more authentic, visceral.
I …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhiannon Lucy Cosslett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Democrat standing in the way of his party’s efforts to protect voting rights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/democrats-voting-rights-joe-manchin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/democrats-voting-rights-joe-manchin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Manchin has publicly signaled that he doesn’t back Democrats’ bill and wants bipartisan support – can senators win him over and move forward?
Happy Thursday,
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levine in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Cataclysmic day’ for oil companies sparks climate hope]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/cataclysmic-day-for-oil-companies-sparks-climate-hope</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/cataclysmic-day-for-oil-companies-sparks-climate-hope"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:38:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Court and investor defeats over carbon emissions a historic turning point, say campaigners and lawyers
A “cataclysmic day” for three major oil companies in which investors rebelled over climate fears and a court ordered fossil fuel emissions to be slashed has sparked hope among campaigners, investors, lawyers and academics who said the historic decisions marked a turning point in efforts to tackle the climate crisis.
A Dutch court on Wednesday ordered Shell to cut carbon emissions from its oil and gas by 45% by 2030. A tiny activist investor group simultaneously won two places on ExxonMobil’s board and Chevron’s management was defeated when investors voted in favour of forcing the group to cut its carbon emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commons suspends Tory MP Rob Roberts over sexual harassment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/commons-suspends-tory-mp-rob-roberts-over-sexual-harassment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/commons-suspends-tory-mp-rob-roberts-over-sexual-harassment"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:09:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MP for Delyn in north Wales given six-week suspension as Commons leader adds to calls for him to resign
The Conservative MP Rob Roberts, who was found to have sexually harassed a member of staff, has been suspended from the House of Commons for six weeks as the Commons leader stepped up the pressure on him by saying it would be “honourable” for him to resign.
An independent panel found that Roberts had made repeated and unwanted sexual advances towards a former member of staff, as well as inappropriate comments of a sexual nature.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British delegates to Cannes hit by new French quarantine rules]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/cannes-film-festival-new-french-quarantine-rules-uk-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/cannes-film-festival-new-french-quarantine-rules-uk-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:44:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[France’s move to prevent the import of Covid variant B.1.716.2 – now on the increase in the UK – could deter British film-makers and press from attending
British participation in at the Cannes film festival is under threat after new quarantine regulations put into place by the French government as the country seeks to successfully exit lockdown.
After delays caused by Covid, the festival confirmed it would take place in early July, but France has announced a seven-day isolation period for visitors from the UK in response to rising concerns over the Covid variant B.1.617.2, first detected in India. The move is likely to affect thousands, both among the press corps and industry delegates, and large numbers of unregistered attendees.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Pulver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disney’s Cruella stitches punk’s overlooked female designers into the fabric]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/disney-cruella-punk-fashion-design</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/27/disney-cruella-punk-fashion-design"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:43:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Disney should be the antichrist to true punk aficionados, but Cruella tips the hat to the forgotten DIY fashionistas who made the movement so visible 
There was a time the very thought of Cruella would have been met with outrage. I know this because I would have been outraged. Of all subcultures to be hijacked by Disney, 70s London wasteland punk is surely the most heinous.
Now? Well, what punk could even mean in 2021 is open to offers. While Disney releases Cruella – a pop blockbuster filtered through $200m of corporate compromise – Danny Boyle is making Pistol, a TV adaptation of the memoir of the Sex Pistols’ Steve Jones. And yes, one of these instinctively feels more punk than the other. And yes, it is Cruella.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danny Leigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your stories of holiday disasters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:32:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about your holiday catastrophes and trips that didn’t go to plan
With travel still subject to strict Covid rules, many of us will be opting to stay put this summer. But while we often idolise the idea of a sun-filled getaway, in reality, our holidays can sometimes fail to meet expectations – and sometimes they can be downright disastrous.
With this in mind, we’d love to hear about your holiday catastrophes and the trips that didn’t go according to plan, as a reminder that we might not always be missing out after all. Perhaps your luxurious city break was ruined by terrible weather? Or maybe your backpacking adventure plans were quashed by a bout of food poisoning? Whether your family vacation ended in tears, or your romantic weekend away was blighted by lost luggage and booking mishaps, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DMX: Exodus review – a bold and bleak posthumous finale]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/27/dmx-exodus-review-a-bold-and-bleak-posthumous-finale</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/27/dmx-exodus-review-a-bold-and-bleak-posthumous-finale"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Def Jam Recordings)
The New York rapper, who died in April, is strong and unsettling over grimy, atonal production, with guest turns from Alicia Keys, Jay-Z and Bono
Hip-hop loves a posthumous album, but DMX’s has arrived sooner than most because it wasn’t supposed to be posthumous at all. Earl Simmons’ career had been in decline since the mid-00s, eventually grinding to a halt amid a litany of legal problems, health issues and financial woes – he filed for bankruptcy three times, was jailed for everything from tax fraud to animal cruelty; struggled with bipolar disorder and addiction and released only one, poorly received official album, 2012’s Undisputed, in the last 15 years. But prior to his death from an apparent drug overdose this April, he was already on the comeback trail.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexis Petridis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Jessen ordered to pay £125,000 to Arlene Foster over tweet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/christian-jessen-ordered-to-pay-damages-to-arlene-foster-over-tweet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/27/christian-jessen-ordered-to-pay-damages-to-arlene-foster-over-tweet"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:22:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TV presenter repeated false rumour on Twitter that Northern Ireland first minister had affair 
The celebrity doctor Christian Jessen has been ordered to pay £125,000 in damages to the Northern Ireland first minister, Arlene Foster, for a tweet that falsely claimed she was having an affair.
The high court in Belfast awarded the record figure on Thursday to vindicate and compensate Foster, the outgoing leader of the Democratic Unionist party (DUP), for what it said was a baseless accusation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll Ireland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brazil aerial photos show miners’ devastation of indigenous people’s land]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/27/brazil-aerial-photos-reveal-devastation-by-goldminers-on-indigenous-land</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/27/brazil-aerial-photos-reveal-devastation-by-goldminers-on-indigenous-land"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:16:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of thousands of wildcat goldminers shown as president Jair Bolsonaro is accused of trying to promote their illegal work
Rare and disturbing aerial photographs have laid bare the devastation being inflicted on Brazil’s largest reserve for indigenous people by thousands of wildcat goldminers whose illegal activities have accelerated under the country’s far-right leader, Jair Bolsonaro.
Activists believe as many as 20,000 garimpeiro prospectors are operating within the Yanomami reserve in northern Brazil using speedboats and light aircraft to penetrate the vast expanse of jungle near the border with Venezuela.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips and Flávia Milhorance in Rio de Janeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Carle obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/27/eric-carle-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/27/eric-carle-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Illustrator and author of classic children’s books including The Very Hungry Caterpillar and Brown Bear, Brown Bear, What Do You See?
Eric Carle, who has died aged 91, was best known as the author-illustrator of The Very Hungry Caterpillar, a deceptively simple 16-page picture book whose original production and story not only entranced very young children with the most arresting “pop!” in literature but also provided entertainment and satisfaction for their parents.
Like many who have an exceptional success, Carle did not like to be acknowledged for the one title only. He was quick and sometimes testy in pointing out that he had created many other books, too – more than 70. But with its adaptability to different formats and the slew of merchandising that sees his character on everything from a pencil to a tea service, The Very Hungry Caterpillar, a “modern classic” that has sold more than 55m copies around the world, remains his biggest legacy. As Carle himself quite happily recalled in an interview, “So much from so little, as one of my friends once put it.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Eccleshare</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where were the critics who could have stopped Johnson leading us to Covid tragedy? | Owen Jones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/tories-britain-covid-dominic-cummings-pandemic-labour-media</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/27/tories-britain-covid-dominic-cummings-pandemic-labour-media"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the disastrous decisions outlined by Dominic Cummings were made, the opposition and many journalists showed only support

Ten days before England locked down too late to prevent tens of thousands of deaths, a senior government official waltzed into No 10 to prophetically declare: “I think we are absolutely fucked. I think this country is heading for a disaster, I think we’re going to kill thousands of people.” In a functioning democracy, you might expect senior journalists briefed by No 10 to have at least questioned what was glaringly obvious to those at the very top – that Britain was disastrously ill-equipped and ill-prepared for a pandemic already sweeping the country.
 Related: The Dominic Cummings circus is an indictment of the entire governing class | Aditya Chakrabortty 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Owen Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Paris mural and Belgian beer: Thursday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/27/paris-mural-belgian-beer-thursday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/27/paris-mural-belgian-beer-thursday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T11:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tottenham hold talks with Mauricio Pochettino over return as manager]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/tottenham-hold-talks-with-mauricio-pochettino-over-return-as-manager</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/27/tottenham-hold-talks-with-mauricio-pochettino-over-return-as-manager"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T11:26:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pochettino believed to be interested in coming back from PSG
Antonio Conte open to discussions after leaving Inter

Tottenham have held talks with Mauricio Pochettino over a sensational return to the club. Pochettino, sacked by Spurs 18 months ago, joined Paris Saint-Germain in January and has caused surprise by entertaining the idea of a swift return to London.
The Argentinian is believed to be interested in reviving his former club, who have encountered frustration in their attempts to replace José Mourinho, and the previously ridiculous notion of a reunion could come to pass.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 challenging UK outdoor adventures for children and teenagers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/10-challenging-uk-outdoor-adventures-for-children-and-teenagers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/10-challenging-uk-outdoor-adventures-for-children-and-teenagers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T10:41:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Activities like hiking, cycling, surfing and kayaking are ideal for enjoying nature as a family. Take your kids’ skills to the next level on one of these advanced trips this half term 
Challenging yourself on an outdoor adventure and overcoming fears, be they of heights, injury or humiliation, is an important rite of passage for older children and teenagers, and a great way to boost self-confidence and resilience. And with many school activity trips cancelled for the second year running, here are some ideas for parents looking to plug that gap off their own back. The kind of transformative experiences kids can only have when they get out into the elements and leave their bedrooms and comfort zones behind.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Haddad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: has long Covid affected you professionally?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/27/tell-us-has-long-covid-affected-you-professionally</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/27/tell-us-has-long-covid-affected-you-professionally"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T10:01:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to know how individuals with long Covid have been treated by their employers
We would like to find out how people with long Covid are being treated by their employers. Are you being offered the time off and sick pay you need? 
We would also like to hear about from employers about how they’re managing staff who have been affected by long Covid. Are you having to adapt work policies? What is the impact on your business? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Roman rotters, river otters and a ridiculous way to get caught – take the Thursday quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/27/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/27/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T10:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia every Thursday lunchtime – how will you fare?
It is time. Thursday lunchtime. Time to enjoy our cunningly titled Thursday quiz. Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia, laced with a few weird facts and some jokes. It is just for fun and there are no prizes, but let us know how you get on in the comments below.
The Thursday quiz, No 5
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Responsive Websites Faster With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Accidental meat’: should carnivores embrace eating roadkill?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/27/accidental-meat-should-carnivores-embrace-eating-roadkill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/27/accidental-meat-should-carnivores-embrace-eating-roadkill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My parents have been eating pheasants killed on the roads for years and encouraging me to try them. Is this the most ethical approach to meat-eating?
Motorists shoot me funny looks as I sheepishly cross a scrubby verge, trying my best to conceal the dead pheasant under my arm. I am in a part of Saddleworth Moor called the Isle of Skye by locals, and have just collected a free meal from the middle of the road.
Nobody can agree on how this area of moorland, in the West Riding of Yorkshire, earned its nickname. Some think it comes from a Victorian navvy, who exclaimed in a broad Irish brogue: “Look, there’s an ’ole in the sky,” as he considered a parting in the thick mist above him. Others think it was named after an inn of the same name. But either way, the area should be immediately renamed Pheasant Cemetery. Because, before I picked up my own bird, I counted 46 pheasant carcasses in various stages of decomposition, scattered and splattered on the road over several miles as I drove to Holmfirth for a day out.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Lavelle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami’s chief heat officer calls for action on ‘silent killer’ in climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/miami-chief-heat-officer-jane-gilbert-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/miami-chief-heat-officer-jane-gilbert-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T08:45:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jane Gilbert urges greater federal and state response to lethal threat posed by rising temperatures
Miami’s new chief heat officer has called for greater federal and state action on the lethal threat posed by rising temperatures after becoming the first official in the US appointed to focus solely on heatwaves.
Jane Gilbert, who has been tasked by Miami-Dade county with coordinating and accelerating efforts to protect lives from extreme heat, said that more focus was needed on what has been called the “silent killer” of the climate crisis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rapid heating of Indian Ocean worsening cyclones, say scientists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T08:41:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising ocean temperatures caused by climate crisis increasing number of cyclones and intensity of storms, say experts
India’s cyclone season is being made more intense by the rapidly heating Indian Ocean, scientists have warned.
Last week India was battered by Cyclone Tauktae, an unusually strong cyclone in the Arabian Sea, resulting in widespread disruption. This week, another severe storm, Cyclone Yaas, formed in the Bay of Bengal, leading to more than a million people being evacuated into safe shelters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Neelima Vallangi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After the inferno: Sierra Leone’s poorest struggle to recover from slum fire – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/27/after-the-inferno-sierra-leones-poorest-struggle-to-recover-from-slum-fire-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/gallery/2021/may/27/after-the-inferno-sierra-leones-poorest-struggle-to-recover-from-slum-fire-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T08:30:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A blaze ripped through the overcrowded settlement of Susan’s Bay in Freetown in March, injuring hundreds. British photographer Henry Kamara, of Sierra Leone descent, documents the aftermath in this coastal community as people try to rebuild their lives
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henry Kamara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Boxing is a mess’: the darkness and damage of brain trauma in the ring]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/time-to-find-out-who-cares-boxing-brain-damage-tris-dixon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/27/time-to-find-out-who-cares-boxing-brain-damage-tris-dixon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T07:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boxing must address the damage done in the ring and a new book by Tris Dixon lays out what’s left after the final bell rings
The writer, the fighter, the doctor and the widow all look down into the darkness and damage of boxing. They understand the previously untold story of brain trauma in the ring and, as they talk to me, their moving testimony underpins a shared belief that change has to come. There is a measured urgency to their words for they love the fighters and they want to offer their knowledge to help make this brutal sport a little safer.
Damage and death have always framed boxing. This harsh truth means that, despite the chaos outside the ring, boxing is shockingly real. It can maim and even kill but, in a strange paradox, boxing also makes most fighters feel more intensely alive than anything else.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald McRae</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do I get my car insurer to reveal the secrets of its black box?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/27/how-do-i-get-my-car-insurer-to-reveal-the-secrets-of-its-black-box</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/27/how-do-i-get-my-car-insurer-to-reveal-the-secrets-of-its-black-box"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scores baffle us but we can’t find out how it arrived at them
When my wife and I bought our first car, the lowest insurance offers involved black boxes to track our driving. We went with Bell, part of the Admiral Group, which promised personalised driving advice, no curfews and tracking for only six months, unless your ratings are in the bottom 5%. We estimated we would travel 10 miles a day, including a margin for the occasional big trip. Usually, it’s nearer 12 miles a week. The manufacturer feedback from my car tells me my speed, braking and anticipation average 85%, but Bell’s first two assessments, after a few months driving no more than four miles a day, gave me an average score of 43% and advised I use the car less.
My third assessment, after driving an extra seven miles to a hospital appointment, scored 35%, with my driving style rated at 19%. Again, I was told to use the car less. Bell’s website gives no detail about how it arrives at the numbers. Its feedback has doubled the number of hours I’ve spent behind the wheel, misinterpreted “direct routes” available, and shrunk my average speed to 3.52mph.
JB, Watford
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Tims</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Workers became poker chips’: the hardship of Thatcher’s Britain – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/27/workers-became-poker-chips-the-hardship-of-thatchers-britain-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/27/workers-became-poker-chips-the-hardship-of-thatchers-britain-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Originally self-published in 1985, Paul Graham’s images were made in the barren waiting rooms and corridors of the UK’s social security and unemployment offices 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Dig coal to save the climate’: the folly of Cumbria’s plans for a new coalmine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/dig-coal-to-save-the-climate-the-folly-of-cumbrias-plans-for-a-new-coalmine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/dig-coal-to-save-the-climate-the-folly-of-cumbrias-plans-for-a-new-coalmine"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supporters of a new coalmine have argued that it will reduce global warming and create green jobs. How could such absurd claims have gained any credibility? 
It was in early 2019 that I first heard about the proposals for a new coalmine in Cumbria. It happened almost by chance. I was speaking with a local government officer who was developing the county’s economic strategy. As someone who has worked with governments on climate issues for many years, I had been asked to offer advice on how to make Cumbria a climate leader. We talked through the opportunities – investing in renewables, helping businesses reduce waste, developing Cumbria’s tourist industry.
And then the government officer mentioned, almost in passing, that they had been helping a company with plans for a new coalmine, to produce coking coal for steel production. I didn’t know what to say. This would be the first new deep coal mine in the UK for 30 years, and the only active one: the last of the old ones closed in 2015. After a long silence I pointed out that digging up coal – the most polluting of all fossil fuels – is no definition of climate leadership. Yet just a couple of weeks later, Cumbria county council’s planning committee voted unanimously in favour of the mine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Willis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Noel Clarke: can the UK film and TV industry bring an end to on-set bullying?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/after-noel-clarke-can-the-uk-film-and-tv-industry-bring-an-end-to-on-set-bullying</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/27/after-noel-clarke-can-the-uk-film-and-tv-industry-bring-an-end-to-on-set-bullying"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For many years, the actor and director’s behaviour was seemingly unchallenged. But there are hopes that the recent claims against him could help spur positive change

After 20 women came forward to tell the Guardian they had been sexually harassed and bullied by the actor, director, screenwriter and producer Noel Clarke, the question on many people’s lips was: did other people in the industry know about this? And if not, why not?
While some of the incidents of harassment or bullying took place without witnesses, others happened in front of colleagues and senior production staff. The assistant film director Anna Avramenko, who worked as an intern on the film Doghouse in 2008, told the Guardian that Clarke approached her on set and “started trying to kiss me on the lips, in front of everyone”. She added: “He probably tried it like three to five times with me, maybe more.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale, Amelia Gentleman and Lucy Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eve Pitts: the Church of England’s first Black female vicar – and one of its fiercest critics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/27/eve-pitts-church-of-england-first-black-female-vicar-fiercest-critics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/27/eve-pitts-church-of-england-first-black-female-vicar-fiercest-critics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T05:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite attempts to drive her out of the church, she has spent decades fighting racism wherever she has encountered it. Now she is pushing the C of E to honour the enslaved people it exploited
Soon after she became the first Black female vicar in the Church of England in the 80s, the Rev Eve Pitts walked into a bar. She had finished theological college at the Queen’s Foundation in Birmingham and had just received her first posting, in Bartley Green, Birmingham. The area was notoriously unwelcoming to minorities, with a strong far-right presence (in 2019, a neo-Nazi living in Bartley Green was jailed for three years under the Terrorism Act). When Pitts took up her post at Saint Michael and All Angels’ church, in 1987, she remembers seeing graffiti with “‘National Front’, ‘niggers go home’, all over the place”.
Her training vicar was worried enough to advise Pitts against going into the local pub. Looking back, Pitts laughs, “he obviously didn’t know me!” Instead, one night the young, diminutive Pitts walked in, past men who looked like “archetypal” neo-Nazis, with “tattoos all over their hands”, marched up to the bar and asked: “So, who’s going to buy me a drink, then?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kehinde Andrews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The government failed’: Dominic Cummings takes aim at No 10’s Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former aide lashed out at every aspect of the government’s approach and Boris Johnson and Matt Hancock in particular
Dominic Cummings spent an hours-long session in parliament on Wednesday giving evidence to a joint committee on the government’s response to the Covid pandemic. He took aim at Boris Johnson for overseeing a chaotic response and at the health secretary, Matt Hancock, for what he alleged was lying over preparedness and PPE stocks.
Guardian columnist Gaby Hinsliff tells Anushka Asthana that it was the first chance to get a detailed firsthand account of what was going on in the heart of government as the crisis unfolded. But how much should Cummings himself be seen as culpable for the failures?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Gaby Hinsliff; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giphy API Tutorial – How to Generate Animated Text GIFs with ReactJS]]></title>
        <id>60a44b9f906c5207e3a7e098</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/giphy-api-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial you will create an app that generates dynamic animated text using Giphy's API with ReactJS. After that I'll go over some of the other API features Giphy provides that you can use to make other interesting projects. You can find the code for the tutorial here. Video]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Contribute to Open Source  Projects – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60abe7fb11ffb70827ef63a6</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-contribute-to-open-source-projects-beginners-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a developer, you've probably come across the term "open source." If you've ever wondered what it's all about and how to contribute, you are in exactly the right place.  I put aside all my fears about how and what to contribute during Hacktoberfest 2020, and made]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Basic Terraform Syntax in 20 minutes]]></title>
        <id>606f4f5fd5756f080ba96b65</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/terraform-syntax-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll give you a brief overview of the configuration syntax of Terraform.  Terraform's docs provide the most comprehensive look at its syntax. But this article should serve as a condensed quick start introduction that'll give new users a simplified overview. We'll focus on the basic structures without]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a GraphQL API Using Laravel]]></title>
        <id>60abc59d11ffb70827ef6304</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-graphql-api-using-laravel/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll walk you through how to set up your own GraphQL API using PHP and Laravel. Two years ago, I started working professionally as a backend developer. And I was very intimidated by all the technology I didn't yet know. Words like Docker, Kubernetes, and GraphQL seemed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hot tub health kick: why a long bath is almost as good for you as a long run]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/hot-tub-health-kick-why-a-long-bath-is-almost-as-good-for-you-as-a-long-run</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/26/hot-tub-health-kick-why-a-long-bath-is-almost-as-good-for-you-as-a-long-run"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:18:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have discovered that prolonged immersion in a piping hot bath has many of the same medical benefits as aerobic exercise
Name: Hot baths.
Age: First used by the ancient Egyptians 4,000 years ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amish girls on holiday at the beach: Dina Litovsky’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/beach-amish-girls-holiday-dina-litovskys-best-photograph</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/26/beach-amish-girls-holiday-dina-litovskys-best-photograph"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:17:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Seeing them with cellphones was shocking at first – seeing one on a hoverboard felt like science fiction’
I picked this image because it’s one of only a few where I got to know the people in the photograph. I usually take a fly-on-the-wall approach, observing groups at a distance. I’m interested in exploring how people kick back, and most of my projects are connected by leisure and contemporary culture. I did a series called Bachelorette, documenting the cultural ritual of bachelorette parties, as a night of release for women. Another looked at the nightlife in Manhattan’s high-gloss Meatpacking district – a microcosm of sexual politics. But I didn’t interact with the people in those pictures or get their names.
 Related: Amish on holiday – photo essay 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Amy Fleming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Super Mario Bros, Zelda, and Space Invaders with Kaboom.js]]></title>
        <id>60aced0011ffb70827ef6d96</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-mario-zelda-and-space-invaders-with-kaboom-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video course I show you how to build three popular games using the latest game development library for JavaScript called Kaboom.js. This course is exciting for two reasons: First of all, I am going to be introducing a new technology designed especially for game development in JavaScript.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what are your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T09:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This bank holiday weekend will be the first opportunity for many to visit loved ones who live further away. We’d like to hear about your plans
What were your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend – the first opportunity many of us have had to visit grandparents and loved ones who live further away?
What impact have these new No-Go zones had on your arrangements: are you going to adapt or abandon your visits – or are you going ahead, as planned?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May’s super flower moon lights up the night skies – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/26/mays-super-flower-moon-lights-up-the-night-skies-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/gallery/2021/may/26/mays-super-flower-moon-lights-up-the-night-skies-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T07:14:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The May full moon, known as the flower moon, coincided with it being at its closest to the Earth during its orbit, making it appear larger and brighter. May’s supermoon also coincides with a lunar eclipse in which the moon will turn red, but that will be visible only in parts of South America, Australia and south-east Asia. This celestial incident, known as super flower blood moon, is the only full lunar eclipse of this year

Here’s how to take a good picture of the full supermoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[California dreams: the natural wonders of Wynn Bullock – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/26/california-dreams-the-natural-wonders-of-wynn-bullock-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/26/california-dreams-the-natural-wonders-of-wynn-bullock-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T06:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new exhibition collects the stunning black and white photography Bullock took of his family and their surroundings in Monterey, Big Sur and beyond
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Britain becoming a hostile environment for EU citizens? | Podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T02:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid travel restrictions begin to be lifted, a new, far less welcoming post-Brexit attitude is greeting EU citizens at the UK border 
EU citizens living and working in the UK are being met with suspicion and in some cases refused entry at the UK border for the first time in their lives, after the implementation of new post-Brexit rules and the lifting of Covid travel restrictions. 
Chloe, a pastry chef from Denmark, tells Anushka Asthana that, because she could not produce a return ticket, she was denied entry at Calais to the UK recently and forced to make the long drive back to Denmark. It is becoming a familiar story, with other EU citizens reporting hostility from officials and some being held at immigration detention centres. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rafael Behr; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep Calm and Hack The Box – Valentine]]></title>
        <id>60ac3a2711ffb70827ef6aec</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/keep-calm-and-hack-the-box-valentine/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T22:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walkthrough for Hack The Box Valentine machine]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chakra UI and React-Hook-Form –How to Build Beautiful Forms]]></title>
        <id>60a93b0011ffb70827ef5b0d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-react-hook-form-with-chakra-ui/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T20:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In HTML, it’s the default behavior for forms to redirect to a new page whenever they're submitted. So in order to provide dynamic functionality, React uses a strategy called controlled components. If you have recently gone through a React course, you probably didn't like this part, because there are]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create Portfolio-Worthy Work – Web Design Best Practices for New Developers]]></title>
        <id>608706aedd38b9088c2c012c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-design-best-practices-for-new-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a beginner developer, it can be difficult to find ways to use your limited knowledge to support yourself. And at the same time, you won't be able to hone your skills if you aren't using them full time.  It's a precarious spot that I remember being in when]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: do you live in a Covid hotspot affected by the variant from India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/20/tell-us-have-you-been-affected-by-the-india-covid-variant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are looking to speak with people who have had to change their plans due to new travel advice about hotspots in England
New travel advice urging people not to travel in or out of Covid hotspots in England affected by the variant first identified in India has been released, but not announced by the government. Eight areas are affected including Bedford, Blackburn and Darwen, Bolton, Burnley, Kirklees, Leicester, Hounslow, and North Tyneside.
We are looking to speak with people in England who have been affected by the B.1.617.2 variant, and who have had to change their plans or behaviour due to the new advice.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two lives changed by the death of George Floyd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/25/two-lives-changed-by-the-death-of-george-floyd-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/25/two-lives-changed-by-the-death-of-george-floyd-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T02:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A year ago, the murder of George Floyd caused outrage in Minneapolis – and kicked off a protest movement that spread across the world. How do the young Black people at the heart of the story live with his legacy?
A year after George Floyd was murdered, the movement instigated by his death has spread across the US and the world, but Black people in Minneapolis are still living with the emotional fallout from that day. Anushka Asthana speaks to Amudalat Ajasa, who was still a student when she heard the news and marched in protest against police brutality against Black people before becoming a Guardian contributor earlier this year. Amudalat looks back on how the crisis has changed her sense of her city and why she felt compelled to document the movement as it took shape.
They also discuss Amudalat’s interview with Chris Martin, the 19-year-old Black man who sold George Floyd a packet of cigarettes and then watched in disbelief as he died on the sidewalk outside. He told how he wrestled with a sense of guilt over his decision to report that the $20 bill Floyd used to pay might be fake, and reflected on how the guilty verdicts after he testified at Derek Chauvin’s trial helped him understand he bore no responsibility.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Amudalat Ajasa; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive produced by Archie Bland and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[proxy-www]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341153</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/justjavac/proxy-www"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T19:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like a good trick. What if… a URL was…  a promise… that fetched said URL?
www.codepen.io.then((response) ={
  console.log(response);
});
That’s what @justjavac did with JavaScript Proxys. A clever trick, that. Don’t @ me about the practicality. Trick…
The post proxy-www appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340626</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wrangling-control-over-pdfs-with-the-adobe-pdf-embed-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T13:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By our last estimate, there are now more PDFs in the world than atoms in the universe (not verified by outside sources) so chances are, from time to time, you’re going to run into a PDF document or two. Browsers …
The post Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raymond Camden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG) From Scratch]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JSON in CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340599</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/json-in-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T22:29:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Neal tweeted a heck of a little CSS trick the other day, putting JSON inside CSS and plucking it out with JavaScript. Valid values for custom properties are quite liberal! So this looks for a CSS rule (e.g. a …
The post JSON in CSS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>