<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-02T00:31:19.518Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-02T00:31:19.518Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US halts all federal executions amid review of capital punishment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/us-federal-executions-halted-attorney-general</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/us-federal-executions-halted-attorney-general"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T00:08:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attorney general orders temporary pause following historic use of death penalty under Trump administration
The US justice department is halting all federal executions after a historic use of capital punishment by the Trump administration, which carried out 13 executions in six months.
The attorney general, Merrick Garland, ordered a temporary pause on Thursday, saying he was imposing a moratorium on federal executions while the justice department reviews its capital punishment policies and procedures.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Trick to Enable Printify Shipping Notifications for Orders in WooCommerce? Customer Notes.]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342994</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/the-trick-to-enable-printify-shipping-notifications-for-orders-in-woocommerce-customer-notes/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T00:02:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a super niche blog post. But it’s been on my list forever to write down because this caused me grief for far too long.
The setup is that you can use WooCommerce to sell things on a WordPress …
The post The Trick to Enable Printify Shipping Notifications for Orders in WooCommerce? Customer Notes. appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wildfires grow in northern California with smoke plumes visible from space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/california-wildfires-lava-salt-fire-smoke</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/california-wildfires-lava-salt-fire-smoke"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T23:58:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefighters battle blazes on multiple fronts in scenes reminiscent of last year’s record season
Hundreds of firefighters are battling in high heat against several wildfires in the forests of far northern California, where the flames have already forced many communities to evacuate.
Mount Shasta, the volcano that towers over the region, was shrouded on Thursday in a haze of smoke plumes so huge they could easily be seen in images from weather satellites in space.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s older than me’: Warholm breaks 29-year-old 400m hurdles world record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/its-older-than-me-warholm-breaks-29-year-old-400m-hurdles-world-record</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/its-older-than-me-warholm-breaks-29-year-old-400m-hurdles-world-record"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Norwegian beats Kevin Young’s mark in front of Oslo fans
Eilish McColgan takes Radcliffe’s British record in 5,000m

Karsten Warholm has finally taken down one of the oldest world records in athletics by beating Kevin Young’s 29-year-old 400m hurdles best in front of his home crowd in Oslo.
After powering home in 46.70sec to break the previous record by 0.07, the 25-year-old Norwegian described it as the “perfect moment” – but admitted he may have to go even quicker to win gold at the Olympics in Tokyo. Incredibly it was the 12th track and field world record set this year in the new era of super spikes. What made Warholm’s achievement particularly impressive was that he broke it running in his first race of the outdoor season.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robinhood sees rapid growth even amid lawsuits and historic fine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/robinhood-profits-ipo-lawsuits-fine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/robinhood-profits-ipo-lawsuits-fine"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:55:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trading platform has grown to more than $80bn in customer assets, Robinhood revealed as it prepares to go public
The trading platform Robinhood, which has gained notoriety for allowing amateur stock investors to play the market, has grown rapidly to more than $80bn in customer assets, it revealed as it prepares to go public, even as it faces dozens of lawsuits and a historic fine over its business practices.
The app that has sent a newly empowered generation of investors to Wall Street saw its revenue soar 309% at the start of the year as a frenzy over so-called meme stocks shook the market.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden comforts ‘amazing, resilient’ families at site of Miami condo collapse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/miami-condo-collapse-joe-biden-visit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/miami-condo-collapse-joe-biden-visit"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:43:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden speaks to grieving relatives and tells of admiration
President and first lady also give thanks to first responders

Joe Biden spent several hours on Thursday comforting grieving relatives at the site of last week’s deadly Miami condo collapse, speaking of his admiration for their fortitude as their agonizing wait for news goes on.
The president and first lady Jill Biden also met with teams of first responders and rescue workers who have been searching painstakingly but fruitlessly for survivors in the rubble of Surfside’s Champlain Towers South for more than a week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Normal’ Jack Grealish revelling in role as England fans’ favourite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/normal-jack-grealish-revelling-in-role-as-england-fans-favourite</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/normal-jack-grealish-revelling-in-role-as-england-fans-favourite"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:30:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aston Villa playmaker set up second goal against Germany and would have been a club promoter in another life
Jack Grealish saunters over, a little tousled, looking as if he has just woken, which he confirms he has. It is 4.30pm at St George’s Park, the England midfielder is late for his media interview – actually he is really late – and, deadlines being deadlines, his audience is shifting uncomfortably. “Yeah, every day, I have my afternoon nap … I ain’t the same man without it,” Grealish says, with a wink.
 Related: Declan Rice’s tightrope skills help England hit the heights at Euro 2020 | Jacob Steinberg 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK residents have tickets cancelled for England’s Euro 2020 Rome quarter-final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/uk-residents-have-tickets-cancelled-for-england-quarterfinal-in-rome</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/uk-residents-have-tickets-cancelled-for-england-quarterfinal-in-rome"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:21:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Uefa acts on request from Italian government
• England to face Ukraine at Rome’s Stadio d’Olimpico
England fans resident in the UK who had precious tickets for the Euro 2020 quarter-final have seen them cancelled at the request of the Italian government.
 Related: ‘Normal’ Jack Grealish revelling in role as England fans’ favourite 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul MacInnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British teenager Emma Raducanu extends thrilling Wimbledon debut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/emma-raducanus-talent-and-poise-keep-dream-wimbledon-debut-rolling-on</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/emma-raducanus-talent-and-poise-keep-dream-wimbledon-debut-rolling-on"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:07:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wildcard beats 2019 French Open finalist Marketa Vondrousova
Skupski brothers earn first win since Ken’s blood clot

In the 44 years since Virginia Wade became the most recent British woman to win Wimbledon, there have been many excellent performances from outstanding prospects at the All England Club. Not all of them have gone on to have big careers but in Emma Raducanu, we may just have uncovered the genuine article.
 Related: ‘Three foot’ Ashleigh Barty battles through with Coco Gauff on horizon 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Cambers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer shrugs off leadership threats as Batley and Spen polls close]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/angela-rayner-forced-to-deny-plans-for-labour-leadership-bid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/angela-rayner-forced-to-deny-plans-for-labour-leadership-bid"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T21:05:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Modest’ signs of hope for Labour following a day of speculation over potential leadership challenge
Keir Starmer’s team insisted they were “relaxed” about the potential for a backlash after the Batley and Spen byelection on Thursday night, amid signs of hope for Labour on the ground.
Scores of MPs descended on the Yorkshire constituency on a sunny day to canvass for Kim Leadbeater, the sister of murdered MP Jo Cox, as senior party figures reported a modest shift towards Labour in recent days.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heather Stewart Political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curran and Morgan guide England to easy ODI series win against Sri Lanka]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/england-sri-lanka-second-one-day-international-cricket-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/england-sri-lanka-second-one-day-international-cricket-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T20:20:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Second ODI: Sri Lanka 241-9; England 244-2
Sam Curran takes five international wickets for first time

Half-centuries from Jason Roy, Eoin Morgan and Joe Root powered England to another one-sided success against Sri Lanka, their eight-wicket win a fifth successive white-ball canter.
It also wrapped up victory in their three-match ODI series with a game to spare, and having prevailed in all three Twenty20 matches the side now heads to Bristol for Sunday’s final fixture in search of a two-format whitewash against thoroughly downhearted opponents.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Burnton at the Kia Oval</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US state department names more than 50 corrupt officials in Central America]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/us-state-department-central-america-corrupt-officials-list</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/us-state-department-central-america-corrupt-officials-list"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T20:05:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among most prominent figures are ex-Honduras president José Porfirio ‘Pepe’ Lobo Sosa and his wife, Rosa Elena Bonilla de Lobo
The US state department has named more than 50 current and former officials, including former presidents and active lawmakers, suspected of corruption or undermining democracy in three Central American countries.
 Related: 'Deeply alarming corruption': US bill would sanction Honduran president 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Guatemala City</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump Organization tax-crime charges: what it all means]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-tax-crime-charges-questions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-tax-crime-charges-questions"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The charges against the company and Allen Weisselberg seem small in scope – but experts say this could be just the beginning
After three years of investigations by New York’s top prosecutors against Donald Trump, many people in his circle and the sprawling Trump Organization business empire, it is perhaps no surprise to see charges finally laid in a New York courtroom.
 Related: Trump Organization CFO Allen Weisselberg pleads not guilty to tax crimes – live 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump Organization and senior executive charged with tax crimes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-allen-weisselberg-charged-tax-related-crimes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-allen-weisselberg-charged-tax-related-crimes"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charges mark a severe blow to ex-president’s family business
CFO Allen Weisselberg surrenders to authorities

The Trump Organization and its chief financial officer, Allen Weisselberg, have been charged with a “sweeping and audacious illegal payment scheme” of tax-related crimes, marking the first criminal charges against the former president’s company following a years-long investigation by New York prosecutors.
 Related: Allen Weisselberg: half of the dynamic duo running Trump’s business empire 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe and Victoria Bekiempis in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steven Yeun and Emerald Fennell among latest invited to be Academy members]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/academy-members-invited-steven-yeun-emerald-fennell</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/academy-members-invited-steven-yeun-emerald-fennell"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest inductees, including Laverne Cox and Issa Rae, are 46% female and 39% from under-represented racial communities
Minari star Steven Yeun, Promising Young Woman actor Laverne Cox and writer-director Emerald Fennell are among the 395 names invited to be Academy members this year.
The annual list, down in size from usual years (last year saw 819 invites), represents another step forward for the group with regards to diversity. The names included are 46% female and 39% from under-represented racial groups.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nissan hasn’t put UK ahead in electric race, it’s just off the starting grid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jul/01/nissan-hasnt-put-uk-ahead-in-electric-race-its-just-got-it-off-the-starting-grid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jul/01/nissan-hasnt-put-uk-ahead-in-electric-race-its-just-got-it-off-the-starting-grid"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:03:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First stage of the Nissan project in Sunderland is welcome but there is a very long way to go in this ‘race’

One can’t grumble too much about ministers’ ra-ra tone over Nissan’s plans to build an electric battery plant, or gigafactory, in Sunderland as part of a £1bn project. The investment is big, the first of its kind and 6,000 jobs are promised. Milking the moment is fair.
We don’t know precisely how much public money has been promised but, if the rumoured £100m is correct, the figure doesn’t sound widely different from what other European governments are throwing around to secure high-profile electric vehicle investments. Everyone’s at it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tomorrow War review – time stretches in Chris Pratt’s alien-invasion sci-fi]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/the-tomorrow-war-review-time-stretches-in-chris-pratts-alien-invasion-sci-fi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/the-tomorrow-war-review-time-stretches-in-chris-pratts-alien-invasion-sci-fi"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pratt plays a teacher turned pre-emptive conscript for a future war with aliens in this overlong and derivative actioner
We’ve come an awfully long way since Chris Pratt was the goofy comic turn Andy Dwyer in TV’s Parks and Recreation, pretending to be top-secret FBI agent Burt Macklin. These days he’s got the chops to be a tough, chiselled action lead who removes his shirt to reveal some serious work with the personal trainer, and this is how he’s presented in this great big overstuffed and overlong sci-fi action thriller from former animation director Chris McKay. In Guardians of the Galaxy and Jurassic World, Pratt had at least some residue of his former comedy existence, and to be fair there are one or two funny lines here (coming largely from JK Simmons, playing Pratt’s grumpy yet adorable dad), but this is a very earnest and generic lead performance.
Pratt plays Dan Forester, an idealistic soldier-turned-high school teacher with a wife and young daughter; he lives in an America that is suddenly terrified by visitors from the future who reveal that in 30 years’ time Earth will be attacked by weird, white, lizard-like creatures (not a million miles away from those in the sci-fi horror A Quiet Place). Humanity is so low on soldiers that they have to time-travel into the past to recruit more personnel and bring them into the future to fight this “tomorrow war” against the alien creatures. And Dan is duly drafted into the head-spinningly weird conflict, coming into contact with fellow warriors like cheerfully nerdy Charlie (Sam Richardson), tough and cynical Dorian (Edwin Hodge) and also Norah (Mary Lynn Rajskub). But most importantly there is the charismatic female commanding officer, played by Yvonne Strahovski (from The Handmaid’s Tale). The encounter messes with Dan’s mind: you’ve heard of back to the future, but this is forward to the past, or maybe sideways to the next generation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As You Like It review – eco-Shakespeare makes case for rewilding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jul/01/as-you-like-it-review-watermill-theatre-newbury-eco-shakespeare</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jul/01/as-you-like-it-review-watermill-theatre-newbury-eco-shakespeare"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watermill theatre, Newbury
With Paul Hart’s production blending into the theatre grounds, the pastoral comedy here becomes an effective vehicle to reflect on our relationship with nature 
It is not often you hear Taylor Swift and the Beach Boys in Shakespeare. But pop music works up the romantic atmosphere in Yolanda Mercy’s adaptation of the pastoral comedy, directed by Paul Hart. Staged in the Watermill’s verdant grounds (weeping willows, ducks, gushing water), the actors sing and play a blend of folksy guitar, ukulele, bass, harp and flute.
Its bigger message is on environmental change and Katie Lias’s set design carries that symbolism: the court, filled with empty oil drums, is part construction site and part derelict greenhouse where characters wear hard-hats and hi-vis vests. The lush forest of Arden blends into the theatre’s grounds so that we are not only told that “all the world’s a stage” but understand that this stage is our own world, too, and needs rewilding. Actors walk among us to blur the boundaries further.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arifa Akbar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on Boris Johnson’s visit to Nissan in Sunderland– cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jul/01/steve-bell-on-boris-johnsons-visit-to-nissan-in-sunderland-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jul/01/steve-bell-on-boris-johnsons-visit-to-nissan-in-sunderland-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T19:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ministers plan to end social distancing in England on 19 July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/ministers-plan-to-end-social-distancing-in-england-on-19-july</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/ministers-plan-to-end-social-distancing-in-england-on-19-july"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:56:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Masks may still be advised in some areas, as NHS bosses warn reopening may push up hospital admissions

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers are planning to remove all mandatory mask and social distancing restrictions in England on 19 July, but national guidance may still encourage caution in high-risk areas such as public transport.
A number of key scientific advisers including England’s chief medical officer, Chris Whitty, and the government’s chief scientific adviser, Patrick Vallance, are said to be behind ministers’ plans to lift restrictions, though they have cautioned that the NHS may come under pressure in the winter.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Denis Campbell and Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS for Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343637</id>
        <link href="https://web.dev/css-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:54:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The marketing for Core Web Vitals (CWV) has been a massive success. I guess that’s what happens when the world’s dominant search engine tells people that something’s going to be an SEO factor. Ya know what language can play a …
The post CSS for Web Vitals appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU Commission urged to reject Hungary’s Covid recovery plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/eu-commission-urged-to-reject-hungary-covid-recovery-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/eu-commission-urged-to-reject-hungary-covid-recovery-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:54:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European Commission vice-president Frans Timmermans condemns Janez Janša’s claims of judicial bias
The opening of Slovenia’s presidency of the EU has descended into farce as the European Commission’s vice-president refused to be photographed with the country’s rightwing prime minister, Janez Janša, after a bitter behind-the-scenes row at a launch event.
During an opening meeting in the Slovenian capital, Ljubljana, with the 27 members of the commission, Janša had shown them a group photograph of a Slovenian judge with a Socialist and Democrat MEP and other members of the country’s Social Democrats party.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Ljubljana and Jennifer Rankin in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Platform on Digital Ocean]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342591</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/app-platform-on-digital-ocean/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:54:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is new stuff from DO.
App Platform is a hosting product, no surprise there, but it has some features that are Jamstack-inspired in the best possible way, and an additional set of unique and powerful features. Let’s start with …
The post App Platform on Digital Ocean appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global tax reform: 130 countries commit to minimum corporate rate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/global-tax-reform-130-countries-commit-to-minimum-corporate-rate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/global-tax-reform-130-countries-commit-to-minimum-corporate-rate"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:47:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Landmark moment for world economy with OECD plan that also covers prevention of profit-shifting
Efforts to force multinational companies to pay a fairer share of tax have taken a decisive step forward after 130 countries and jurisdictions agreed to plans for a global minimum corporate tax rate.
In a landmark moment for the world economy, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) issued a statement committing each of the countries to a two-pillar plan to radically reshape the global tax system.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Intrusive and cruel’: struggles in applying for UK settled status]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/intrusive-cruel-struggles-applying-uk-settled-status</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/intrusive-cruel-struggles-applying-uk-settled-status"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:33:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We speak to three people after late surge in EU citizens trying to meet  deadline for applications

Over 50,000 EU citizens apply for settled status in a day to beat deadline

There was a huge rush by EU citizens for UK settled status on Wednesday, with more than 50,000 people scrambling to beat the midnight deadline on 30 June, it has emerged.
The Home Office said that more than 5.6m applications had been received with 5m people granted settled or pre-settled status. We speak to three people who have been struggling with the process.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman and Lisa O'Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Website Theming? How to Use CSS Custom Properties and Gatsby.js to Customize Your Site]]></title>
        <id>60dc72b527f80207bcdbbd8f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/website-theming-with-css-custom-properties-and-gatsbyjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'm going to show you how to theme your website so users can customize certain elements to their tastes.  We'll talk about website themes, how theming works, and we'll end with a demo so you can see it in action. Let's dive in. Table of Contents:What]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haribo struggles to deliver to UK shops due to lorry driver shortage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/haribo-struggles-to-deliver-to-uk-shops-due-lorry-driver-shortage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/haribo-struggles-to-deliver-to-uk-shops-due-lorry-driver-shortage"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:08:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[German sweet maker has reportedly cancelled promotions on share bags as it tries to maintain availability
The lorry driver shortage could become tangfastically real for British children and their parents after the confectionery manufacturer Haribo told shopkeepers it was struggling to deliver enough bags of sweets.
Jelly babies, gummy bears and mini-fried eggs could all be affected as the German firm said it was having trouble getting its products to customers in the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham and Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MP queries watchdog’s ability to protect UK jobs amid private equity deals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/mp-queries-watchdog-cma-ability-protect-uk-jobs-private-equity-deals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/mp-queries-watchdog-cma-ability-protect-uk-jobs-private-equity-deals"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:05:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Business committee’s Darren Jones raises concerns over CMA’s powers as Morrisons is latest to be targeted
The head of an influential committee of MPs has raised concerns about regulators’ ability to protect jobs and customers during a spate of private equity takeovers of key British businesses, after Morrisons became one of the latest listed companies to receive a buyout offer.
Darren Jones, the chair of the business, energy and industrial strategy select committee, has written to the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) to ask the watchdog to clarify its powers to intervene “when new owners act irresponsibly”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on England and the union: we need to talk | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-view-on-england-and-the-union-we-need-to-talk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-view-on-england-and-the-union-we-need-to-talk"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:05:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Politics in Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland is focused on the way the UK is working. It is time the largest nation got more serious too
This country needs a serious conversation about England. Not about the England football team – that’s for another day. The conversation this country – the United Kingdom – needs is about England’s future political and constitutional relationship with the rest of the union.
A particular version of that conversation simmers perpetually in Northern Ireland. A dynamic one rages in Scotland. A third variation is developing in Wales. In England itself, the conversation lurks between niche and nonexistent. The issue is nevertheless latent. Its manifestations, refracted through issues including Brexit, are pored over by a minority. But the English question has rarely been explicit.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on replacing Simon Stevens: the NHS needs an expert | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-view-on-replacing-simon-stevens-the-nhs-needs-an-expert</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-view-on-replacing-simon-stevens-the-nhs-needs-an-expert"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:04:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The health service and the public face colossal risks. The last thing NHS England needs is a ministerial crony in charge 
It hardly needs saying that the appointment of a new chief executive to run NHS England is an enormously important moment. Sir Simon Stevens has run the service for seven years and his departure coincides with a shake-up. His successor will be a less powerful figure, who stands, in an upcoming health bill, to be stripped of the independence granted as part of the last round of Conservative reforms.
Giving control back to ministers was always a questionable move, particularly given the government’s record during the pandemic. Circumstances surrounding the departure of Matt Hancock have heightened concerns about cronyism. But the prospect of the service’s new boss being chosen by a newcomer, Sajid Javid, does not inspire confidence either (the task is undertaken jointly with NHS England’s board). At a time of great peril for the service and the 56 million people who rely on it (just 11% of the UK population are thought to have private health insurance), the situation is chaotic, with health minister Lord Bethell also facing questions about why he sponsored Gina Coladangelo for a parliamentary pass.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML List – How to Use Bullet Points, Ordered, and Unordered Lists]]></title>
        <id>60c0897ad3126007592d5701</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-list-how-to-use-bullet-points-ordered-and-unordered-lists/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Listing items on a web page is a common task you'll have to do as a web developer. You may have to list shopping cart items, the order of students based on their grades, dogs with the loudest bark – and so on. So you need to know the different ways]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour MP shares addiction struggles in Commons Pride debate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/labour-mp-shares-his-struggles-with-addiction-in-commons-debate-for-pride</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/labour-mp-shares-his-struggles-with-addiction-in-commons-debate-for-pride"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Be proud of who you are,’ Dan Carden urges young people as he recalls trauma of hiding his sexuality
An MP has fought back tears as he revealed his alcohol addiction twice nearly killed him amid the pressure of trying to hide his sexuality.
Labour’s Dan Carden urged young people to “be proud of who are you” and “[who] you choose to love” as he recalled the “constant fear of being found out” growing up LGBT.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for global treaty to end production of ‘virgin’ plastic by 2040]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/call-for-global-treaty-to-end-production-of-virgin-plastic-by-2040</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/call-for-global-treaty-to-end-production-of-virgin-plastic-by-2040"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists say agreement must cover extraction of raw materials and pollution that blights seas and land
A binding global treaty is needed to phase out the production of “virgin” or new plastic by 2040, scientists have said.
The solution to the blight of plastic pollution in the oceans and on land would be a worldwide agreement on limits and controls, they say in a special report in the journal Science.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandra Laville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pain and positivity: the fuel for Romelu Lukaku’s journey to the top | Ed Aarons]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/pain-and-positivity-the-fuel-for-romelu-lukakus-journey-to-the-top</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jul/01/pain-and-positivity-the-fuel-for-romelu-lukakus-journey-to-the-top"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belgium striker’s career path has not been straightforward but he takes on Italy as a hero in his homeland and a Serie A winner
Ariël Jacobs remembers vividly the day he realised Romelu Lukaku was something very special. The striker, having scored an incredible 131 goals in 94 matches for Anderlecht’s youth team, had been called up to train with the first team despite still having to attend school and being a few weeks from his 16th birthday.
“I had the chance to have some in-depth discussions with him and it became clear that as well as scoring lots of goals, Romelu’s second major quality, and one I could feel immediately, was his positive mindset,” says Jacobs, a former defender who spent five years as Anderlecht’s manager.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Aarons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French court orders government to act on climate in next nine months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/french-court-orders-government-to-act-on-climate-in-next-nine-months</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/french-court-orders-government-to-act-on-climate-in-next-nine-months"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:58:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Council of State says it will assess state’s actions after 31 March 2022, and could issue substantial fines
France’s top administrative court has ordered the government to take “all necessary additional steps” within the next nine months to enable it to reach its climate crisis targets or face possible sanctions, including substantial fines.
The Council of State said in a final ruling published on Thursday, with no possibility for appeal by the government, that France was not on track to meet its goal of achieving a 40% cut in emissions from 1990 levels by 2030.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jon Henley Europe correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Los Angeles police injure 17 in explosion after detonating fireworks they seized]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/los-angeles-police-fireworks-explosion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/los-angeles-police-fireworks-explosion"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department causes explosion on residential block, flipping cars and smashing windows
The Los Angeles police department detonated a cache of homemade fireworks it had seized, causing a major explosion on a residential block that injured 17 people, flipped and damaged cars and smashed windows in nearby homes.
It could take days to determine why what was supposed to be a safe operation to handle explosives that police said were too unstable to remove turned into a huge explosion.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fibromyalgia may be a condition of the immune system not the brain – study]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jul/01/fibromyalgia-may-be-a-condition-of-the-immune-system-not-the-brain-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jul/01/fibromyalgia-may-be-a-condition-of-the-immune-system-not-the-brain-study"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:41:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New research challenges widely held view of the condition and could pave way for better treatment
Fibromyalgia – a poorly understood condition that causes widespread pain throughout the body and extreme tiredness – may be caused by be an autoimmune response that increases the activity of pain-sensing nerves throughout the body.
The findings, published in the Journal of Clinical Investigation, challenge the widely held view that the condition originates in the brain, and could pave the way for more effective treatments for the millions of people affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda Geddes Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Murray faces true test of his fitness against Denis Shapovalov | Simon Cambers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/andy-murray-faces-true-test-of-his-fitness-against-denis-shapovalov</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/andy-murray-faces-true-test-of-his-fitness-against-denis-shapovalov"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:39:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two-time Wimbledon champion still feeling his way back from injury and Canadian 10th seed is a serious obstacle
In the 16 years since Andy Murray made his debut at Wimbledon, the Scot has experienced almost every emotion imaginable at the All England Club: from devastation and tears when he was beaten in the final by Roger Federer in 2012, to jubilation the following year when he won the title, more elation when he did so again in 2016 and sheer agony in 2017 when his sore hip finally began to give way.
 Related: ‘Pathetic’: Andy Murray slams 1% pay offer made to NHS workers 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Cambers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It was like the scene of a horror movie’: how Jaivet Ealom escaped from Manus Island]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/02/it-was-like-the-scene-of-a-horror-movie-how-jaivet-ealom-escaped-from-manus-island</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/02/it-was-like-the-scene-of-a-horror-movie-how-jaivet-ealom-escaped-from-manus-island"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After fleeing persecution in Myanmar, Ealom was detained in a ‘torture camp’. Using tricks learned from Prison Break, he snuck his way out
In 2013, when Jaivet Ealom sat squeezed in a boat with other asylum seekers, he prayed, not for the first time, for an easy death. They were far from shore off the coast of Indonesia, the vessel was sinking, and Ealom could not swim.
Fishermen from a nearby island came to the rescue, hauling each passenger from the half-submerged vessel. Ealom was saved. But during the chaos, a small baby fell into the ocean. “It never resurfaced,” remembers Ealom. “[The mother] just screamed from the bottom of her lungs. It was traumatising.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clarissa Sebag-Montefiore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Happy hookers’: how prescribing creativity might help wellbeing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/02/happy-hookers-how-prescribing-creativity-might-help-wellbeing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/02/happy-hookers-how-prescribing-creativity-might-help-wellbeing"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mental health professionals are exploring the benefits of creative hobbies – and referring their patients accordingly 
During press conferences signalling rising Covid-19 case numbers last week, a list of projects began percolating in my mind. The Peppermint pocket skirt, a Wattlebird jumpsuit, definitely the Hudson tracksuit pants.
Now locked down, my girls grab the whiteboard from my home office, rub out ‘Freelance Projects 2021’ and write a list for the school holidays; T-shirt decorating, play pirates, paint crazy things, bake a cake. I add sewing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jennifer Macey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AK Blakemore wins Desmond Elliott prize for ‘stunning’ debut novel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/01/ak-blakemore-wins-desmond-elliott-prize-debut-the-manningtree-witches</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/01/ak-blakemore-wins-desmond-elliott-prize-debut-the-manningtree-witches"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Manningtree Witches takes the £10,000 first novel award for its ‘clever and unexpected’ story of a 17th-century Suffolk village’s moral panic
AK Blakemore has won the Desmond Elliott prize for best debut, with her historical novel about the English witch trials of the 17th century, The Manningtree Witches, praised by judges as a “stunning achievement”.
Following the story of Rebecca West, who is husbandless, fatherless and barely tolerated by the villagers of Manningtree, Essex, the novel depicts the fallout as pious newcomer Matthew Hopkins begins to ask after the women on the margins of society. It is Blakemore’s first novel, although the author has previously published two collections of poetry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British rule in India: an abusive relationship | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/british-rule-in-india-an-abusive-relationship</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/british-rule-in-india-an-abusive-relationship"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:26:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arguments that ‘it was not all bad’ can quickly descend into a catalogue of justifications for atrocious acts and behaviours, writes Dr Nandini Boodia-Canoo. Plus letters from Geof Wood, John Griffiths and David Bentley
Amartya Sen has delivered a critical appraisal of British rule in India (Illusions of empire: Amartya Sen on what British rule really did for India, 29 June). Yet what is missing from his ponderings is a clear critique of the apologist arguments which underpin inquiries into the so-called “achievements” of colonialism.
Instead, he highlights an issue of methodology, namely the impossibility of envisaging an India in which British rule had not occurred. While Sen acknowledges the difficulty of such an evaluation, he finds merit in queries which seek to establish how India was lacking at the time of British conquest and how those deficiencies were met by the new rulers. He promptly embarks on such an examination.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Split infinitives: the English ‘rule’ that refuses to quietly die | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jul/01/split-infinitives-the-english-rule-that-refuses-to-quietly-die</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jul/01/split-infinitives-the-english-rule-that-refuses-to-quietly-die"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:25:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salley Vickers, Angelica Goodden, John Doherty, Eddy York and Barbara Benedict weigh in on an eternal linguistic debate
Re David Roberts’ letter deploring your use of a split infinitive (29 June); Fowler, the acknowledged authority on English usage, says: “The split infinitive is … best avoided, especially when it is stylistically awkward. But it is not a major error nor a grammatical blunder; it is acceptable, even necessary, when considerations of rhythm and clarity require it.” What’s good enough for Fowler is good enough for me.
Salley Vickers
London
• The “rule” about not splitting infinitives doesn’t apply to English: it derives from the mistaken notion that the English verb consists in a single word that mustn’t be interrupted in the middle, in common with Latin and the Romance languages derived from it. “To hardly try” is correct English; “to try hardly” is nonsense, and “hardly to try” in most contexts sounds formal. I always encourage students to write expressively, which often entails putting something (normally an adverb) between “to” and whatever verb is being used.
Angelica Goodden
Emeritus professor of French, University of Oxford
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US supreme court deals blow to voting rights by upholding Arizona restrictions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/us-voting-rights-supreme-court-arizona</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/us-voting-rights-supreme-court-arizona"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:18:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Court curbs challenges to restrictive laws on racial grounds
Justices uphold statutes that restrict mail-in ballots

The US supreme court has upheld two Arizona voting restrictions in a ruling that dealt a major blow to the Voting Rights Act, the landmark 1965 civil rights law designed to prevent voting discrimination.
In a 6-3 ruling, the justices upheld Arizona statutes that prohibit anyone other than a close family member or caregiver from collecting mail-in ballots, which are widely used in the state.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levine in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wales appoints UK’s first wildlife and rural crime coordinator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/wales-appoint-uk-first-wildlife-and-rural-crime-coordinator</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/wales-appoint-uk-first-wildlife-and-rural-crime-coordinator"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T17:09:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rob Taylor will work with police to fight crimes ranging from sabotage of an osprey nest to fly-tipping
His patch takes in mountain ranges, farmland, rivers, estuaries and almost 1,000 miles of coastline. His in-tray includes getting to the bottom of a dreadful act of sabotage on the nest of a spectacular bird of prey and making sure the arrival of tourists in the summer holidays does not lead to a spike in dog attacks on sheep and cattle.
The Welsh government on Thursday unveiled its wildlife and rural crime coordinator, the first role of its kind in the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump gonna Trump: ex-president diverts and deflects as legal woes mount]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-prosecutors-legal-woes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/trump-organization-prosecutors-legal-woes"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:59:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The former president appeared to mount a typically Trumpian bid to focus attention away from the growing scandal at his company
No one could accuse Donald Trump of lying low when the long arm of the law finally caught up with him.
On Wednesday the former US president visited the Mexico border, highlighting his favourite campaign issue, then held an hour-long televised town hall with Sean Hannity, his favourite Fox News host.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith Washington bureau chief</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid ‘perfect storm’ as more patients hit by fungal infections]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/01/covid-perfect-storm-as-more-patients-hit-by-fungal-infections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/01/covid-perfect-storm-as-more-patients-hit-by-fungal-infections"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weakened lungs and immune systems make people increasingly vulnerable, warn scientists

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A rash of cases of a rare “black fungus” infection affecting thousands of critically ill Covid patients in India caused alarm last month. Now scientists are warning that other dangerous or even deadly fungal infections have spawned in critically ill coronavirus patients globally, including in the UK.
Fungi are ubiquitous – in soil, water, air, faeces and human skin. Usually, people’s elaborate, adaptive immune systems are enough of a repellent but when that shield is weakened by disease, congenital conditions or age, they are far more vulnerable to microscopic assailants.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Everard vigil report further damages trust in Met chief, say activists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/inquiry-condemns-policing-of-sarah-everard-vigil-and-bristol-protests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/inquiry-condemns-policing-of-sarah-everard-vigil-and-bristol-protests"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:52:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reclaim These Streets says Cressida Dick ‘has led an organisation that has disregarded women’s rights’
The group that initially organised the London vigil for Sarah Everard has said a damning report by a cross-party group of MPs and peers about policing at the event has further undermined trust in the Met commissioner, Dame Cressida Dick.
The all-party parliamentary group on democracy and the constitution found the Metropolitan police’s actions and that of Avon and Somerset constabulary (A&SC) at “kill the bill” demonstrations in Bristol breached fundamental rights to protest and involved unnecessary and disproportionate use of force.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backend Web Development with Python - Full Course]]></title>
        <id>60d5e7ae6e1a1407b6b0bc5a</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/backend-web-development-with-python-full-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:51:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The backend of a website can be written in many different programming languages. It is becoming increasingly common for to use Python for the backend of a website. We just published a full backend web development with Python course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. This comprehensive course is for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gas supply crunch stirs fears of winter price hike in UK and Europe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/gas-supply-crunch-stirs-fears-of-winter-price-hike-in-uk-and-europe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/gas-supply-crunch-stirs-fears-of-winter-price-hike-in-uk-and-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:42:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reserves in storage facilities at record lows while cost of imports from global market continues to rise
A gas supply crunch in Europe has reignited fears over winter energy costs after market prices for the fossil fuel climbed to new highs across the UK and the Netherlands.
The market price for gas has soared by over 50% this year as reserves in storage facilities across Europe have dwindled to record lows, and the cost of importing shipments from the global market continues to climb.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An awkward, lifeless shrine – the Diana statue is a spiritless hunk of nonsense | Jonathan Jones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jul/01/the-diana-statue-ian-rank-broadley-sculpture</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jul/01/the-diana-statue-ian-rank-broadley-sculpture"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The only provocative thing about Ian Rank-Broadley’s characterless sculpture is how shamelessly it plays up to mawkish Diana worship
Ian Rank-Broadley’s statue of Diana, commissioned by her sons, was kept secret until its unveiling as if it might be wildly provocative. Looking through the artist’s previous oeuvre, I noticed he has a taste for the nude and created a statue for the late Felix Dennis called Lord Rochester, His Whore and a Monkey. That raised the fascinating prospect of a naked Diana for everyone to get furious about.
Instead, he’s let it all hang out in a different way. The sentiment splurges across the flower beds like an uncontrolled wail of artistically absurd pathos. A larger than life Diana, who stands in an awkward, stiff, lifeless pose and has a face that’s more manly than I remember, modelled apparently with thickly gloved hands and no photo to consult, protects two children in her arms while a third lurks behind her. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chess: 12-year-old Abhimanyu Mishra breaks youngest grandmaster record]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/chess-12-year-old-abhimanyu-mishra-breaks-youngest-grandmaster-record</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/chess-12-year-old-abhimanyu-mishra-breaks-youngest-grandmaster-record"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:33:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The American beat Sergey Karjakin’s 2002 mark in Budapest to take the record that has been held by Boris Spassky, Bobby Fischer and Judit Polgar
One of the most enduring chess records, Sergey Karjakin as the youngest grandmaster ever at 12 years seven months, was finally broken on Wednesday afternoon. Abhimanyu Mishra, from Englishtown, New Jersey, US, who was already the youngest ever international master at 10 years nine months, achieved his third and final GM norm at 12 years four months. Mishra achieved the 2500 rating requirement a few weeks ago, and his title will soon be confirmed by Fide. Mishra learned to play chess at two-and-a-half and became the youngest ever US expert at seven.
Karjakin’s record had narrowly survived serious attempts by India’s current generation of talents, but Mishra’s concentrated campaign, launched after the pandemic derailed his competitive play for the best part of a year, reached its target with 66 days to spare. His father’s key move was a one-way air ticket from the US to Budapest, which currently has a continuous series of GM and IM tournaments.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonard Barden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rumsfeld’s much-vaunted ‘courage’ was a smokescreen for lies, crime and death | Richard Wolffe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/donald-rumsfeld-defense-secretary-lies-crime-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/donald-rumsfeld-defense-secretary-lies-crime-death"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are still living with the catastrophic consequences of Rumsfeld and his gang. And it’s not as if this chain of events was unimaginable at the time
It is customary, at times like these, to gloss over the failures and foibles of recently deceased officials: to paint a portrait in broad brush strokes about their achievements and qualities and public service.
 Related: History unlikely to forgive Donald Rumsfeld’s Iraq warmongering 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Wolffe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten councils join scheme that could help Home Office deport rough sleepers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/ten-councils-join-scheme-that-could-help-home-office-deport-rough-sleepers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/ten-councils-join-scheme-that-could-help-home-office-deport-rough-sleepers"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:27:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data supplied by councils could be used to help remove foreign nationals from UK – either voluntarily or forcibly
Ten English local authorities have signed up to a controversial Home Office service that could lead to the removal of some migrant rough sleepers from the UK, the Guardian has learned.
A freedom of information response from the Home Office obtained by the Public Interest Law Centre has revealed that at least 10 councils have signed up to the Home Office’s Rough Sleepers Support Service between 15 September 2020 and 13 May 2021.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘No one has waited longer’: trailblazing female pilot Wally Funk will go to space with Bezos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/01/jeff-bezos-space-flight-pilot-wally-funk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/01/jeff-bezos-space-flight-pilot-wally-funk"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:22:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funk, who was denied the job of astronaut in the 1960s over her gender, will be the oldest person ever to travel into space
Wally Funk, a trailblazing female pilot denied the job of astronaut in the 1960s over her gender, will finally get the chance to fulfill her dreams of going into space.
Billionaire and Amazon founder Jeff Bezos announced Thursday on Instagram that Funk will be part of a four-person crew set to be launched into space by Blue Origin during a 10-minute flight on his rocket New Shepard later this month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Betancourt and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post-Brexit talks on City access to EU have stalled, Sunak reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/post-brexit-talks-on-city-access-to-eu-have-stalled-rishi-sunak-reveals-mansion-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/post-brexit-talks-on-city-access-to-eu-have-stalled-rishi-sunak-reveals-mansion-house"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Mansion House debut speech, chancellor sets out series of reforms in bid to help finance industry
Talks to secure City of London access to the EU have stalled, Rishi Sunak has confirmed in his first Mansion House speech to financiers, as he set out sweeping reforms designed to help Britain’s finance industry embrace global opportunities after Brexit.
Addressing a hand-picked gathering of 40 young financial workers at a slimmed-down version of what was, in the days before the pandemic, a landmark annual gathering, the chancellor said a deal on a comprehensive post-Brexit financial services settlement with the EU had not happened.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK drivers will no longer need insurance ‘green card’ in EU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/01/uk-drivers-insurance-green-card-eu-brexit-northern-ireland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/01/uk-drivers-insurance-green-card-eu-brexit-northern-ireland"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:15:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit requirement to be dropped for UK-registered vehicles, including those from Northern Ireland
Millions of UK motorists will no longer have to obtain an insurance “green card” before taking their car to EU countries after the requirement for extra Brexit-related paperwork was dropped.
The European Commission announced it had waived the obligation when it unveiled several other concessions designed to defuse tension around the implementation of the Northern Ireland protocol.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The pension triple-lock is an insult to the UK’s young people | Polly Toynbee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/pension-triple-lock-uk-young-people-boris-johnson-generations</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/pension-triple-lock-uk-young-people-boris-johnson-generations"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:12:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Boris Johnson panders to older voters, younger generations’ prospects are bleaker than ever
Here’s a tale of two generations, the pensioners and young workers. As the pandemic furlough winds down this week, one generation is destined for a mighty windfall from the government while the other gets nothing. The reason is clear: the Tories win three times more votes from one group than the other.
As of this week, employers start picking up the furlough bill, previously paid by the government, and many will let staff go, with their businesses still running on empty. Most of those losing jobs will be young people in the low-paid hospitality, arts, entertainment and tourism sectors, who, warns the Resolution Foundation, will struggle to find work: reports of worker shortages “have been overplayed”, and so have reports of steep pay rises. But those artificial pay-rise figures are about to deliver a bonanza for pensioners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Polly Toynbee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Met officers face gross misconduct inquiry over Bianca Williams search]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/met-officers-face-gross-misconduct-inquiry-over-bianca-williams-search</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/met-officers-face-gross-misconduct-inquiry-over-bianca-williams-search"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British sprinter and her partner were stopped by police in July 2020 while driving with three-month-old son
Police officers involved in the stopping, searching and handcuffing of the British sprinter Bianca Williams and her partner are now under investigation for gross misconduct over alleged racism and dishonesty, the Guardian has learned.
Williams and Ricardo dos Santos were stopped on 4 July last year in north-west London by officers from the Metropolitan police’s Territorial Support Group.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vikram Dodd Police and crime correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: previews and predictions for the quarter-finals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/who-scored-blog/2021/jul/01/euro-2020-previews-quarter-finals-switzerland-spain-belgium-italy-czech-denmark-ukraine-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/who-scored-blog/2021/jul/01/euro-2020-previews-quarter-finals-switzerland-spain-belgium-italy-czech-denmark-ukraine-england"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T16:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All the team news for Switzerland v Spain, Belgium v Italy, Czech Republic v Denmark and Ukraine v England
By Ben McAleer for WhoScored
The quarter-finals kick off on Friday afternoon, when the survivors of manic Monday meet in St Petersburg. Switzerland beat world champions France in a dramatic encounter in Romania in the last 16. After taking an early lead and then missing their chance to double it from the penalty spot, Switzerland had to fight back from 3-1 down to take the game to extra time before eventually winning on penalties.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben McAleer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tour de France: Mark Cavendish proves the comeback king of Châteauroux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/mark-cavendish-wins-remarkable-second-tour-de-france-stage-chateauroux-cycling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jul/01/mark-cavendish-wins-remarkable-second-tour-de-france-stage-chateauroux-cycling"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British rider makes it a hat-trick of victories in Châteauroux
Cavendish is only two wins shy of Eddy Merckx’s record

An irrepressible Mark Cavendish made it a hat-trick of wins in Châteauroux, blasting past his sprint rivals once more to claim his 32nd stage win in the Tour de France. Victory in stage six’s drag-strip finish, which he described as a “massive old-school Tour de France sprint”, demonstrated that the momentum once lost to his career has returned with a vengeance.
With two stage wins in three days, the rider whose form was so cold that he was virtually frozen out of cycling is now piping hot again. This time there were few tears, just jubilation, as he hugged his Deceuninck-Quick-Step teammates beyond the finish line.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Whittle in Châteauroux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remove Windrush payout scheme from Home Office, urges Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/remove-windrush-payout-scheme-from-home-office-urges-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/remove-windrush-payout-scheme-from-home-office-urges-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:52:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs highlight delays and difficulties in accessing compensation, in Commons debate marking Windrush Day
The Windrush compensation scheme should be removed from the Home Office’s administration and passed to another department, Labour has said during a parliamentary debate.
The Home Office minister Kit Malthouse rejected the proposal, arguing that it would cause disruption and further delays. He said the government was thinking about new ways to mark the contribution made by the Windrush generation. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Gentleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nowhere is safe, say scientists as extreme heat causes chaos in US and Canada]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/nowhere-is-safe-say-scientists-as-extreme-heat-causes-chaos-in-us-and-canada</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/nowhere-is-safe-say-scientists-as-extreme-heat-causes-chaos-in-us-and-canada"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:35:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Governments urged to ramp up efforts to tackle climate emergency as temperature records smashed
Climate scientists have said nowhere is safe from the kind of extreme heat events that have hit the western US and Canada in recent days and urged governments to dramatically ramp up their efforts to tackle the escalating climate emergency.
The devastating “heat dome” has caused temperatures to rise to almost 50C in Canada and has been linked to hundreds of deaths, melted power lines, buckled roads and wildfires.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Taylor and Leyland Cecco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highgate cemetery revamp to fell trees and open views across London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/highgate-cemetery-revamp-to-fell-trees-and-open-views-across-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/highgate-cemetery-revamp-to-fell-trees-and-open-views-across-london"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:29:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plan inspired by 1839 painting chosen for reshaping of historic but overgrown burial ground
Hundreds of “spindly” trees at Highgate cemetery are set to be felled under a proposed revamp that aims to open the famous burial ground to views across London.
The first images have been released showing how the final resting place of Karl Marx, George Eliot and Michael Faraday might look in future.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Weaver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 50,000 EU citizens apply for settled status in a day to beat deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/eu-citizens-scramble-beat-uk-settled-status-deadline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/eu-citizens-scramble-beat-uk-settled-status-deadline"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:12:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Home Office receives fivefold daily rise in applications as people tell of fear and anger

‘Intrusive and cruel’: struggles in applying for UK settled status

There was a fivefold increase in applications by EU citizens for UK settled status on Wednesday, with more than 50,000 people scrambling to beat the midnight deadline, it has emerged.
Such was the last-minute rush that the Home Office extended the time applications would be accepted to 9am on Thursday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[William and Harry unveil Diana statue at Kensington Palace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/william-and-harry-unveil-diana-statue-at-kensington-palace</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/01/william-and-harry-unveil-diana-statue-at-kensington-palace"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:07:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bronze artwork depicts princess flanked by children to represent ‘generational impact of her work’
The long-awaited statue of Diana, Princess of Wales was finally unveiled in a scaled-down ceremony on Thursday which saw the dukes of Cambridge and Sussex reunited in tribute to their mother, setting aside their recent differences.
On what would have been Diana’s 60th birthday, the brothers appeared together for the first time since the Duke of Edinburgh’s funeral, after Prince Harry flew in from California for the brief ceremony.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Europe’s first kosher ecohotel opens in Kent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/europe-first-kosher-eco-hotel-opens-in-kent-sadeh-farmhouse-jewish-traditions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/europe-first-kosher-eco-hotel-opens-in-kent-sadeh-farmhouse-jewish-traditions"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:43:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Environmental awareness and Jewish traditions are the focus of Sadeh Farmhouse, a family-friendly retreat near Orpington
It seems an unlikely place to find in Kent’s greenbelt, but Europe’s first kosher ecohotel is putting itself on the map with a mix of kibbutz-like vibe, Jewish values and environmental evangelism.
Sadeh Farmhouse (sadeh means field in Hebrew), in a 17th-century manor house just inside the M25 near Orpington, opened recently after major refurbishment transformed it from a residential activity centre for city schoolchildren to a rural ecoretreat for families.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the age of casual hugging could be over]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/hugs-covid-coronavirus-the-return</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/hugs-covid-coronavirus-the-return"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:43:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I know that when it’s safe, I’m going to be an enthusiastic hugger again. But I’ll first be asking if it’s OK
When I was 17, during a confessional campfire round-robin on a school trip, a teaching aide made a striking admission. “I don’t know when it suddenly became the thing to hug all of your friends, but I don’t really like hugging,” I remember her saying.
This eminently reasonable personal preference surprised me. In the mid-late aughts of my western Canadian adolescence, social hugging was so ubiquitous that it never occurred to me to question the practice. I hugged people frequently throughout my youth: my family, my schoolmates, the kindly lady who taught me piano.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrienne Matei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hack the “Deploy to Netlify” Button Using Environment Variables to Make a Customizable Site Generator]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343092</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hack-the-deploy-to-netlify-button-using-environment-variables-to-make-a-customizable-site-generator/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:40:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re anything like me, you like being lazy shortcuts. The “Deploy to Netlify” button allows me to take this lovely feature of my personality and be productive with it.

Clicking the button above lets me (or you!) instantly …
The post Hack the “Deploy to Netlify” Button Using Environment Variables to Make a Customizable Site Generator appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cassidy Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From classic to disposable: Gap UK closures reveal muddied identity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/from-classic-to-disposable-gap-uk-closures-reveal-muddied-identity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/01/from-classic-to-disposable-gap-uk-closures-reveal-muddied-identity"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:29:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time will tell if alliance with Kanye West and plans for online-only presence will pay off
The news that Gap is to close all 81 of its stores in the UK and Ireland will hardly come as a surprise to those in the fashion industry. Once a favourite of insiders looking for classic minimal pieces without the price tags of catwalk labels, its position has faded in recent years, replaced by brands including Arket, Weekday and Uniqlo.
Founded in 1969 in San Francisco, Gap came to the UK in 1987 and has long been known for American classics such as khakis, jeans and white T-shirts. After various sweatshop allegations in the 90s and early 00s, it positioned itself as the home of premium basics and kept its fashion relevance for a long time by balancing its blue-chip heritage with collaborations with buzzy young designers including Alexander Wang, Rodarte and Band of Outsiders. These names reworked classic designs that would showcase in slick adverts with supermodels including Liya Kebede.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Cochrane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure mounts on Bolsonaro amid rising anger over vaccine corruption scandal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/bolsonaro-brazil-vaccine-covid-scandal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/bolsonaro-brazil-vaccine-covid-scandal"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:24:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tens of thousands to demand Bolsonaro’s removal from office after incendiary reports on allegedly corrupt deals to acquire vaccines 
Jair Bolsonaro has been plunged into arguably the most treacherous moment of his presidency, as the Brazilian leader faces a snowballing scandal over allegedly corrupt Covid vaccine deals and mounting public rage over his handling of an epidemic that has killed more than half a million people.
Tens of thousands of protesters are expected to return to the streets on Saturday to demand Bolsonaro’s removal from office – the third such mass demonstration in just over a month. On Wednesday a curious coalition of left- and rightwing opponents submitted a fresh petition for Bolsonaro’s impeachment after the Brazilian media published incendiary claims about supposedly dodgy dealings to acquire coronavirus vaccines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips in Rio de Janeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ewan McGregor’s 20 best movie performances – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/ewan-mcgregors-20-best-performances-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/ewan-mcgregors-20-best-performances-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With his new film, The Birthday Cake, out next week, we take a look at the best roles of the Scottish actor – and no, Phantom Menace is not on it
Lip-syncing in Dennis Potter’s 1993 musical drama Lipstick on Your Collar was all very well. Crooning for real opposite Nicole Kidman, McGregor looks and sounds strained to say the least. But then his entire floundering performance represents a mere fender bump in Baz Luhrmann’s car crash of a musical. “His idea of conveying high emotion is to let his mouth hang wide open,” noted the critic Anthony Quinn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Gilbey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeremy Heywood’s widow questions Greensill inquiry chief’s independence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/jeremy-heywoods-widow-questions-greensill-inquiry-chiefs-independence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/jeremy-heywoods-widow-questions-greensill-inquiry-chiefs-independence"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T14:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Suzanne Heywood raises concerns about Boris Johnson’s appointee, Nigel Boardman
The widow of the man who was the UK’s top civil servant during the early years of the Greensill lobbying scandal has raised concerns over the independence of the official appointed by Boris Johnson to run an inquiry into the affair.
Suzanne Heywood, whose husband, Jeremy Heywood, was the cabinet secretary when the financier Lex Greensill entered Downing Street, questioned whether Nigel Boardman was the right person to run an inquiry into many conflicts of interest.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can we now live with the coronavirus? There are still no easy answers | Devi Sridhar]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/live-with-coronavirus-delta-variant-virus-children</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/live-with-coronavirus-delta-variant-virus-children"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:57:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Delta variant surging, questions about how to control infections, especially in children, are as urgent as ever

At the start of the pandemic, the ideal path – for those countries able to control their frontiers – was elimination of the virus within their borders pending the arrival of vaccines and treatments.
The UK didn’t make that choice – and it has paid the price in ways we know all too well. However, we’re now in a different phase, with highly effective and safe vaccines allowing us to work towards population immunity through inoculation rather than natural infection. We also find ourselves in the position of being a Petri dish for the latest variant, Delta, and how vaccines hold up against it. So far the signs are hopeful – but since the protection offered by one dose of the vaccine is much lower, there’s every incentive to get as many people double-jabbed as quickly as possible.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Devi Sridhar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brittany Howard: ‘I think back and I can’t even recognise that kid now’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jul/01/brittany-howard-i-think-back-and-i-cant-even-recognise-that-kid-now</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jul/01/brittany-howard-i-think-back-and-i-cant-even-recognise-that-kid-now"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:56:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing our series where stars recall their teenage obsessions, the Alabama Shakes frontwoman remembers fishing, home recording and leftfield spirituality
When I was 11 years old, I saw my first live band performance, in our old gym at school. Some kids who were four years older than me had a band and they played cover songs: Weezer, Pearl Jam, Nirvana – lots of grunge music. I remember thinking it was a superpower because they could make people dance. That’s when I knew that was what I wanted to do.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Stephanie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spain records surge in Covid cases among unvaccinated young people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/spain-records-surge-in-covid-cases-among-unvaccinated-young-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/spain-records-surge-in-covid-cases-among-unvaccinated-young-people"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:54:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Regions speed up plans to vaccinate under-30s as more than 1,000 cases traced to Mallorca school trip

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Authorities and health experts in Spain have called for prudence and responsibility amid a surge in cases among young people who are still waiting to be vaccinated after more than 1,000 Covid cases across the country were traced back to an end-of-year school trip to Mallorca.
Although more than a third of Spain’s 47 million people have been fully vaccinated against the coronavirus, case numbers have been rising over recent days – most notably among younger people still waiting to get their shots.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afghan civilians take up arms against Taliban as foreign troops depart]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/afghan-civilians-forced-to-fight-taliban-as-foreign-troops-depart</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/afghan-civilians-forced-to-fight-taliban-as-foreign-troops-depart"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:34:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Citizens react to spiralling violence with militants seizing at least 50 of county’s nearly 400 districts since May
Haji Ghoulam Farouq Siawshani watched the Taliban rampage across northern Afghanistan this month, weighing up the threat from militants on his doorstep. Then, 10 days ago, the former oil trader turned militia commander issued a call to arms.
“Where the Taliban go, they bring destruction, and they are one kilometre away from my village,” he told the Guardian. “We decided to respond.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Graham-Harrison in Gozara district, Afghanistan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘History’s on our side’: Turkish women fighting femicide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jul/01/historys-on-our-side-turkish-women-fighting-femicide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jul/01/historys-on-our-side-turkish-women-fighting-femicide"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:11:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Turkey quits the Istanbul convention, Gülsüm Kav’s group We Will Stop Femicide is helping keep women alive amid a rise in gender-based violence
“History is on our side,” says Gülsüm Kav. She leans in and speaks intensely. She has a lot to say: Kav helped create Turkey’s We Will Stop Femicide (WWSF) group, and has become one of the country’s leading feminist activists even as the political environment has grown more hostile.
Amid protests, Turkey withdrew from the Istanbul convention, the landmark international treaty to prevent violence against women and promote equality, on Thursday. The Turkish president, Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, has long attacked women’s rights and gender equality, suggesting that feminists “reject the concept of motherhood”, speaking out against abortion and even caesarean sections, and claiming that gender equality is “against nature”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruth Michaelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Not cricket’: Lib Dem Chesham victor says Tories recoiled from Johnson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/lib-dems-new-mp-sarah-green-happy-to-change-the-narrative-with-chesham-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jul/01/lib-dems-new-mp-sarah-green-happy-to-change-the-narrative-with-chesham-win"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T13:08:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Green’s explanation of her shock byelection victory has some troubling themes for the PM
Little more than a fortnight after pulling off one of the more remarkable byelection wins of recent years, the new MP for Chesham and Amersham, Sarah Green, is attempting something arguably just as difficult: setting up her parliamentary operation from scratch.
She has a temporary office and two staff on secondment from Liberal Democrat colleagues, but she also has to recruit employees for her Buckinghamshire constituency, where the party does not have a long-established presence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How residential schools in Canada robbed Indigenous children of their identity and lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jul/01/residential-schools-canada-indigenous-childrens-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jul/01/residential-schools-canada-indigenous-childrens-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T12:53:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Canada, more than 1,000 unmarked graves have been discovered on the grounds of former church-run residential schools, where an estimated 150,000 First Nations children were sent as part of a campaign of forced assimilation for more than a century until 1996. 
A historic truth and reconciliation commission was conducted in the 2000s. In 2015 it concluded that the residential school system amounted to cultural genocide and that unmarked graves would be found in the former school grounds, but the recent findings still shocked many Canadians and prompted calls for a new investigation. Leyland Cecco explains how the discovery is just the tip of the iceberg in uncovering Canada's traumatic colonial past
In Canada, Crisis Services Canada can be contacted at any time on 1.833.456.4566, or via text on 45645 from 4pm-12am ET  


Canada must reveal ‘undiscovered truths’ of residential schools to heal

 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leyland Cecco, Monika Cvorak, Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Poverty divides us’: gap between rich and poor poses threat to China]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/xi-jinping-gap-between-rich-and-poor-poses-biggest-threat-to-china</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/01/xi-jinping-gap-between-rich-and-poor-poses-biggest-threat-to-china"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T12:52:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xi Jinping himself has warned China’s wealth gap is not only economic but political and could threaten party’s legitimacy
When Wang Zhenyu moved out of his small village in central Henan province to the coastal city of Dalian at 18, he was astonished. “It was like a culture shock for me, even though it was just a big city in my country, not a foreign land.” A few years later when he was enrolled in Peking University as a graduate student, he found much fewer students in the country’s top university coming from a similar background to his.
Growing up in a small village of 2,000 farmers, many of Wang’s childhood friends dropped out of school after finishing their nine years of compulsory education. Now with a decent academic job, Wang begins to experience “reverse culture shock” every time he goes back to his village for the annual lunar new year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni China affairs corresponent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridges and bypasses win votes – but their ability to ‘level up’ Britain is less certain | Andy Beckett]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/bridges-bypasses-votes-level-up-britain-boris-johnson-build-north</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/bridges-bypasses-votes-level-up-britain-boris-johnson-build-north"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T12:47:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even if Boris Johnson comes good on promises to build big in the north, the economy’s centre of gravity will stay where it is
All governments love building things. Fascists, communists, social democrats, even conservatives who demand austerity in other matters – politicians can rarely resist the potential rewards of commissioning new infrastructure. From announcement to construction to opening, new public amenities provide ministers with multiple opportunities to show voters that their administration is making a difference.
“Infrastructure improves everyday life,” said the chancellor, Rishi Sunak, in March. “This is why I created the levelling-up fund … to invest £4.8bn in high-value local infrastructure.” Such investment, said the fund’s prospectus, was about “giving people pride in their…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Beckett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s A (Front-End Testing) Trap! Six Common Testing Pitfalls And How To Solve Them]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/07/frontend-testing-pitfalls/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/07/frontend-testing-pitfalls/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When writing front-end tests, you’ll find a lot of pitfalls along the way. In sum, they can lead to lousy maintainability, slow execution time, and — in the worst case — tests you cannot trust. But it doesn’t have to be that way. In this article, I will talk about common mistakes developers make, at least in my experience, and, of course, how to avoid them. Testing doesn’t need to be painful, after all.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ramona Schwering)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet Tooth: the prescient pandemic hit bringing joy to the masses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/01/sweet-tooth-netflix-apocalypse-pandemic-hit-nonso-anozie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/01/sweet-tooth-netflix-apocalypse-pandemic-hit-nonso-anozie"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T11:53:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Centred on a killer virus, Sweet Tooth could have been the most troubling TV to watch during Covid. Instead, as its creators and star Nonso Anozie attest, the Netflix show has become a smash because it’s so redemptive – and happy

The pandemic might not be over yet, but you can already trace a line through the culture it has produced. The overenthusiastic “let’s put on a show!” mania of cast reunions filmed over Zoom quickly gave way to the gnawing listlessness depicted in Bo Burnham’s comedy special Inside. Another part of the line, however, happened by accident.
Netflix’s Sweet Tooth is a series about a devastating global pandemic that kills millions of people and resets humanity. It was filmed last summer, in that brief golden gulp between Covid lockdowns. However, Sweet Tooth wasn’t rush-produced to reflect the situation; instead, it is based on a decade-old graphic novel and has been in development for five years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A royal fan and Hong Kong protest: Thursday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jul/01/royal-fan-hong-kong-protest-thursday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jul/01/royal-fan-hong-kong-protest-thursday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T11:41:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world

 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tamara Lawrance: ‘It’s OK to know you don’t want kids’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/tamara-lawrance-its-ok-to-know-you-dont-want-kids</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/01/tamara-lawrance-its-ok-to-know-you-dont-want-kids"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T11:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Horror film Kindred finds a pregnant young woman battling sinister in-laws –  not a position its star plans to find herself in. She explains why she’s drawn to strong, resilient characters
Tamara Lawrance says she has “very little desire to be pregnant” and, given the subject matter of her latest film, who can blame her? She stars in the dread-filled psychological horror Kindred as Charlotte, a young woman living in an isolated part of rural England, whose life plans go awry when she gets pregnant with her boyfriend (Edward Holcroft) and is taken into the quasi-care of his sinister family, in their crow-infested, crumbling mansion. Fiona Shaw makes for an imperious matriarch, while Jack Lowden is unnervingly obsequious as the black-sheep stepbrother.
“I really enjoyed the fact that [Charlotte] was not maternal,” says Lawrance, describing the allure of the script by writer-director Joe Marcantonio. “It’s an assumption that women are born with this innate, God-given inclination to take care of babies and there’s countless testimonies of that, but there’s also a wealth of other experience and evidence out there.” To be a woman aged anywhere between 25 and 45 is to be bombarded with images of maternal fulfilment, plus a constant stream of questions regarding one’s womb.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ellen E Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Themed trails around the UK – readers’ travel tips]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/themed-trails-around-the-uk-readers-travel-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/themed-trails-around-the-uk-readers-travel-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T10:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Toady and Ratty, modern art and something fantastically funereal … our tipsters’ favourite trails turn a walk into an event
I love to walk and be surrounded by nature but my children not so much. One thing we all love is the Wind in the Willows so when we saw there was a trail at Hanningfield reservoir in Essex, I was keen to try and get their little legs moving so we packed a picnic and set off in pursuit of Mr Toad and the gang. We bought a map for £1 which my youngest loved as it made him feel like a pirate! The walk was enjoyed by all as we excitedly spotted our favourite characters brilliantly carved from wood. Later we borrowed binoculars from the visitor centre to spot birds, which was an added bonus and extended the day nicely.
Tania Compton
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day in Britain that millions of neighbours become foreigners | Daniel Trilling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/britain-eu-settlement-scheme-european-citizens-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/britain-eu-settlement-scheme-european-citizens-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T10:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[However the government sugarcoats the EU settlement scheme, European citizens living in the UK will now be seen as outsiders
“We asked for workers, we got human beings instead,” was how the Swiss author Max Frisch summed up the “guest worker” schemes that helped wealthy European countries rebuild their economies after the second world war. His quip lives on because it expresses the absurdity of societies that treat immigration as purely a question of economic need, reducing people to units that can be moved here and there as capital sees fit.
However partial and flawed it may be, the EU’s system of internal free movement is an attempt to escape that trap. In stripping away the obstacles and restrictions that continue to govern migration for most of the world, it is an acknowledgment that when people move, they develop new attachments to the places they come to call home and to the people they come to call neighbours – and a wager that the best way to grow a shared sense of belonging is to make that process as easy as possible.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Trilling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Canada Day, let’s remember: this country was built on genocide | Mumilaaq Qaqqaq]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/this-canada-day-lets-remember-this-country-was-built-on-genocide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/01/this-canada-day-lets-remember-this-country-was-built-on-genocide"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports of unmarked graves of Indigenous children have shocked many Canadians. But these just confirmed what we knew all along
People across the country are waking up to the reality that Canada is a country built on the violent dispossession of Indigenous peoples. The horrifying reports of unmarked graves of children at residential “schools” in Kamloops, British Columbia, Brandon, Manitoba, and most recently Cowessess First Nation in Saskatchewan have shocked many Canadians and others around the world. However, these were not discoveries, but confirmations of what we knew all along: Canada was built on genocide.
 Related: The Guardian view on Canada’s residential schools: an atrocity still felt today | Editorial 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mumilaaq Qaqqaq</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big cats, vampire bats and a hapless chap called Matt – take the Thursday quiz]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia-july-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/01/the-guardian-thursday-quiz-general-knowledge-topical-news-trivia-july-1"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fifteen questions on general knowledge and topical news trivia plus a few jokes every Thursday – how will you fare?
Pinch, punch, first day of the month, and you’ve got a quiz to tackle. The usual drill – 15 questions, some topical, some general knowledge, some with jokes, some with weird facts, and one with anagrams just because we can. It’s only for fun and to pass the time, but let us know how you get on in the comments.
The Thursday quiz, No 10
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Belam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Threat to vulnerable Americans rises as Delta variant spreads]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/delta-variant-us-coronavirus-us-vulnerable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/01/delta-variant-us-coronavirus-us-vulnerable"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T10:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts worry that immunocompromised people and those who unable to access the vaccine have been forgotten
Just as the troubling Delta variant was spreading through the US, Charis Hill got a worrying call from their doctor.
The medications Hill takes to treat their spondylitis affect their immune system, and they knew the Covid-19 vaccine might not work as well for them as it does for others. So weeks after their second shot, they got a test.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edinburgh fringe: plans unveiled for far smaller ‘joyous’ festival]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/01/edinburgh-fringe-plans-unveiled-for-far-smaller-joyous-festival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/01/edinburgh-fringe-plans-unveiled-for-far-smaller-joyous-festival"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T09:15:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Venues include beaches, city squares and pedestrianised streets as organisers adapt to Covid rules

What to see at Edinburgh fringe 2021

The producers of the Edinburgh festival fringe are hoping for a “joyous, beautiful experience” after unveiling the schedule for a far smaller season of theatre, dance, comedy and music.
Tickets for this year’s fringe went on sale on Thursday morning with producers favouring outdoor venues such as beaches, city squares, courtyards and pedestrianised streets, as they adapt to Scotland’s stricter Covid lockdown rules.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Severin Carrell Scotland editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia ranks last for climate action among UN member countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/australia-ranks-last-for-climate-action-among-un-member-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jul/01/australia-ranks-last-for-climate-action-among-un-member-countries"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T09:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nation scores just 10 out of 100 on tackling fossil fuel emissions in new report on sustainable development goals
Australia has been ranked last for climate action out of nearly 200 countries in a report assessing progress towards global sustainable development goals.
The Sustainable Development Report 2021, first reported by Renew Economy, scored Australia last out of 193 United Nations member countries for action taken to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa Cox</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Six chickens somehow turned into 60!’ Meet the families trying to live the Good Life in the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/01/six-chickens-60-families-live-good-life-pandemic-grow-food</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/01/six-chickens-60-families-live-good-life-pandemic-grow-food"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T09:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many people yearn to grow their own food and live a simpler life – but, when coronavirus hit, some decided it was now or never. Have their dreams of burgeoning veg patches and frolicking livestock come true?
On their one-acre plot of Hertfordshire countryside, Sarah Apps and Liam Armstrong live with three chickens, 59 tomato plants and – until this morning – three pigs. “It’s been an emotional day,” says Apps. They plan to get more pigs later in the summer, and next week more chickens are arriving; then ducks and a goat, a couple of turkeys for Christmas and, maybe next year, bees. Living on their own land, and becoming more self-sufficient, had been a bit of a dream for the couple, but it took the Covid pandemic to make it happen. “You just didn’t know what was going to happen,” says Apps. “Young people were dying, older people were dying … I think you really need to live for the days that you’ve got.”
When they spotted a run-down bungalow that came with an acre of land, they went for it. They had been living in Romford, East London. “We could hear the roar of the M25 and I could barely be bothered to mow the small patch of lawn we had,” says Apps. They moved in November and spent the winter creating raised vegetable beds, putting in fencing and making animal enclosures. It has been gruelling physical work – they have done it mostly by hand – moving around 30 tonnes of soil. “It was our fitness thing through lockdown,” says Apps. But now they have growing just about every type of vegetable you’d find in a well-stocked supermarket, eggs every day, and in a few days the pigs will return for the freezer. She breaks off to check on a chicken who is in their kitchen. “She’s just had a bath. She’s not very well.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emine Saner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of Manchester’s best restaurants and food markets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/10-best-manchesters-restaurants-food-markets-street-food</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jul/01/10-best-manchesters-restaurants-food-markets-street-food"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Manchester international festival starting this week, we pick restaurants and street food venues to fuel the brain after all that culture
Starting on Thursday and running until 18 July, the Manchester international festival will see the city come alive with cultural activity. The central Festival Square will showcase good food too, from operators such as Neapolitan-style pizza perfectionists Honest Crust and high-quality chef and producer collective Eat Well MCR. But what of refuelling options across Manchester? Here are 10 standouts, from takeaways to ambitious restaurant dining.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tony Naylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From pedestrians to drag queens: everyday Africans – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/01/pedestrians-drag-queens-everyday-africans-in-pictures-photoespana-events-social-zanele-muholi</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/01/pedestrians-drag-queens-everyday-africans-in-pictures-photoespana-events-social-zanele-muholi"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Couples, shantytowns, refugees, soldiers … here are the highlights from Events of the Social, a show gathering together 10 years of images from Africa that’s currently at PHotoEspaña 2021
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese Communist party celebrates 100th anniversary – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/01/chinese-communist-party-celebrates-100th-anniversary-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/01/chinese-communist-party-celebrates-100th-anniversary-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T05:16:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since its origins in Shanghai in 1921, the Chinese communist party has grown to be one of the world’s most powerful political parties. It celebrated its 100th birthday on 1 July.
President Xi Jinping told a crowd of 70,000 in Beijing’s Tiananmen Square that the era of China being bullied was ‘gone forever’ and the country would not allow ‘sanctimonious preaching’ from foreign forces. Anyone who tried ‘will find themselves on a collision course with a steel wall forged by 1.4 billion people’
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Culture has been wrecked’: swimmers lament changes to Hampstead ponds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jul/01/culture-has-been-wrecked-swimmers-lament-changes-to-hampstead-ponds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jul/01/culture-has-been-wrecked-swimmers-lament-changes-to-hampstead-ponds"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T05:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New fees have saddened many who use the area to connect with friends and nature

Disabled woman begins legal action over Hampstead ponds fees

Micah Sami spent her teenage years swimming in the Hampstead ladies’ pond. The freedom to access the water, or sit in the meadow, helped her cope whenever she wasn’t feeling great.
But since the City of London Corporation (CoLC) enforced charges for the first time in the history of the ponds last year – and raised them again earlier this year, a move now the subject of a legal challenge – it doesn’t feel the same.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2021 New Coder Survey is Now Live – and Here&#x27;s How We Designed It]]></title>
        <id>60dc78e927f80207bcdbbddc</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/2021-new-coder-survey/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T04:36:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello freeCodeCamp community! I'm Dilan, a PhD candidate in sociology at Boston University. I'm an absolute coding newbie, but I do know a bit about surveys. 😃 I have been working with freeCodeCamp founder Quincy Larson over the past few months to design the 2021 New Coder Survey. And I'm thrilled]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a pro-democracy newspaper in Hong Kong died]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jul/01/how-a-pro-democracy-newspaper-in-hong-kong-died</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jul/01/how-a-pro-democracy-newspaper-in-hong-kong-died"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T02:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Daily was a beacon of free speech. Now it has been forced to close by China’s sweeping national security law. Does its demise signal a new chapter in Hong Kong?
Apple Daily is one of Hong Kong’s most popular newspapers, standing for freedom of speech and backing the city’s pro-democracy movement as it attempted to resist Beijing’s draconian national security law and wider attempts to muzzle dissent. Last week, after hundreds of police raided the publication’s headquarters, confiscated journalists’ laptops and arrested senior staff, it published its final edition. Even after many setbacks for activists, the closure of the newspaper has been seen as a significant development – and, some argue, the end of freedom of speech in the city.
Rachel Humphreys spoke to a journalist there as they worked to put out that last issue. And she hears from Helen Davidson, reporting from Taipei, about how events of the past fortnight have unfolded, and the Guardian’s China affairs correspondent, Vincent Ni, about what the closure says about Beijing’s approach to Hong Kong – and what signal it sends to China’s citizens about the perils of dissent.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Helen Davidson and Vincent Ni; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do you make a layout with pictures down one side of a page matched up with paragraphs on the other side?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343224</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-do-you-make-a-layout-with-pictures-down-one-side-of-a-page-matched-up-with-paragraphs-on-the-other-side/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T20:36:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I got this exact question in an email the other day, and I thought it would make a nice blog post because of how wonderfully satisfying this is to do in CSS these days. Plus we can sprinkle in polish …
The post How do you make a layout with pictures down one side of a page matched up with paragraphs on the other side? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn the CSS Box-Shadow Property by Coding a Beautiful Button ✨]]></title>
        <id>6063b8d69618b008528a9d79</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/css-box-shadow-property-with-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T18:49:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we're gonna learn how to use CSS's box-shadow property to make beautiful website components. Along the way, we'll create a button and get hands-on experience using this property. Let's get started. 🎖️ Table of Contents Why you should use the CSS box-shadow propertyThe syntax of the box-shadow propertyHow to make]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the heatwaves in the US and Canada?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/weather/2021/jun/30/heatwaves-us-canada-how-affected-you</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/weather/2021/jun/30/heatwaves-us-canada-how-affected-you"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T16:56:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those who live or work in areas that have been affected, as well as those working in the emergency services
Dozens of deaths have been linked to a record-breaking heatwave in the western US and Canada. The US president, Joe Biden, has blamed the climate crisis for also causing blackouts and wildfires. In Canada, the temperature hit 49.6C (121.1F) in the town of Lytton, British Columbia.
We would like to hear from those affected as well as those working in the emergency services.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It can be very lonely’: confessions of a customer service agent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/30/it-can-be-very-lonely-confessions-of-a-customer-service-agent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/30/it-can-be-very-lonely-confessions-of-a-customer-service-agent"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T15:08:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using digital technologies for less complex tasks can improve the lot of call centre workers, increasing job satisfaction and making time for proper interaction with customers
“I really enjoy my job,” says Sarah*, a customer service agent working for a public sector organisation, “but we’re treated terribly.” This statement will not come as a surprise to anyone who has worked in a similar role. Customer service agents typically have gruelling roles and often bear the brunt of people’s anger when things go wrong – even if the fault had nothing to do with them.
The daily deluge of irate and even abusive customers can take its toll, leaving agents feeling anxious and lonely. We spoke to anonymous customer service agents about their experiences and the impacts of doing such a job.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rae Ritchie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slack attack or productivity pro? Take our quiz to find out how you’re dealing with working from home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/30/slack-attack-or-productivity-pro-take-our-quiz-to-find-out-how-youre-dealing-with-working-from-home</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/30/slack-attack-or-productivity-pro-take-our-quiz-to-find-out-how-youre-dealing-with-working-from-home"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T15:05:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid working is set to become a permanent feature of life for many office workers. But are you rocking remote working or still struggling with your work-life balance? Test yourself with this quiz
Want to learn more about what’s next at work? Visit us at servicenow.co.uk
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah LaBrecque</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prom week in Ukraine: Michal Chelbin’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/30/katya-prom-week-ukraine-michal-chelbins-best-photograph</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/30/katya-prom-week-ukraine-michal-chelbins-best-photograph"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T14:58:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I went there to take pictures of kids at the end of their school years. Katya is dressed as a woman – but she’s still a girl’
Two things particularly have always drawn me in my work: teenagers and costumes. I am interested in the age, around 16 and 17, that is full of transition. During those years there is confusion everywhere: confusion about roles, confusion about gender. There are a lot of changes for people to deal with.
In 2008, I travelled to Ukraine to take pictures of kids during the week of their prom that marks the end of their school years. They are very young but they are entering a stage in their lives where they are expected to act like adults. The prom is an example of this. They don’t always feel comfortable in the clothes they’re wearing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When a Click is Not Just a Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343064</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/when-a-click-is-not-just-a-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T14:45:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The click event is quite simple and easy to use; you listen for the event and run code when the event is fired. It works on just about every HTML element there is, a core feature of the DOM API.…
The post When a Click is Not Just a Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Travis Almand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing a Bug in Low-Resolution Mode]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343182</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/fixing-a-bug-in-low-resolution-mode/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T14:44:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was working on a bug ticket the other day where it was reported that an icon was sitting low in a button. Just not aligned like it should be. I had to go on a little journey to figure …
The post Fixing a Bug in Low-Resolution Mode appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is The C Programming Language? A Tutorial for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>6055c55b687d62084bf68804</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-the-c-programming-language-beginner-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T14:25:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This tutorial is an overview of basic concepts of the C programming language.  It goes over the history of the language, why and where it is used, the compilation process, and some very basic programming concepts that are common in most popular programming languages. It is not a complete guide]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn React Router]]></title>
        <id>60d5ea736e1a1407b6b0bc8d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-react-router/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T14:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React Router is commonly used to make different routes for pages in React Applications. We just released a crash course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you how to create routes in your React applications. Piyush Agarwal developed this course. Piyush is a prolific course creator on]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living statues, cooling off and a rocket launch: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/30/living-statues-cooling-off-and-a-rocket-launch-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/30/living-statues-cooling-off-and-a-rocket-launch-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T13:17:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The State Of Web Workers In 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-workers-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-workers-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The web is single-threaded. This makes it increasingly hard to write smooth and responsive apps. Workers have a bad rep, but can be an important and useful tool in any web developer's toolbelt for these kinds of problems. Let’s get up to speed on Workers on the Web!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Surma)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Many Shades Of July (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-july-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-july-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s welcome July with some fresh desktop wallpapers. Designed by artists and designers from around the world, they are available with and without a calendar. Enjoy!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Record-breaking heatwave sweeps Canada – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/30/record-breaking-heatwave-sweeps-canada-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/30/record-breaking-heatwave-sweeps-canada-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T08:27:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A searing heatwave that settled over western Canada has been blamed for contributing to the deaths of dozens of people in the Vancouver area
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guy Lane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the Batley and Spen byelection turned toxic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/30/how-the-batley-and-spen-byelection-turned-toxic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/30/how-the-batley-and-spen-byelection-turned-toxic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T02:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maya Wolfe-Robinson visits the Labour-held West Yorkshire seat of Batley and Spen, which votes in an increasingly heated byelection tomorrow
When the Labour candidate Tracy Brabin won the race to be mayor of West Yorkshire in May, it meant she had to give up her seat in parliament representing Batley and Spen. The resulting byelection takes place tomorrow and the race to replace her as MP is far from assured for Labour. Their candidate Kim Leadbeater is sister of Jo Cox, the Batley and Spen MP murdered by a far-right terrorist in 2016. 
Maya Wolfe-Robinson tells Anushka Asthana how she has been visiting the constituency for weeks and describes an increasingly fraught campaign, which was upended by the entry of former Labour MP George Galloway into the race. His candidacy threatens to split the Labour vote by appealing directly to the area’s Muslim population on issues such as Palestinian rights and the crisis in Kashmir. Meanwhile, the Conservative candidate Ryan Stephenson is hoping to benefit from a reduced Labour vote that would allow him to add to Boris Johnson’s majority and take a seat last won by his party in 1992. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Maya Wolfe-Robinson and Alex Mistlin ; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does `font: 110%/1.4 system-ui` mean?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343470</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-does-font-110-1-4-system-ui-mean/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T22:43:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I use this line, or one like it, in a lot of quick demos. Not that it’s not a production-worthy line of code—I just tend to be a bit more explicit on bigger projects. 
html {
  font: 110%/1.4 system-ui;
}
…
The post What does `font: 110%/1.4 system-ui` mean? appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chromium spelling and grammar features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343260</id>
        <link href="https://www.azabani.com/2021/05/17/spelling-grammar.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T20:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Delan Azabani digs into the (hopefully) coming soon ::spelling-error and ::grammar-error pseudo selectors in CSS. Design control is always nice. Hey, if we can style scrollbars and style selected text, why not this?
The squiggly lines that indicate possible spelling or grammar errors 
…
The post Chromium spelling and grammar features appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding Interview Backtracking Problems Crash Course – The Only One You&#x27;ll Ever Need]]></title>
        <id>60db519527f80207bcdbb6fa</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/coding-interview-backtracking-problems-crash-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T20:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you are new to coding interviews or are already familiar with the concept of backtracking, this is the crash course for you. We will learn about an all-purpose coding template and apply it to two LeetCode hard problems. Ready to crunch your next coding interview? Let's go!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux List Processes – How to Check Running Processes]]></title>
        <id>604b8c6ea7946308b7687683</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/linux-list-processes-how-to-check-running-processes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T19:47:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every day, developers use various applications and run commands in the terminal. These applications can include a browser, code editor, terminal, video conferencing app, or music player.  For each of these software applications that you open or commands you run, it creates a process or task. One beautiful feature of]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use timedelta Objects in Python to Work with Dates]]></title>
        <id>60daf29027f80207bcdbb3fe</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-timedelta-objects-in-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T18:25:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why do we need the timedelta object?When you're working with dates and times in Python, you'll often use the datetime module.  In this post, we'll see how we can use the timedelta object in the datetime module. It denotes a span of time and can help when we need]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[:nth-child Between Two Fixed Indexes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342736</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/nth-child-between-two-fixed-indexes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T14:37:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I needed to select some elements between two fixed indexes the other day — like literally the second through fifth elements. Ironically, I have a whole post on “Useful :nth-child Recipes” but this wasn’t one of them. 
The answer, it …
The post :nth-child Between Two Fixed Indexes appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacking enlightenment: can ultrasound help you transcend reality? - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/video/2021/jun/29/hacking-enlightenment-can-ultrasound-help-you-transcend-reality</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/video/2021/jun/29/hacking-enlightenment-can-ultrasound-help-you-transcend-reality"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T11:06:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can technology improve the way we meditate? At the University of Arizona, Dr Jay Sanguinetti and master meditator Shinzen Young are using ultrasound to improve our ability to achieve mindfulness – as well as enhance our cognition and wellbeing. They believe it could revolutionise the way we treat those with depression and trauma. But as investors from Silicon Valley become interested in the technology, the pair are fighting to make sure the device is used in the right way and for the right reasons.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lina Lyte Plioplyte, Tom Silverstone and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Down Bulky Builds With Netlify And Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/breaking-down-bulky-builds-netlify-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/breaking-down-bulky-builds-netlify-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Static Generation is great for performance — until the app gets too big and build-times go through the roof. Today, we’ll have a look at how Netlify’s fresh On-Demand Builders can fix that.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young people: share your thoughts on double vaccinations and travelling abroad]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/29/share-your-thoughts-on-double-vaccinations-and-travelling-abroad</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/29/share-your-thoughts-on-double-vaccinations-and-travelling-abroad"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T10:09:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear what you think about some countries requiring travellers to be double jabbed to avoid quarantining on arrival
Portugal is the latest country to require travellers to be double vaccinated in order to avoid quarantining for two weeks on arrival. Some have expressed concern that young people will be unable to travel to countries that older people who have been double jabbed will be able to.
We would like to hear form young people over the age 18 about your thoughts on double vaccinations and travelling abroad. Are you still waiting to receive your second jab? How do you feel about not being able to travel if you have not been fully vaccinated? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 40 Mike Cavaliere: What Is Chakra UI For React?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-40/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-40/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T05:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about Chakra UI. What is it and how can it help with your React projects? Drew McLellan talks to expert Mike Cavaliere to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock’s downfall]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/29/matt-hancock-downfall-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/29/matt-hancock-downfall-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T02:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson has a new health secretary this week after the resignation of the man tasked with leading the government’s Covid response. But there are plenty of unanswered questions, says Jonathan Freedland
When Britain awoke on Friday morning to tabloid pictures of the health secretary, Matt Hancock, in a ‘steamy clinch’ with a colleague, it was clear that his career hung by a thread. He had been a harsh critic of other prominent figures breaking lockdown rules, and here was what appeared to be a clear breach of his own social distancing guidelines. Later that day he was given the backing of the prime minister, who considered the matter closed. It was anything but. 
The following morning saw the release of a full CCTV version of the incident in his office, and on the airwaves there was a distinct lack of colleagues willing to support him. Later that day his resignation letter was accepted by Boris Johnson. Hancock was gone. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Jonathan Freedland; produced by Alex Atack, Elizabeth Cassin and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[System *Things]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343040</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/system-things/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T22:14:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I think we’re all largely aware of colors like this:
color: OldLace;
background: rebeccapurple;
I guess you’d just call those “named colors” in CSS. 
Those aren’t the only kind of named colors there are though. Some of them are …
The post System *Things appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working around the viewport-based fluid typography bug in Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343139</id>
        <link href="https://www.sarasoueidan.com/blog/safari-fluid-typography-bug-fix/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T21:17:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sara digs into a bug I happened to have mentioned back in 2012 where fluid type didn’t resize when the browser window resized. Back then, it affected Chrome 20 and Safari 6, but the bug still persists today in Safari …
The post Working around the viewport-based fluid typography bug in Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Positioning Overlay Content with CSS Grid]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342971</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/positioning-overlay-content-with-css-grid/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T14:25:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not news to any web developer in 2021: CSS Grid is an incredibly powerful tool for creating complex, distinct two-dimensional modern web layouts.
Recently, I have been experimenting with CSS Grid and alignment properties to create component layouts that …
The post Positioning Overlay Content with CSS Grid appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan Mulligan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Organizations Should Consider Building a Website Backed by a CRM Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=343072</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/scaling-organizations-should-consider-building-a-website-backed-by-a-crm-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T13:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To make some terminology clear here:
CMS = Content Management System
CRM = Customer Relationship Management
Both are essentially database-backed systems for managing data. HubSpot is both, and much more. Where a CMS might be very focused on content and …
The post Scaling Organizations Should Consider Building a Website Backed by a CRM Platform appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Custom Emmet Snippets In VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/custom-emmet-snippets-vscode/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/custom-emmet-snippets-vscode/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Manuel explains why Emmet is one of his favorite productivity tools for writing HTML and CSS, and how you can create custom Emmet snippets in Visual Studio Code to help you improve your front-end workflows even more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Manuel Matuzović)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is chronic pain and how does it work? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/28/what-is-chronic-pain-and-how-does-it-work-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/28/what-is-chronic-pain-and-how-does-it-work-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T05:08:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For years people with conditions such as fibromyalgia or bad back pain – to name just two – have been told the pain is all in their head. With no obvious physical symptoms, nociplastic pain can be difficult to diagnose but its effects are very, very real. Research suggests that the immune system plays a role in nociplastic pain, giving people 'feel bad' symptoms including fatigue, anxiety and nausea

Sufferers of chronic pain have long been told it’s all in their head. We now know that’s wrong
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Fanner, Laura Murphy-Oates Gabrielle Jackson Marni Cordell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Property Brain Twisters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=342718</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-property-brain-twisters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:39:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am part of that 82% that got the answer to Lea Verou's quiz wrong. Stephen Shaw posted a similar quiz as well and it's a fun exercise sharpen your CSS chops.
The post Custom Property Brain Twisters appeared first on CSS-Tricks. You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anywhere but Westminster: 10 years in 10 minutes – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/jun/25/anywhere-but-westminster-10-years-in-10-minutes-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:47:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a decade of reports from all over the UK, the Guardian's flagship video series has won this year's Orwell prize for political journalism. Here, John Harris and John Domokos collect the highlights of their journey and ask viewers a simple question: where should they go next?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris and Noah Payne-Frank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating A Multi-Author Blog With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/creating-multi-author-blog-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article explains how we can connect different types of content in a Next.js application. With this technique, we can add any kind of one-to-one, one-to-many, or even many-to-many relationship to our projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Dom Habersack)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Run A UX Audit For A Major EdTech Platform (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/ux-audit-edtech-platform-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article is a case study of how a UX audit affects a UI. It explains how a famous educational platform can be analyzed edX against Jakob Nielsen’s usability guidelines. To get started, Mark Lankmiller shares all of the criteria and metrics he used for his UX audit.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mark Lankmilier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How trans kids' rights are under attack in the US – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/jun/25/how-trans-kids-rights-are-under-attack-in-america-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T07:39:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the first day of Pride month, the governor of Florida signed a law banning transgender girls from joining girls’ sports teams in schools and colleges. It was just one of 13 anti-trans bills conservative lawmakers in the US passed this year – and one of more than 110 proposed bills, many of which also target access to gender-affirming healthcare. This is by far the largest number filed in a single year in US history.
Guardian LA correspondent, Sam Levin, and Prof Jules Gill-Peterson, a historian and expert on trans kids, examine how this legislative attack has escalated and how the presence of trans kids in America is not a new phenomenon

Mapping the anti-trans laws sweeping America: ‘A war on 100 fronts’

In the US, the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255. In the UK and Ireland, Samaritans can be contacted on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org or jo@samaritans.ie. In Australia, the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears and her battle for freedom: what we know so far – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/video/2021/jun/24/britney-spears-what-we-know-so-far-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:31:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britney Spears has spoken out publicly for the first time against the controversial legal arrangement that has stripped her of independence for 13 years – and handed control of her estate, career and aspects of her personal life to her father, Jamie Spears, who also at times had authority over her medical and mental health treatment. 

The 39-year-old delivered an emotional speech to a Los Angeles court on Wednesday 23 June, saying she has been forced to work against her will, and that the conservatorship has blocked her from getting married and from having her IUD birth control removed so she could try to have another child. She added: 'I just want my life back.'
Her allegations were detailed and disturbing, and will fuel the growing #FreeBritney movement, as Guardian US correspondent Sam Levin explains.

‘Denied a baby’: key claims from Britney Spears testimony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rise Of Design Thinking As A Problem Solving Strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-thinking-problem-solving-strategy/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the dynamic and unpredictable environments in which we work, even the most carefully crafted solutions can have a short shelf life. When we accept that our work is impermanent and our problem-solving abilities are limited, our goal can shift from delivering full solutions to developing tools that empower our users to adaptively design for themselves.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Josh Singer)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you an EU citizen waiting to be granted settled status in the UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/23/tell-us-are-you-an-eu-citizen-waiting-to-be-granted-settled-status-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/23/tell-us-are-you-an-eu-citizen-waiting-to-be-granted-settled-status-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T15:18:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from people with EU citizenship living in the UK who have applied for settled status but are still awaiting a decision by the Home Office
With a week to go before the cut-off date of 30 June, we’re keen to hear from people who have applied for the EU Settlement Scheme, but still awaiting status decisions due to the Home Office backlog in processing applications.
We are also interested in hearing from EU citizens who have wrongly been told by councils, NHS staff or landlords that they are not eligible for a service because they do not yet have settled or pre-settled status, despite being in the process of applying.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Online Workshops (July-October 2021)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/new-smashing-online-workshops-frontend-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frontend and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run [online workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automating Screen Reader Testing On macOS Using Auto VO]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/automating-screen-reader-testing-macos-autovo/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Automated testing is an important part of any software project, including testing for accessibility. There are already tools for linting and integration testing accessibility, but what about end-to-end testing with real assistive technology? Since I hadn’t seen this before, I set out to build Auto VO, a driver for the VoiceOver screen reader.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cameron Cundiff)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing With Code: A Modern Approach To Design (Development Challenges)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/design-code-modern-approach-development-challenges/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of innovation in both tools and processes, the struggle between design and development is still real. This article focuses on the best practices for improving the design to development processes and how cutting-edge solutions, such as UXPin powered by Merge technology, can help in facilitating the change.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image To Text Conversion With React And Tesseract.js (OCR)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-text-conversion-react-tesseract-js-ocr/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have to process data manually because it is served through images or scanned documents? An image-to-text conversion makes it possible to extract text from images to automate the processing of texts on images, videos, and scanned documents. In this article, we look at how to convert an image to text with React and Tesseract.js(OCR), preprocess images, and deal with the limitations of Tesseract (OCR).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ayobami Ogundiran)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Alternative Voice UI To Voice Assistants]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/alternative-voice-ui-voice-assistants/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistants are currently the most popular use case for voice user interfaces. However, due to the bad feedback loop resulting from voice assistants can only solve simple user tasks such as setting an alarm or playing music. In order for voice user interfaces to really break through, feedback to the user must be visual, not auditive.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ottomatias Peura)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client-Side Routing In Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/client-side-routing-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js has a file-based routing system in which each page automatically becomes a route based on its file name. This article will guide you through almost everything you need to know about Routing in Next.js and point you in the direction of related topics and concepts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adebiyi Adedotun)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: were you affected by the 2011 England riots?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/17/tell-us-were-you-affected-by-the-2011-england-riots"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is 10 years since the riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester. We would like to hear from those who witnessed them
This year marks the tenth anniversary of the 2011 riots in London, Birmingham and Manchester which followed protests after the police shooting of Mark Duggan. We would like to hear from those affected – including witnesses, former police officers, and people who participated. How did the riots affect you? What is your perspective now?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Image Is Probably Not Decorative]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/img-alt-attribute-alternate-description-decorative/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Image placement on the modern web is highly intentional, helping to communicate the overall purpose of a page or view. This means that nearly every image you declare needs to have an alternate description.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eric Bailey)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Accessibility Tooling]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/complete-guide-accessibility-tooling/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a new short series of posts, we highlight some of the useful tools and techniques for developers and designers. Recently we’ve covered HTML Emails and SVG Generators. This time we look into different kinds of tools to help you streamline your accessibility testing process. Don’t miss the next one.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nic Chan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spinning Up Multiple WordPress Sites Locally With DevKinsta]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/multiple-wordpress-sites-locally-devkinsta/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T10:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When developing themes and plugins for WordPress, we need to test them in different environments. How can we create multiple testing sites on our computer, quickly and easily, without having to become a sysadmin?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 39 With Addy Osmani: Image Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-39/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we’re talking about image optimization. What steps should we follow for performant images in 2021? We talk to expert Addy Osmani to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When CSS Isn’t Enough: JavaScript Requirements For Accessible Components]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/css-javascript-requirements-accessible-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spoiler alert: tooltips, modals, tabs, carousels, and dropdown menus are some of the user interface components that require more than CSS. To ensure accessibility of your interface, JavaScript is a necessary addition to accomplish focus management, respond to keyboard events, and toggle ARIA attributes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: Making Use Of Audio]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/web-design-done-well-audio/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design often revolves around visuals, but the other senses deserve love too. In this article, we tune in to audio features that are making sites sing.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful Front-End Boilerplates And Starter Kits]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/useful-frontend-boilerplates-starter-kits/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t need to write everything from scratch every single time. With boilerplates and starter kits, we can set up our projects faster, and get to work immediately.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Front-End Auditing Tools I Discovered Recently]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/three-frontend-auditing-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building a faster website can be a rocket task these days. There are so many things to consider, so it’s challenging to get everything right. Here are some less-known tools that might help you get there.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stefan Judis)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Gaza street, 43 deaths: ‘The real war is the aftermath' – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/10/one-gaza-street-43-deaths-the-real-war-is-the-aftermath-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T11:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Omar Abu al-Ouf lost his parents, grandparents and two siblings when his building was bombed by the Israeli military last month, in a street where 43 people were killed. Two weeks after the 16-year-old was pulled from the rubble, he leaves hospital to visit his remaining family and return to what’s left of his devastated neighbourhood in Gaza City. Many of Omar’s neighbours also lost loved ones, and search through the rubble for possessions, after a war which killed more than 250 people in Israel and Gaza, the vast majority of them Palestinians 

‘One name in a long list’: the pointless death of another West Bank teenager
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fady Hanona, Christopher Cherry, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The way we work: how to manage hybrid teams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/04/the-way-we-work-how-to-manage-hybrid-teams</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/04/the-way-we-work-how-to-manage-hybrid-teams"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:27:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To maximise productivity and engagement, managers of hybrid teams should ensure that both onsite and remote employees are given the same experiences and opportunities

“Nobody knows exactly what the workplace is going to look like after the pandemic,” says Margreet Brenkman, ServiceNow’s area vice president of employee experience, EMEA. “But we do see a hybrid future – and hybrid teams and distributed work are going to be a big part of the way we work.”
The Covid-19 pandemic has been described by some as the greatest experiment in remote working the world has ever known. McKinsey now estimates that up to 25% of the workforces in advanced economies could work from home between three and five days a week.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhymer Rigby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the flow: meet the tech firm putting workflows at the heart of businesses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/04/in-the-flow-meet-the-tech-firm-putting-workflows-at-the-heart-of-businesses</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lets-workflow-it/2021/jun/04/in-the-flow-meet-the-tech-firm-putting-workflows-at-the-heart-of-businesses"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:25:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By automating many of the time-consuming, mundane processes involved in running a business, ServiceNow has become integral to some of the world’s biggest companies. Here, Jordi Ferrer, vice president and general manager UK&I, explains how the cloud platform works
It’s easy to mock business and IT jargon. So much of it sits somewhere on the spectrum between meaningless and pointless. However, some words deserve their place in our everyday language because they are genuinely useful. They help us better understand the world of work.
One such term is workflow – a word coined 100 years ago to define the processes a piece of work passes through from initiation to completion. As well as being a useful shorthand, it’s crucial to the functioning of any business.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Pattenden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>