<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-07T00:54:20.943Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-07T00:54:20.943Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The darkest days are coming’: Myanmar’s journalists suffer at hands of junta]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/the-darkest-days-are-coming-myanmars-journalists-suffer-at-hands-of-junta</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/07/the-darkest-days-are-coming-myanmars-journalists-suffer-at-hands-of-junta"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T00:11:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalism has been outlawed in all but name since the coup, with reporters and editors fleeing the country or leading double lives to survive
As a cyclone rolled over the Bay of Bengal on 24 May, American journalist Danny Fenster, 37, contemplated the brooding skies near a terminal window at Yangon international airport.
For a while, the threat of foreigners being seized at the airport by Myanmar’s military was real, but after watching international reporters exit the country safely in April, the Michigan native was more worried about turbulence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian reporter in Bangkok</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yuka Saso wins US Women’s Open after Lexi Thompson’s final day collapse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/yuka-saso-wins-us-womens-open-lexi-thompson-golf</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/yuka-saso-wins-us-womens-open-lexi-thompson-golf"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:57:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Saso becomes only the second teenager to win the US Open
Thompson held five-shot lead at one point on final day

Yuka Saso birdied the third playoff hole to beat Nasa Hataoka on Sunday and become the second teenager to win the US Women’s Open after Lexi Thompson collapsed down the stretch.
Saso overcame back-to-back double bogeys early in the round to make the playoff. She then won it with a 10ft putt on the ninth hole to become the first player from the Philippines to win a golf major. Saso matched 2008 winner Inbee Park as the youngest US Women’s Open champion at 19 years, 11 months and 17 days.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden to affirm US-UK special relationship at G7 meeting with Johnson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/biden-to-affirm-us-uk-special-relationship-at-g7-meeting-with-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/07/biden-to-affirm-us-uk-special-relationship-at-g7-meeting-with-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:54:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President also expected to discuss post-Brexit difficulties in Northern Ireland with the prime minister
Joe Biden has issued a statement pledging to affirm his “special relationship” with Britain when he meets Boris Johnson at this week’s G7 summit in the UK and discuss matters including the impasse in Northern Ireland.
In an article for the Washington Post published on Sunday before his first foreign travel trip as president, Biden wrote: “In the United Kingdom, after meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson to affirm the special relationship between our nations, I will participate in the G7 summit.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 15: England]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-team-guides-part-15-england</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-team-guides-part-15-england"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate’s talented team have high hopes going into the tournament but he must find the right balance
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
Although the hype around England has ended up looking ridiculous in previous years, the optimism feels justified this time. There is no need to adopt an inferiority complex. It is not entitled to point out that Gareth Southgate’s side are capable of ending the talk of 1966 and all that.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg and Simon Burnton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matters of life and death: Kneehigh theatre’s wild times – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/jun/07/matters-of-life-and-death-kneehigh-theatres-wild-times-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/jun/07/matters-of-life-and-death-kneehigh-theatres-wild-times-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The award-winning Kneehigh theatre company has announced it is closing down. Revisit its past hits including Rapunzel, A Matter of Life and Death and The Tin Drum
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cupid’s needle? UK under-30s wooed with dating app vaccine bonus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/cupid-needle-uk-under-30s-courted-dating-app-vaccine-bonus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/cupid-needle-uk-under-30s-courted-dating-app-vaccine-bonus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apps such as Hinge and Bumble will offer benefits to vaccinated users amid fears of low take-up 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

First came the idea of making Covid vaccinations mandatory to go to the pub, while Israel offered free pizza and beer with a shot. Now UK officials have hit on what they hope is an even more persuasive reason for young people to get their jab: more chance of getting a date.
In an eye-catching policy coinciding with the rollout of vaccinations for the under-30s beginning this week, the Department of Health and Social Care (DHSC) has teamed up with popular dating apps to encourage take-up of the programme.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low-paid UK workers ‘most at risk of losing jobs when furlough ends’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/low-paid-uk-workers-most-at-risk-of-losing-jobs-when-furlough-ends</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/low-paid-uk-workers-most-at-risk-of-losing-jobs-when-furlough-ends"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Resolution Foundation’s analysis is in line with experience of financial crisis more than 10 years ago

See all our coronavirus coverage

Low-paid workers face the highest risk of losing their jobs when the UK government’s furlough scheme ends in September, according to analysis by a leading thinktank.
The government’s coronavirus job retention scheme, which pays 80% of furloughed workers’ wages, is widely believed to have prevented millions of job losses when the economy collapsed but economists are concerned that some jobs will still not be viable when it ends on 30 September.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK second to France again for attracting foreign investment in Europe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/07/uk-second-to-france-again-for-attracting-foreign-investment-in-europe-brexit-covid-19</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/07/uk-second-to-france-again-for-attracting-foreign-investment-in-europe-brexit-covid-19"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britain loses out for second year in row as Brexit and Covid-19 disrupt 2020 

See all our coronavirus coverage

The UK lost out to France as the most popular European destination for foreign investors for the second year in a row, amid disruption from Brexit and the coronavirus pandemic.
During 2020 the UK secured 975 inward investment projects compared with France’s 985 projects, according to accountancy firm EY.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waterloo and City line in London reopens for first time since March 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/waterloo-and-city-line-in-london-reopens-for-first-time-since-march-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/07/waterloo-and-city-line-in-london-reopens-for-first-time-since-march-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:01:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The tube line, closed during most of the Covid pandemic, will provide extra capacity for commuters at peak times 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 
The Waterloo and City line on the underground reopens on Monday for the first time since the start of the pandemic.
The important London commuter link, which connects Waterloo and Bank stations in the centre of the capital, closed in March 2020. Services will now run every five minutes Monday to Friday from 6am to 10am and 3.30pm to 7pm.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of lockdown poses Boris Johnson one of his toughest decisions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/end-of-lockdown-poses-boris-johnson-one-of-his-toughest-decisions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/07/end-of-lockdown-poses-boris-johnson-one-of-his-toughest-decisions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: prime minister faces a backlash from his own MPs if he delays lifting the last of England’s restrictions

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

At some point towards the end of next week Boris Johnson will make one of the trickier decisions even of this pandemic period: whether to lift the final tranche of Covid rules. Some of those watching the closest will be his own MPs.
The PM and his aides will be mindful of both the more vocal lockdown dissenters centred on the Covid Recovery Group, and also for any signs that a wider group of Tory backbenchers could be setting themselves against delay.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker and Aubrey Allegretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Puffin island: a voyage to one of Scotland’s remotest habitats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/06/puffin-island-a-voyage-to-one-of-scotlands-remotest-habitats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/06/puffin-island-a-voyage-to-one-of-scotlands-remotest-habitats"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T22:46:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Murdo MacLeod sailed from Mull over to Lunga, the largest of the Treshnish Isles, to photograph the world of the puffin
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Murdo MacLeod</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour asks NHS and Matt Hancock to pause plans for sharing patient data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/labour-asks-nhs-and-matt-hancock-to-pause-plans-for-sharing-patient-data</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/labour-asks-nhs-and-matt-hancock-to-pause-plans-for-sharing-patient-data"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T21:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shadow health minister Alex Norris and doctors’ groups believe proposals risk undermining trust in GPs
Labour has urged the NHS and Matt Hancock to pause their plan to share medical records from GPs to allow time for greater consultation on how the idea would work, saying that maintaining patients’ trust must be paramount.
In a letter to the head of NHS Digital and the health secretary, the shadow public health minister, Alex Norris, said Labour backed the principle of improved data collaboration but shared the concerns of some doctors’ groups.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are there calls for patient data-sharing scheme to be halted?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/why-are-there-calls-for-a-pause-to-patient-data-sharing-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/why-are-there-calls-for-a-pause-to-patient-data-sharing-scheme"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T21:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: doctors’ groups and Labour say there has been a lack of consultation over major overhaul

Labour asks NHS and Matt Hancock to pause plans for sharing patient data

Labour has written to the head of NHS Digital asking for a pause in the planned rollout of a new data-sharing scheme for GP surgeries. Here are some of the key questions and concerns about the proposals.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cobby, oldest chimpanzee in North American zoos, dies aged 63]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cobby-oldest-chimpanzee-in-north-american-zoos-dies-aged-63</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cobby-oldest-chimpanzee-in-north-american-zoos-dies-aged-63"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T21:19:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[San Francisco zoo reports death of much-loved primate
Chimpanzee performed in short-lived children’s TV series

Cobby, the oldest male chimpanzee in an accredited North American zoo, died on Saturday at the San Francisco Zoo & Gardens. He was 63. 
 Related: Cobby the chimp: searching for the Sugarman of the ape world 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time review – Sean Bean and Stephen Graham astound in enraging prison drama]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/06/time-review-sean-bean-and-stephen-graham-astound-in-enraging-prison-drama</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/06/time-review-sean-bean-and-stephen-graham-astound-in-enraging-prison-drama"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T21:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Its two stars give exceptional performances as inmate and officer respectively, in a series about the inhumanity of the penal system which lays bare Jimmy McGovern’s genius
There is a moment near the start of Jimmy McGovern’s latest drama, Time (BBC One), that perfectly encapsulates his genius. Mark Cobden (Sean Bean) is arriving for processing at the prison in which he will serve his four-year sentence. Among the questions barked at him – name, age, is he on any medication – is one about his religion. Nervous and disoriented, he mumbles something about not really believing in God. “I’ll put you down as Anglican then,” comes the brisk reply (and standard joke, though not here played as one). “No, no,” Mark responds, kicked into focus. “More … more lapsed Catholic.”
It’s irrelevant in the grand scheme of things – Time is a drama about the supposed strengths and many failures of the penal system and Mark’s religion affects his experiences inside not one iota. But it is the perfect demonstration and measure of McGovern’s two greatest strengths – his psychological acuity and his ability to evoke an entire interior world with one brief exchange. He knows a cradle Catholic, even in the most dire straits, would be recalled to himself under the threat of being demoted to Anglican. And he tells us something about the core of the man who is about to be tested as never before, as he enters a world of rules, regulations, petty bullying and sudden violence. It is a place of shifting alliances – a wing full of men who may be mad or bad but are almost always, directly or indirectly, dangerous to know.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global G7 deal may let Amazon off hook on tax, say experts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/global-g7-deal-may-let-amazon-off-hook-on-tax-say-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/global-g7-deal-may-let-amazon-off-hook-on-tax-say-experts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T20:23:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: communique from ministers suggests deal only applies to ‘profit exceeding a 10% margin’, which could rule out Amazon
Experts have raised concerns that Amazon may escape paying significantly more tax in some of its biggest markets unless world leaders close a large loophole in a historic global deal.
Finance ministers in London from the G7 group of wealthy nations, including representatives of the UK, US and EU, on Saturday agreed the landmark deal aimed at making the biggest companies such as Apple, Microsoft, Google and Facebook pay more tax.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pretending that booing England is about ‘keeping politics out’ is cowardly | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/06/england-fans-booing-taking-knee-euro-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/06/england-fans-booing-taking-knee-euro-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T20:15:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This shameful and hurtful act in response to taking the knee before the game only adds to the fraught buildup to Euro 2020
Romania’s players agreed to take the knee for the first time at the Riverside Stadium as a gesture of solidarity with their English hosts. As loud, angry boos rang out around the ground the Romanians must have wondered what they’d stumbled into here. What kind of weird, contorted, backwards kind of country is this England anyway? Didn’t they used to be someone? Welcome to England 2021. Divided, belligerent, set against itself – and reduced now by the formalities of a football match to debating the idea of “Englishness” until it falls apart at the seams.
This is England a week away from a de facto home Euros, two weeks away from the great unlocking after a year of angst-ridden isolation. This is England, and everything’s going to be OK. Probably.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baftas 2021: Michaela Coel dedicates win to intimacy coordinator]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/06/baftas-2021-michaela-coel-dedicates-win-to-intimacy-coordinator</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/06/baftas-2021-michaela-coel-dedicates-win-to-intimacy-coordinator"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T20:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coel picks up acting award as her hit drama I May Destroy You, which deals with sexual assault, wins best mini-series 

The full list of winners 

Bafta TV awards red carpet – in pictures

Michaela Coel and her hit drama I May Destroy You won big at the 2021 television Baftas on Sunday – with Coel dedicating her acting award to the series’ intimacy coordinator.
Accepting awards for a show that dealt with sexual abuse and consent, Coel said film and television sets were vulnerable places for actors and crew members. Not to have intimacy experts was “thoughtless” and showed a “lack of mindfulness”, she added.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Brown Arts correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s Ollie Robinson suspended from international game for tweets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/joe-root-defends-englands-approach-as-first-new-zealand-test-ends-in-draw</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/joe-root-defends-englands-approach-as-first-new-zealand-test-ends-in-draw"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T19:54:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bowler Robinson will miss second Test at Edgbaston
Joe Root criticised for not chasing New Zealand target

Ollie Robinson has been suspended from all international cricket pending an investigation into offensive tweets he published as a teenager and which resurfaced while he was starring on debut for England in their drawn first Test against New Zealand at Lord’s.
The decision means they will head to Edgbaston for the second Test without the player who most impressed in the first, while Robinson returns to Sussex to ponder what has been a uniquely dramatic week. “From a performance point of view, on the field he has had an exceptional debut,” Joe Root said of the 27-year-old.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Burnton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excited, pursuing bear: Florida officials seek unusual urban visitor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/naples-florida-black-bear</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/naples-florida-black-bear"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T19:25:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sightings of black bear continue but state wildlife officials unsuccessful in attempts to trap and relocate it
In a summer’s tale to enthrall inhabitants of the south-western Florida city of Naples, a black bear seen wandering around downtown eluded wildlife officials – even as sightings of the animal continued.
Police said the bear was first spotted in the city on Friday, near 12th Avenue South and 6th Street South. Several unsuccessful attempts were made to trap the bear in hopes of relocating it, the Naples Daily News reported.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicola Jennings on Boris Johnson’s Covid balancing act — cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/06/nicola-jennings-on-boris-johnsons-covid-balancing-act-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/06/nicola-jennings-on-boris-johnsons-covid-balancing-act-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T19:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s in a name? The meanings of Lilibet Diana Mountbatten-Windsor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/whats-in-a-name-the-meanings-of-lilibet-diana-mountbatten-windsor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/whats-in-a-name-the-meanings-of-lilibet-diana-mountbatten-windsor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:47:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have named their new arrival with the royal family in mind
As the Duke and Duchess of Sussex welcome their new baby, Lilibet Diana Mountbatten-Windsor, to the world, many are curious to know what the names of Prince Harry and Meghan’s second child and first daughter mean.
Lilibet refers to the Queen’s nickname within the family, and was first used when Princess Elizabeth was just a toddler and unable to pronounce her name correctly.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meghan and Harry announce birth of baby daughter Lilibet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/meghan-and-harry-announce-birth-of-baby-daughter-lilibet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/meghan-and-harry-announce-birth-of-baby-daughter-lilibet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:37:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Child named after the family nickname for the Queen, the baby’s great-grandmother
The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have announced the birth of a daughter they have named Lilibet “Lili” Diana Mountbatten-Windsor.
Harry and Meghan’s daughter, who was born in hospital in California on Friday, weighed 7lb 11oz (3.4kg) and has been named after the family nickname for the Queen, the baby’s great-grandmother. Her middle name was chosen to honour her late grandmother Diana, Princess of Wales, the couple said. The baby is the Queen’s 11th great-grandchild and is eighth in line to the throne.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kent threatens Home Office with legal action over unaccompanied child migrants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/kent-threatens-home-office-with-legal-action-over-unaccompanied-child-migrants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/kent-threatens-home-office-with-legal-action-over-unaccompanied-child-migrants"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:05:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Council says services for unaccompanied child migrants are at breaking point for second time in less than a year
Kent county council has issued legal proceedings against the home secretary as it warns its services for unaccompanied child migrants are at breaking point for the second time in less than a year.
The authority said it may no longer be able to accept new unaccompanied asylum-seeking children (UASC) within days, and has served a formal letter before action to the Home Office.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alistair Brownlee disqualified for ‘ducking’ and faces Olympic omission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/alistair-brownlee-disqualified-for-ducking-and-faces-olympic-omission</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/alistair-brownlee-disqualified-for-ducking-and-faces-olympic-omission"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:05:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2012 and 2016 triathlon gold ‘pushed’ rival underwater
Winner Alex Yee set for second spot with Jonny Brownlee

Alistair Brownlee’s hopes of winning a third successive Olympic title appear to be over after he was disqualified for “ducking” a rival during a World Triathlon Championship Series race in Leeds.
 Related: Netherlands’ Sifan Hassan smashes women’s 10,000m record by 10 seconds 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If Britain wants to set an example to the G7, it must restore its aid pledge | Andrew Mitchell]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/britain-set-example-g7-aid-pledge-mps</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/britain-set-example-g7-aid-pledge-mps"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs have a chance to ensure Boris Johnson arrives at the summit as first among equals at this time of multiple crises

Andrew Mitchell was international development secretary from 2010 to 2012

Ahead of this week’s G7 summit in Cornwall, illustrators of much loved children’s books have joined families across the UK in tracing their hands – raising them in unison to call for action from world leaders on the Covid pandemic, injustice, the climate crisis and nature loss. The Wave of Hope is supported by 75 civil society organisations in the Crack the Crises coalition.
On the high streets of my own constituency, in the Royal Town of Sutton Coldfield, charity shops are also getting involved. This feels very different to Make Poverty History or the If campaign, which formed the backdrop to the last occasion on which Britain hosted the G8. This time, international development campaigners have joined the green movement and civil society to put their collective force behind the campaign.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Mitchell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Merkel’s CDU beats far right in crucial German state election]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/angela-merkels-cdu-beats-far-right-in-crucial-german-state-election</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/angela-merkels-cdu-beats-far-right-in-crucial-german-state-election"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative win in Saxony-Anhalt seen as last big test ahead of national election in September
Angela Merkel’s Christian Democratic Union (CDU) fought off a challenge from the far right in a state election on Sunday seen as the last big test for Germany’s political parties before a national vote in September that will end the chancellor’s 16 years atop German politics.
In exit polls the CDU, whose current leader, Armin Laschet, will vie for the top job in September, improved on its 2017 performance to gain 36% of the vote in the eastern state – a result the state premier, Reiner Haseloff, said symbolised “a clear demarcation against the far right”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shokupan is the anti-sourdough: the rise of Japanese milk bread]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/06/shokupan-is-the-anti-sourdough-the-rise-of-japanese-milk-bread</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/06/shokupan-is-the-anti-sourdough-the-rise-of-japanese-milk-bread"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subtly sweet, soft and highly photogenic, a slew of Japanese-inspired bakeries and cafes are introducing Australians to a different kind of bread
Reiji Honour grew up eating soft white bread in Singapore and Japan. When he and his family moved to an Australian country town in 2005, the closest they could get to shokupan – Japanese milk bread – was white bread from Brumby’s Bakery.
“My mother, who is Japanese, would buy a whole loaf and cut thick slices of it. But it was never quite the same. There’s a subtle sweetness with shokupan which does not exist in white bread.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annie Hariharan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the G7 global tax deal: genuine progress | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/the-guardian-view-on-the-g7-global-tax-deal-genuine-progress</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/the-guardian-view-on-the-g7-global-tax-deal-genuine-progress"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finance ministers’ agreement on a fairer global tax system for multinationals is a step in the right direction. But there is a long way to go
Last week the Guardian reported that an Irish subsidiary of the US tech giant Microsoft paid no corporation tax at all last year, on profits of $315bn (£222bn). This is because Microsoft Round Island One, which collects licence fees for Microsoft software, is “resident” for tax purposes in Bermuda. Since Bermuda does not levy corporation tax, the only payout came in the form of bumper dividends for Microsoft shareholders, worth a total of $55bn.
Over recent decades, such shameless chicanery has become the way of the world. But at the weekend, G7 finance ministers took a first step towards dismantling this footloose, beggar-thy-neighbour version of capitalism, which has deprived treasuries of hundreds of billions of pounds in tax receipts. International corporate tax rules were designed a hundred years ago, to protect multinational companies from predatory governments and the threat of double taxation. But since the late 20th century, and particularly in the digital era, the power relationship has been inverted. In the age of high globalisation, multinational giants played pick and mix with tax jurisdictions, salted away profits offshore through baroque ownership structures, and used their power to play countries off against each other.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serena Williams out of French Open after straight sets defeat by Rybakina]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/serena-williams-out-of-french-open-after-straight-sets-defeat-to-rybakina</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/06/serena-williams-out-of-french-open-after-straight-sets-defeat-to-rybakina"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:28:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[American loses 6-3, 7-5 against Elena Rybakina in Paris
Williams was only top-20 player left in her half of draw

The only certainty in the bottom half of the women’s singles draw at the French Open this year is the constant thrill of uncertainty. On Sunday afternoon the final top-20 player in the section fell and it was the most successful of them all as Serena Williams was thoroughly outplayed by a young Kazakh star called Elena Rybakina, who won 6-3, 7-5.
With Williams’ defeat Rybakina, Anastasia Pavlyuchenkova, Tamara Zidansek and Paula Badosa remain in the bottom half of the draw. None has ever braved a major semi-final and only Pavlyuchenkova has contested a quarter-final. One will seize the moment and become the newest first-time grand-slam finalist.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the god of science: a divine but rational disagreement | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/the-guardian-view-on-the-god-of-science-a-divine-but-rational-disagreement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/the-guardian-view-on-the-god-of-science-a-divine-but-rational-disagreement"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:25:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A key maths tool during the pandemic came about because of an 18th-century debate about Christianity. The lesson we can draw today is that moral philosophy matters
Do the laws of science and mathematics explain everything, without any need to bring God into it? The pious once believed that wrathful deities could unleash plagues. As reason emerged in the temple of thinking, there was a move to claim God was behind the advance of reason. In this struggle between beliefs, new pathways of thought emerged, to the benefit of humanity.
The fruits of this theological and scientific collision have been revealed during Covid. The work of Thomas Bayes, an 18th-century clergyman and mathematician, has become central to understanding the pandemic. Bayes’ theorem shows how to calculate the accuracy of lateral flow tests used to map the spread of coronavirus. The maths is used to work out the conditional probability that a person is not infected, given a positive test. This is just the tip of the Bayesian spear. David Spiegelhalter and Anthony Masters wrote in April that many complex pandemic analyses “have been ‘Bayesian’, including modelling lockdown effects, the ONS infection survey, and Pfizer-BioNTech’s vaccine trial”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NHS data grab: why we should be concerned about plans for GPs’ records | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/the-nhs-data-grab-why-we-should-be-concerned-about-plans-for-gps-records</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/the-nhs-data-grab-why-we-should-be-concerned-about-plans-for-gps-records"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:18:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Rector believes NHS data is a major resource for medical research, but the scheme needs safeguards. Plus letters from Irene Stratton, Alison Macfarlane, Robert Oulton and Celia Berridge
Thank you for your report highlighting the government’s grab of GPs’ data (GPs warn over plans to share patient data with third parties in England, 30 May) and the accompanying editorial (The Guardian view on medical records: NHS data grab needs explaining, 30 May). There are even more issues than you cite.
First, the government’s website is disingenuous and misleading. At the top it says patients can opt out at any time; at the bottom it says that when opting out, all existing information will be retained – only new information will not be collected. It states that there is no deadline, but if you opt out after your records have been uploaded, the existing information will not be deleted.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An aesthetic defence of the Edward Colston statue and its sculptor | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/sculptor-of-colston-statue-not-mediocre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/sculptor-of-colston-statue-not-mediocre"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T17:18:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[John Cassidy, the creator of the bronze memorial to the Bristol slave trader, produced radical and evocative work, writes Simon Casimir Wilson
It is perhaps a little ironic that a professor of public history at the University of Manchester should dismiss, and in the Guardian moreover, the sculptor John Cassidy’s now notorious statue of Edward Colston as a “mediocre piece of late-Victorian public art” (‘A potent historical artefact’: the statue of Edward Colston’s new role, 4 June).
Cassidy (1860-1939) was a Mancunian sculptor, whose Victoria jubilee fountain adorns Albert Square and whose masterpiece, the allegorical group Adrift, is a prominent feature of St Peter’s Square. It represents, he wrote, “the dependence of human beings upon one another, the response of human sympathy to human needs”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netanyahu says Israeli coalition poised to unseat him is result of ‘election fraud’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/netanyahu-says-israeli-coalition-is-result-of-election-fraud</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/netanyahu-says-israeli-coalition-is-result-of-election-fraud"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T16:51:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accusation comes as security services warn of an escalation in violent discourse in the country

Benjamin Netanyahu has said a newly formed Israeli coalition that is poised to unseat him as prime minister was the result of “the greatest election fraud” in the history of democracy.
The sweeping accusation, similar in tone to those made about the US election by his former close ally Donald Trump, came as Israeli security services warned of an escalation in violent discourse in the country.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure on UK as Germany backs ending free carbon permits for airlines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/pressure-uk-germany-backs-ending-free-carbon-permits-airlines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/pressure-uk-germany-backs-ending-free-carbon-permits-airlines"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T16:45:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson has pledged to give details of how UK will meet its climate targets before Cop26

The German government is backing an extension of EU carbon pricing that will end free carbon permits for airlines, putting pressure on the UK to put in place a similar package to meet climate targets.
The European Commission will propose a dozen climate policies on 14 July, each designed to slash greenhouse gases faster in line with an EU goal to cut net emissions by 55% by 2030 from 1990 levels.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid: more than 200 leaders urge G7 to help vaccinate world’s poorest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/covid-global-leaders-urge-g7-to-help-vaccinate-worlds-poorest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/covid-global-leaders-urge-g7-to-help-vaccinate-worlds-poorest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T16:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former PMs, presidents and ministers sign letter saying richest should pay two-thirds of $66bn needed

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

More than 100 former prime ministers, presidents and foreign ministers are among 230 prominent figures calling on the leaders of the powerful G7 countries to pay two-thirds of the $66bn (£46.6bn) needed to vaccinate low-income countries against Covid.
A letter seen by the Guardian ahead of the G7 summit to be hosted by Boris Johnson in Cornwall warns that the leaders of the UK, US, France, Germany, Italy, Japan and Canada must make 2021 “a turning point in global cooperation”. Fewer than 2% of people in sub-Saharan Africa have been vaccinated against Covid, while the UK has now immunised 70% of its population with at least one dose.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley Health editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MailOnline mocked for suggesting Didsbury is ‘no go’ area for white people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/mailonline-mocked-for-suggesting-didsbury-is-no-go-area-for-white-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/mailonline-mocked-for-suggesting-didsbury-is-no-go-area-for-white-people"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T16:25:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inclusion of affluent, mainly white Manchester suburb in list of Muslim-dominated towns derided by locals
MailOnline has been criticised for a story claiming there are British towns that are no-go areas for white people, generating particular ridicule for the inclusion of the Manchester suburb of Didsbury.
The article is based on a book by former Islamist radical Ed Husain called Among the Mosques: A Journey Across Muslim Britain, in which he details how he believes communities have become divided.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla Model 3 becomes most popular battery electric car on UK roads]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/tesla-model-3-becomes-most-popular-battery-electric-car-on-uk-roads</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/tesla-model-3-becomes-most-popular-battery-electric-car-on-uk-roads"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T15:54:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Surge in sales for US carmaker in first four months of 2021 pushes Nissan Leaf into second place
The Tesla Model 3 has become the most popular battery electric car on British roads after a surge in sales, as the race to dominate the car industry’s new era heats up.
The number of Model 3s on British roads overtook Nissan’s Leaf models during the first four months of 2021, according to calculations by Matthias Schmidt, an independent electric car analyst. There are now 39,900 Model 3s in the UK, compared with 38,900 Leafs, many of which are built at Nissan’s factory in Sunderland.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 deal is as much about balance of power as global tax reform | Richard Partington]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/g7-deal-is-as-much-about-balance-of-power-as-global-tax-reform</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/g7-deal-is-as-much-about-balance-of-power-as-global-tax-reform"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T15:10:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The real story includes the reconciling of domestic interests with international demands
A historic agreement has been reached. For decades, multinational corporations have abused gaps in an international tax system that has barely changed since agreements made at the League of Nations in the 1920s.
After meetings in London at the weekend, the message from the G7 group of wealthy nations is clear: time is up on tax havens. In a landmark move, a global minimum rate of corporation tax has been agreed, alongside measures forcing large firms and online tech giants such as Facebook, Apple and Google to pay more tax in the markets where they make their money regardless of physical presence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour warns on next NHS England chief as Dido Harding expected to apply]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/labour-warns-on-next-nhs-england-chief-as-dido-harding-expected-to-apply</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/labour-warns-on-next-nhs-england-chief-as-dido-harding-expected-to-apply"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:59:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former head of test and trace considering throwing her hat in ring to replace Simon Stevens

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The next chief executive of NHS England must be someone with “a proven track record”, Labour has said, after it emerged that the former test and trace chief Dido Harding was expected to stand.
It is understood that Harding, a Conservative peer, is considering formally applying to replace Sir Simon Stevens, who is leaving the job in July after seven years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virginia supreme court to hear cases challenging removal of Confederate statue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/virginia-supreme-court-confederate-statue-robert-e-lee</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/virginia-supreme-court-confederate-statue-robert-e-lee"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:45:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Governor’s plan to take down a 131-year-old statue of Gen Robert E Lee came after George Floyd was murdered by a police officer
The supreme court of Virginia will this week hear arguments in legal challenges to Governor Ralph Northam’s plan to take down a 131-year-old statue of Confederate Gen Robert E Lee, a move met with widespread praise from activists who had long seen it as a symbol of white supremacy.
 Related: Memphis exhumes body of Klan leader Nathan Bedford Forrest from city park 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Richmond, Virginia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calls for Keith Haring mural to stay at Barcelona site being turned into care home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/keith-haring-barcelona-mural-to-be-moved-as-former-club-faces-demolition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/keith-haring-barcelona-mural-to-be-moved-as-former-club-faces-demolition"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artwork in building slated for demolition faces uncertain future, though city has pledged to save it

It all began one February night in 1989. Cesar de Melero was DJing in the Ars Studio club in Barcelona when someone told him that the artist Keith Haring was outside but the doorman wouldn’t let him in.
“The place was packed, so I put on a record and pushed through the crowd,” De Melero told the Guardian. “And there he was with his saintly, innocent face and I told the doorman to let him in and I said to the boss: ‘Champagne for Keith Haring.’”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Burgen in Barcelona</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rape cases in England and Wales will be hit hard by backlog, says police chief]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/rape-and-domestic-violence-cases-will-be-hardest-hit-by-justice-backlog-says-police-chief</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/rape-and-domestic-violence-cases-will-be-hardest-hit-by-justice-backlog-says-police-chief"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:08:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Austerity, mismanagement and ‘reckless neglect’ has left system at crisis point, says crime commissioner 
Rape and domestic violence cases in England and Wales will be among the worst hit from the growing backlog in the judicial system, and trials could soon start collapsing because of severe delays, the new crime commissioner for England’s second biggest force has warned.
Simon Foster, the Labour commissioner for West Midlands police, said underfunding and “mismanagement and reckless neglect” of the justice system over the past 10 years had left it at crisis point, and he had heard of one crown court trial date being set for as far off as 2024 – though the Ministry of Justice denied this.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s a love letter to adventure’: the British musical about jogging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/06/these-hills-are-ours-running-musical-show-daniel-bye-boff-whalley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/06/these-hills-are-ours-running-musical-show-daniel-bye-boff-whalley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inspired by a 90-mile run to the Peak District, These Hills Are Ours explores the muddy joys of trail running – then invites its audience out for a jog
Daniel Bye is twisting in his seat, recalling the day he set out from his home in Lancaster, ran through the city’s streets and then up the nearby peak of Clougha Pike. “It was like I’d left one world, and entered another,” he says. Cue a song from Boff Whalley – the former guitarist of anarcho-punk band Chumbawamba – who is sitting in the chair next to him: a wistful, lilting melody about the joys of running out in the hills.
“We’d worked together doing other shows in the past,” Whalley tells me later, “and we realised we always ended up talking about running. So we thought, let’s do a show about running.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adharanand Finn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Phair: Soberish review – forgettable coffee-table pop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/06/liz-phair-soberish-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/06/liz-phair-soberish-review"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T14:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Chrysalis)
The Liz Phair who brought frankness and feminism to 90s alt-rock is sadly absent on this, her first album in a decade
It’s almost three decades since Liz Phair brought uncompromisingly frank lyrics and a feminist sensibility to the boys’ club that was the early 90s US alt-rock scene. In her first album in 11 years, she is reunited with Brad Wood, producer of her career high points, 1993’s Exile in Guyville and the following year’s Whip-Smart. But anybody hoping for a return to the days when she was a genuinely exciting proposition will be disappointed: the focus here is far more on the mainstream pop and soft-rock of Phair’s post-94 oeuvre than the spiky indie that preceded it.
It’s not as excruciating as 2010’s Funstyle, with its misfiring experiments with dance beats and pitchshifted vocals, but at least that was entertainingly bad in places. While it’s clear from Soberish that Phair still knows her way around an arresting confessional lyric – witness Good Side’s opening: “There are so many ways to fuck up a life/ I’ve tried to be original” – musically, this is unforgivably mediocre. A memorable chorus will occasionally appear from nowhere, as on Hey Lou (and Soul Sucker wins points for its unexpected nod to Blue Boy’s Remember Me), but for the most part the coffee-table pop on offer here is remarkable only for being so forgettable. Tracks such as In There and The Game sound like mechanically recovered leftovers from Madonna’s Ray of Light album sessions; more upbeat opener Spanish Doors is Carly Rae Jepsen as reimagined by outdated AI software. Best avoided. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phil Mongredien</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Sea snot’: Turkish minister announces plan to tackle slimy scourge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/sea-snot-turkish-minister-announces-plan-tackle-slimy-scourge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/sea-snot-turkish-minister-announces-plan-tackle-slimy-scourge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:54:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Substance has spread through sea south of Istanbul, posing threat to marine life and fishing industry
Turkey’s environment minister has pledged to defeat a plague of “sea snot” threatening the Sea of Marmara, with a disaster management plan he said would secure its future.
A thick slimy layer of the organic matter, known as marine mucilage, has spread through the sea south of Istanbul, posing a threat to marine life and the fishing industry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson’s paltry education package risks scarring a generation | Natalie Perera]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/boris-johnson-education-young-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/boris-johnson-education-young-people"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:43:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unless schools receive far more support, any recent progress in reducing inequalities will be wiped out
It’s a pledge that we’ve heard repeatedly. Since lockdowns were enforced and schools first shut their gates, the government has made promises to the nation to prioritise education recovery for young people.
The need to help them regain lost learning is palpable, with pupils said to be on average between two and three months behind where they would ordinarily be had the pandemic not happened. We also know that pupils starting now need more support with basic skills like communication: teachers have raised alarm bells about worrying speech and language delays in the very youngest children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Perera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump aide asked DoJ to investigate bizarre ‘Italygate’ claim votes were changed by satellite]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/donald-trump-mark-meadows-doj-italygate</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/donald-trump-mark-meadows-doj-italygate"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:35:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conspiracy theory says people in Italy used military satellites to make US voting machines switch votes for Biden

Biden touts democracy abroad as threats grow at home

Donald Trump’s final White House chief of staff, Mark Meadows, pressured the acting attorney general to help push the lie of electoral fraud in Trump’s defeat by Joe Biden – even asking him to investigate a conspiracy theory which said people in Italy used military satellites to make US voting machines switch votes for Biden.
 Related: China, Fauci and hoaxes: Donald Trump takes aim at usual suspects in return to stage 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Priti Patel seeks ban on social media posts that ‘glamourise’ migrant crossings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/priti-patel-seeks-ban-on-social-media-posts-that-glamourise-migrant-crossings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/priti-patel-seeks-ban-on-social-media-posts-that-glamourise-migrant-crossings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:23:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home secretary accused of deflecting blame from government policies after letter to social media companies
Priti Patel has been accused of attempting to deflect blame from the UK government’s failure to assist refugees after she told social media companies to remove posts that “glamourise” migrant crossings.
The home secretary wrote to firms on Saturday urging them to do more to remove “totally unacceptable clips” that she said promote “lethal crossings”. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My dream of a holiday abroad this summer alas was just magical thinking | Emma Brockes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/dream-holiday-summer-pandemic-costa-rica</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/dream-holiday-summer-pandemic-costa-rica"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I discovered the dreadful toll of the pandemic in Costa Rica, I realised there were worse things than holidaying at home
I’d been aware, for a while, that wealthy friends had resumed travelling, and a few months ago – in the first flush of vaccination optimism and with Covid rates in New York plunging – it looked easy. Perhaps we can do this, I thought. Countries reliant on tourism dollars were reopening. Airline prices were still low. It was, I told myself, safer to go to Costa Rica than to Florida. If JetBlue thought it was OK to travel to San José, then that was good enough for me. Besides which, I thought, with stubborn servility, if it really was dangerous to fly to Central America, the US government wouldn’t let me do it. (Ha.)
That was in late March. Last summer we had, along with everyone else lucky enough to be able to leave the city, rented a minivan and, after driving north for three hours – the minimum journey required to clear the extraordinary inflation-hitting resort rates near New York – sat out August in a house in Massachusetts. There was no question of flying to England or anywhere else, and if we missed seeing friends and family, there was some consolation in having that option removed. Of course, people still flew last summer. But their circumstances were generally so different from our own that it removed the pain of decision-making.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Brockes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: if sarcasm is the lowest form of wit, what is the highest?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/readers-reply-if-sarcasm-is-the-lowest-form-of-wit-what-is-the-highest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/readers-reply-if-sarcasm-is-the-lowest-form-of-wit-what-is-the-highest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T13:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
If sarcasm is the lowest form of wit, what is the highest? Dr Willis Stone, London
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iran election candidate threatens to try rival for treason during TV debate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/iran-presidential-election-candidate-threatens-try-rival-treason-tv-debate-abdolnaser-hemmati</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/iran-presidential-election-candidate-threatens-try-rival-treason-tv-debate-abdolnaser-hemmati"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former leader of Revolutionary Guards rounds on ex-central banker in bruising first debate 
Iran’s presidential election candidates have engaged in a fiery and bruising first television debate, during which one promised to put another, the former governor of the central bank, on trial for treason and ban him and other members of the government from leaving the country.
The threat to put Abdolnaser Hemmati on trial was made on Saturday by the former leader of the Revolutionary Guards Mohsen Rezaei, currently secretary of the Expediency Council. He claimed the Iranian currency had been devalued so much by Hemmati that “the train of the revolution has turned into a scooter”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A shortage of workers is driving up wages: are we entering a new economic era? | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/fall-in-workers-rise-in-wages-new-economic-era-pandemic-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/fall-in-workers-rise-in-wages-new-economic-era-pandemic-work"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:44:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour problems may be an early sign of inevitable economic readjustments around the world following the pandemic
Jamie Rogers is a former semi-finalist in the BBC’s Masterchef: The Professionals, and the founder of an award-winning restaurant called Twenty Seven, located in the south Devon town of Kingsbridge. As it reopened for business after the recent lockdown, a handful of staff handed in their notice. As he told me last week, he then began to explore what was happening in his part of the economy, and was confronted with huge changes: “Jobs that were worth £10 an hour last year are suddenly paying double that.”
Brexit is part of the story. “A lot of international people have gone home – a lot of people are telling me that,” he said. So too is a shift among British-born workers. “I bumped into someone the other day who was working in Tesco. He used to be a head chef. He said, ‘I’m happy where I am now.’ He’s seen that he doesn’t have to work a 60- or 70-hour week, and he’s still probably making the same money.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devil runners and parkour in the West Bank: the weekend’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/06/devil-runners-and-parkour-in-the-west-bank-the-weekends-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/06/devil-runners-and-parkour-in-the-west-bank-the-weekends-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:42:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Plimmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Mix and match’ Covid booster jabs may be offered in UK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/mix-and-match-covid-booster-jabs-may-be-offered-in-uk-vaccine-autumn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/mix-and-match-covid-booster-jabs-may-be-offered-in-uk-vaccine-autumn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:32:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers testing whether second dose of different vaccine could generate stronger immune response

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Ministers are considering giving people a different type of Covid vaccine as an autumn booster, it has emerged, after early results from “mix and match” trials appeared to show promise for an enhanced immune response.
Four different coronavirus jabs have been approved for use in the UK, with more under regulatory review. While people are currently offered two doses of the same jab, researchers have been exploring whether offering a second dose of a different Covid vaccine could generate a stronger immune response.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden trumpets democracy abroad in Post op-ed – as threats spread at home]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/biden-democracy-washington-post-oped-trump-republicans-china-russia-putin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/biden-democracy-washington-post-oped-trump-republicans-china-russia-putin"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:16:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President sets out vision for European visit
How long can America call itself a democracy?
Voting rights: VP Kamala Harris takes on new role

Joe Biden will use his visit to Europe this week to “rally the world’s democracies” in a reset of US foreign policy after four turbulent years under Donald Trump – all while threats to American democracy, stoked by Trump, proliferate at home.
 Related: After Trump: Biden set to outline US policy to Johnson, Putin and more 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My best friend at school moved in with us – and taught me to trust again]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/shes-my-soulmate-my-childhood-bff-is-still-my-best-friend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/shes-my-soulmate-my-childhood-bff-is-still-my-best-friend"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How a close and enduring relationship forged in the school playground turned my life around
My school bully came in an unlikely package. She was a bushy-haired, bespectacled, briefcase-carrying pocket rocket who made my life miserable for a significant portion of Year 8 when I was 12 years old. I met her on the first day at our large and rowdy comprehensive school. With all my existing friends assigned to different forms, I was on high alert for someone to attach myself to as soon as possible. With her outwardly gawky appearance, she seemed like the ideal candidate and I approached her with the rather arrogant assumption that she would jump at the chance of my friendship.
It didn’t take me long to realise I’d severely misjudged the situation. Her meek physical persona belied a serious rebellious streak and I struggled to keep up from the start. When she dared me to join her in “the jungle” – a wooded area of the school grounds off limits to students, I shakily agreed. We eluded capture from the lunchtime supervisors who patrolled its perimeters, but my time in the jungle brought me little exhilaration or pleasure. More tests and challenges soon followed, all proposed with a glint in her eye that I came to dread.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa Williamson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nero: The Man Behind the Myth review – legend and truth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/nero-the-man-behind-the-myth-review-legend-and-truth</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/06/nero-the-man-behind-the-myth-review-legend-and-truth"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British Museum, London
This Roman blockbuster features relics from the great fire of AD64 and invites the visitor to judge the emperor’s true nature
Fiddling while Rome burns is a hard charge to dislodge. Nero did nothing, or he played the violin (so I was taught as a child), while the city went up in flames. Blaming Christians for the fire, he had them burned alive in pits, before building a giant golden palace on the ruins. He also murdered his mother, brother, two of his wives and much of the Roman elite.
The only surviving accounts of Nero (37-68 AD) – by Tacitus and Suetonius, near-contemporary historians, and Cassius Dio in the second century – are almost unanimously hostile. A teenager put on the throne by his scheming mother, Agrippina, Nero is greedy, violent and homicidal. In addition to fratricide, matricide and uxoricide, he is even guilty of the unusual crime of “urbicide”, having set fire to Rome himself.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK needs national register for eating disorder deaths, MPs say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/uk-needs-national-register-for-eating-disorder-deaths-mps-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/uk-needs-national-register-for-eating-disorder-deaths-mps-say"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T12:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for better data collection on anorexia and bulimia comes as experts warn of underreported crisis

‘Young people need help’: parents call for change in eating disorder care

Eating disorder deaths need to be recorded on a national register, MPs are urging, as experts warn of an underreported “crisis” in the growing number of people in the UK experiencing life-threatening disorders.
While Office for National Statistics figures show 36 people died in 2019 from conditions such as anorexia, there are concerns this underestimates the true toll. A high-level US study gives estimated data on death rates that when transposed to the UK indicates that the annual death rate could be about 1,860 people a year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds detained without trial in Uganda in new wave of repression]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/uganda-bobi-wine-yoweri-museveni-hundred-opposition-activist-detained-without-trial-new-wave-repression</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/uganda-bobi-wine-yoweri-museveni-hundred-opposition-activist-detained-without-trial-new-wave-repression"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T11:15:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roundup of opposition activists took place in May around date of swearing-in ceremony for President Yoweri Museveni
A new wave of repression in Uganda has led to the abductions of dozens more opposition activists by security forces and at least one alleged death. Several hundred people are thought to have been detained without trial in the east African country in secret prisons where they are subjected to a brutal regime of mistreatment. The country has suffered a series of crackdowns aimed at stamping out dissent since campaigning began for presidential elections late last year.
The trigger for the most recent repression by security services appears to have been the swearing-in ceremony of Uganda’s veteran president, the 76-year-old Yoweri Museveni, in May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke in Johannesburg and Samuel Okiror in Kampala</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martina Topley-Bird: ‘I wasn’t trying to be famous. I was embarrassingly earnest about being authentic’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/06/martina-topley-bird-forever-i-wait-tricky-maxinquaye-aftermath</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/06/martina-topley-bird-forever-i-wait-tricky-maxinquaye-aftermath"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T11:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The vocalist breaks her long silence to talk about grieving for her daughter, her pioneering work with Tricky on Maxinquaye and finally making an album she’s 98% happy with…
Martina Topley-Bird is struggling with her voice today. “It was awful last night,” she says, croakily, down the line from her home in Valencia. “My first interview in 11 years and then this happens!” As it turns out, Topley-Bird’s will hold out for well over an hour. But it won’t always take her to where she wants to go. She’s agreed to an interview to promote Forever I Wait, her first album since 2010’s Some Place Simple, but she doesn’t enjoy talking about herself; she’s fully aware of her tendency to let conversations drift, leave sentences unfinished, not quite pin down the message she wants to deliver. Speaking to her can be like listening to some of her dreamier music: captivating, meditative, yet somehow with a sense of her barely being there at all. A typical anecdote might grind to a halt midway through: “But yeah… I don’t know… sorry, vagued out again!”
There is also a subject that is never going to be easy to talk about. In 2019, Topley-Bird’s daughter, Mazy, also known as Mina, killed herself at the age of 24. She had suffered a psychotic episode following a gig with her band 404 and died after being admitted to West Park hospital, Darlington. An inquest led to the coroner saying he would make two prevention of future death reports to reduce the risk of patients self-harming on the ward. At the time, Topley-Bird put out a statement saying: “Sweet baby, life won’t be the same without you.” But she hasn’t spoken since. She’s said in advance today that the subject can be broached, but that doesn’t make it any less difficult. “I’m only just beginning to process it,” she later admits.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Jonze</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tory party threatens the success of UK soft power with this inhumane act | David Davis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/tory-party-threatens-success-of-uk-soft-power-with-this-inhumane-act</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/tory-party-threatens-success-of-uk-soft-power-with-this-inhumane-act"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T10:15:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To cut our commitment to Africa now is both self-destructive and, worse, cruel
As a Foreign Office minister in the mid-1990s, I saw dramatic changes following the fall of the Berlin Wall. But these could be overtaken in historical significance by the combination of Covid-19, climate change and the rise of China. As a former chairman of the public accounts committee, I’m under no illusions about the cost of misusing public money but I have also seen the price we pay when we fail to invest in Britain’s global interests. And as Brexit secretary, I saw first hand the way that developing countries value the UK’s role in international development.
Across Africa, the UK has let its natural advantage slip. As we looked away, China powered in. Britain’s bilateral trade has suffered and British influence is now being compromised. In the shadow of Covid, people are fearful and anxious. Economies are fragile. The continent is ripe for exploitation by foreign powers in brute pursuit of profit and control.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Davis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artist asks Blackpool council to demolish his seafront sculpture over safety fears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/artist-liam-curtin-asks-blackpool-to-demolish-high-tide-organ-sculpture</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/artist-liam-curtin-asks-blackpool-to-demolish-high-tide-organ-sculpture"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T10:07:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liam Curtin says lack of maintenance has left Blackpool High Tide Organ in a poor condition
An artist is calling on council officials to take down his most famous work after claiming that a lack of maintenance has left it in a poor state and a threat to public safety.
Liam Curtin’s Blackpool High Tide Organ was constructed along the town’s new promenade in 2002. Commissioned by Blackpool council and designed by Curtin and John Gooding, the structure is primarily made of Corten steel – the same material used for the Angel of the North sculpture.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer pickles and cheese sandwiches | Nigel Slater]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/06/nigel-slaters-recipes-for-summer-pickles-and-cheese-sandwiches</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/06/nigel-slaters-recipes-for-summer-pickles-and-cheese-sandwiches"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T09:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether in a cheddar toastie or a bagel with avocado and mozzarella, sandwich season calls for bright, sharp pickles
A pot of pickled vegetables is useful to have in the fridge. The pickles – carrot, cucumber, radish, maybe some strips of cabbage – but also the pickle juice itself, the astringent potion of vinegar and spice.
I make my own refrigerator pickles, though not all the time. It gives the opportunity to increase the salt or decrease the sugar as you wish. (We are not talking long-term storage here.) You can use allspice instead of juniper, mustard seeds in place of coriander, and lead the pickling liquor in whatever direction you choose – east (star anise and clove), south (chillies and garlic) or north (juniper and dill). I also include ready-made sauerkraut in mine, too.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nigel Slater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyram Yarbro, Gen Z’s skincare saviour: ‘YouTube gave me a reason to live’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/06/hyram-yarbro-the-most-powerful-skinfluencer-on-social-media-talks-to-funmi-fetto</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/06/hyram-yarbro-the-most-powerful-skinfluencer-on-social-media-talks-to-funmi-fetto"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T09:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How did a boy from a Mormon farming family become social media’s most powerful ‘skinfluencer’?
Truthfully, I didn’t expect to blow up to this scale. And yes, I know this is going to sound clichéd, but if you told me, even a year ago, that it was going to be this big, I would not have believed it.” Considering the trajectory of Hyram Yarbro, the 25-year-old Gen Z skincare guru set on making skincare “accessible”, it is easy to believe him.
His success in the past year, driven by a lockdown-fuelled obsession with skincare and social media, has made Yarbro the world’s most powerful “skinfluencer”. His young, captivated, skincare-obsessed disciples – 1.2m on Instagram, 4.5m on YouTube, 6.8m on TikTok (pre-lockdown 1.0, it was 100,000) – all diligently follow his skincare recommendations via his unfiltered, straight-shooting videos. At the beginning of the pandemic, he says he was uploading content on YouTube five to six times a week and posting three TikToks a day. “But I’ve scaled it back a little,” he says now, “because I was literally not sleeping”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Funmi Fetto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A year on, the battered and graffitied Colston is finally a potent memorial to our past | David Olusoga]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/year-on-battered-graffitied-colston-finally-potent-memorial-to-our-past</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/06/year-on-battered-graffitied-colston-finally-potent-memorial-to-our-past"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T09:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The slave trader’s statue is back on show in Bristol. There’s something electric about seeing it supine in a museum
Last week, for the first time in months, the burning eye of the outrage industry pivoted westwards and came to rest upon the city of Bristol. On Friday, the statue of the 17th-century slave trader Edward Colston, toppled last June during a Black Lives Matter protest, was put on display. To the fury of some, it was not returned triumphantly to its pedestal in the centre of the city, but exhibited in Bristol’s M Shed museum.
The debate around Colston in the summer of 2020 was largely conducted in a fact-free zone. So it is surely disconcerting for those determined to defend the memorialisation of a mass murderer that in this new setting Colston’s bronze effigy is surrounded by displays that give a detailed history of the slave trader’s grim career and the strange story that explains why, in the 19th century, a cult was created around him and the statue erected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Olusoga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fears for rights of EU citizens still waiting for UK settled status]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/fears-for-rights-of-eu-citizens-still-waiting-for-uk-settled-status-post-brexit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/06/fears-for-rights-of-eu-citizens-still-waiting-for-uk-settled-status-post-brexit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:45:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Backlog of 305,000 applications in post-Brexit settlement scheme prompts calls for extension of 30 June deadline
Hundreds of thousands of European citizens face legal limbo if the Home Office fails to clear a backlog of more than 300,000 applications before the EU settlement scheme closes at the end of this month, campaigners have warned.
With about three weeks to go before the deadline for EU workers and their families to apply for permanent residency in the UK, campaigners say anxiety and confusion remain over the rights of the 305,000 who have applied and are waiting for a decision, with many fearing that they risk a loss of rights similar to that experienced by the Windrush generation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Townsend Home Affairs editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[David Mitchell: ‘The world still thinks autistic people don’t do emotions’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/06/david-mitchell-the-reason-i-jump-autism</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/06/david-mitchell-the-reason-i-jump-autism"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The writer on how translating The Reason I Jump for his non-verbal autistic son was a lifesaver and his excitement at seeing the new Matrix film he co-wrote
Author David Mitchell, 52, was born in Southport, grew up in Malvern and now lives near Cork in Ireland. He published the first of his nine novels, Ghostwritten, aged 30. He has been twice shortlisted for the Man Booker prize, for number9dream and Cloud Atlas. He has also written opera libretti and screenplays. Mitchell translated the autism memoir The Reason I Jump from Japanese to English with his wife, Keiko Yoshida. Written by Naoki Higashida when he was 13, the book became an international bestseller and has now been turned into an award-winning documentary also featuring Mitchell.
What was your experience of reading The Reason I Jump for the first time?
My son had been fairly recently diagnosed. We had no idea what was happening in his head or how to help him. It felt a little like we’d lost our son. My wife ordered this book from Japan, began reading it at the kitchen table and verbally translating bits for me. There were startling overlaps between Naoki and our son’s behaviours – plus pretty persuasive explanations for those behaviours. Our four-year-old was hitting his head repeatedly on the kitchen floor and we had no clue why. This book arrived in the middle of that and, God, it was a lifesaver.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Hogan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Blair calls for new pass to allow vaccinated people more freedoms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/tony-blair-calls-for-new-pass-to-allow-vaccinated-people-more-freedoms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/06/tony-blair-calls-for-new-pass-to-allow-vaccinated-people-more-freedoms"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:24:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former PM says those who have had both jabs should be treated differently from those who have not
People who have been vaccinated against Covid-19 should be able to travel abroad using a new digital pass and go to “vaccine-only” venues such as restaurants or sports stadiums, Tony Blair says today.
Releasing a report entitled “Less Risk, More Freedom”, by the Tony Blair Institute for Global Change, the former prime minister says the time has come “to distinguish for the purposes of freedom from restriction between the vaccinated and unvaccinated”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK foreign aid cuts ‘will leave 100,000 refugees without water’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/06/uk-foreign-aid-cuts-will-leave-100000-refugees-without-water</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/06/uk-foreign-aid-cuts-will-leave-100000-refugees-without-water"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:13:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aid agencies write to Foreign Office minister as pressure grows on Boris Johnson ahead of Commons vote
UK aid cuts of 42% will leave about 70,000 people without health services and 100,000 without water in Cox’s Bazar, the world’s largest refugee settlement, before the deadly cyclone season, the Foreign Office minister for Asia has been warned.
A private letter sent to him last week by a group of aid agencies working in the area comes before a vote on Monday designed to force ministers to guarantee they will restore UK aid to 0.7% of gross national income next year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft’s Kate Crawford: ‘AI is neither artificial nor intelligent’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/microsofts-kate-crawford-ai-is-neither-artificial-nor-intelligent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/microsofts-kate-crawford-ai-is-neither-artificial-nor-intelligent"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The AI researcher on how natural resources and human labour drive machine learning and the regressive stereotypes that are baked into its algorithms 
Kate Crawford studies the social and political implications of artificial intelligence. She is a research professor of communication and science and technology studies at the University of Southern California and a senior principal researcher at Microsoft Research. Her new book, Atlas of AI, looks at what it takes to make AI and what’s at stake as it reshapes our world.
You’ve written a book critical of AI but you work for a company that is among the leaders in its deployment. How do you square that circle?
I work in the research wing of Microsoft, which is a distinct organisation, separate from product development. Unusually, over its 30-year history, it has hired social scientists to look critically at how technologies are being built. Being on the inside, we are often able to see downsides early before systems are widely deployed. My book did not go through any pre-publication review – Microsoft Research does not require that – and my lab leaders support asking hard questions, even if the answers involve a critical assessment of current technological practices.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoë Corbyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little-known deadline threatens to scupper homebuyers’ dreams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/06/little-known-deadline-threatens-to-scupper-homebuyers-dreams</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/06/little-known-deadline-threatens-to-scupper-homebuyers-dreams"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An obscure completion date for help-to-buy loans could wreck people’s plans to get on the property ladder
Sam Walker was looking forward to moving into his new home with his family once all the construction work was done. But then his plans looked at risk of collapse.
He realised he could lose the Bradford property he bought off-plan because the January 2022 completion date disqualified it from the scheme he used to buy it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Tims</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The mystery of Denmark’s vanishing wolf pack – are hunters to blame?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/06/the-mystery-of-denmarks-vanishing-wolf-pack-are-hunters-to-blame</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/06/the-mystery-of-denmarks-vanishing-wolf-pack-are-hunters-to-blame"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T08:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite a resurgence in lowland Europe, numbers almost halve in the country
Wolves could become extinct again in Denmark and other lowland European countries unless the population is topped up by migrating animals, according to a new study.
A wolf pack crossed the border from Germany into Denmark in 2017, ending a 200-year absence of wolves in the country. But 48% of Denmark’s wolf population has subsequently been illegally killed or disappeared, with shooting the only plausible explanation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just don’t do it: 10 exercise myths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/just-dont-do-it-10-exercise-myths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/just-dont-do-it-10-exercise-myths"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T07:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We all believe we should exercise more. So why is it so hard to keep it up? Daniel E Lieberman, Harvard professor of evolutionary biology, explodes the most common and unhelpful workout myths
Yesterday at an outdoor coffee shop, I met my old friend James in person for the first time since the pandemic began. Over the past year on Zoom, he looked just fine, but in 3D there was no hiding how much weight he’d gained. As we sat down with our cappuccinos, I didn’t say a thing, but the first words out of his mouth were: “Yes, yes, I’m now 20lb too heavy and in pathetic shape. I need to diet and exercise, but I don’t want to talk about it!”
If you feel like James, you are in good company. With the end of the Covid-19 pandemic now plausibly in sight, 70% of Britons say they hope to eat a healthier diet, lose weight and exercise more. But how? Every year, millions of people vow to be more physically active, but the vast majority of these resolutions fail. We all know what happens. After a week or two of sticking to a new exercise regime we gradually slip back into old habits and then feel bad about ourselves.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel E Lieberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracy Brabin: ‘I looked around and all the other mayors were men…’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/06/tracy-brabin-all-the-other-mayors-were-men-interview-west-yorkshire-jo-cox</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/06/tracy-brabin-all-the-other-mayors-were-men-interview-west-yorkshire-jo-cox"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T07:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new mayor for West Yorkshire on how her friendship with Jo Cox inspired her to enter politics and how she hopes to ‘bring back northern pride’
In all the fevered commentary about how Labour might reconnect with its lost voters in England’s northern towns, one credible answer seems to have been hiding in plain sight. The latest symbolic red wall defeat to the Tories, in the Hartlepool byelection last month, overshadowed another result that might give the opposition party some cause for hope: Tracy Brabin, the former Coronation Street actor and shadow culture minister, was elected the inaugural metro mayor of newly “devolved” West Yorkshire.
Brabin’s victory, with almost 60% of the vote, gives her strategic powers in a region with a population of 2.3 million. It also, she believes, establishes a new red “thread” across the Pennines – a link with fellow Labour metro mayors Andy Burnham in Greater Manchester, Steve Rotheram in the Liverpool city region and Dan Jarvis in South Yorkshire. If the past year has revealed one thing in the changing political landscape, it is that these regional figureheads, with their direct local mandate, can be a potent voice of opposition to Westminster government in a way that council leaders rarely are. The prime minister spent the first wave of Covid criminally avoiding consultation with local government, but the second being forced to listen, in particular to Burnham, Labour’s “northern leader”. Michael Heseltine, one political godfather of the metro mayors, told Brabin in a call after her victory that it was now her solemn political duty to “kick the government’s butt” in every possible way on behalf of the people of West Yorkshire. When I met her last week in Batley, 10 miles south of Leeds, it was clear she couldn’t wait to get started.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The battle to save England’s chalk streams, one of the planet’s rarest habitats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/06/the-battle-to-save-englands-chalk-streams-one-of-the-planets-rarest-habitats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/06/the-battle-to-save-englands-chalk-streams-one-of-the-planets-rarest-habitats"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T06:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rivers are especially vulnerable to water abstraction and global heating, but now there is hope for River Chess
Conservationist Allen Beechey remembers a time, in the 1990s, when trout swam along the River Chess as it meandered through the centre of his home town of Chesham. “It was a gentle, reassuring sight and it helped trigger my love of nature,” Beechey said last week.
Then came the droughts, the river dried up – sometimes for several years at a stretch – and the fish died out. They have yet to come back to the Buckinghamshire town.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie Science Editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: a father and daughter’s Main Street march]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/jun/06/the-big-picture-a-father-and-daughters-main-street-march</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/2021/jun/06/the-big-picture-a-father-and-daughters-main-street-march"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T06:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This memorable shot of a civil rights protest in Memphis was taken by Ernest Withers, later revealed to be an FBI informant
One of the early civil rights marches down Main Street in Memphis, Tennessee, was for fathers and daughters only. It was hoped the presence of young girls might reduce the chance of violence against protesters. In later life, Renee Andrewnetta Jones, who was eight months old at the time of this famous picture, looked back on the events in which she had been an unwitting participant. She had grown up to become a paediatrician in Memphis.
“To my understanding, my father, William Edwin Jones, made the sign himself,” she said. “He was a tall, stately man and as the police approached us, they had these intimidating looks, but my father wasn’t a man to be intimidated. A year after the picture was taken he was selected as one of the first black foreign service officers in the United States, posted with his family to Nigeria.” She had never forgotten the emotional force of the sign itself. “I always try to live without any boundaries,” she said, “because that is the way we were raised.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Trump: Biden set to outline US policy to Johnson, Putin and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/trump-biden-us-policy-johnson-putin-queen-erdogan-eu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/06/trump-biden-us-policy-johnson-putin-queen-erdogan-eu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The president will meet the Queen and Erdoğan as well as democratic leaders but experts including John Bolton wonder what purpose his Russia summit will serve
Joe Biden will make his first overseas trip as US president this week, determined to convince allies and adversaries “America is back” after four years under Donald Trump.
 Related: Arizona emails show Trump pushed ‘to prove any fraud’ before Capitol attack 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My beloved parents treat me as if I am still 10 years old | Dear Mariella]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/dear-mariella-my-beloved-parents-treat-me-as-if-i-am-sill-10-years-old</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/06/dear-mariella-my-beloved-parents-treat-me-as-if-i-am-sill-10-years-old"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T05:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s time to break free, says Mariella Frostrup. They may be acting from the most caring of motives, but you can’t allow your family to prevent you being your best possible self
The dilemma I am a woman in my early 30s. I have financial independence, a job I love, my own home, wonderful friends, and pets I adore. Despite all of this my parents, who I love dearly, still treat me as if I’m 10. How I spend my money (even on groceries) is monitored. New clothes or books are noted and commented on. I would like to try new hobbies, but my mother always comes up with a reason why I shouldn’t. With my father it’s more about my physical safety: I’m not allowed to travel or take jobs in certain cities.
I’ve tried moving away, limiting calls and only visiting once a week. This has not been successful. I feel like I am incapable of functioning without their opinion or presence, but is that because I need them, or because of how I’ve been raised?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariella Frostrup</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cattle thieves kill 66 villagers in north-west Nigeria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cattle-thieves-nigeria-kill-villagers-</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cattle-thieves-nigeria-kill-villagers-"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T00:28:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police still searching for more bodies after gunmen on motorcycles attacked seven villages 
A gang of cattle thieves have killed 66 people in raids on seven villages in north-west Nigeria’s Kebbi state, police say.
Dozens of assailants on motorcycles attacked seven neighbouring villages in Danko-Wasagu district on Thursday, Kebbi state police spokesman Nafiu Abubakar told AFP on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing lightning: a photographer’s pursuit of the elements – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will Eades is an award-winning photographer based on the mid north coast of NSW. His mission is to see and capture spectacular moments in nature, and to share these rare moments with others. A self-taught Nikon shooter, Will’s main focus is on storms and other weather phenomena as he strives to be present when the elements align for a great photograph
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Eades/ willeadesphotography</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A journey down WA’s mighty Martuwarra, raging river and sacred ancestor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Traditional owners are standing together to protect the Fitzroy – a ‘beautiful, living water system’. Just watch out for the bird-sized spiders …
A Nyikina man, Mark Coles Smith, and his fellow travellers began their 400km journey down the mighty Martuwarra (Fitzroy River) on a flood plain covered in giant spiders.
“Bird-sized” spiders were clinging to the canopy, jostling for space on branches protruding above flood water that stretched for kilometres in every direction.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorena Allam;  production: Carly Earl; photographs: Jackson Gallagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where mining meets rainforest: the battle for Tasmania’s Tarkine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/06/where-mining-meets-rainforest-the-battle-for-tasmanias-tarkine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/06/where-mining-meets-rainforest-the-battle-for-tasmanias-tarkine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners say plans for a new tailings dam threatens wilderness that should be declared a heritage area
Four days before the Morrison government was due to decide the future of a mining development in the takayna/Tarkine, 77-year-old Frits Harmsen planted a camping chair in front of trucks on an unsealed road snaking through Australia’s largest temperate rainforest.
Harmsen, a former French horn player with the Tasmanian Symphony Orchestra, was part of a small band of Bob Brown-endorsed protesters who on Friday began a 19th day attempting to block work by MMG, a majority Chinese-owned minerals company, in Tasmania’s remote north-west.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Morton Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One death, 11 jailed teenagers: was a Moss Side murder trial racist?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/one-death-11-jailed-teenagers-was-a-moss-side-trial-racist</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/one-death-11-jailed-teenagers-was-a-moss-side-trial-racist"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:22:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, 11 Manchester teenagers were jailed for a total of 168 years for their part in a killing. Now three are appealing amid claims that the investigation and trials were riddled with racism
Early one morning in Moss Side, Manchester, several winters ago, a group of teenagers gathered at a youth club to make a rap video. The shoot had been arranged by Kemoy Walker, an award-winning youth worker who is now a head of year at a large school in the city and an ambassador for Manchester city council.
Walker’s organisation, “Manchestarz”, had attracted public funding, including from Greater Manchester Police (GMP), for work that engaged young people in music. The video, shot by a film student at Manchester Metropolitan University who had answered a call on the social network Instagram for somebody with the necessary skills, was the perfect project. “We met early in the morning, everybody came on time,” recalls Walker. “We made the video in the park – it was quite cold – and it was really good. It was friends coming together and creating music.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second world war through the lenses of German soldiers – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/05/the-second-world-war-through-the-lens-of-german-soldiers-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/05/the-second-world-war-through-the-lens-of-german-soldiers-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T09:52:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1939, thousands of German soldiers, many of them conscripts, were dispatched across Europe. They went armed not only with weapons but with cameras – the famous German Leica and Rolleiflex – in their bags and orders to capture what they saw.

As Britain, France and the Allied countries mark the 77th anniversary of the Normandy landings on D-day this weekend, a recently released book All at War: Photography by German Soldiers 1939-45, is a compilation of these photographs taken from a vast collection held by the Archive of Modern Conflict in London. Here are some of the photographs from the book
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Search and Filter Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b3480c11ffb70827ef9a88</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/search-and-filter-component-in-reactjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're building a React app, you want your users to be able to search and get exact results. And if you are getting tons of items from an API, then you need to create a way for users to be able to find various items easily.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning in Python – The Top New Scikit-Learn 0.24 Features You Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60ba33d7acb62507dd1d9050</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-python-new-scikit-learn-features-you-should-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scikit-learn is one of the most popular open-source and free machine learning libraries for Python.  The scikit-learn library contains a lot of efficient tools for machine learning and statistical modeling including classification, regression, clustering, and dimensionality reduction. Many data scientists, machine learning engineers, and researchers rely on this library for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Recover from Deployment Hell – What I Learned After My Discord Bot Crashed on a 1000+ User Server]]></title>
        <id>60b8f5c7acb62507dd1d8500</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recovering-from-deployment-hell-what-i-learned-from-deploying-my-discord-bot-to-a-1000-user-server/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I deployed a Discord bot to a 1000+ user server. In the first hour, Deployment Hell struck and my bot crashed. In the next hour, I brought it back, surviving and even thriving in Deployment Hell. In this post, I'll show you how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn TypeScript Basics in this Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b2a4c611ffb70827ef9842</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-typescript-basics/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TypeScript has taken the development world by storm. No wonder it has over 15 million weekly downloads on npm. But what is TypeScript, and what do you need to know about it?  In this article, I am going answer those questions. By the end you'll have a grasp of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you meeting family and friends in a ‘green list’ country to avoid quarantine?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:58:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those who are meeting others in countries that are listed as safe to travel to without quarantine

Friends, families and couples who have been separated by coronavirus restrictions and want to avoid quarantine are able to meet in some countries that are listed as safe to travel to.
We want to hear from those who are travelling to other countries to meet loved ones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World leaders ‘ignoring’ role of destruction of nature in causing pandemics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ending the destruction of nature to stop outbreaks at source is more effective and cheaper than responding to them, scientists say 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The root cause of pandemics – the destruction of nature – is being ignored, scientists have warned. The focus of world leaders on responding to future outbreaks overlooks the far cheaper and more effective strategy of stopping the spillover of disease from animals to humans in the first place, they have said.
The razing of forests and hunting of wildlife is increasingly bringing animals and the microbes they harbour into contact with people and livestock. About 70% of new infectious diseases have come from animals, including Covid-19, Sars, bird flu, Ebola and HIV.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences during the Covid pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you’ve suffered in the past year or been lucky enough to escape the worst of it, we would like to hear your stories about the pandemic
The pandemic has been a difficult, dramatic time for so many of us, for so many different reasons. We have lost loved ones, had our families torn apart, struggled financially and emotionally. Some of us have been stressed by overwork; others by sudden unemployment. We have had to shield from the outside world – or been reluctantly obliged to mix with it.
If you have a story to share we would love to hear from you. You might be a doctor working flat out in A&E, a student who was locked down at university, a key worker forced to serve the public with inadequate PPE, a single mother who had to go months without childcare, a son who couldn’t visit his dying father in the care home … or even one of the lucky ones who has come out of the past year feeling stronger and more optimistic about life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN body pushed to demand stronger climate action from Australia to save Great Barrier Reef]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T06:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservationists lobby World Heritage Committee to demand Australia reduce emissions or risk reef being placed on ‘in danger’ list
Members of the United Nations World Heritage Committee are being lobbied to pressure Australia to commit to more ambitious climate action as part of its plan to slow the decline of the Great Barrier Reef ahead of a key July meeting.
Conservationists have lobbied representatives of 13 of the 21 countries that make up the committee, saying the threat of placing the reef on an “in danger” list should be used to lever more domestic action on greenhouse gas emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Readfearn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python for Bioinformatics: Use Machine Learning and Data Analysis for Drug Discovery]]></title>
        <id>60b98ebfacb62507dd1d8ec4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-for-bioinformatics-use-machine-learning-and-data-analysis-for-drug-discovery/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you looking for a way to apply Python and machine learning to a real-world application? You should consider Bioinformatics. Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data, in particular when the data sets are large and complex. We just released a course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s mouse plague - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Families and farmers in New South Wales are doing everything they can to fend off a biblical incursion of rodents. Guardian Australia’s Matilda Boseley has spent months reporting on the story – and hearing the experiences of those who have been affected
When mice started breeding in large numbers in New South Wales more than six months ago, residents went to war to repel them. Now they have reached a grim acceptance of their presence – and are counting the costs of a “plague” that has seen crops ravaged and homes ruined.
Rachel Humphreys spoke to Matilda Boseley, who has been reporting on the story, about how the mice came, what damage they have caused, and how difficult it is to get rid of them. And we hear residents’ accounts of what life is like with thousands of mice underfoot, in hay bales, and even in the washing machine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Matilda Boseley; produced by Hannah Moore and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Tutorial – How to Set Up a Front End Development Project]]></title>
        <id>60b11ff811ffb70827ef8f94</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-set-up-a-front-end-development-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T21:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you plan to build a website. Before you start, you want to set up a few tools to make your life easier. But which tools should you have? The JavaScript ecosystem is changing so fast that it can be overwhelming to pick the best tools to use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield&#x27;s Laws of Computing – What they Are and Why You Should Know Them]]></title>
        <id>60afd68611ffb70827ef86d8</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/schofields-laws-of-computing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:46:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield's Laws of Computing are principles that anyone who works with computers should know. They're focused on data portability, integrity, and security.  Jack Schofield was a prolific journalist who wrote for The Guardian and covered technology for nearly four decades. During that time, he wrote three particular articles called "Schofield's]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lists in Python – A Comprehensive Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b7c02cacb62507dd1d7b80</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lists-in-python-comprehensive-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:42:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s suppose you’re planning to visit your neighborhood store to stock up on essentials. What is the first thing you’d do?  Have the answer already? Yes, you'd probably write down a shopping list! Python also has a built-in data structure called List that’s very similar to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Hackintosh - Install MacOS Big Sur on a PC Using OpenCore]]></title>
        <id>60affbe411ffb70827ef8951</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-hackintosh/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Hackintosh is a non-Mac computer system, made with PC parts, that runs the macOS operating system. In this tutorial, you will learn how to create a Hackintosh. You will learn how to install macOS Big Sur (or any other version of macOS) using OpenCore. The main benefit of a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless vs Fully Managed Services: What&#x27;s the Difference?]]></title>
        <id>60aa708711ffb70827ef5f4b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/serverless-fully-managed-service-difference/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're new to cloud technologies, you might be confused about the difference between serverless technologies and managed services.  So in this article you'll learn what these terms mean and what the main differences are.    What Are Managed Services? A managed service let the end-user focus on using a service]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your best tips for giving up smoking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T13:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on how best to quit smoking 
After a 40-year decline, the number of smokers in England has increased during the pandemic, according to a new study. The biggest rise has been among 18 to 24-year-olds.
We know that many smokers are keen to kick the habit, but quitting can notoriously difficult. With this in mind, we’d love to hear your top tips for giving up. Perhaps you found nicotine replacements, such as patches or chewing gum, helpful while trying to quit? Or maybe you found you needed a distraction, such as a crossword or a Rubik’s cube, to keep your hands and mind busy? Tell us what worked for you.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wuhan lab leak theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden has asked US intelligence services to urgently investigate the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, including the possibility that it began with an accident in a laboratory. The Guardian’s Peter Beaumont looks at the available evidence 
When Covid-19 first emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan, much of the focus of the initial investigation fell on a seafood market that also sold exotic animals for human consumption. But in the months since, no definitive link has been proven and the precise origin story remains unsolved. 
In the intervening period numerous conspiracy theories have spread: that somehow 5G phone signals could be involved, or that the virus is a hoax. Bracketed in with these was a theory that Covid-19 may have been released (accidentally or otherwise) from a lab. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Peter Beaumont; produced by Sami Kent and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the eviction ban ending?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from renters in England who are at risk from losing their home due to the lifting of the eviction ban
The eviction ban in England was lifted on 31 May leaving nearly two million private renters concerned about whether they will be able to find another property if they lose their home. 
We would like to hear from those who have been affected by the eviction ban ending.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad’s decade of destruction in Syria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T02:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Syria’s president, Bashar al-Assad, has presided over a devastating civil war that has caused the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. Martin Chulov describes a man who came back from the brink of defeat to strengthen his grip on a country deeply scarred by war
Bashar al-Assad succeeded his father as president of Syria in 2000. He was just 34, had studied in London, and some hoped he would open up the autocratic country. Instead, following the Arab spring uprising he has cracked down harder than ever on the Syrian people. In the decade-long civil war that followed, more than 500,000 people are thought to have died. 
The Guardian’s Middle East correspondent, Martin Chulov, tells Anushka Asthana that as Assad lost control of vast areas of Syria following the uprising, he was at maximum vulnerability. But the intervention of Iran and Russia proved decisive. Now, after a widely discredited election victory with 95% of the vote, Assad begins his fourth term as president of a country deeply scarred by war. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Martin Chulov; produced by Alice Fordham and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An act of terrorism America tried to forget – 360 video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T07:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This video is best viewed on YouTube. Click here.
On the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, artist Bayeté Ross Smith uses archival photos to create immersive 360 scenes of these events. He finds that the underlying political and economic injustices were not only never addressed, but repeated time and again over the past century.
This story was suppressed from history books and the white perpetrators were never held accountable. And it wasn't just Tulsa. Dozens of other racial terrorism events from 1917 to 1921 have also gone untold, even within the victims' families. 

This is part one of Red Summers, a 360 video series by artist and filmmaker Bayeté Ross Smith on the untold American history of racial terrorism from 1917 to 1921. The project is funded by Black Public Media, Eyebeam, Sundance Institute, Crux XR and the Open Society Foundations.

Read more

Essay: It was among the worst acts of violence in US history, and no one was held accountable – how much has changed in the last 100 years?
‘The loss is incalculable’: descendants of the Tulsa massacre on what was stolen from them 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bayeté Ross Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free radicals to antioxidants: the science behind caring for oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:27:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problem skin often needs special attention. Here’s how to keep a blemish-prone complexion in check
Dr Emma Craythorne has spent her life studying skin; she is a consultant dermatologist, dermatological and laser surgeon and has a private practice on Harley Street. Problem skin, or skin types that can be challenging to manage, is something Craythorne knows a lot about. Here, she gives her unique insight into the way she helps people identify whether they have oily, blemish-prone skin and the skincare ingredients that’ll work best to target it …
Understand your skin type
“The first step in choosing the right skincare products is understanding what your skin type is,” says Craythorne. “To find out if you have oily skin, you want to assess what it feels like after you’ve washed it in the morning and patted it down. Wait 20 minutes; if after 20 minutes oily areas are appearing then you have oily skin.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Gunavardhana</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin and the city: why your serum needs to protect against urban living]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollution, ultraviolet radiation and cigarette smoke can all cause havoc on our skin – but it doesn’t have to. Here’s how to guard your skin from everyday threats
Our skin is the body’s largest organ and works especially hard to cope with the demands of urban living, protecting your body against the impact of free radical-forming ultraviolet (UV) radiation, pollution and cigarette smoke. Dr Ifeoma Ejikeme, dermatologist and founder of Adonia Medical Clinic, says: “Damage to the skin by free radical or reactive oxygen species can include hyperpigmentation, prominent appearance of pores, dull-looking skin and eventually fine lines and premature ageing.”
These skin stressors, combined with the added dermatological strain after months of life in lockdown – being indoors with the central heating on, anxiety and lack of sleep – can also leave the skin looking dull and prone to blemishes. A good night’s rest, meditation, a balanced diet and regular exercise can all help with internalised stress and anxiety, but what about the effects of pollution on the skin?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ateh Jewel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>