<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-12T00:29:01.315Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-12T00:29:01.315Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.6.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech playing growing role in UK domestic abuse cases, experts say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/12/tech-playing-growing-role-in-uk-domestic-abuse-cases-experts-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/12/tech-playing-growing-role-in-uk-domestic-abuse-cases-experts-say"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T23:01:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Complex cases involve perpetrators using multiple accounts and devices to abuse, control and monitor partners

‘It was so terrifying’: one woman’s experience of ‘tech abuse’

Domestic abuse cases requiring specialist support because technology has played a key role have soared over the last year, the largest specialist provider of domestic abuse investigation services in England and Wales has warned.
Complex tech abuse cases involve perpetrators using multiple accounts and devices to abuse, control and moni…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Grierson Home affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Love our bogs’: UK should harness all its landscapes in fight for climate – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/love-our-bogs-uk-should-harness-all-its-landscapes-in-fight-for-climate-report-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/12/love-our-bogs-uk-should-harness-all-its-landscapes-in-fight-for-climate-report-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T23:01:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First complete assessment of how UK nature-based solutions can combat the climate and biodiversity crises released ahead of crucial environment summits
Regenerating native woodland, restoring grassland and rewetting peatland must be priorities when tackling the “two defining crises of our age”, according to the first complete assessment of how UK nature-based solutions can combat the climate and biodiversity crises.
More than 100 ecologists examined how all kinds of landscapes – from urban to agricultural t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Weston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS in England and Wales treated fewest ever violence-related injuries in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/12/nhs-in-england-and-wales-treated-fewest-ever-violence-related-injuries-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/12/nhs-in-england-and-wales-treated-fewest-ever-violence-related-injuries-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T23:01:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown was reason behind sharp fall in number of people treated by NHS for injuries outside the home, say researchers
Lockdown led to the smallest number of people on record being treated by the NHS for injuries caused by violence away from the home, a study shows.
The closure of pubs, clubs and other venues that sell alcohol as part of the bans on social mixing was a key reason for the sharp decline in serious violence, the researchers say.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It was so terrifying’: one woman’s experience of ‘tech abuse’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/12/it-was-so-terrifying-one-womans-experience-of-tech-abuse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/12/it-was-so-terrifying-one-womans-experience-of-tech-abuse"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T23:01:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amy Aldworth was bombarded with aggressive messages, leading to anxiety and panic attacks

Tech playing growing role in UK domestic abuse cases, experts say

Amy Aldworth went on a date with a banker she met through an app and she thought it had gone well after both agreed to meet again.
But before the second date happened, she received an unusual message from the man, whom she has asked the Guardian not to name, insinuating she had given him a sexually transmitted disease.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Grierson Home affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Selenium and Python to Scrape Websites More Effectively]]></title>
        <id>6096aafe2cd0545b5e944430</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-web-scraping-with-selenium/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're scraping data from the web with Python, Selenium will often come up as an helpful tool to use. It was originally designed for automated testing, but its scraping capabilities are impressive, too. This is because Selenium can do things that other libraries or frameworks often can't when collecting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brit awards 2021: every performance reviewed, from Coldplay to Arlo Parks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/11/brit-awards-2021-every-performance-reviewed-coldplay-arlo-parks-rag-n-bone-man</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/11/brit-awards-2021-every-performance-reviewed-coldplay-arlo-parks-rag-n-bone-man"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:52:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Coldplay’s opening spectacular on the Thames to Rag’n’Bone Man movingly performing with an NHS choir, we rate all of this year’s live performances

News: Women dominate 2021 Brit awards as Dua Lipa tops winners

Coldplay are the Brits in band form: trying to be cool and youthful, way too corporate to get away with it, and yet almost always enjoyable. Chris and co are in that tricky part of a career recently faced by Katy Perry and others, where they’re not ready for a life on Radio 2, but their age mea…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brit awards 2021: the best of the ceremony and red carpet – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/brit-awards-2021-the-best-of-the-ceremony-and-red-carpet-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/brit-awards-2021-the-best-of-the-ceremony-and-red-carpet-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:42:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The highlights from the 41st Brit awards

Report: women dominate awards as Dua Lipa tops winners
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Compiled by Michael Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doctors  in London report fivefold increase in children swallowing magnets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/11/doctors-in-london-report-fivefold-increase-in-children-swallowing-magnets</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/11/doctors-in-london-report-fivefold-increase-in-children-swallowing-magnets"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:30:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Button batteries and magnets found in certain types of children’s toys associated with complications
There has been a fivefold increase in magnet ingestion over the past five years in young children amid a steady rise in hospital admissions in London caused by the swallowing of foreign objects, doctors have said.
While most of the time objects pass out of the body naturally without incident, button batteries and small permanent magnets found in cordless tools, hard disk drives, magnetic fasteners and certai…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340359</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-pie-timer-re-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitty reflected on an ancient blog post here on CSS-Tricks on how to make an animated pie timer. The old technique is still clever. The new technique is equally clever and much easier. I particularly like the steps() animation function&#8230;
The post CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer aide Carolyn Harris resigns in wake of Rayner row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/keir-starmer-aide-carolyn-harris-resigns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/keir-starmer-aide-carolyn-harris-resigns"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:33:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs have suggested Labour leader’s parliamentary aide had stoked tensions during bitter briefing war
Keir Starmer’s closest parliamentary aide, Carolyn Harris, has resigned after MPs suggested she had stoked tensions during the bitter briefing war between Starmer’s office and his deputy, Angela Rayner.
Harris, who was Starmer’s parliamentary private secretary (PPS) and acts as a liaison with other MPs, resigned on Tuesday, becoming the latest casualty after a difficult reshuffle over the weekend, in which R…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women dominate 2021 Brit awards as Dua Lipa tops winners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/11/women-dominate-2021-brit-awards-as-dua-lipa-tops-winners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/11/women-dominate-2021-brit-awards-as-dua-lipa-tops-winners"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:31:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[2020’s heavily male ceremony reversed with wins for Arlo Parks, Haim and Billie Eilish, as Little Mix become first all-woman winner of British group

Brit awards 2021: every performance reviewed, from Coldplay to Arlo Parks

Dua Lipa has topped the winners at the 2021 Brit awards, calling for Boris Johnson to approve “a fair pay rise” for frontline NHS staff as she picked up gongs including the top prize of British album for her chart-dominating disco spectacular Future Nostalgia.
She also won female solo a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas and Tobi Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Democrats propose quick reaction force in $2.1bn Capitol security bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/house-democrats-capitol-security-quick-reaction-force-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/house-democrats-capitol-security-quick-reaction-force-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:21:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proposal also includes construction of retractable fencing
Recommendations follow 6 January insurrection at US Capitol

House Democrats plan on Wednesday to unveil a $2.1bn supplemental bill to enhance security at the Capitol that will propose creating a quick reaction force to guard against future threats in the wake of the Capitol attack, according to sources familiar with the matter.
The proposed bill will also include the construction of a retractable fencing system around the Capitol, the sources said.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugo Lowell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ings’ double helps Southampton to welcome win over Crystal Palace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/southampton-crystal-palace-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/southampton-crystal-palace-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:13:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This game was always in danger of being forgotten but Danny Ings was determined to ensure his return did not go unnoticed. The striker scored twice to offer Gareth Southgate a timely reminder of his talents with two weeks to go until the England manager names his 26-man squad for Euro 2020. A couple of smart finishes helped Southampton prevail against Crystal Palace, who led inside two minutes courtesy of Christian Benteke.
Since the start of last season, only Harry Kane, Mohamed Salah and Jamie Vardy have …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at St Mary's</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boy, nine, dies after apparently being struck by lightning in Blackpool]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/boy-nine-dies-after-apparently-being-struck-by-lightning-in-blackpool</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/boy-nine-dies-after-apparently-being-struck-by-lightning-in-blackpool"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:11:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say the boy was on a football field at the time of the incident
A nine-year-old boy has died after apparently being struck by lightning on a football field in Blackpool, police have said.
Officers from Blackpool police were called shortly after 5pm on Tuesday to fields near to School Road after reports a child had been injured.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Press Association</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[31 people dead as Netanyahu vows to intensify Gaza attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/dead-in-gaza-after-jerusalem-violence-spreads</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/dead-in-gaza-after-jerusalem-violence-spreads"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medics say 28 Palestinians, two Israelis and an Indian woman have died after day of fierce confrontation

Explainer: what has caused Jerusalem’s worst violence in years? 

The Israeli prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, has vowed to increase the intensity of attacks on Gaza, after a day of ferocious confrontations that left 31 people dead as Israeli jets and Palestinian militants traded airstrikes and rockets.
As medics on both sides put the death toll at 28 Palestinians, including 10 children, two Israelis…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I could build this during the weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340186</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/joaoqalves/i-could-build-this-during-the-weekend-aa093c5e"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many times have you heard that (or even uttered it under your own breath)? I know I&#8217;ve heard it in conversations. I also know I&#8217;ve wondered the same thing about a product or two — hey, the idea here &#8230;
The post I could build this during the weekend appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ten people shot dead in Ballymurphy were innocent, inquest finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/inquest-to-report-on-alleged-killings-by-british-soldiers-in-ballymurphy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/inquest-to-report-on-alleged-killings-by-british-soldiers-in-ballymurphy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:03:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report says killings during British army operations in Belfast in 1971 were unjustified 
Ten people killed in Belfast during a British army operation in 1971 were unarmed, innocent civilians and posed no threat to soldiers, an inquest in Northern Ireland has found.
The damning findings in a long-awaited coroner’s report implicated the army in an atrocity to rival Bloody Sunday, potentially galvanising a new push to prosecute army veterans.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rory Carroll and Heather Stewart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hospital review – guaranteed to make you scream at your screen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/11/hospital-review-guaranteed-to-make-you-scream-at-your-screen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/11/hospital-review-guaranteed-to-make-you-scream-at-your-screen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BBC series homes in on University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire Trust, where a pandemic backlog and dire lack of funds has led to agony all round. Show them the money! 

Just. Give. Them. Some. Money. That’s all. Such has been the unavoidable – however unbiased the makers – message of every documentary about the NHS since … well, let’s say for simplicity’s sake, since documentaries set in NHS hospitals and other outposts began. With Covid-19, the number of the documentaries and the intensity of th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man accused of killing eight people in Atlanta spa shootings indicted on murder charges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/atlanta-spa-shootings-man-indicted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/atlanta-spa-shootings-man-indicted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T20:07:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hate crime charges and the death penalty are being sought against Robert Aaron Long, accused of killing six women of Asian descent
A Fulton county grand jury indicted Robert Aaron Long, 22, in the March 16 slayings of Sun Cha Kim, 69; Soon Chung Park, 74; Hyun Jung Grant, 51; and Yong Ae Yue, 63. The indictment only covers those four killings that happened at two spas in Atlanta, and not the attack in Cherokee county in which Xiaojie “Emily” Tan, 49; Daoyou Feng, 44; Delaina Yaun, 33; and Paul Michels, 54, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Write a Résumé – Practical Guide with Example Résumé]]></title>
        <id>6093929601fc34080ef81a0f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-write-a-resume-with-example/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T19:40:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing a résumé can be a little intimidating. And the pressure to make it really good and fill in each detail can be tiresome and scary. This is especially true if you're doing it for the first time, because you might not know what to add in or what to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greece offers €300,000 reward for killers who strangled British-born student in front of baby]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/greece-offers-300000-reward-for-killers-who-strangled-british-born-student-in-front-of-baby</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/greece-offers-300000-reward-for-killers-who-strangled-british-born-student-in-front-of-baby"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T19:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minister says country ‘shaken up’ by killing of Caroline Crouch, 20, while husband tied up and dog hung from banister
The Greek government has offered a €300,000 (about £257,000) reward to try to track down the culprits behind the murder of a British-born student in her suburban Athens home.
The reward was publicised hours after Caroline Crouch, 20, was strangled in front of her baby daughter by armed burglars who had bound her husband, Babis Anagnostopoulos, to a chair after breaking in. The intruders also…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helena Smith in Athens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Imperious campaign’ – player ratings for Manchester City’s title winners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/player-ratings-for-manchester-city-premier-league-title-winners</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/player-ratings-for-manchester-city-premier-league-title-winners"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T19:12:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two of Guardiola’s squad get 10 out of 10 for their contributions to the club’s third Premier League title in four years
The epitome of the modern goalkeeper, his passing is more important than his shot-stopping for Pep Guardiola. The Brazilian even managed an assist for Ilkay Gündogan in the win over Spurs. His 18 clean sheets should not be glossed over, as they offer proof of City’s new-found rigidity.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Unwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on the Queen’s speech and plans for mandatory voter ID – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/11/ben-jennings-on-the-queens-speech-and-plans-for-mandatory-voter-id-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/11/ben-jennings-on-the-queens-speech-and-plans-for-mandatory-voter-id-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T19:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City’s title is a triumph of class and refinement on the hoof | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/manchester-city-title-triumph-class-and-refinement-on-the-hoof-premier-league-pep-guardiola</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/manchester-city-title-triumph-class-and-refinement-on-the-hoof-premier-league-pep-guardiola"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:56:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Look beyond the wealth and admire the solutions found by Pep Guardiola and his team in this draining, bubble-bound season
Was it ever in doubt? Funnily enough, the answer to this question is yes. Such has been the serene, high-spec nature of Manchester City’s passage through the second half of the season it is easy to forget that the drive towards a third Premier league title in four years contained its own wrong turns, crunched gears and a sustained period of meandering in the doldrums.
Even the moment of …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amigo Loans rescue in doubt after FCA says it will object in court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/amigo-loans-rescue-in-doubt-after-fca-says-it-will-object-in-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/amigo-loans-rescue-in-doubt-after-fca-says-it-will-object-in-court"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shares in high-cost lender down by almost quarter after regulator’s U-turn
Rescue plans put forward by the high-cost lender Amigo Loans were thrown into doubt on Tuesday after a U-turn by the main financial regulator, which said it would object in court to a deal, reversing its previous stance.
Shares in the company, which charges 49.9% interest and requires borrowers to provide a friend or family member to act as a guarantor, tumbled by almost a quarter after the intervention by the Financial Conduct Autho…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Britain warns EU that Northern Ireland protocol unsustainable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/britain-warns-eu-that-northern-ireland-protocol-unsustainable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/britain-warns-eu-that-northern-ireland-protocol-unsustainable"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:53:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brexit minister says UK would ‘consider all our options’ after meeting with business leaders

The UK government has warned that the special Brexit arrangements for Northern Ireland as they stand are unworkable, in an intervention made at a sensitive phase in talks with the EU on the controversial border checks.
After a visit to meet business leaders in Belfast on Tuesday, the Brexit minister, Lord Frost urged the EU to take a pragmatic approach in talks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City win the Premier League after United lose to Leicester]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/manchester-city-crowned-premier-league-champions-united-lose-leicester</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/manchester-city-crowned-premier-league-champions-united-lose-leicester"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:51:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardiola’s side are champions for third time in four seasons
‘This was the hardest one,’ says City’s manager

Pep Guardiola said his third Premier League title as Manchester City manager was “the hardest one” to win after they were crowned champions following Manchester United’s defeat by Leicester.
 Related: Manchester City’s title is a triumph of class and refinement on the hoof | Barney Ronay 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebels are right that a £2m rise is pushing it – even for AstraZeneca’s superstar | Nils Pratley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/rebels-are-right-that-a-2m-pay-cherry-is-pushing-it-even-for-astrazenecas-superstar</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/rebels-are-right-that-a-2m-pay-cherry-is-pushing-it-even-for-astrazenecas-superstar"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:51:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fund managers tried to vote down Pascal Soriot’s package for fear of more boardroom pay inflation 
A majority is a majority, but a rebellion of 40% against an executive pay policy is too large to be pinned solely on those brain-dead fund managers who outsource their thinking to proxy voting agencies.
At AstraZeneca some serious institutions, with Aviva Investors and Standard Life Aberdeen to the fore, clearly thought the company was pushing things too far by adding a potential £2m cherry on top of their chi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No carriages and a solo throne – the Covid-compliant Queen’s speech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/covid-rules-strip-back-pomp-and-pageantry-of-queens-speech</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/covid-rules-strip-back-pomp-and-pageantry-of-queens-speech"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:31:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There were just 34 seated guests in the royal gallery, socially-distanced, wearing masks – and tested

There were no horses or carriages and the Queen sat alone on her throne at the state opening of parliament, with pomp and pageantry pared back because of Covid restrictions.
The Queen, on her first engagement outside Windsor Castle since the death of the Duke of Edinburgh, wore day dress instead of the usual state robes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Queen’s speech: sins of omission | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/the-guardian-view-on-the-queens-speech-sins-of-omission</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/the-guardian-view-on-the-queens-speech-sins-of-omission"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By yet again kicking social care reform into the long grass, the government has wasted a moment of national solidarity
The occasion was unusually austere, pared-down and sombre. But though the form of the Queen’s speech ceremony on Tuesday was dictated by Covid, the substance was all about moving beyond it. As the country gradually but steadily reopens, after 15 months of total or partial lockdown, this was the first major opportunity for Boris Johnson to fill out his vision for post-pandemic Britain.
That …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Jerusalem and Gaza: old struggles bring fresh violence | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/the-guardian-view-on-jerusalem-and-gaza-old-struggles-bring-fresh-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/the-guardian-view-on-jerusalem-and-gaza-old-struggles-bring-fresh-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:28:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new outbreak is the predictable result both of recent grievances and accumulated injustices
Ten children were among 28 killed in Gaza in the Holy month of Ramadan, while two Israeli women were killed as Israeli air strikes pounded the territory and Palestinian militants fired rockets. In Jerusalem, Israeli police fired stun grenades, teargas and rubber bullets at one of Islam’s holiest sites, leaving 300 Palestinians injured. Could this get worse? Yes. The prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, has vowed t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US airline chiefs add to pressure for transatlantic travel to restart]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/us-airline-chiefs-add-to-pressure-for-transatlantic-travel-to-restart</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/us-airline-chiefs-add-to-pressure-for-transatlantic-travel-to-restart"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:22:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[American, Delta and United bosses join BA and Virgin Atlantic in saying US-UK vaccination levels mean routes should reopen 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Major US airlines have weighed in alongside UK carriers to urge the reopening of transatlantic travel, calling on governments in Washington and London to arrange a summit as soon as possible.
The airlines said safely reopening borders was essential for economic recovery and asked the nations’ leaders to meet before the G7,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Queen’s a class act but the bills she has to read out are not | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/the-queens-a-class-act-but-the-bills-she-has-to-read-out-are-not</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/the-queens-a-class-act-but-the-bills-she-has-to-read-out-are-not"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:19:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s Queen’s speech wish list of legislation has some big omissions and dubious inclusions
First came Charles and Camilla, followed a short while later in a black Range Rover by the Queen and her lady-in-waiting. This may have been a pared-back state opening of parliament for these Covid times – no posh frocks from the dressing-up box and tiaras from Claire’s accessories for the women in the Lords and just a handful of MPs in the Commons – but there were standards to maintain. For the crown if no…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More than 2m voters may lack photo ID required under new UK bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/more-than-2m-voters-may-lack-photo-id-required-under-new-uk-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/more-than-2m-voters-may-lack-photo-id-required-under-new-uk-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:08:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critics warn older, disabled and homeless people risk being unfairly denied democratic say
More than 2 million UK voters could lack the necessary ID to take part in future elections, according to a government analysis of its flagship bill on voting rights, spurring warnings that “decades of democratic progress” risk going into reverse.
The plan for mandatory photo ID at elections – a central element of Tuesday’s Queen’s speech – risks disproportionately hitting older, disabled and homeless voters who are le…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker, Heather Stewart and Haroon Siddique</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Butchers: novel set in Irish BSE crisis wins Ondaatje prize]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/11/the-butchers-ruth-gilligan-wins-ondaatje-prize</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/11/the-butchers-ruth-gilligan-wins-ondaatje-prize"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ruth Gilligan’s thriller about eight men who cull cattle in rural Ireland wins £10,000 for books that ‘best evoke the spirit of a place’
Ruth Gilligan’s literary thriller The Butchers, set in the Irish borderlands during the BSE crisis, has won the Royal Society of Literature’s Ondaatje prize for books that “best evoke the spirit of a place”.
Gilligan’s novel beat titles including James Rebanks’ memoir of his family farm, English Pastoral, and Nina Mingya Powles’ poetry collection Magnolia, 木蘭 to the £10,00…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour can be reformed if it looks outwards, not just inwards | Peter Mandelson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/labour-can-be-reformed-if-it-looks-outwards-not-just-inwards</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/labour-can-be-reformed-if-it-looks-outwards-not-just-inwards"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party gains from its trade union links with working people, but it’s damaged by union leaders who use it as their political plaything
Earlier this week I wrote that “hard left factions seeking to control our largest trade unions should not have a guaranteed place in the governing counsels of the party”. I did not realise that affirmation would come so quickly from Aslef’s general secretary Mick Whelan, who chairs the national trade union-Labour organisation, Tulo. He demanded that Keir Starmer repudiate…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Mandelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tour de France organisers reveal women’s race will be revived in 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/tour-de-france-organisers-reveal-womens-race-will-be-revived-in-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/tour-de-france-organisers-reveal-womens-race-will-be-revived-in-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Race expected to take place after men’s Tour next summer
Christian Prudhomme: ‘We want a race that will stay the course’

The Tour de France organiser, Christian Prudhomme, has confirmed to the Guardian that there will be a women’s race in 2022 and that it will be held after the men’s Tour. Further details will be confirmed in October, around the time that the men’s Tour is usually launched.
“It will take place next year, that’s certain,” Prudhomme said. “It would have happened this year if it had not been …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>William Fotheringham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starmer can be PM if he curbs power of Labour factions, says Mandelson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/keir-starmer-curb-power-labour-factions-peter-mandelson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/keir-starmer-curb-power-labour-factions-peter-mandelson"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T18:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peer says urgent changes are needed so Labour can face outwards rather than struggle with internal battles

Opinion: ‘Labour can be reformed if it looks outwards, not just inwards’

Labour can win under Keir Starmer’s leadership if the party makes major changes to curb the influence of internal factions, Peter Mandelson has said in an article for the Guardian.
Lord Mandelson, who was Tony Blair’s first secretary of state and MP for Hartlepool, is said to have offered informal advice to Starmer’s team, thoug…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Héctor Bellerín and Bernd Leno could leave as Arsenal look at changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/hector-bellerin-and-bernd-leno-could-leave-as-arsenal-look-at-changes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/11/hector-bellerin-and-bernd-leno-could-leave-as-arsenal-look-at-changes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Luiz likely to leave Emirates in summer
Pierre-Emerick Aubameyang happy to stay at club

Héctor Bellerín is among a group of senior Arsenal players who could leave during a summer that will bring swingeing changes to Mikel Arteta’s squad.
As many as five established names are in the frame to depart as Arsenal measure up the financial cost of missing out on Champions League or Europa League qualification, with some of the players in question reluctant to commit to a club currently rooted in mid-table.
…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames and David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Beautiful Page Transitions in Angular]]></title>
        <id>609a73156008950828b3f2ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/beautiful-page-transitions-in-angular/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:50:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In today’s world, just having a website is not enough. The website needs to have a clean UI and it needs to be intuitive. And most importantly, it needs to have some sort of interactive element. Interactivity keeps users glued to your site for longer periods of time. As]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plaque unveiled to mark the birth of the Manchester Guardian]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/plaque-unveiled-to-mark-the-birth-of-the-manchester-guardian</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/plaque-unveiled-to-mark-the-birth-of-the-manchester-guardian"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:33:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mayor Andy Burnham describes paper’s foundation as an ‘important piece of British social history’
Two hundred years after the Manchester Guardian was founded in the aftermath of a bloody anti-establishment protest, a plaque has been erected to mark its birth.
Speaking at the unveiling in Manchester city centre, Andy Burnham described the foundation of the newspaper in 1821 – now the Guardian – as a “truly important piece of British social history”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Pidd North of England editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Labour MP told staffer ‘he craved her body’, tribunal hears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/ex-labour-mp-told-staffer-he-craved-her-body-tribunal-hears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/ex-labour-mp-told-staffer-he-craved-her-body-tribunal-hears"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:29:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Hill, formerly Hartlepool’s MP, is also accused of climbing into claimant’s bed on two occasions
A Labour MP wrote to a member of parliamentary staff saying he craved her body and climbed into her bed twice, an employment tribunal was told on Tuesday.
Mike Hill, who represented Hartlepool, resigned as Labour MP in March, sparking Thursday’s byelection and a victory for the Conservatives. Hill is facing claims of sexual harassment and victimisation, which he denies, at the tribunal in central London.
 C…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rajeev Syal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get a Job by Building Relationships – Advice from a Senior Software Engineer]]></title>
        <id>609552842cd0545b5e943bcd</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-get-a-job-by-building-relationships/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:29:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The job search is exhausting. You apply to countless jobs through LinkedIn and company websites. Apply, apply, apply. Submit, submit, submit. You're tired.  But you know that's not even the worst part. The worst part is the black hole your applications seem to fall into 95% of the time. Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s too late to save the union, Gordon Brown | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/its-too-late-to-save-the-union-gordon-brown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/its-too-late-to-save-the-union-gordon-brown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:25:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to the former prime minister’s hope for a middle way for Scotland rather than independence
Like Banquo’s ghost, Gordon Brown returns to haunt the independence debate in Scotland (Many Scots don’t want independence, but a more cooperative union, 9 May). And much like said spirit, he has come to represent not salvation but bad portents, because the last time he appeared was with “the vow” to deliver greater autonomy for Scotland within the union, in the hope of puncturing greater aspirations j…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In defence of Peter Preston’s handling of the Sarah Tisdall case | Letter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/in-defence-of-peter-preston-handling-of-the-sarah-tisdall-case</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/in-defence-of-peter-preston-handling-of-the-sarah-tisdall-case"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:24:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The editor’s decision to return the leaked documents was made after agonised deliberations and much consultation with staff, writes the Guardian’s former deputy editor David McKie
In your print-edition supplement (We were there: The 200 moments that made the Guardian, 9 May), you say of Peter Preston’s decision to hand back the document that would send Sarah Tisdall to prison, that he did this “to the dismay of both staff and readers”. I was there, and I think that’s misleading, and somewhat unjust to Peter…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helmut Jahn obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/11/helmut-jahn-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/11/helmut-jahn-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:22:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Architect known for his flamboyant, postmodernist buildings in Chicago, Berlin and other cities around the world
Standing on a corner of downtown Chicago as a dazzling rocket ship of mirrored glass and salmon pink steel, the James R Thompson Center, more than any other building, encapsulates the flamboyant oeuvre of the German-American architect Helmut Jahn, who has died aged 81 in a cycling accident. 
The glitzy government building, originally known as the State of Illinois Center, is a fitting monument to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Wainwright</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden administration approves first major US offshore windfarm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/biden-administration-approves-first-major-us-offshore-windfarm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/biden-administration-approves-first-major-us-offshore-windfarm"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:18:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 84-turbine site off Massachusetts will be capable of generating power for 400,000 homes and businesses
Joe Biden’s administration has approved the construction of the US’s first large-scale offshore windfarm, with 84 turbines to be erected off the coast of Massachusetts.
The approval of the project, which will generate about 800 megawatts of energy, enough to power around 400,000 homes and businesses, is a boost to Biden’s agenda of ramping up renewable energy production across the US in order to confro…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose and Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs executive quits after making millions from Dogecoin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/goldman-sachs-executive-quits-after-making-millions-from-dogecoin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/goldman-sachs-executive-quits-after-making-millions-from-dogecoin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:14:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The crypto asset is down more than 30% this week but is still up by more than 1,000% from the start of 2021
A senior manager at Goldman Sachs in London has quit the US investment bank after making millions from investing in Dogecoin, the joke crypto asset which has risen by more than 1,000% in value this year.
City sources said Aziz McMahon, a managing director and head of emerging market sales, had resigned from the bank after making money from investing in the digital currency based on the Doge internet m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oaks contenders set to go head-to-head in Musidora Stakes at York]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/oaks-contenders-head-to-head-musidora-stakes-york-horse-racing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/oaks-contenders-head-to-head-musidora-stakes-york-horse-racing"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:13:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teona and Noon Star riding high in Classic betting
Hardwicke Stakes hope Ilaraab also running at York

Only four of the eight fillies lining up for the Group Musidora Stakes at York on Wednesday also hold entries in the Oaks but they include Teona and Noon Star, the current second and third-favourites respectively for the Classic at Epsom next month.
Both have shown considerable promise in limited careers to date but Teona, while shorter in the betting for Epsom, is making her turf debut on Wednesday and ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK diplomat: few signs Taliban willing to engage in peace talks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/uk-diplomat-few-signs-taliban-willing-to-engage-in-peace-talks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/uk-diplomat-few-signs-taliban-willing-to-engage-in-peace-talks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T17:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alison Blake, UK ambassador to Afghanistan, says power-sharing talks are ‘nowhere near where we hoped’
There are few signs that the Taliban is willing to engage in peace talks, Alison Blake, the British ambassador to Kabul, has said.
With the UK joining the US in a military exit from Afghanistan by September, she told a Chatham House conference that the Taliban was engaged in psychological warfare and was ignoring western voices calling for power sharing and a commitment to protect women’s rights.
 Continue…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pontins death: decision to restrain man unlawful – inquest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/pontins-death-decision-to-restrain-man-unlawful-inquest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/pontins-death-decision-to-restrain-man-unlawful-inquest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:58:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jury finds Pontins staff in Suffolk failed to follow policy while restraining Paul Reynolds
A father of three who died at a Pontins holiday park would have lived had he not been restrained by the neck and placed in a prone position by security staff there, an inquest jury has found.
Paul Reynolds, 38, from Colchester, died in hospital two days after the incident at Pontins Pakefield in Lowestoft, Suffolk, on 14 February 2017, in which he became involved in an altercation with another guest.
 Continue readin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Russian-speaking cyber gang threatens release of Washington police data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/washington-police-hack-russian-speaking-babuk-gang</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/washington-police-hack-russian-speaking-babuk-gang"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:53:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Babuk group says it will release data unless police raise price
Extortion threat comes amid separate US ransomware attack

A Russian-speaking ransomware syndicate that stole data from the Washington DC police department says negotiations over payment have broken down and it will release sensitive information that could put lives at risk if more money is not offered.
 Related: GCHQ chief: west faces ‘moment of reckoning’ over cybersecurity 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Our children are getting killed’: the human cost of Israel-Gaza violence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/our-children-are-getting-killed-the-human-cost-of-israel-gaza-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/our-children-are-getting-killed-the-human-cost-of-israel-gaza-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:50:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As attacks leave 28 Palestinians and two Israelis dead, residents caught in the fighting share their stories
Lying in Gaza’s main hospital and unconscious for most of the night, the patient was unsure which members of his family were still alive.
Muhammad al-Masri, 22, was in front of his house on Monday night, just before breaking his fast for Ramadan. “I heard the sound of a bombardment coming towards us from the frontier,” he said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hazem Balousha in Gaza and Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instagram for kids – the social media site no one asked for]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/shortcuts/2021/may/11/instagram-for-kids-the-social-media-site-no-one-asked-for</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/shortcuts/2021/may/11/instagram-for-kids-the-social-media-site-no-one-asked-for"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:40:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook has been busy developing a child-friendly social media platform. But why are US lawmakers so unhappy?

Name: Instagram for kids.
Age: That is very much the question. How old are you? Old enough to be reading this pass notes, I hope.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC cuts Prince Andrew joke from RuPaul’s Drag Race]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/bbc-cuts-prince-andrew-joke-from-rupauls-drag-race</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/bbc-cuts-prince-andrew-joke-from-rupauls-drag-race"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:36:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joke in Australian version at expense of Queen’s scandal-hit son deemed not suitable for British audiences
The BBC is embroiled in a bizarre row about censorship, the royal family and drag queens after editing an episode of RuPaul’s Drag Race to remove a joke about Prince Andrew.
The national broadcaster is currently showing episodes of the new series RuPaul’s Drag Race Down Under on its iPlayer streaming service but edited out a comment made by a drag artist dressed as Queen Elizabeth II, apparently in the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Waterson Media editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The Flash Gordon of architecture’: Helmut Jahn’s bombastic marvels – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/flash-gordon-architecture-helmut-jahn-bombastic-greatest-buildings-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/flash-gordon-architecture-helmut-jahn-bombastic-greatest-buildings-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:29:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He took the power-dressing pomp of the 1980s and directed it at banks, airports and corporate HQs. Here are some of the greatest buildings of the German-American architect, who has died aged 81
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serena Williams and Rafael Nadal still unsure of playing in Tokyo Olympics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/rafael-nadal-and-serena-williams-still-unsure-of-playing-in-tokyo-olympics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/rafael-nadal-and-serena-williams-still-unsure-of-playing-in-tokyo-olympics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:28:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I don’t know my calendar,’ says the men’s world No 2
Williams: ‘I definitely need to figure out my next moves’

Rafael Nadal has added his voice to the chorus of tennis players expressing doubts about either their presence at the Olympic Games this summer or whether the event should be held under current circumstances.
“Honestly, I can’t give you a clear answer because I don’t know,” Nadal said at the Italian Open in Rome. “I don’t know my calendar. In a normal world I will never see about missing the Olym…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have you decided to create a regular ‘lockdown day’ for yourself or your family?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/11/have-you-decided-to-create-a-regular-lockdown-day-for-yourself-or-your-family</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/11/have-you-decided-to-create-a-regular-lockdown-day-for-yourself-or-your-family"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:26:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the country opening back up as Covid restrictions ease, some of us are choosing to shut back down every now and then to focus on ourselves and our family
With the country due to open up, are you going to have a regular 'lockdown day' when you close back down, shut the doors to the outside world and focus on yourself or your family?
What will do you on your lockdown days? Will you concentrate on a hobby you picked up during lockdown or will your family do something together? What was positive about lock…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nine dead in school shooting in Kazan, say Russian officials]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/russia-school-shooting-kazan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/russia-school-shooting-kazan"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:16:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President of Tatarstan republic describes incident as ‘great tragedy for the whole country’
Seven students and two staff members were killed on Tuesday in Russia deadliest school shooting in years when a gunman opened fire in the city of Kazan.
Rustam Minnikhanov, the president of the Tatarstan republic where Kazan is the capital, said four male and three female eighth-grade students died in “a great tragedy for the whole country”. Minnikhanov’s press service later said a teacher and another female staff me…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subnautica: Below Zero review — life begins at minus 30]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/may/11/subnautica-below-zero-review-life-begins-at-minus-30</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/may/11/subnautica-below-zero-review-life-begins-at-minus-30"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T16:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, Switch, PC, Mac; Unknown Worlds
Survive under the waves on a frozen planet in this freeform adventure where following the instinct to explore is the real goal

I’m planning a trip. I’m going to load my sea truck with provisions, pick a direction and travel as far as I dare before pitching camp on an iceberg. First up, I need to craft a compass; while I’m doing that, I might as well make a bunch of beacons to mark points of interest for later. I could also do with some se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Bramwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More care home residents died of Covid in second wave than first in England and Wales]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/more-care-home-residents-died-of-covid-in-second-wave-than-first-in-england-and-wales</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/more-care-home-residents-died-of-covid-in-second-wave-than-first-in-england-and-wales"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:59:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ONS data shows 20,664 deaths from March to September 2020, and 21,677 from September to April

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

More people died with Covid in care homes in England and Wales in the second wave of the pandemic than in the first, according to official figures.
Data released by the Office for National Statistics shows that, while the rise in coronavirus deaths among care home residents was much sharper during the first wave between March and September 2020, the nu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Duncan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starmer accuses Johnson of ‘short-term gimmicks’ after Queen’s speech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/queens-speech-unveils-johnsons-populist-and-interventionist-plans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/11/queens-speech-unveils-johnsons-populist-and-interventionist-plans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:57:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monarch unveils prime minister’s plans on free speech, policing and voter ID in pared-back ceremony 

Queen’s speech live - latest news and reaction

Keir Starmer has accused the government of failing to grasp “the urgency and the scale of the transformation that is needed” after the Covid pandemic in his response to the Queen’s speech.
The Labour leader pointed to Joe Biden’s programme for rebuilding the US economy as he claimed Boris Johnson was “papering over the cracks” and too focused on “short-term gi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker and Lisa O'Carroll</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Defiance in the face of Israeli aggression gives Palestinians everywhere hope | Ziad al-Qattan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/israeli-palestinians-violence-jerusalem</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/israeli-palestinians-violence-jerusalem"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:56:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The violence in Jerusalem is part of a plan to repress Palestinian life in the city. Yet there is a heartening refusal to be cowed

As a Palestinian watching the scenes unfold in my homeland on social media, I have been consumed by a range of conflicting emotions. I have felt pain and despair at these violent restrictions on basic Palestinian rights and freedoms; but I have also noticed a spirit of care and solidarity among Palestinians that has been inspiring.
How did we get here? Over the past week, thous…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ziad al-Qattan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What happens when WhatsApp’s new terms start on 15 May?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/what-happens-when-whatsapp-new-terms-start-on-15-may</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/11/what-happens-when-whatsapp-new-terms-start-on-15-may"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:46:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Messaging app will begin to turn off features until users agree to Facebook’s updated terms of service
If you have not agreed to WhatsApp’s controversial new terms of service by 15 May, the app will begin to turn off features until you do, Facebook announced in an update to its FAQ page.
At that point, the screen asking users to accept the terms of service set by Facebook, WhatsApp’s parent company, will become permanent, with users needing to click through to directly use WhatsApp at all. Users will still …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-English National Ballet dancer convicted of sexually abusing young students]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/ex-english-national-ballet-dancer-convicted-of-sexually-abusing-young-students</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/ex-english-national-ballet-dancer-convicted-of-sexually-abusing-young-students"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:45:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yat-Sen Chang is told he faces long jail term after jury finds him guilty of 13 sexual offences against four teenagers
A revered former English National Ballet (ENB) principal dancer faces a lengthy prison sentence after he was convicted of sexually abusing young dance students in his care.
Yat-Sen Chang, 49, a leading figure within the British and international ballet scene, used his “power and prestige” to commit sexual offences against young students at ENB, a trial heard.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: Biden administration holding tens of thousands of migrant children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/us-migrant-children-opaque-network-facilities</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/us-migrant-children-opaque-network-facilities"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:37:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Confidential data obtained by AP shows the number of children in government custody more than doubled in the past two months
The Biden administration is holding tens of thousands of asylum-seeking children in an opaque network of some 200 facilities that the Associated Press has learned spans two dozen states and includes five shelters with more than 1,000 children packed inside.
Confidential data obtained by the AP shows the number of migrant children in government custody more than doubled in the past two…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Garance Burke, Juliet Linderman and Martha Mendoza for the Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[With Rayner’s reshuffle, Starmer has destabilised his base within the party | Sienna Rodgers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/rayner-sacking-starmer-base-labour-deputy-leader</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/rayner-sacking-starmer-base-labour-deputy-leader"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:24:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By moving his admired deputy, he risks awakening party factions and raising questions about his own abilities as leader
Keir Starmer picked a fight with his deputy Angela Rayner last weekend and lost. He sacked her as party chair and national campaign coordinator on Saturday, when the election results were still rolling in – and some of them deserved to be celebrated, unlike the wounding defeats that had emerged until that point. The timing was poor, with many wondering why the leader would not wait for the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sienna Rodgers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Hash Table – Associative Array Hashing in JS]]></title>
        <id>60856789dd38b9088c2bf4ff</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-hash-table-associative-array-hashing-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:24:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hash Tables are a data structure that allow you to create a list of paired values. You can then retrieve a certain value by using the key for that value, which you put into the table beforehand. A Hash Table transforms a key into an integer index using a hash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Start Using Chakra UI]]></title>
        <id>60977de12cd0545b5e944661</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/why-should-you-start-using-chakraui/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:22:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll talk about what ChakraUI is and why you should use it.  Chakra UI is a component-based library. It's made up of basic building blocks that can help you build the front-end of your web application.  It is customizable and reusable, and most importantly it supports ReactJs,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not just racism and sexism. The Golden Globes have been sunk by sheer stupidity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/11/its-not-just-racism-and-sexism-the-golden-globes-have-been-sunk-by-sheer-stupidity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/11/its-not-just-racism-and-sexism-the-golden-globes-have-been-sunk-by-sheer-stupidity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:20:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The preposterous Hollywood Foreign Press Association gravy train might have chugged on for ever if its members had just swallowed their pride and done more for diversity
An investigative report by the Los Angeles Times into the Hollywood Foreign Press Association, that notoriously rackety organisation which administers the Golden Globes, has shown an eminently corruptible body drenched in antediluvian attitudes; this has resulted in NBC cancelling its TV coverage of next year’s ceremony and Tom Cruise handi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trillions of brood X cicadas move closer to emergence as soil temperatures rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/trillions-brood-x-cicadas-soil-temperatures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/trillions-brood-x-cicadas-soil-temperatures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:20:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Great Eastern Brood set to emerge in the last two weeks of May and into early June, with hordes of bugs to push up from underground
Brood X, otherwise known as the great cicada hatching of 2021, is drawing closer as soil temperatures in some parts of America move closer to 64F (18C) – the trigger, according to scientists, for trillions of the insects to push up to the surface and into the trees to mate.
 Related: If we want to save the planet, the future of food is insects 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man appears in court charged with murder of PCSO Julia James]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/callum-wheeler-in-court-charged-murder-pcso-julia-james</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/11/callum-wheeler-in-court-charged-murder-pcso-julia-james"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:17:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Callum Wheeler, 21, remanded in custody to appear at Maidstone crown court on Thursday

A 21-year-old man charged with the murder of PCSO Julia James has been remanded in custody after appearing in court.
Callum Wheeler, from Aylesham in Kent, appeared in person at Medway magistrates court, where he was remanded to appear at Maidstone crown court on Thursday. Flanked by two security officers in the dock, Wheeler spoke only to confirm his name, date of birth and address.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forest the size of France regrown worldwide over 20 years, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/forest-size-of-france-regrown-worldwide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/forest-size-of-france-regrown-worldwide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 59m hectares of forests have regrown since 2000, showing that regeneration in some places is paying off
An area of forest the size of France has regrown around the world over the past 20 years, showing that regeneration in some places is paying off, a new analysis has found.
Nearly 59m hectares of forests have regrown since 2000, the research found, providing the potential to soak up and store 5.9 gigatonnes of carbon dioxide – more than the annual emissions of the entire US.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘No reason’ Joshua v Fury fight in Saudi Arabia won’t be finalised this week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/no-reason-joshua-v-fury-fight-in-saudi-arabia-wont-be-finalised-this-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/11/no-reason-joshua-v-fury-fight-in-saudi-arabia-wont-be-finalised-this-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T15:04:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British pair expected to meet in Jeddah on either 7 or 14 August
‘People are getting frustrated’, admits Eddie Hearn over delays

Eddie Hearn has insisted there is “no reason” why Anthony Joshua’s world heavyweight unification showdown with Tyson Fury will not be finalised this week, with the fight expected to take place in Jeddah in Saudi Arabia on either 7 or 14 August.
Hearn’s pronouncement came after Joshua expressed his frustration at the lack of a deal, saying on social media that he was “tired” of wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative candidate to replace Angela Merkel accused of allowing antisemitism]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/conservative-candidate-to-replace-angela-merkel-accused-of-allowing-antisemitism</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/conservative-candidate-to-replace-angela-merkel-accused-of-allowing-antisemitism"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leading environmentalist criticises Armin Laschet for refusing to sack former spy chief Hans-Georg Maaßen 
The conservative candidate for German chancellor in September’s elections has been told by the country’s leading environmentalist that he is legitimising antisemitism by refusing to oust the former head of domestic intelligence from his party.
The accusation was levelled at Armin Laschet, the leader of the CDU, by Luisa Neubauer, the face of the Fridays for Future movement in Germany, in a standoff on …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Gen CSS: @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339138</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/next-gen-css-container/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is experimenting with @container, a property within the CSS Working Group Containment Level 3 spec being championed by Miriam Suzanne of Oddbird, and a group of engineers across the web platform. @container brings us the ability to &#8230;
The post Next Gen CSS: @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Una Kravets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340106</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/distributed-persistent-rendering-dpr/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:33:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like Jamstack, Netlify is coining this term.
If your reaction is: great, a new thing I need to know about and learn, know that while Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) does involve some new things, this is actually a push &#8230;
The post Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump family members got ‘inappropriately close’ to Secret Service agents, book claims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/trump-family-members-secret-service</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/11/trump-family-members-secret-service"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Concerns over bonds involving Trump’s then daughter in-law Vanessa and daughter Tiffany revealed in Carol Leonnig’s Zero Fail
Two Trump family members got “inappropriately – and perhaps dangerously – close” to agents protecting them while Donald Trump was president, according to a new book on the US Secret Service.
 Related: Secret Service extension for Trump’s adult children cost $140,000 in a month 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s terrifying’: the English village overwhelmed by landfill stink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/english-village-silverdale-walleys-quarry-landfill-stink</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/english-village-silverdale-walleys-quarry-landfill-stink"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:09:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For miles around Walleys Quarry in Silverdale, people have reported waking up in the night struggling to breathe
It may have been labelled the country’s smelliest village but it is much more than a bad stench from the local landfill making life miserable for the residents of Silverdale in Staffordshire, who have now started crowdfunding for potential legal action against the site.
For miles around Walleys Quarry landfill near Newcastle-under-Lyme, people have reported waking up in the middle of the night st…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson the civil libertarian wants to have his voter ID card and eat it | Marina Hyde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/johnson-civil-libertarian-voter-id-card-fraud-tories</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/johnson-civil-libertarian-voter-id-card-fraud-tories"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:52:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The solution to the virtually nonexistent problem of voter fraud just happens to be one that favours the Tories
“If I am ever asked,” Boris Johnson once wrote of ID cards, “on the streets of London, or in any other venue, public or private, to produce my ID card as evidence that I am who I say I am, when I have done nothing wrong and am simply ambling along and breathing God’s fresh air like any other freeborn Englishman, then I will take that card out of my wallet and physically eat it in the presence of w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Hyde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FCA investigates Greensill as David Cameron’s lobbying texts are made public]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/fca-greensill-david-cameron-lobbying-texts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/fca-greensill-david-cameron-lobbying-texts"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:42:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Regulator announces move as 56 of ex-PM’s messages to Rishi Sunak, Michael Gove and others released

Greensill: the scale of David Cameron’s lobbying texts revealed

David Cameron lobbied ministers and senior officials 56 times at the height of the pandemic in an increasingly desperate attempt to beg the government to support a controversial bank he worked for and owned a stake in.
The scale of the former prime minister’s chummy lobbying – by text, WhatsApp, email and phone calls – on behalf of Greensill Ca…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angellica Bell: ‘My puppet sidekick became real to me’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/11/angellica-bell-my-puppet-sidekick-became-real-to-me-cbbc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/11/angellica-bell-my-puppet-sidekick-became-real-to-me-cbbc"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The TV presenter and host of Leonardo: The Official Podcast on her love of Bullseye and Dallas – and what happened when Victoria Beckham came to CBBC
Growing up, I would always try to finish my dinner in time to get my weekly dose of Dallas with my grandma. I would dread being given liver because I couldn’t eat it, and I’d be crushed if I had to miss the drama and the cliffhangers. I just loved that JR was so bad, and the way my grandma would talk about it as if it were real life. She would be talking to th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Hannah J Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in England: what are your plans on 17 May?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from those in England about how they feel and what they plan to do when restrictions are further eased
Hugging and mixing indoors with friends and family will be allowed in England from next week. We’d like to know what your plans are for 17 May and how you feel about the further easing of restrictions.
We’d like to hear about who you will meet first under the new rules, and what you will do. We are also interested in hearing how people feel about society reopening and being able to mix wi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dress to impress: how to make the perfect salad dressing | Kitchen aide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/how-to-make-the-perfect-salad-dressing-kitchen-aide</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/how-to-make-the-perfect-salad-dressing-kitchen-aide"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As in so much cooking, vinaigrette is all about balance. We ask some of our favourite chefs for their salad dressing secrets
• Got a culinary dilemma? Email feast@theguardian.com
What’s the secret to a great salad dressing? Mine’s always bitter.
Hilary, Alnwick, Northumberland
Vinaigrette consists of oil, salt and acid (vinegar or citrus juice, usually). There’s a bit more to it, of course – but not much. As in life, it all comes down to balance, which for chef Raymond Blanc means a 3:1 ratio of extra-virgi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Berrill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Design Good Typography - Free Treehouse Course]]></title>
        <id>60998ee76008950828b3ed10</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-design-good-typography/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T12:56:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typography is one of the most important aspects of good design. It is especially important for web designers. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you all you need to know about creating good typography as a UX Designer. Hope Armstrong developed this]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandatory voter ID would dangerously undermine UK democracy | Jess Garland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/mandatory-voter-id-uk-democracy-electoral-system-voters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/mandatory-voter-id-uk-democracy-electoral-system-voters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T12:46:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The best electoral systems are the most inclusive. This government plan will lock out many legitimate voters
Last week millions of voters across Britain went to the ballot box in a bumper set of elections. But government plans to restrict access to the ballot box could mean that Thursday’s elections will have been among the last of their kind to be fair and free in the UK.
Proposals to introduce mandatory voter ID, as unveiled in today’s Queen’s speech, are a dangerous attack on our democratic rights that c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Garland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Covid lab staff hired via pay scheme with tax scam hallmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/nhs-covid-lab-staff-hired-via-pay-scheme-with-tax-scam-hallmarks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/11/nhs-covid-lab-staff-hired-via-pay-scheme-with-tax-scam-hallmarks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T12:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: Hundreds of workers recruited for Milton Keynes lab were employed by multiple mini companies
A recruitment firm that hires workers to conduct NHS Covid-19 tests – and is co-owned by a well-known football executive – has been supplying staff employed through a contrived network of companies that possesses many of the hallmarks of a notorious tax scam.
Industrious Recruitment has supplied laboratory staff to the Lighthouse laboratories in Milton Keynes, which was launched by the health secretary, Ma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Goodley and Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whiskers, claws and applause: Andrew Lloyd Webber’s Cats – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/11/whiskers-claws-and-applause-andrew-lloyd-webbers-cats-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/11/whiskers-claws-and-applause-andrew-lloyd-webbers-cats-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:59:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since its debut in May 1981, the poetically inspired Cats has become one of the most popular stage shows in the world. Forty years on, here’s a look back at how the long-running musical began
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what do you think of government proposals to introduce adult student loans?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/11/tell-us-what-do-you-think-of-government-proposals-to-introduce-adult-student-loans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/11/tell-us-what-do-you-think-of-government-proposals-to-introduce-adult-student-loans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:47:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear what readers think of proposals to let mature students take out flexible education loans, and whether people have taken out loans to study in later life

The government is planning to set up student loans that will be open to adults of all ages, and can be used at any time in life, it was announced in the Queen’s Speech.
A ‘Lifelong Loan Entitlement’ would replace the student finance system, allowing adults to apply for up to four years of flexible student loans for full- or part-time cour…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel Slater’s grilled lamb cutlets, peas and rocket recipe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/nigel-slater-grilled-lamb-cutlets-peas-and-rocket-recipe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/nigel-slater-grilled-lamb-cutlets-peas-and-rocket-recipe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blend peas and rocket for a tasty sauce to go with lamb
Bring a medium-sized saucepan of water to the boil. Add 150g of peas and leave them for 3 or 4 minutes until tender.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nigel Slater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do people’s names affect their personality?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/11/do-peoples-names-affect-their-personality</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/11/do-peoples-names-affect-their-personality"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
Do people’s names affect their personality? Max Crane, Sydney
Post your answers (and new questions) below or send them to nq@theguardian.com. A selection will be published on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves&nbsp;
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other vi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Crumpets have been my saviour!’: readers on their 14 best comfort meals of lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/crumpets-have-been-my-saviour-readers-on-their-14-best-comfort-meals-of-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/11/crumpets-have-been-my-saviour-readers-on-their-14-best-comfort-meals-of-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:30:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Food has felt more important than ever this past year – particularly meals that offer solace. From rösti to Coco Pops, here are the dishes that got us through

For me, lockdown has meant an absolutely manic schedule, working from home with back-to-back Zoom calls and long hours. Crumpets have been my saviour. Yes, factory made, perfectly consistent and versatile: top with yoghurt and frozen berries at 8am, blue cheese and leeks at 1pm, followed by eggs and spinach at 7pm, and you have a full day’s menu. For…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours &mdash; but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[London’s pain could become the north’s gain, but Johnson isn’t up to the job | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/london-north-johnson-political-gimmicks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/11/london-north-johnson-political-gimmicks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T09:22:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stemming the ‘brain drain’ to London is a vast undertaking that will take a lot more than political gimmicks
Modern British government is a lurch from catchphrase to cliche. Policy is rarely in sight. Following the Tories’ remarkable success in the local elections, Boris Johnson will today announce a new campaign to “stop the brain drain” from northern cities. Bitten by Covid’s big spending bug, he will tip cash into infrastructure to get people to “live local and prosper”.
Two consequences follow, both sig…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘More than a job’: the meal delivery co-ops making the gig economy fairer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/more-than-a-job-the-meal-delivery-co-ops-making-the-gig-economy-fairer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/more-than-a-job-the-meal-delivery-co-ops-making-the-gig-economy-fairer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T09:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Across Europe, worker-led delivery collectives are springing up to reclaim control from corporate platforms

Cristina González did a lot of waiting in 2018. Back then, the 29-year-old was a courier for the Spanish food delivery platform Glovo in her Basque home town, Vitoria-Gasteiz. She talks about feeling as if she was on standby the whole time: “You’re effectively having to be working constantly.”
While Glovo serves restaurants, customers can also order from supermarkets. This, Gonzalez says, was “a comp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sophie Atkinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BPPA press photographer of the year 2020 – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/gallery/2021/may/11/bppa-press-photographer-of-the-year-2020-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/gallery/2021/may/11/bppa-press-photographer-of-the-year-2020-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T08:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We take a look at some of the images from the winning portfolios at the inaugural BPPA press photographer of the year awards. The brand new competition was created by press photographers for press photographers, to showcase the outstanding and unprecedented photography taken for, and used by, the UK media. The overall winner was Adam Gray of SWNS who took first place in two categories, photo essay and the Covid-19 essay
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Why go to the Sahara when you can visit Kent?’: ‘desert’ life in Dungeness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/11/why-go-to-the-sahara-when-you-can-visit-kent-desert-life-in-dungeness</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/11/why-go-to-the-sahara-when-you-can-visit-kent-desert-life-in-dungeness"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T07:24:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking for transformative journeys near home, travel writer Nick Hunt found inspiration in a corner of south-east England
The place that is sometimes called “England’s only desert” can be reached by a miniature railway line that runs to a nuclear power station on one of the largest expanses of shingle beach in Europe.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Hunt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the deadly ‘black fungus’ seen in Covid patients in India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/11/what-is-the-dangerous-black-fungus-being-seen-in-covid-patients-in-india-mucormycosis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/may/11/what-is-the-dangerous-black-fungus-being-seen-in-covid-patients-in-india-mucormycosis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T06:18:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usually very rare, mucormycosis has a high mortality rate and is difficult to treat 
A rare “black fungus” that invades the brain is being increasingly seen in vulnerable patients in India, including those with Covid-19, as the health system continues to struggle in the midst of the pandemic.
The health ministry on Sunday released an advisory on how to treat the infection. In the state of Gujarat, about 300 cases had been reported in four cities, including Ahmedabad, according to data from state-run hospita…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Davey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The rudest things they ever said about the Guardian]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/guardian-200-the-rudest-things-they-ever-said-blair-aitken</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/11/guardian-200-the-rudest-things-they-ever-said-blair-aitken"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T06:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This newspaper has upset public figures from Blair to Trump. Here we look at some of the resultant indignation

The Guardian has never tried to ingratiate itself with the rich and powerful. But its reporting has, over the years, provoked indignation, pique and even rudeness from prime ministers, presidents and corporate titans as well as the odd pop singer and Hollywood movie star.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global renewable energy industry grew at fastest rate since 1999 last year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/global-renewable-energy-industry-grew-at-fastest-rate-since-1999-last-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/11/global-renewable-energy-industry-grew-at-fastest-rate-since-1999-last-year"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T06:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New wind and solar power projects in China, Europe and the US spurred 45% rise in capacity
The world’s renewable energy industry grew at its fastest pace since 1999 last year, despite the disruption caused by the Covid-19 pandemic, and may have established a standard for growth in the future, according to the International Energy Agency (IEA).
The global energy watchdog revealed that the delivery of renewable energy projects, including windfarms and solar power projects, grew by 45% last year in a step chan…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose Energy correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hidden scars: mentally ill patients lost in Yemen’s war]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/11/hidden-scars-mentally-ill-patients-lost-in-yemens-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/11/hidden-scars-mentally-ill-patients-lost-in-yemens-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T06:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With one psychiatrist for 750,000 people and huge stigma about mental health, patients get little help
Radhwan Ali Hassan lives with his mother in a small house perched at the top of a sleepy Yemeni village called Aqeeqah, on the outskirts of Taiz city. From inside his bare-walled room, the 35-year-old hears the distant sound of an ice-cream van. He sees children running past his window and can smell goats, but he cannot remember the last time he walked outside.
Thick metal shackles around his ankles are at…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isobel Yeung in Taiz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why China and east Asia’s ageing population threatens global Covid recovery]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/analysis-chinas-ageing-population-predicament-global-implications-east-asia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/11/analysis-chinas-ageing-population-predicament-global-implications-east-asia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T05:53:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Beijing’s census data confirms trend reflected across a region that is looked to as engine of post-pandemic growth

Full report: China’s population growing at slowest rate in generations

For many years China watchers have been concerned that its ageing population will slow economic growth, causing social as well as political problems. So today’s census data may be an alarm bell for leaders in Beijing.
But it is not just China that is witnessing this trajectory. Most countries in east Asia, even w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ni China affairs correspondent, and Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sole of a nation: how Clarks became Jamaica’s favourite footwear]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/11/sole-of-a-nation-how-clarks-became-jamaicas-favourite-footwear</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/may/11/sole-of-a-nation-how-clarks-became-jamaicas-favourite-footwear"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T05:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has long been a unique connection between the Somerset-based shoe-maker and the Caribbean island. It goes way beyond shoes - as a new edition of book Clarks in Jamaica demonstrates
The reggae producer Bunny Lee said: “Clarks stand the test of time inna Jamaica. All the other shoes come and bow down at Clarks’ foot.” DJ Trinity said in the 70s that you couldn’t get a girlfriend if you didn’t wear Clarks. And the dancehall star Vybz Kartel dedicated no fewer than three hit songs to the shoes. Clarks mig…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Cochrane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The bells v the boutique hotel: the battle to save Britain’s oldest factory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/may/11/whitechapel-bell-foundry-battle-save-britains-oldest-factory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/may/11/whitechapel-bell-foundry-battle-save-britains-oldest-factory"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T05:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whitechapel Bell Foundry dates back to 1570, and was the factory in which Big Ben and the Liberty Bell were made. But it shut in 2017 and a fight for its future has been raging ever since
On a November evening in 2019, Nigel Taylor, who had until recently been the longest-standing employee at the oldest factory in England, took a seat inside a council chamber in the shadow of Canary Wharf in London. The room looked more like the setting of a US daytime TV court drama than a provincial government building in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hettie O'Brien</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Post Office scandal – part 2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/11/the-post-office-scandal-part-2</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/11/the-post-office-scandal-part-2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T02:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Janet Skinner was jailed for false accounting after being wrongfully accused by her employer, the Post Office, of responsibility for the loss of more than £59,000. Now, with her conviction quashed, she and others are demanding answers
The Post Office brought prosecutions against dozens of its employees after accusing them of theft and false accounting based on evidence from its IT system called Horizon. 
Janet Skinner was one of those who went to jail for false accounting and last month she was one of 39 fo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Janet Skinner and Richard Brooks; produced by Sami Kent, Ned Carter Miles and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Your First Developer Job through Intelligent, Genuine Networking]]></title>
        <id>605cf4879618b008528a77e2</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/networking-for-aspiring-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T01:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's not about what you know, it's about whom you know." "70-80% of jobs are found via someone's network." Most of us have heard cliches and stats like the above. And I think most of us intuitively know that having a network of people that can help us find opportunities]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘My head is on fire’: Roger Ballen finds poetry in pain – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/my-head-is-on-fire-roger-ballen-finds-poetry-in-pain-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/11/my-head-is-on-fire-roger-ballen-finds-poetry-in-pain-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paint, collage and photography combine in Ballen’s tumultuous The Earth Will Come to Laugh and Feast. Italian poet Gabriele Tinti reflects on his work ... 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topframe]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/topframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is extremely fun. Jeff Lindsay has created Topframe, and writes:
Anybody that knows how to mess around with HTML can now mess around with their desktop computing experience.&#160;Topframe&#160;is an open source tool that lets you 
&#8230;
The post Topframe appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340208</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/migrating-from-parcel-to-snowpack-build-tool-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I find build tooling endlessly interesting, especially right now as we&#8217;re in a juicy next-gen transitional period with players like Vite, wmr, Snowpack, and esbuild. Hugh Haworth has a good run-down of the new players, and we&#8217;ve chatted on &#8230;
The post Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Ace Your Coding Interview – Advice from a Senior Software Engineer]]></title>
        <id>60953e202cd0545b5e943a8b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-acing-your-coding-interview-advice-from-senior-software-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T17:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Technical interviews are one of the most stressful parts of landing a job in tech.  You don't know what questions the interviewer is going to ask. What if you have no idea how to solve the problem in front of you? What if you freeze up and look like you]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339203</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/variable-aspect-ratio-card-with-conic-gradients-meeting-along-the-diagonal/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently came across an interesting problem. I had to implement a grid of cards with a variable (user-set) aspect ratio that was stored in a --ratio custom property. Boxes with a certain aspect ratio are a classic problem in &#8230;
The post Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Tudor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Semuliki: on the trail of the ADF’s Islamist militants | photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/welcome-to-semuliki-on-the-trail-of-the-adfs-islamist-militants-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/may/10/welcome-to-semuliki-on-the-trail-of-the-adfs-islamist-militants-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T06:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photojournalist Hugh Kinsella Cunningham has been embedded with Congolese soldiers in the DRC’s ‘triangle of death’. The elusive insurgents they are hunting have pledged allegiance to Islamic State
At the border between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Uganda, in a vast territory that ranges from the lofty Rwenzori mountains to the lush rainforest of the Semliki valley, one of the world’s most active militant groups is responsible for the massacre of hundreds of civilians.
The ADF (Allied Democratic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Kinsella Cunningham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Post Office scandal – part 1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/10/exposing-the-great-post-office-scandal-part-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/10/exposing-the-great-post-office-scandal-part-1"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T02:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a computer system installed by the Post Office went haywire, it led to the convictions of scores of subpostmasters for theft and false accounting. Lives were wrecked. But after a devastating ruling by the court of appeal, the full truth can now be finally told about the extent of the great Post Office scandal
When the Post Office installed a new accounting system called Horizon across its branches in 1999, it hoped to bring a lumbering and much-loved institution into the 21st century. What happened nex…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Janet Skinner and Richard Brooks; produced by Sami Kent and Ned Carter Miles; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning Systems Book Recommendations – Learn How to Build and Understand ML Systems]]></title>
        <id>609558382cd0545b5e943c6f</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-systems-book-recommendations/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T21:07:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Good friends, good books, and a sleepy conscience: this is the ideal life.” ― Mark TwainI hope you’re reading this blog in your pjs looking forward to a rejuvenating and healthy weekend.  I have been working on multiple projects lately, from creating Machine Learing Engineering and Machine Learning Operations courses]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is CSS a Programming Language?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339781</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/is-css-a-programming-language/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:56:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a real distaste for this question. It might seem like a fun question to dig into on the surface, but the way it enters public discourse rarely seems to be in good faith. There are ulterior motives at &#8230;
The post Is CSS a Programming Language? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Typography]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339574</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-typography/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T13:54:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[These are a few great links about typography that have been burning a hole in my saved bookmarks folder that I'm just now getting around to sharing. There's good stuff in there, from how to choose typefaces for app design to ideas for how to fix the concept of font sizing in CSS.
The post Links on Typography appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day three: women, from suffragists to sexploitation

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I Email…]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339822</id>
        <link href="https://www.caniemail.com/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:38:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While I&#8217;m 85% certain you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Use&#8230;, I bet there is only a 13% chance that you&#8217;ve seen and used Can I Email&#8230;. It&#8217;s the same vibe—detailed support information for web platform features—except instead &#8230;
The post Can I Email&#8230; appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noel Clarke and the allegations that have shaken the film and television industry – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/07/noel-clarke-and-the-allegations-that-have-shaken-the-film-and-television-industry-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T02:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalists Lucy Osborne and Sirin Kale discuss the allegations of verbal abuse, bullying and sexual harassment by 20 women against Clarke
On 10 April 2021, the actor, director and writer Noel Clarke was awarded one of the most prestigious accolades bestowed by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts, the prize for outstanding British contribution to cinema. But 13 days before presenting Clarke with his award, Bafta was informed about the existence of several allegations of verbal abuse, bullying an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Sirin Kale and Lucy Osborne, produced by Alex Atack and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340015</id>
        <link href="https://betterprogramming.pub/apparently-you-can-use-route53-as-a-blazingly-fast-database-dd416b56b005"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T20:03:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Route53 is DNS management service by AWS. DNS is absolutely not a database, and yet here&#8217;s Nicholas Martin writing up some very clever trickery originally done by Corey Quinn:
When you think about it, DNS configuration is actually a 
&#8230;
The post Apparently, You Can Use Route53 as a Blazingly Fast Database appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339936</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-googles-new-page-experience-update-means-for-images-on-your-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T19:57:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to forget that, as a search engine, Google doesn’t just compare keywords to generate search results. Google knows that if people don’t enjoy their experience on a web page, they won’t stay on the page long enough to &#8230;
The post What Google’s New Page Experience Update Means for Images on Your Website appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339586</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/custom-state-pseudo-classes-in-chrome/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T14:28:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is an increasing number of “custom” features on the web platform. We have custom properties (--my-property), custom elements (&#60;my-element&#62;), and custom events (new CustomEvent('myEvent')). At one point, we might even get custom media &#8230;
The post Custom State Pseudo-Classes in Chrome appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Šime Vidas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Astro]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339563</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/astro/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T21:49:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t even look at code or documentation for Astro (publicly) yet — it&#8217;s an in-progress idea — but you can watch a video of Fred showing it off to Feross. 
I gotta admit: it looks awesome. I&#8217;m bullish &#8230;
The post Astro appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339954</id>
        <link href="https://infrequently.org/2021/04/progress-delayed/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T16:51:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The bombshell article of the week is from Alex Russell of Google/Chrome. Alex has long been super critical of Apple, particularly about how there is literally no option to run any other browser than Safari on iOS. This article isn&#8217;t &#8230;
The post Progress Delayed Is Progress Denied appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: did you separate from your long-term partner?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/05/tell-us-did-you-separate-from-your-long-term-partner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/05/tell-us-did-you-separate-from-your-long-term-partner"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T14:34:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to speak to people who separated from their partner after a long-term relationship about how they came to terms with it
This week, Bill and Melinda Gates announced they were divorcing after 27 years of marriage. One of the world’s wealthiest couples, the Microsoft founder and his wife have established a charitable foundation and raised three children.
We’d like to speak to other couples who have separated after long term relationships.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums&nbsp;


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heroin to Holyrood? Man behind 'illegal' drug van runs for Scottish parliament – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/video/2021/apr/29/heroin-to-holyrood-man-behind-drug-van-runs-for-scottish-parliament-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:31:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Krykant, who operates a van in Glasgow where people can safely take illegal drugs, is running for Holyrood as part of a campaign calling for the Scottish government to establish legal sites.&nbsp;
A former&nbsp;heroin&nbsp;addict, he is pushing for drug reform in Scotland, which has a reported drug deaths rate 15 times higher than the European average. "People are dying out there,' says Krykant, who is able to treat addicts who overdose in his van. Could interventions such as his change Scotland's sta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Cherry, Maeve Shearlaw and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian at 200: Announcing a digital festival from Guardian Live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/apr/28/the-guardian-at-200-announcing-a-digital-festival</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/membership/2021/apr/28/the-guardian-at-200-announcing-a-digital-festival"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us as we celebrate 200 years of The Guardian, with our very first digital festival.
To mark the 200th anniversary of The Guardian, we are launching our very first digital festival - a mix of conversations about politics, activism, the environment, TV, music and more - brought to you, wherever you are in the world.
On Tuesday 11 May, we will be returning to The Guardian’s Manchester roots, to shine a spotlight on different aspects of the city’s vibrant life: its radical history, its progressive politics…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early &mdash; when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the UK government sidestepped the data on coronavirus – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/apr/16/uk-government-coronavirus-response-data-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T11:37:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This time last year, NHS bosses asked doctors and nurses to ‘wear aprons’ and&nbsp;work without protective full-length gowns&nbsp;when treating Covid-19 patients, as hospitals were within hours of running out of supplies.
This is just one example of how the UK government has been slammed for its handling of the pandemic, through a series of missteps, U-turns, lockdowns, denials – and more than 150,000 deaths.
Twelve months on, the Guardian's Pamela Duncan looks at three major areas where officials were out …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Duncan, Monika Cvorak and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seven Mistakes To Avoid In Your Technical Interviews]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/mistakes-technical-interviews/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s no secret that the technical interview process leaves something to be desired; it’s often riddled with anxiety and stress. In this article, we’ll take a look at seven of the most common mistakes candidates make in their technical interviews and explore ways you can avoid them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Emma Bostian)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Get Web Design Clients Fast (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-clients-fast-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Selling is key to growing your web design business, but it doesn’t have to be complicated! With clear goals, customer research, and proven closing techniques, anyone can find new clients.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephen Roe)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Cats With Love: New Navigation, Guides And Workshops]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/from-cats-with-love-navigation-guides-workshops/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-15T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Smashing, we’ve been busy over the last few months. We’ve set up new workshops, redesigned our navigation, refined performance and improved accessibility. There are subtle UX changes coming in, and we’d love to share what we’ve been cooking.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overflow Issues In CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/css-overflow-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-14T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we will explore the causes of overflow issues and how to solve them. We will also explore how modern features in the developer tools (DevTools) can make the process of fixing and debugging easier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Ahmad Shadeed)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Video Streaming App With Nuxt.js, Node And Express]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/building-video-streaming-app-nuxtjs-node-express/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-13T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be building a video streaming app using Nuxt.js and Node.js. Specifically, we’ll build a server-side Node.js app that will handle fetching and streaming videos, generating thumbnails for your videos, and serving captions and subtitles.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Deven Rathore)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To HTML Email]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-html-email-templates-tools/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-12T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently we’ve covered CSS generators, SVG generators and accessible front-end components. This time we look into HTML email, with tools, templates and guides for designers and developers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>