<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-02T01:52:24.712Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-02T01:52:24.712Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WHO approves China’s Sinovac Covid vaccine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/who-approves-chinas-sinovac-covid-vaccine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/who-approves-chinas-sinovac-covid-vaccine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T00:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emergency use listing gives countries, funders, procuring agencies and communities assurance it has met international standards

See all our coronavirus coverage

The World Health Organization has approved the Sinovac Covid-19 vaccine for emergency use – the second Chinese vaccine to receive the WHO’s green light.
The UN health agency signed off on CoronaVac, a two-dose vaccine developed by the Beijing-based firm which is already being deployed in several countries around the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden declares white supremacists ‘most lethal threat’ to US as he marks Tulsa race massacre - as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/01/joe-biden-tulsa-oklahoma-race-massacre-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/01/joe-biden-tulsa-oklahoma-race-massacre-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T00:01:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden noted he is the first US president to commemorate the event
Hundreds killed by white mob in Oklahoma 100 years ago
Administration announces new efforts to narrow racial wealth gap 

 1.01am BST 
– Joan E Greve and Maanvi SIngh
 12.35am BST 
The Biden administration formally ended the Trump-era “remain in Mexico” policy that forced thousands of asylum seekers from Central America to wait in Mexico while the US to process their cases. 
The administration had paused the program in January. In a memo sent to agency leaders today, Department of Homeland Security (DHS) secretary Alejandro Mayorkas said the policy did not “adequately or sustainably enhance border management.” 
A dusty soccer ball lay idle and forgotten a few days ago at an empty dwelling that had been knitted together from billowing, fraying plastic tarps tied to dead trees in the Mexican city of Matamoros.
The vignette of the abandoned shelter is expected to replicate across the makeshift migrant camp in the coming weeks, wedged between the edge of the city and the swirling Rio Grande, across the border from south-east Texas.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh (now) and Joan E Greve (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Discord AI Chatbot that Talks Like Your Favorite Character]]></title>
        <id>60b5025111ffb70827ef9ebe</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/discord-ai-chatbot/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:47:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's build an AI model that speaks just like your favorite character and deploy that model as a Discord chatbot. All the coding and deployment happen in the cloud (for free!), so you don't even need a local IDE to follow along.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘No political story allowed’: Hong Kong broadcaster falls silent on sensitive subjects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/no-political-story-allowed-hong-kong-broadcaster-falls-silent-on-sensitive-subjects</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/02/no-political-story-allowed-hong-kong-broadcaster-falls-silent-on-sensitive-subjects"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:14:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Employees at public broadcaster RTHK voice fears for future amid gradual erosion of media freedoms 
Normally at this time of year Hong Kong media are bustling to prepare coverage of Friday’s anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre which, before Covid restrictions hit, usually included a huge vigil in Victoria Park. The event is illegal in China but had been proudly held in Hong Kong for decades.
But this year journalists at the respected public broadcaster RTHK say they’ve been told to stand down.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Key species at risk if planet heats up by more than 1.5C, report finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/key-species-at-risk-if-planet-heats-up-by-more-than-15c-report-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/02/key-species-at-risk-if-planet-heats-up-by-more-than-15c-report-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WWF report finds puffins, penguins and many other species will face issues such as habitat loss and food insecurity
Corals will bleach, penguins will lose their Antarctic ice floes, puffins around the UK coast will be unable to feed their young, and the black-headed squirrel monkey of the Amazon could be wiped out if the world fails to limit global heating to 1.5C above pre-industrial levels.
Beyond a 1.5C rise, many species will face increasing problems finding food or surviving, according to a report from WWF on the effects of climate breakdown on 12 key species across the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ambulance crews in England to get body cameras after 30% rise in assaults]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/ambulance-crews-in-england-to-get-body-cameras-after-30-rise-in-assaults</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/02/ambulance-crews-in-england-to-get-body-cameras-after-30-rise-in-assaults"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data shows 3,569 ambulance staff physically attacked by the public last year 
Thousands of ambulance crews in England will be given body cameras after a sharp rise in attacks on NHS staff treating patients, the government has announced. Data shows that 3,569 ambulance staff were physically assaulted by members of the public last year – 30% more than in 2016-17.
The plans come after successful trials in London and the north-east. The cameras will be given to crews in 10 ambulance trusts across the country. Medics will wear the cameras and be able to press a button to start recording if patients or the public become aggressive or abusive, and the film will be given to the police where needed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 5: Belgium]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/euro-2020-team-guides-part-5-belgium</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/02/euro-2020-team-guides-part-5-belgium"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s top-ranked team are packed with attacking flair but Roberto Martínez must protect an ageing defence
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
Ten wins out of 10. Forty goals scored, three conceded. Qualification for the Euros was a pretty easy ride for Belgium, in a group with Russia and Scotland as the main opponents. Tactics haven’t changed much over the past few years. It’s easy to predict Belgium’s lineup when everybody is fit. In the 26-man squad, there are barely any newcomers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristof Terreur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pupils to be offered 100m hours of tuition in Covid catch-up plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/02/pupils-to-be-offered-100m-hours-of-tuition-in-covid-catch-up-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/02/pupils-to-be-offered-100m-hours-of-tuition-in-covid-catch-up-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government’s £1.4bn programme of tutoring courses won’t be enough, warns its education recovery tsar

Pupils will be offered an extra 100m hours of tuition under post-pandemic catch-up plans unveiled today – but the government faced immediate criticism of the £1.4bn programme, with its own tsar warning “more will be needed”.
After months of unprecedented school closures, £1.4bn will be spent on up to 6m sets of 15-hour tutoring courses for disadvantaged pupils as well as an expansion of an existing fund for helping 16- to 19-year-olds with subjects such as English and maths, the Department for Education (DfE) said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker and Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gatsby, Ripley and the fake heiress: inside the tech fantasy Anna X]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/joseph-charlton-anna-x-emma-corrin-social-media</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/joseph-charlton-anna-x-emma-corrin-social-media"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalist turned playwright Joseph Charlton on how the Anna Sorokin case inspired his play about identity and power, starring Emma Corrin
One night, while out with friends in London and looking for a place open late, Joseph Charlton decided to talk his way into Soho House. It wouldn’t be that difficult, he reasoned. He’d been working as a journalist and recently had a meeting at the private members’ club, so it was just a matter of using someone else’s name to gain entry. He and his friends paid their own tab, but there was a Ripley-ish thrill to accessing a place off limits to all but a few.
Charlton references Patricia Highsmith’s con artist Tom Ripley several times when discussing his play Anna X, which is part of the Re:Emerge season, created by producer Sonia Friedman, to bring new voices to the West End.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natasha Tripney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Journalists asked to share stories of abuse in government safety drive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/journalists-asked-to-share-stories-of-abuse-in-government-safety-drive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/02/journalists-asked-to-share-stories-of-abuse-in-government-safety-drive"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T23:01:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home Office say evidence will help to understand scale of threats and the criminal justice system’s response
Journalists are being encouraged to share their experiences of being threatened, abused and intimidated as part of a government drive to protect their safety.
The Home Office said the call for evidence would help to better understand the scale of the problem, the criminal justice system’s response to it and the impact that such incidents have on the industry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kate Winslet says she refused offer to edit sex scene showing ‘bulgy belly’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/kate-winslet-says-she-refused-offer-to-edit-sex-scene-showing-bulgy-belly</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/kate-winslet-says-she-refused-offer-to-edit-sex-scene-showing-bulgy-belly"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Craig Zobel, director of Mare of Easttown, offered to show actor in a more flattering light but Winslet said: ‘Don’t you dare’
Kate Winslet has said she refused a director’s offer to edit a sex scene in which she showed a “bulgy bit of belly” for her latest television series.
The actor claimed Craig Zobel, the director of her new HBO series Mare of Easttown, had offered to show her body in a more flattering light.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden suspends Trump-era oil drilling leases in Alaska’s Arctic refuge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/biden-suspends-oil-drilling-leases-alaska-arctic-refuge-trump-era</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/biden-suspends-oil-drilling-leases-alaska-arctic-refuge-trump-era"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:12:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Interior department order follows a temporary moratorium on oil and gas lease activities imposed by president on first day in office
The Biden administration on Tuesday suspended oil and gas leases in Alaska’s Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, reversing a drilling program approved by Donald Trump and reviving a political fight over a remote region that is home to polar bears and other wildlife – and a rich reserve of oil.
The interior department order follows a temporary moratorium on oil and gas lease activities imposed by Joe Biden on his first day in office. Biden’s 20 January executive order suggested a new environmental review was needed to address possible legal flaws in a drilling program approved by the Trump administration under a 2017 law enacted by Congress.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated  Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One firefighter killed in shooting at Los Angeles fire station – reports]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/la-shooting-fire-station-latest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/la-shooting-fire-station-latest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T21:28:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sheriff’s deputies responded to reports of gunshot victims just before 11am in the Agua Dulce area near Santa Clarita
An off-duty firefighter fatally shot a fellow firefighter and wounded another at their small community fire station in Los Angeles county on Tuesday, before going to his nearby home, setting it on fire and apparently killing himself, authorities have said.
The gunman opened fire shortly before 11am, killing a 44-year-old fire specialist and wounding a 54-year-old firefighter at a station about 45 miles (72 kilometers) north of Los Angeles, according to fire chief Daryl Osby. The wounded man was in critical but stable condition at a hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City chairman vows to replace Agüero amid Kane links]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/manchester-city-chairman-vows-to-replace-aguero-amid-kane-links</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/manchester-city-chairman-vows-to-replace-aguero-amid-kane-links"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T21:08:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Club are interested in signing the Tottenham captain
City lost Champions League final against Chelsea 

Manchester City chairman Khaldoon Al Mubarak says his club intend to send a message in this summer’s transfer window and has vowed to find the right replacement for Sergio Agüero this summer.
City look set to spend big on reshaping Pep Guardiola’s squad and have a large hole to fill following record goalscorer Agüero’s move to Barcelona. Tottenham striker Harry Kane has been heavily linked with a move to the Etihad Stadium, and even named Kevin De Bruyne as his ideal team-mate, while Borussia Dortmund’s Erling Haaland has also been touted as a possible target.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anne Boleyn review – spoiler alert: she won’t make it out alive!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/anne-boleyn-review-spoiler-alert-she-wont-make-it-out-alive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/anne-boleyn-review-spoiler-alert-she-wont-make-it-out-alive"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T21:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jodie Turner-Smith flashes fire and fury in Channel 5’s oh-so-serious Tudor drama, complete with a silly surplus of metaphors – and a weirdly wimpy Henry VIII. Wolf Hall it is not

If it’s pigs heads on platters, it must be Tudors. And so it is. 1536, to be precise. Opening captions for the new Channel 5 drama Anne Boleyn, stripped across three nights, inform us that Anne has been queen for two and half years, has provided Henry VIII with one daughter, had two miscarriages and is now pregnant again. She is the most powerful woman in England, and she has just five months to live. Dum-dum-DAH!
I added the dum-dum-DAH! Anne Boleyn (the drama) takes itself too seriously for that. This is not The Tudors, this is Proper History and it delivers on all the basics. The caprice of Henry (Mark Stanley). The claustrophobia of court. The power of a misplaced word or a deliberate strike. The power struggles between Cromwell (Barry Ward) and Anne (Jodie Turner-Smith). The quiet progress of the “little mouse” Jane Seymour (Lola Petticrew). The importance of an heir. The horse-trading between countries to secure alliances, and the seven-dimensional chess being played behind the scenes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas governor threatens to defund state legislature after Democrats block voting bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/texas-governor-greg-abbott-restrictive-voting-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/texas-governor-greg-abbott-restrictive-voting-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T20:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Abbott excoriated for bizarre threat after Democrats thwart 11th-hour attempt to pass bill that would have made voting harder
Voting rights advocates on Tuesday excoriated Texas governor Greg Abbott’s bizarre threat to defund the state legislature after Democratic lawmakers thwarted an 11th-hour attempt to pass his priority bill that would have made it even harder for the public to cast a ballot in elections.
“At the end of the day, it’s so embarrassing that our governor can’t take a setback without throwing a tantrum about it,” Emily Eby, staff attorney at the Texas Civil Rights Project, told the Guardian.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Villarreal in Austin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police make six arrests after 14-year-old boy stabbed to death in Birmingham]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/boy-14-stabbed-to-death-in-birmingham</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/boy-14-stabbed-to-death-in-birmingham"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T20:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[West Midlands police refer themselves to police watchdog amid claims killing was racially motivated
Police in Birmingham hunting for a group of men who chased then stabbed a 14-year-old black child to death have made six arrests and referred themselves to the police watchdog amid claims the killing was racially motivated.
West Midlands police initially said there was nothing to support a racial motive in Monday’s stabbing, despite concerns raised in the community. However, on Tuesday evening the force changed that stance, saying they were keeping an open mind as to the motive.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray and Vikram Dodd</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data Analytics with Pandas – How to Drop a List of Rows from a Pandas Dataframe]]></title>
        <id>60b1eed311ffb70827ef9504</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/drop-list-of-rows-from-pandas-dataframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T20:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Pandas dataframe is a two dimensional data structure which allows you to store data in rows and columns. It's very useful when you're analyzing data.  When you have a list of data records in a dataframe, you may need to drop a specific list of rows depending on the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Our society is totally nuts’: Fauci emails lift lid on life in eye of the Covid storm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/anthony-fauci-emails-covid-coronavirus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/anthony-fauci-emails-covid-coronavirus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T20:30:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Communications from America’s top infectious diseases expert shed light on panic and confusion in early stages of pandemic
As Anthony Fauci, the US’s leading infectious diseases official, grappled with the early stages of the coronavirus pandemic last spring, he was pulled in many directions.
Donald Trump’s White House, which was downplaying the dangers, was demanding he portray the outbreak on their terms; the media was hungry for answers; and Fauci’s email inbox was constantly full with officials, the public and celebrities offering advice and seeking information about the world’s deadliest health crisis for a century.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe and Martin Pengelly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rafael Nadal wins in straight sets as he launches French Open defence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/rafael-nadal-wins-in-straight-sets-as-he-launches-defence-of-french-open</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/rafael-nadal-wins-in-straight-sets-as-he-launches-defence-of-french-open"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T19:43:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nadal beat Australia’s Alex Popyrin 6-3, 6-2, 7-6 (3)
Ashleigh Barty battles injury in her three-set win

Eight months ago in the soggy, cold surrounds of a rare autumn Roland Garros, there were ample doubts circling Rafael Nadal – the loudest from himself – as he began his title defence in conditions that blunted his heavy topspin. It went quite well in the end: Nadal finished the fortnight with just one set lost, and winning the first in the final, against Novak Djokovic, 6-0.
There will be no such questions this year. Even while seeded third and the possibility of a semi-final with Djokovic looming, Nadal is the heavy favourite until further notice. On Tuesday Nadal started his campaign for an absurd 14th title by defeating Alexei Popyrin 6-3, 6-2, 7-6 (3) in the sun to reach the second round with his 101st win at Roland Garros, to just two losses, clinching his 31st consecutive victory.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England an impossible job no more given talent at Southgate’s disposal | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/england-an-impossible-job-no-more-given-talent-at-southgates-disposal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/england-an-impossible-job-no-more-given-talent-at-southgates-disposal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T19:05:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager has a glut of defenders and a front line of rare skill – how he balances his options will determine Euro 2020 fate
Alea iacta est. The die, after endless beard-scratching permutation, is cast. Squad chemistry has been distilled, club finals waited out, and the story cycle of Trent and the fourth-place right-back slot enshrined in the national myth kitty for centuries to come.
And so here we are with a list of names. The intangibles around England’s Euro 2020 squad have finally been unravelled, options refined, full-backs stockpiled. It is now time to cross the Rubicon into these delayed Covid Euros, and a period of high-summer crisis that will, rightly or wrongly, define Gareth Southgate’s time as England manager.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chris Gethard: Half My Life review – arresting snapshots of a standup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/01/chris-gethard-half-my-life-review-standup</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/01/chris-gethard-half-my-life-review-standup"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T19:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Available online
Part behind-the-scenes doc and part reiteration of Gethard’s faith in comedy, this is a vivid portrait of a peripatetic life
Chris Gethard’s new film opens with the 40-year-old performing at 9am to a pancake-guzzling audience in Buffalo, New York. Truly, the life of a touring standup is not all glamour. That’s partly the point that Half My Life is making: it finds the New Jersey man revisiting a handful of his favourite venues, ruminating on life as a mid-career comedian, and pining for his wife and baby son back home. Between the scenes of this diary-cum-documentary, footage is spliced from the shows on the tour.
It’s a diverting behind-the-scenes document of the peripatetic comic’s life – if not a particularly surprising one. We see Gethard and support act Carmen Christopher gridlocked on the interstate under lowering clouds, electric-scootering around Asbury Park, New Jersey, in the hours before showtime – then post-gig, posing for photos by the merch stall. None of it looks like the big time; Gethard jokes that he couldn’t fill an arena if he tried. But then, he began life as a tyro punk comic, and if Half My Life conjures with Gethard’s career disillusion, it also advertises his fidelity to those roots.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Logan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on Boris Johnson v the Delta variant — cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/01/ben-jennings-on-boris-johnson-v-the-delta-variant-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/01/ben-jennings-on-boris-johnson-v-the-delta-variant-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T19:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool hand Kane Williamson plays down New Zealand’s run of success | Andy Bull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/kane-williamson-new-zealand-england-first-test-cricket</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/kane-williamson-new-zealand-england-first-test-cricket"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T19:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Captain says focus is looking forward, not back, with two Tests against England and then India in World Test Championship
For all those books explaining what the British could learn about health, happiness and everything else from the Scandinavians, Japanese and French, no one seems to have done anything much on what the New Zealanders have to teach us. Perhaps the problem is in persuading them to talk openly about their achievements. Like Tim Southee said the other day: “It’s not really the Kiwi way.”
So here they are, one of the smallest cricket-playing countries, with one of the slightest budgets and the sparsest player pools, ranked first in the one-day rankings, second in Tests, third in T20s and about to play India in the first World Test Championship final.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Bull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Record manufacturing jump boosts markets in UK, US and eurozone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/01/record-manufacturing-jump-boosts-markets-uk-us-eurozone-oil</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/01/record-manufacturing-jump-boosts-markets-uk-us-eurozone-oil"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T18:52:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oil prices surge as pent-up demand in May adds to last month’s growth records 

A record jump in manufacturing activity in the UK, the US and the eurozone lifted stock markets on both sides of the Atlantic on Tuesday.
Pent-up demand after a year of stop-start activity due to the coronavirus outbreak pushed factory order books to fresh highs in May, adding to previous growth records set in April, according to a bellwether survey of factory owners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Petra Kvitova out of French Open after injuring ankle during press duties]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/petra-kvitova-out-french-open-injury-during-press-duties</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/petra-kvitova-out-french-open-injury-during-press-duties"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T18:37:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kvitova fell and hurt her ankle leaving broadcast interview
Naomi Osaka left event on Monday over press conference row

Petra Kvitova was forced to withdraw from the French Open before her second-round match after sustaining a freak injury during her press duties. Kvitova fell as she left a broadcast interview and hurt her ankle, and decided to withdraw after undergoing an MRI scan.
“It is with great disappointment that I announce my withdrawal from Roland Garros,” Kvitova wrote in a statement on social media. “During my post-match press requirements on Sunday, I fell and hurt my ankle. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We got woken by cows mooing’: Guardian readers share bank holiday stories]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/guardian-readers-share-bank-holiday-stories-lifting-covid-restrictions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/guardian-readers-share-bank-holiday-stories-lifting-covid-restrictions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T18:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers make the most of a hot bank holiday weekend after the lifting of some Covid restrictions 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 
After a sweltering bank holiday weekend, Guardian readers describe how they spent the first public holiday since Covid restrictions on indoor hospitality and visits to tourist spots were eased.
Becky, 49, a nurse from Sheffield, had originally made plans to attend a music festival, but had to make other arrangements when it was cancelled.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jedidajah Otte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lord Ashcroft’s daughter-in-law on manslaughter charge after officer death]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/partner-of-ashcroft-son-on-manslaughter-charge-after-police-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/partner-of-ashcroft-son-on-manslaughter-charge-after-police-death"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T18:10:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jasmine Hartin denied bail after she was found near body of Supt Henry Jemmott in Belize
The daughter-in-law of the former Conservative party treasurer Lord Ashcroft has been charged in Belize with manslaughter by negligence over the shooting death of a police superintendent.
Jasmine Hartin was being held following the discovery of the body of Henry Jemmott, 42, near a jetty in the resort town of San Pedro early on Friday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Scary stuff’: International Space Station robotic arm struck by space junk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/01/international-space-station-robotic-arm-space-junk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/01/international-space-station-robotic-arm-space-junk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:49:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Lucky strike’ did not endanger seven astronauts on board
Not known what debris struck station or when it occurred

The sudden appearance of a small hole in a robotic arm aboard the international space station (ISS) has brought renewed attention to the danger posed by space junk.
 Related: Chinese cargo craft docks with future space station in orbit 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Luscombe in Miami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China confirms first human case of H10N3 bird flu strain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/china-confirms-first-human-case-h10n3-bird-flu-strain-man-jiangsu</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/china-confirms-first-human-case-h10n3-bird-flu-strain-man-jiangsu"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:48:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Man, 41, in Jiangsu, diagnosed on 28 May but risk of avian virus spread is low, says state health agency
A 41-year-old man in China’s eastern province of Jiangsu has been confirmed as the first human case of infection with the H10N3 strain of bird flu, although health officials in China said the risk of large-scale spread remained low.
The man, a resident of the city of Zhenjiang, went to hospital on 28 April after developing a fever and other symptoms, China’s national health commission said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Beijing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Next.js and Make React Development Simpler]]></title>
        <id>60b668c0acb62507dd1d710b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-next-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:43:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next.js makes developing React applications simpler. It provides a common structure that allows you to build frontend React applications, and transparently handles server-side rendering for you. We just released a full course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you the basics of Next.js.  Kapehe developed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on global vaccination rates: a tale of two pandemics | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/the-guardian-view-on-global-vaccination-rates-a-tale-of-two-pandemics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/the-guardian-view-on-global-vaccination-rates-a-tale-of-two-pandemics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:39:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[G7 leaders meeting in Cornwall next week must act over the unacceptably low numbers of vaccinations available in poorer nations
During the eurozone debt crisis, the then president of the European Central Bank, Mario Draghi, deployed a phrase that demonstrated the transformative power of strong leadership in dangerous circumstances. By vowing that he would do “whatever it takes” to protect the euro from aggressive speculation by bond markets, Mr Draghi eased the pressure and defused a crisis that, left unchecked, posed an existential threat to the European Union.
The spirit of “whatever it takes” is required this summer from richer nations, if a durable and morally just exit from the Covid-19 pandemic is to take place. As G7 leaders prepare to meet in Cornwall next weekend, a cross-party group of more than 100 MPs has called on Boris Johnson to match each vaccine administered in Britain with a donated dose to developing nations, where there is a desperate shortage. In a joint plea, the heads of the World Health Organization, the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank and the World Trade Organization have warned that the gulf in levels of vaccination is creating a “two-track pandemic”. Some low-income countries have received less than 1% of global Covid vaccinations, while rich ones have hoovered them up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer: coming months are make-or-break for Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/keir-starmer-coming-months-are-make-or-break-for-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/keir-starmer-coming-months-are-make-or-break-for-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:38:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Party leader tells Piers Morgan in TV interview that political space will open up as lockdown eases
The coming months are a potentially make-or-break period for the Labour party, Keir Starmer has told Piers Morgan in an in-depth TV interview that also covered areas including his early life and family, legal career, and intense dislike for his middle name.
Starmer said that after a tricky few weeks for his leadership of Labour he was hopeful that, post-Covid restrictions, a summer speaking to sceptical voters could help turn the tide. “Let me get out there, let me take the mask off. As we come out of this, it allows the political space to open up, and allow me to open up,” he told ITV’s Piers Morgan’s Life Stories.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on Britain and the Chagos Islands: time for justice | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/the-guardian-view-on-britain-and-the-chagos-islands-time-for-justice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/the-guardian-view-on-britain-and-the-chagos-islands-time-for-justice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:38:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[International courts say the archipelago belongs to Mauritius, not the UK. What is Britain waiting for?

Britain’s forced eviction of up to 2,000 Chagos Islanders from their homes on the Indian Ocean archipelago, to make way for a huge US military base on Diego Garcia, was shameful – by the admission of the UK government itself. But if the last half century has made it more willing to acknowledge its original sin, it has come no closer to addressing it seriously. The only noticeable progress in recent years was the creation of a £40m fund for the displaced islanders, of which only a tiny fraction has been spent.
Meanwhile, international opinion is inexorably moving against the UK. Last month, the council of the UN’s Universal Postal Union recommended that stamps issued by the British Indian Ocean Territory – as the UK designates the islands – should not be recognised. What on its own sounds trivial reflects the overwhelming shift to recognition of the archipelago as belonging to Mauritius, from which it was severed when the country gained independence in the 1960s, in exchange for a £4m payment. (Mauritius says it was coerced.) United Nations maps have already been redrawn. Little by little, legal decisions are having their effect.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Michelangelo of Middlesbrough’ hailed for 27,000-hour model project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/michelangelo-of-middlesbrough-hailed-for-27000-hour-model</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/michelangelo-of-middlesbrough-hailed-for-27000-hour-model"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:35:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown hobbyist painted 1m tiny cobbles for scale model of Yorkshire town’s demolished St Hilda’s district 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Lockdown has inspired many of us to take up new hobbies, but for one Middlesbrough man, the pandemic just meant more time to devote to a mammoth project already nine years in the making.
“It was business as usual,” says Steve Waller, 61, a model artist and historian known affectionately as the “Michelangelo of Middlesbrough” who has spent almost a decade recreating the town’s historical St Hilda’s district in his bedroom.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Mistlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The real Keir Starmer – tears, blokey bonding and no politics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/the-real-keir-starmer-tears-blokey-bonding-and-no-politics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/the-real-keir-starmer-tears-blokey-bonding-and-no-politics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:32:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Piers Morgan’s interview offered a few insights into the Labour leader but not the state of the party

“Why are you doing this?” asked Piers Morgan. A good question. Why does anyone agree to do Piers Morgan’s Life Stories (ITV) unless they have an ulterior motive? Why put yourself through the ordeal of an ersatz This is Your Life therapy session with an interviewer whose eyes are firmly fixed on ratings fodder and has little concern for your mental wellbeing? So best to get the elephant out of the room first.
Keir Starmer smiled nervously and joked about this being the first time he had had an opportunity to talk to a live audience since becoming leader of the Labour party. But we all knew that was only a half-truth. The real reasons he was there were the opinion polls that showed Labour consistently behind the Tories, the recent disastrous local election results and voters saying they didn’t know much about what made Starmer tick.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the ‘good war’ went bad: elite soldiers from Australia, UK and US face a reckoning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/02/how-the-good-war-went-bad-elite-soldiers-from-australia-uk-and-us-face-a-reckoning</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/02/how-the-good-war-went-bad-elite-soldiers-from-australia-uk-and-us-face-a-reckoning"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As coalition troops prepare to withdraw from Afghanistan after 20 years, former soldiers, key officers and the public are asking what went wrong with some special forces 
“Whatever we do … ,” one Australian special forces soldier said of his service in Afghanistan, “I can tell you the Brits and the US are far, far worse.
“I’ve watched our young guys stand by and hero worship what they were doing, salivating at how the US were torturing people. You just stand there and roll your eyes and wait for it to end.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Doherty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carlo Ancelotti returns to Real Madrid as manager after leaving Everton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/carlo-ancelotti-in-line-for-real-madrid-return-manager-if-compensation-agreed-with-everton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/01/carlo-ancelotti-in-line-for-real-madrid-return-manager-if-compensation-agreed-with-everton"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T17:07:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ancelotti says he could not reject ‘unexpected opportunity’
Nuno a possible target but Moyes close to new West Ham deal

Everton have started the search for their sixth permanent manager in five years having been stunned by Carlo Ancelotti’s sudden departure for Real Madrid.
The 61-year-old signed a three-year contract with the Spanish club on Tuesday after Madrid’s president, Florentino Pérez, having missed out on Massimiliano Allegri as a replacement for Zinedine Zidane, made a concerted effort to rehire the three-times Champions League-winning coach. Ancelotti informed Everton earlier in the day of his desire to leave after only 18 months.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter, Fabrizio Romano and Jacob Steinberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid outbreak forces Gloucester to cancel final home match of season]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/covid-outbreak-forces-gloucester-to-cancel-final-home-match-of-season</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/01/covid-outbreak-forces-gloucester-to-cancel-final-home-match-of-season"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bath will be awarded 28-0 win, boosting European hopes
Scotland name 17 uncapped players in 37-man summer squad

Gloucester’s final home match of the season against Bath on Saturday has been cancelled because of a Covid‑19 outbreak which threatens major disruptions to the climax of the season.
Premiership Rugby announced on Tuesday that the match had been called off because of a number of cases detected at Gloucester after symptoms had been reported on Sunday. As a result Bath are set to be awarded a 28-0 win which would significantly boost their hopes of a top-eight finish and qualification for next season’s Champions Cup, all the while denting Gloucester’s hopes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruel forced adoptions are still happening today | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/01/cruel-forced-adoptions-are-still-happening-today</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/01/cruel-forced-adoptions-are-still-happening-today"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:51:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nina Lopez points to adoptions occurring against the wishes of birth families, while one reader recalls how their sister was forced to give up her baby. And John Peniket says it was the prevailing social attitudes to sex and childbirth that were to blame
Gaby Hinsliff (The UK’s forced adoption scandal was state-sanctioned abuse, 27 May) draws an important parallel between the adoptions forced on single mothers between the 1950s and 1970s, the Rochdale, Windrush and Grenfell scandals, and preventable Covid-19 deaths. She points to “state-sanctioned abuse” of people “dehumanised in the eyes of officialdom”.
But she seems unaware that forced adoptions have not stopped. Of about 3,500 adoptions a year, 90% are against the will of the birth family. They are hidden by a closed family court system that was found to be ridden with sexism, racism and classism by the government’s review of harm in the family courts’ treatment of domestic violence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mystified by Catholic church’s blessing for Boris Johnson’s wedding | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/mystified-by-catholic-churchs-blessing-for-boris-johnsons-wedding</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/mystified-by-catholic-churchs-blessing-for-boris-johnsons-wedding"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:48:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers question why the twice-divorced prime minister was allowed to marry at Westminster Cathedral
I worked for 10 years as a Roman Catholic priest in south London and was obliged to leave the ministry when I met Clare and we decided to get married (Catholics question why Boris Johnson was able to marry in church, 30 May). Pope John Paul II refused us permission to be married in church. Is it that Boris Johnson always gets what he wants, or is it that the church’s rules defy any rational logic, or is it perhaps both?
Chris Larkman
London
• Twenty-eight years ago, my wife and I were refused a blessing in a Catholic church in Bournemouth on the grounds that I was divorced. My first marriage took place in a register office, but there was no mention of an exemption being made on the grounds that this was not a Catholic ceremony. However, as I had no children from my first marriage, the priest asked if my first wife had refused to have children, as this might be grounds for an annulment. Obviously, this could not be applied to Boris Johnson, given his fecundity. We thought it would not be a good way to start a new relationship if it were to be based on a lie, and so we declined the “offer”.
Philip and Tina Wragg
Campillos, Málaga, Spain
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should lockdown lifting go ahead as concerns swirl over Covid variants?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/should-lockdown-lifting-go-ahead-as-concerns-swirl-over-covid-variants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/should-lockdown-lifting-go-ahead-as-concerns-swirl-over-covid-variants"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:43:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts weigh in on whether limits on social contact should be removed in three weeks’ time 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The final step out of lockdown in England is set for 21 June, when the government will remove “all legal limits on social contact” – although some social distancing and mask-wearing rules will remain.
However, a senior government minister has said that it is too early to speculate about whether this will go ahead as planned, amid concern about increasing cases of the Delta variant, first detected in India and known as B.1.617.2.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Marsh and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eritrean soldiers killed 19 civilians in latest Tigray atrocity, locals claim]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/eritrean-soldiers-killed-19-civilians-in-latest-tigray-atrocity-locals-claim</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/eritrean-soldiers-killed-19-civilians-in-latest-tigray-atrocity-locals-claim"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:40:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Killings took place near Ethiopia’s Abuna Yemata church on 8 May, according to multiple testimonies
Eritrean soldiers killed 19 civilians in a village at the foot of an internationally celebrated rock-hewn church in Tigray three weeks ago, witnesses, relatives and local residents have claimed, the latest alleged atrocity in the war-torn Ethiopian region.
Most of the victims in the alleged attack were women and young children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Journey – How I Got a Remote Job and Increased My Salary While Contributing to Open Source]]></title>
        <id>60acf28e11ffb70827ef6dd9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-developer-journey-how-i-increased-my-salary-and-got-a-remote-job/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone, my name is Santosh. In this article, I will tell you how I ramped up my career and ended up increasing my salary as a developer.  I'll share what I learned from each job along the way, how you can stand out, tips for negotiating salary, and how]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get a Cybersecurity Job in 2021]]></title>
        <id>60aff2d711ffb70827ef8829</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-get-a-cybersecurity-job/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:34:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This informative tutorial goes deep into how to get a cybersecurity job, with insights from senior leaders and hiring managers in the field.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man, 20, arrested on suspicion of murdering London flower seller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/man-20-arrested-london-flower-seller-tony-eastlake-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/man-20-arrested-london-flower-seller-tony-eastlake-death"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:27:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say suspect is believed to be known to Tony Eastlake, killed near his Islington stall on Saturday

A 20-year-old man has been arrested on suspicion of the murder of a flower seller in north London at the weekend.
Tony Eastlake, 55, died from a knife wound close to his stall on Essex Road in Islington on Saturday. Police attended along with the London ambulance service at about 5.30pm and provided first aid but he was pronounced dead at the scene.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frenchwoman gives up legal fight for return of Nazi-looted Pissarro]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/frenchwoman-gives-up-legal-fight-for-return-of-nazi-looted-pissaro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/frenchwoman-gives-up-legal-fight-for-return-of-nazi-looted-pissaro"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T16:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Léone-Noëlle Meyer, 81, drops legal action against University of Oklahoma after being threatened with fines
A French heiress has been forced to give up her battle to recover a Pissarro painting the Nazis looted from her adoptive parents.
Léone-Noëlle Meyer, 81, announced on Tuesday she had been left with “no choice” but to drop legal action to retrieve La Bergère Rentrant des Moutons (Shepherdess Bringing in Sheep) after she was threatened with large fines if she continued.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All eyes on Carrie Johnson in first role as UK first lady at G7 summit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/all-eyes-on-carrie-johnson-in-first-role-as-uk-first-lady-at-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/all-eyes-on-carrie-johnson-in-first-role-as-uk-first-lady-at-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:50:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newly wed, at 33 she may be youngest spouse but her political nous should serve her well in keeping the plus-ones happy
Newly wed and with her new married name, Carrie Johnson takes on her first challenge as the UK’s first lady when she hosts the partners of world leaders at next week’s G7 summit.
At 33, the conservationist and erstwhile political PR will be the youngest spouse as she stands by the side of Boris Johnson, 56, at their first key event since their secret marriage on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swizz Beatz: ‘DMX was a hero. He would give clothes off his back to the homeless’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/01/swizz-beatz-dmx-was-a-hero-he-would-give-clothes-off-his-back-to-the-homeless</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/01/swizz-beatz-dmx-was-a-hero-he-would-give-clothes-off-his-back-to-the-homeless"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:49:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The superproducer is married to Alicia Keys and has made hits for Jay-Z and Beyoncé – but his current role is custodian of DMX’s legacy. He explains the particular power of the late rapper
Don’t call DMX’s Exodus a “posthumous album”. Its executive producer, Swizz Beatz, is adamant about that. “I keep seeing that, and it’s so annoying that I can’t correct everybody,” he says. That description suggests a project pieced together from odds and ends to make a quick dollar, but DMX completed Exodus before he died on 9 April, aged 50, after a heart attack. It is the final pillar propping up a broad legacy: DMX was the first artist to have five albums in a row debut at No 1 in the US, and Exodus will surely also top the charts this week.
Swizz Beatz’ phone contacts is a list of musical aristocracy – he’s made key tracks for Jay-Z, Beyoncé, Busta Rhymes and more, and is married to Alicia Keys – but his name has always been tethered to DMX like no other: he produced two of his biggest hits, Party Up (Up in Here) and Ruff Ryders’ Anthem, and handled the majority of the beats on his second album Flesh of My Flesh, Blood of My Blood. “For me and him to go back in the studio like this, we had to go big,” Swizz says, speaking over Zoom. “He deserved it to be big, and he accepted it to be big. That’s the thing: you can have a big plan for someone but if they don’t have that plan for themselves, it’s just you having a plan. The key with this is that he was ready.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dean Van Nguyen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man arrested on suspicion of murdering woman and child in Louth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/man-arrested-murdering-woman-child-louth-daniel-boulton</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/man-arrested-murdering-woman-child-louth-daniel-boulton"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Boulton, 29, is also suspected of injuring Lincolnshire police officer

A 29-year-old man has been arrested on suspicion of murdering a woman and child and stabbing an off-duty police officer who tried to apprehend him in a “tragic, extraordinary and worrying” case, police said.
Daniel Boulton was sought by police after his ex-partner, 26-year-old Bethany Vincent, and her nine-year-old son, Darren Henson, were found dead at a property in Louth, Lincolnshire, on Monday evening, with multiple stab wounds.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Tatchell’s life on film: ‘So far I’ve been violently assaulted 300 times’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/hating-peter-tatchell-documentary-netflix-lgbt-rights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/01/hating-peter-tatchell-documentary-netflix-lgbt-rights"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:19:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peter Tatchell has protested against everyone from Mike Tyson to Tony Blair. So what did the human rights campaigner make of the Netflix documentary Hating Peter Tatchell?
The title of Hating Peter Tatchell was the brainchild of its director, Christopher Amos. When, in 2015, he first became interested in making a documentary about my 54 years of LGBTQ+ and other human rights activism, he was taken aback by the volume and ferocity of hatred against me.
So far I’ve been violently assaulted over 300 times, had 50 attacks on my flat, been the victim of half a dozen murder plots and received tens of thousands of hate messages and death threats over the last five decades, mostly from homophobes and far-right extremists. Amos envisaged a film that documented how and why my campaigns generated such extreme hatred.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Tatchell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belarusian activist stabs himself in court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/belarusian-activist-tries-to-stab-himself-in-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/belarusian-activist-tries-to-stab-himself-in-court"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:06:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stsiapan Latypau carried out unconscious after claiming he was pressured to plead guilty
A Belarusian opposition activist stabbed himself in the throat with a pen during a court hearing after claiming investigators had pressured him to plead guilty or face his family and friends being arrested.
Footage from Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty showed Stsiapan Latypau, who has organised protests against the country’s authoritarian leader, Alexander Lukashenko, lying inside a defendant’s cage as witnesses screamed in a courtroom in Minsk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Roth in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicola Sturgeon confirms Glasgow Covid restrictions will ease]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/nicola-sturgeon-confirms-glasgow-covid-restrictions-will-ease</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/nicola-sturgeon-confirms-glasgow-covid-restrictions-will-ease"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T15:03:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Glasgow moves to level 2 from Saturday with residents able to meet indoors

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Nicola Sturgeon has confirmed that Glasgow will move down a level of Covid controls to level 2 from Saturday, with residents able to hug, drink alcohol indoors and meet in each other’s homes for the first time in eight months, as she slowed the easing of restrictions elsewhere across central Scotland.
Scotland’s largest city had remained in the second-toughest lockdown regime, with an additional travel ban in place, while the rest of the country’s restrictions were relaxed, after the rapid spread of the Delta variant in the southside of the city.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon US customers have one week to opt out of mass wireless sharing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/01/amazon-us-customers-given-one-week-to-opt-out-of-mass-wireless-sharing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/01/amazon-us-customers-given-one-week-to-opt-out-of-mass-wireless-sharing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:55:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critics raise transparency fears over plan to turn all smart home devices into ‘mesh network’

Amazon customers have one week to opt out of a plan that would turn every Echo speaker and Ring security camera in the US into a shared wireless network, as part of the company’s plan to fix connection problems for its smart home devices.
The proposal, called Amazon Sidewalk, involves the company’s devices being used as a springboard to build city-wide “mesh networks” that help simplify the process of setting up new devices, keep them online even if they’re out of range of home wifi, and extend the range of tracking devices such as those made by Tile.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern Technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[150 years old: how the quest for eternal life found its natural limit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/01/150-years-old-how-the-quest-for-eternal-life-found-its-natural-limit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/01/150-years-old-how-the-quest-for-eternal-life-found-its-natural-limit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:51:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new study reveals that humans could potentially live to 150 – and dogs can also look forward to much greater longevity
Name: 150 years old.
Age: 150 years old.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A banal, excruciating mess – you review Friends: the Reunion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/a-banal-excruciating-mess-you-review-friends-the-reunion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/a-banal-excruciating-mess-you-review-friends-the-reunion"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:40:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The show you’ve waited 17 years for aired at last – and could you BE any more emotional? But what did you rate and what did you hate? And why did Matt LeBlanc come out on top?
Friends was a huge part of my life. Growing up, and realising I was gay but having nobody to talk to, I felt very alone and very isolated. Watching Friends got me through some really dark moments. 
I sat down to watch [the reunion], fully expecting to hate it, but was crying within minutes. All the feelings I had growing up came back. I loved seeing the cast get together and hearing how they felt on set and how they reacted when they arrived. The bond they all share is so clear and strong. I always felt as if I was a part of Friends, as silly as that may sound, but watching it definitely influenced my personality. I’m sarcastic like Chandler, a clean freak like Monica and a little bit different like Phoebe. 
Seeing them all together again just reminds you that lifelong ‘Friends’ are achievable. I just wish I could let the cast and the writers know how much it means to me. Scott, 30, Essex
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers and Rachel Obordo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s outdone Henry VIII in having his third marriage blessed by the Catholic church | Christopher Lamb]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/boris-johnson-henry-viii-third-marriage-catholic-church-divorced</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/boris-johnson-henry-viii-third-marriage-catholic-church-divorced"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It seems like double standards when the twice-divorced prime minister can marry in church while other divorcees cannot
The prime minister’s marriage to Carrie Symonds in Westminster Cathedral has left many Catholics with a question. If the mother church of the Catholic church in England and Wales can kill the fatted calf and welcome the twice-divorced prime minister as a prodigal son, why are so many other divorcees being turned away?
People are upset by what feels like double standards. Too often it seems church leaders are willing to bend over backwards to accommodate the powerful in ways the poorest, or those without influence, are simply not offered.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Lamb</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Who are we performing for?’: Will McPhail on the strange art of small talk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/01/cartoonist-will-mcphail-in-graphic-novel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/01/cartoonist-will-mcphail-in-graphic-novel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T13:38:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The New Yorker cartoonist’s debut graphic novel In follows an aimless artist who struggles to connect with others. He talks about his own experiences, and his love for drawing ‘characterful’ pigeons
One morning this week, Will McPhail went out to buy a coffee. While fishing for his keys, he rested the takeaway cup on the roof of his car. A passerby spotted him.
“Oof,” the man said, with a convivial, wotcha-cobber gesture at the coffee. “Don’t drive off!”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elle Hunt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German CDU leader says ‘firewall’ against far right will hold firm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/german-cdu-leader-armin-laschet-says-firewall-against-far-right-will-hold-firm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/german-cdu-leader-armin-laschet-says-firewall-against-far-right-will-hold-firm"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T13:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Armin Laschet, who hopes to succeed Angela Merkel as chancellor, rules out cooperation with AfD
Armin Laschet, the leader of Angela Merkel’s Christian Democratic Union and her potential successor as chancellor, has insisted his party’s “firewall” against the far right will remain intact, as the CDU braces itself for a strong performance by the nationalist Alternative für Deutschland (AfD) in Sunday’s state elections in Saxony-Anhalt.
The AfD, which first entered the German parliament in 2017, is stagnant on about 11% of the vote in polls for the national vote in September, but has shored up its influential positions in several states of the formerly socialist east.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Oltermann in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Human challenge: the people volunteering to be infected with Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/human-challenge-people-volunteering-infected-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/human-challenge-people-volunteering-infected-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T13:06:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amid claims PM wanted to be infected with Covid on TV, volunteers tell of taking part in a human challenge trial 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

If Dominic Cummings is to be believed, Boris Johnson was so sceptical that Covid-19 was a threat early last year that he was willing to inject himself with the virus that causes the disease on television. But there are actual volunteers – young and healthy people – who elected to be infected with the virus, all in the name of science.
These volunteers lined up to participate in “human challenge trials”, which have long been successfully employed to develop vaccines for diseases from typhoid to cholera.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[While China’s borders remain closed, the global economy suffers | Daniel Falush]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/china-borders-covid-global-economy-winter-olympics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/china-borders-covid-global-economy-winter-olympics"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T13:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rigorous testing and 20 million vaccinations a day might see Beijing ready to host the Winter Olympics 2022
In March 2020, I wrote that life was returning to normal in China, but that other countries faced a longer wait. I did not imagine that this longer wait would extend until the summer of 2021. Meanwhile, China has returned to and maintained an essentially pre-Covid state – becoming a kind of parallel universe. In the last year, I have hiked in five provinces, organised a week-long in-person meeting in a tropical botanical garden involving scientists from 20 academic institutions, and attended scores of live music and dance events, featuring maskless musicians playing to packed, maskless crowds. GDP in the first quarter of this year grew 18.3%; in the EU, it fell 0.6%.
China has achieved this success due to the effectiveness of its test, trace and isolate measures. There have been numerous outbreaks of Covid-19 since last spring, varying in size from single cases to hundreds, but all of them have been ended swiftly, with modest, generally localised disruption. The key to this success has been the rapidity and rigour of the measures taken to curtail community transmission.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Falush</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – as long as they shut up and play | Marina Hyde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/sport-athletes-mental-health-tennis-naomi-osaka</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/sport-athletes-mental-health-tennis-naomi-osaka"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:55:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The grand slams say Naomi Osaka’s decisions about press are ‘injurious’ to tennis. Perhaps they should look closer to home
Amazing, really, that the most appalling people in tennis are not the ones who applaud piously when the Wimbledon umpire tells the crowd to ensure their mobile phones are switched to silent, nor even the ones who are far more hysterically enchanted by the appearance of a pigeon on Centre Court then they ever could be by an otherworldly Roger Federer forehand.
Much more ghastly are those simply unable to deal with world No 2 Naomi Osaka announcing last week that she didn’t feel mentally up to doing press conferences at the French Open. This drew frothing anger from all the usual suspects, including the only highly paid news anchor in history so fragile that he recently stormed off air on his own show. The French Open fined Osaka for missing her first-round press conferences, and the official Roland Garros Twitter account posted (then later deleted) a collage of players doing press conferences with the leadenly pointed caption: “They understood the assignment.” On Monday, Osaka announced that she would be pulling out of the entire tournament , revealing she had had long bouts of depression since winning the US Open in 2018, and had often struggled to cope.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Hyde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK’s first day of summer – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/01/uks-first-day-of-summer-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/gallery/2021/jun/01/uks-first-day-of-summer-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:55:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1 June is the first day of the meteorological summer and with fine weather forecast around the country, schools on half-term and the recent relaxation of coronavirus restrictions, people are getting out in the sun. The UK could experience record conditions for the second day in a row after temperatures hit 25C on bank holiday Monday, making it the warmest day of the year so far 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matt Fidler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A year since Blackout Tuesday, has equality in music improved?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/01/a-year-since-blackout-tuesday-has-equality-in-music-improved</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/01/a-year-since-blackout-tuesday-has-equality-in-music-improved"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:52:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amid the BLM protests of 2020 came a call to make the music industry accountable on race – but while new initiatives are helping, real change is still slow in the UK
It is a year since two Black female music executives, Jamila Thomas of Atlantic Records and Brianna Agyemang of Platoon, called for the music industry to shut down for the day in protest following the killing of George Floyd. “Our mission is to hold the industry at large, including major corporations + their partners who benefit from the efforts, struggles and successes of Black people accountable,” wrote the women under the hashtag #theshowmustbepaused, which was shared more than 700,000 times.
On what became colloquially known as Blackout Tuesday, labels shared messages of support and suspended business, as did artists including the Rolling Stones, Rihanna, and Yoko Ono. The outpouring of support for racial justice was welcomed, but a year on, many in the industry are piling on the pressure to ensure the companies that shared black squares of solidarity fulfil their promises to change. “Were they completely sincere in it? I really can’t tell you,” says music consultant Melanie Rudder of Three Thirty Music, who has worked in the industry for more than 20 years. “I don’t feel like some were, but they had to act on it, because once you put that black square up, people were like: ‘OK, so what are you doing about this, then?’”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephanie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sarah Everard died from compression of the neck, say police]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/sarah-everard-died-from-compression-of-the-neck-say-police</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/sarah-everard-died-from-compression-of-the-neck-say-police"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police reveal results of postmortem on Everard, 33, who went missing in south London on 3 March
Sarah Everard, whose body was found in woodland in Kent a week after she went missing, died from compression of the neck, a postmortem has found.
Everard, a 33-year-old marketing executive, went missing after leaving a friend’s house in Clapham, south London, at about 9pm on 3 March. She is believed to have walked through Clapham Common on her way home to Brixton, a journey that should have taken about 50 minutes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pink skies, Paris murals and boat bikes: Tuesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/01/pink-skies-murals-bikes-tuesday-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/01/pink-skies-murals-bikes-tuesday-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:22:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Plimmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is your willpower failing? I tried hypnotherapy – and it worked almost too well | Deborah Frances-White]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/is-your-willpower-failing-i-tried-hypnotherapy-and-it-worked-almost-too-well</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/is-your-willpower-failing-i-tried-hypnotherapy-and-it-worked-almost-too-well"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:18:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown seemed the ideal time to attempt to become one of those people who hits their deadlines while eating mindfully. Who knew my inner elephant could actually be tamed?

A hypnotherapist once explained to me at a dinner party that willpower doesn’t work. I had assumed that it was just mine that was broken. Apparently, it’s because the conscious is such a small part of the brain. Almost everything you know and have experienced has to be stashed downstairs most of the time so that if you’re at the movies, say, you can focus on what Cruella is saying, the taste of the strawberry ice-cream, the second-dateness of the situation – and the kid kicking the back of your seat. There’s no room for more.
We’ve all seen a person riding an obedient elephant, but we know that if the elephant wants to run rogue, there’s not a thing the rider can do about it. People who want to go to the gym have an inner-mental elephant that was going to go anyway. The only way to access this elephantine unconscious is to put your know-it-all rider of a conscious into a trance to shut it up. I decided that lockdown was an ideal time to align my goals with my shoddiest behaviours to see if I could become one of those people who hits their deadlines, while eating mindfully and folding their laundry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deborah Frances-White</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Emily in Paris, you monster! What Rishi Sunak’s taste in TV reveals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/not-emily-in-paris-you-monster-what-rishi-sunaks-taste-in-tv-reveals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/01/not-emily-in-paris-you-monster-what-rishi-sunaks-taste-in-tv-reveals"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:09:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The chancellor has confessed his love of Emily in Paris, TV so bad even its own writers are ambivalent. But why did he namedrop Netflix when he was meant to be talking about the BBC?

Politicians should be banned from divulging their pop culture picks to the public. What purpose does it serve? Does it make them more attractive to voters? I hope not. Imagine meeting anyone whose voting criterion was how many of their favourite shows a politician liked. Imagine not immediately flicking them on the nose. You can’t. It’s impossible.
Still, at least we cannot accuse Rishi Sunak of being relatable. Because, according to an interview in the Radio Times, his favourite show is Emily in Paris. Emily in Paris, for crying out loud. What sort of monster would willingly sit through entire episodes of Emily in Paris? Nobody likes Emily in Paris. Even the show’s own writers seem ambivalent about it. The only way Emily in Paris could get anyone to like Emily in Paris was to send a load of journalists on a swanky press trip to Paris – and that move was deemed so questionable that it helped to dent the reputation of a 78-year-old awards show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stuart Heritage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will ‘freedom day’ go ahead? The only thing we know is we don’t know | Simon Jenkins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/freedom-day-england-21-june-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/01/freedom-day-england-21-june-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T12:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid data emerges, decisions over England’s easing on 21 June will go down to the wire. We must hope No 10 gets it right

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

England faces the tensest two weeks of its entire lockdown. On 14 June, the government must decide if the long-promised “freedom day” of 21 June can proceed as promised. That promise has now been plunged into doubt. A three-day surge in “cases” of the variant of Covid first detected in India may, or may not, mark the start of a third wave of the coronavirus. Boris Johnson has promised that any more lockdown will be over his dead body, but Johnson’s body has already lost more lives than the proverbial cat.
We now know, thanks to the new patron saint of whistleblowers, Dominic Cummings, the scale of government ineptitude and shambles that attended the first two lockdowns. People can now scream at ministers to make up their minds, show judgment, give a steer, keep their promises. But today the issue is not one of judgment, but of facts. We await data much as a nation awaits news of a battle in distant parts. Without news, we cannot think how to act.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Jenkins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How are you enjoying the hot weather in the UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/how-are-you-enjoying-the-hot-weather-in-the-uk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/how-are-you-enjoying-the-hot-weather-in-the-uk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T11:51:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With uncertainty around the lifting of restrictions at the end of June, we would like to hear your plans for the warm weather 
People across the country have been enjoying the hot weather over the bank holiday with the heatwave to last throughout the week.
This comes as the government’s former chief scientific adviser, Prof Sir Mark Walport, said it was “not impossible” that the country was in the foothills of a new wave as the government said it would be guided by data when it comes to deciding whether to lift restrictions in England on 21 June.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TfL gets £1bn bailout in return for making case for driverless trains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/tfl-cash-boost-made-dependent-on-driverless-tube-trains</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/01/tfl-cash-boost-made-dependent-on-driverless-tube-trains"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T11:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[London mayor says funds are a ‘sticking plaster’ and he will fight introduction of driverless tubes
Work to introduce driverless tube trains has been demanded by ministers as part of an emergency funding agreement for Transport for London, with the government injecting just over £1bn to help the capital recover from the pandemic.
TfL will be obliged to produce business cases for driverless trains on the Piccadilly and Waterloo and City lines in return for the latest funding, which also comes with a requirement to make £300m of annual cuts and slash pensions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel Slater’s recipe for crumbed aubergines with peppers and fennel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/01/nigel-slater-midweek-dinner-crumbed-aubergine-with-peppers-and-fennel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/01/nigel-slater-midweek-dinner-crumbed-aubergine-with-peppers-and-fennel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T11:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crisp golden aubergine rounds served with tasty herby veg
Cut 4 medium-sized red peppers in half, then into long, 1cm thick strips. In a heavy, shallow pan, heat 5 tbsp of olive oil, add the peppers, season and add rosemary, then fry over moderate heat, stirring, for about 5 minutes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nigel Slater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If sarcasm is the lowest form of wit, what is the highest?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/if-sarcasm-is-the-lowest-form-of-wit-what-is-the-highest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/if-sarcasm-is-the-lowest-form-of-wit-what-is-the-highest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T11:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
If sarcasm is the lowest form of wit, what is the highest? Dr Willis Stone, London
Post your answers (and new questions) below or send them to nq@theguardian.com. A selection will be published on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Throw the ingredients together with reckless abandon!’: Guardian readers on their tastiest foolproof bakes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/throw-the-ingredients-together-with-reckless-abandon-guardian-readers-on-their-tastiest-foolproof-bakes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/throw-the-ingredients-together-with-reckless-abandon-guardian-readers-on-their-tastiest-foolproof-bakes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T10:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to rustle up something delicious that is guaranteed to work? Here are nine recipes to try
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Race for space’ fuels 10.9 % surge in UK house prices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/01/race-for-space-fuels-surge-in-uk-property-prices</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/01/race-for-space-fuels-surge-in-uk-property-prices"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T10:19:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nationwide puts annual rise at highest for seven years, with buyers looking for bigger homes and gardens
Younger house buyers are just as keen on building a new life in the country as they are to move to the bright lights of a big city as they react to the post-pandemic changes in working patterns and rapidly rising property prices.
Data released on Tuesday by the Nationwide building society showed that demand for property has pushed average house prices up 10.9% over the past year, the fastest pace for almost seven years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK ranked last in Europe for bathing water quality in 2020]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/01/uk-ranked-last-in-europe-for-bathing-water-quality-in-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/01/uk-ranked-last-in-europe-for-bathing-water-quality-in-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T10:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European Environment Agency judges only 110 British coastal and inland sites to be excellent
Swimmers in the UK hoping to enjoy waters certified clean and healthy this summer have been let down again. Only 110 coastal and inland sites were judged excellent in the latest bathing water quality data from Europe’s environmental watchdog.
Most of the UK’s bathing sites were not classified in 2020, however, because Covid-19 restrictions prevented sampling. This meant that out of 640 sites, 457 received no verdict in the rankings, compiled annually by the European Environment Agency and published on Tuesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden corporate tax plan could earn EU and UK billions, study shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/biden-corporate-tax-plan-could-earn-eu-and-uk-billions-study-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/biden-corporate-tax-plan-could-earn-eu-and-uk-billions-study-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:45:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EU forecast to reap extra €50bn per year with UK expected to gain €200m from BP alone
A proposal to be tabled by the US president, Joe Biden, at the upcoming G7 meeting for a 15% global corporate tax rate could reap the EU €50bn (£43bn) a year, and earn the UK nearly €200m extra alone from the British multinational BP, according to research.
Should the tax rate be set higher at 25%, the lowest current rate within the seven largest world economies, the EU would earn nearly €170bn extra a year – more than 50% of current corporate tax revenue and 12% of total health spending in the bloc.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your experience of Heathrow airport’s new ‘red list’ terminal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/share-your-experience-of-heathrow-airports-new-red-list-terminal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/share-your-experience-of-heathrow-airports-new-red-list-terminal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:43:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from travellers who have passed through Heathrow’s new dedicated terminal for arrivals from country’s on the UK’s coronavirus ‘red list’
From 1 June, passengers arriving in the UK from countries on the British ‘red list’ of destinations with a high risk of Covid-19 will pass through a separate terminal at London’s Heathrow airport.
Travellers arriving on direct flights from such a country will now transit through Terminal Three, in a bid to prevent the spread of new coronavirus variants in the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The baseball shirt: cultural icon and fashion accessory – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/01/the-baseball-shirt-cultural-icon-and-fashion-accessory-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/01/the-baseball-shirt-cultural-icon-and-fashion-accessory-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T08:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The evolution of the baseball shirt, on and off the field, and its journey from item of sportswear to emblem of American culture and catwalk regular, is charted in an exhibition opening 12 June at the Worcester Art Museum, MA. Covering 170 years of design, with an accompanying book by Erin R Corrales-Diaz – The Iconic Jersey: Baseball x Fashion is published by D Giles Ltd
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Gilbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From fantastic views to fox urine: the joys and perils of outdoor theatre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/01/the-joys-and-perils-of-outdoor-theatre</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/01/the-joys-and-perils-of-outdoor-theatre"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T07:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Faced with indoor restrictions, theatres are venturing outside, and creating thrilling work in the process. Brollies at the ready!

Modern Toss on the summer of culture to come

This summer, while indoor theatres reckon with stringent social distancing measures, some are combating Covid-19-related issues by taking things outdoors.
 Related: The Guide: Staying In – sign up for our home entertainment tips 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natasha Tripney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrant guards in Qatar ‘still paid under £1 an hour’ ahead of World Cup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/01/migrant-guards-in-qatar-still-paid-under-1-an-hour-ahead-of-world-cup</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/01/migrant-guards-in-qatar-still-paid-under-1-an-hour-ahead-of-world-cup"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T06:29:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Promises of better working conditions ring hollow for tens of thousands of security guards, who say they still work long hours for low pay
Every day at 5pm, Samuel boards the company bus that takes him to his night shift as a guard at a luxury high-rise tower near Qatar’s capital, Doha. When his shift ends 12 hours later, he says he will have earned £9, just 75p an hour.
Samuel, who is from Uganda, says he almost never has a day off. “You have to tell lies, like ‘you are sick, you’re not feeling good’, so that you get a day off,” he says.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pete Pattisson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diamond geysers: a cruise through Iceland – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/01/diamond-geysers-a-cruise-through-iceland-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/01/diamond-geysers-a-cruise-through-iceland-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T06:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jessica Auer moved to a small community in Iceland’s eastern fjords to photograph the tourist boom that some see as a blessing, others a curse
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I need a real person from BT to answer my urgent call]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/01/i-need-a-real-person-from-bt-to-answer-my-urgent-call</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/01/i-need-a-real-person-from-bt-to-answer-my-urgent-call"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An elderly neighbour’s alarm system is linked to a landline, but it is out of order
My 97-year-old neighbour has an alarm system supplied by social services linked to her landline. She has a fob she can press to summon help if she has a fall.
The problem is that her landline is out of order. I reported the fault to BT but found it impossible to speak to a real person. The automated system confirmed there was a fault on her line and promised an engineer would call – but only before midnight on a date four days away.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miles Brignall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tulsa race massacre, a century later: wounds still open and weeping]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/tulsa-race-massacre-a-century-later</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/01/tulsa-race-massacre-a-century-later"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T06:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 24 hours on 31 May 1921, Tulsa witnessed what is thought to be the worst single event of white supremacist violence against African Americans in the nation’s history

Tulsa massacre: act of terrorism America tried to forget

The full-page advert in a special Black History edition of USA Today presents a technicolor vision of modern-day Tulsa, with sparkling images of public parks and brightly painted murals celebrating the local Black community under the banner headline: “Tulsa Triumphs.”
“Tulsa is leading America’s journey to racial healing,” the text says, inviting visitors from across the US to sample the delights of Oklahoma’s second-largest city. The enticements include “an emotional opportunity for learning and reflection” and a “space for reconciliation … Tulsa triumphs, and you can be a part of this pilgrimage.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Pilkington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baby boy is first to receive £1.8m treatment for spinal muscular atrophy on NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/01/baby-boy-is-first-to-receive-18m-treatment-for-spinal-muscular-atrophy-on-nhs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/01/baby-boy-is-first-to-receive-18m-treatment-for-spinal-muscular-atrophy-on-nhs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arthur Morgan, who is five months old, was given the potentially life-saving one-off gene therapy called Zolgensma
A five-month-old baby has become the first patient in England treated with a potentially life-saving drug on the NHS that can prolong the lives of children with spinal muscular atrophy.
Arthur Morgan, who was diagnosed with the condition earlier this month, received the one-off gene therapy at Evelina London children’s hospital on 25 May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Press Association</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disaster patriarchy: how the pandemic has unleashed a war on women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/disaster-patriarchy-how-the-pandemic-has-unleashed-a-war-on-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/01/disaster-patriarchy-how-the-pandemic-has-unleashed-a-war-on-women"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid-19 has swept the world there has been an explosion of violence against women, and a full-blown assault on their rights. It’s time to fight back against a system that allows women to be sacrificed, erased and violated

Covid has unleashed the most severe setback to women’s liberation in my lifetime. While watching this happen, I have started to think we are witnessing an outbreak of disaster patriarchy.
Naomi Klein was the first to identify “disaster capitalism”, when capitalists use a disaster to impose measures they couldn’t possibly get away with in normal times, generating more profit for themselves. Disaster patriarchy is a parallel and complementary process, where men exploit a crisis to reassert control and dominance, and rapidly erase hard-earned women’s rights. All over the world, patriarchy has taken full advantage of the virus to reclaim power – on the one hand, escalating the danger and violence to women, and on the other, stepping in as their supposed controller and protector.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V (formerly Eve Ensler)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why every single statue should come down | Gary Younge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/01/gary-younge-why-every-single-statue-should-come-down-rhodes-colston</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/01/gary-younge-why-every-single-statue-should-come-down-rhodes-colston"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Statues of historical figures are lazy, ugly and distort history. From Cecil Rhodes to Rosa Parks, let’s get rid of them all

Having been a black leftwing Guardian columnist for more than two decades, I understood that I would be regarded as fair game for the kind of moral panics that might make headlines in rightwing tabloids. It’s not like I hadn’t given them the raw material. In the course of my career I’d written pieces with headlines such as “Riots are a class act”, “Let’s have an open and honest conversation about white people” and “End all immigration controls”. I might as well have drawn a target on my back. But the only time I was ever caught in the tabloids’ crosshairs was not because of my denunciations of capitalism or racism, but because of a statue – or to be more precise, the absence of one.
The story starts in the mid-19th century, when the designers of Trafalgar Square decided that there would be one huge column for Horatio Nelson and four smaller plinths for statues surrounding it. They managed to put statues on three of the plinths before running out of money, leaving the fourth one bare. A government advisory group, convened in 1999, decided that this fourth plinth should be a site for a rotating exhibition of contemporary sculpture. Responsibility for the site went to the new mayor of London, Ken Livingstone.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gary Younge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refugee women and children ‘at risk of being abandoned’ in Home Office policy shift]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/refugee-women-and-children-at-risk-of-being-abandoned-in-home-office-policy-shift</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/01/refugee-women-and-children-at-risk-of-being-abandoned-in-home-office-policy-shift"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two-thirds who have been accepted as refugees would have been turned away under proposed changes, data shows
Thousands of women and child refugees will be abandoned if the government’s New Plan for Immigration goes ahead, according to research.
If agreed by parliament, the rules would mean that most people who would currently be accepted as refugees – meaning those confirmed to have fled war or persecution following rigorous official checks – would no longer have their rights recognised in the UK due to their method of arrival. Half of those would be women and children.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diane Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Rylance: arts should tell ‘love stories’ about nature to tackle climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/01/mark-rylance-arts-should-tell-love-stories-about-nature-to-tackle-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/01/mark-rylance-arts-should-tell-love-stories-about-nature-to-tackle-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: actor says individuals rather than government should lead way as he launches wetlands drama
Sir Mark Rylance has called on the arts to help solve the climate crisis by telling stories that persuade people to “fall in love with nature again” and prompt government to back green policies. 
The Oscar-winning actor is starring with Sophie Okonedo in an innovative BBC Radio 4 drama set in a nature reserve that charts the challenges conservationists face in a time of rapid environmental change.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tara Conlan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travellers on UK border controls: ‘I’ve noticed a change of attitude’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/travellers-on-uk-border-controls-ive-noticed-a-change-of-attitude</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/01/travellers-on-uk-border-controls-ive-noticed-a-change-of-attitude"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers share their views on how things are different since the end of freedom of movement with the EU

Detained, fingerprinted, treated with hostility and suspicion: are EU citizens right to be concerned about entry to the UK? Many have written to us to share their views and experiences of the border. 
 Related: I miss my French in-laws, but the new UK border rules mean they may be too scared to visit | Emma Beddington 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll Brexit correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logical Fallacies – Definition and Fallacy Examples]]></title>
        <id>607f5fafdd38b9088c2bd0c9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/logical-fallacies-definition-fallacy-examples/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T04:19:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're debating someone, you want to use all the resources at your disposal to convince them you're right. But you should be careful that you don't end up using a logical fallacy to help you make your point. What is a Logical Fallacy?A logical fallacy is an error]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Tokyo really host a pandemic Olympics?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/01/will-tokyo-really-host-pandemic-olympic-games-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/01/will-tokyo-really-host-pandemic-olympic-games-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T02:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Games were meant to be a moment of national celebration but – with coronavirus cases rising in Japan – this summer’s postponed Olympics are the subject of recrimination and protest. Can widespread public opposition overcome huge commercial pressure to go ahead?
When Tokyo’s bid to host the Olympics succeeded eight years ago, a supportive public expected the 2020 Games to be a moment of national unity – and, after the Fukushima nuclear disaster, a declaration that the country was open for business. Instead, the coronavirus pandemic forced a delay to 2021.
With the rearranged Games due to take place in less than two months the expected respite from the pandemic has not materialised, and with vaccination rates in Japan stubbornly low, polls suggest that as much as 80% of the public wants to see them postponed again or even called off. Justin McCurry, the Guardian’s Tokyo correspondent, tells Anushka Asthana why the movement to cancel the Games is facing an uphill battle in the face of vast financial pressure to go ahead.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Justin McCurry; produced by Joshua Kelly and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australian fashion week: Romance Was Born remake and upcycle – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/01/australian-fashion-week-romance-was-born-remake-and-upcycle-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/01/australian-fashion-week-romance-was-born-remake-and-upcycle-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T22:40:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the rest of the world decluttered and reimagined ways of doing things, fashion design due Anna Plunkett and Luke Sales of Romance Was Born were doing exactly the same. Over the past 18 months, the pair have been working through boxes of remanent fabric and vintage finds from their studio. On 31 May, they debuted the result at Australian fashion week: two collections constructed almost entirely from dead stock, vintage pieces and other treasures that have piled up over their 16 years in business.
‘I joke that Anna is a bit of a hoarder,’ says Sales. ‘It’s ... a sentimental way of holding on to something. So if we’ve ever used something in the past and there’s been a scrap of something beaded, Anna has always put it away … kept it stashed for the right time.
‘During Covid we had the time. That was the right time.’
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Photography by Jessica Hromas and words by Alyx Gorman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU’s greenhouse gas emissions fell by nearly 4% in 2019, data shows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/eus-greenhouse-gas-emissions-fell-in-2019-data-shows</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/eus-greenhouse-gas-emissions-fell-in-2019-data-shows"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:11:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fall of 3.8% for member states brought emissions to 24% below 1990 levels
The EU’s greenhouse gas emissions fell by nearly 4% in 2019, data from Europe’s environmental watchdog has shown, as countries met online for the first time in UN climate negotiations.
The fall of 3.8% for EU member states in 2019 brought EU emissions to 24% below 1990 levels – or 26% if carbon sinks are taken into account – according to the European Environment Agency.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Human-induced global heating ‘causes over a third of heat deaths’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/human-induced-global-heating-causes-over-third-heat-deaths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/31/human-induced-global-heating-causes-over-third-heat-deaths"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T15:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between 1991 and 2018, human activity contributed to 37% of all heat-related deaths in locations studied
More than a third of all heat-related deaths around the world between 1991 and 2018 can be attributed to human-induced global heating, research has found.
Climate breakdown has a range of effects ranging from wildfires to extreme weather. As the temperatures rise, more intense and frequent heatwaves disproportionately affect elderly people and those with underlying chronic conditions such as asthma, making them more vulnerable to disease and premature death.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[1921 Tulsa race massacre remembered – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/may/31/1921-tulsa-race-massacre-remembered-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2021/may/31/1921-tulsa-race-massacre-remembered-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T08:18:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the darkest chapters in the long and turbulent history of racial violence in America is commemorated in Oklahoma on Monday, the 100th anniversary of a rampage by a white mob that left an estimated 300 Black people dead. Hundreds of Black-owned businesses, churches and homes were burned, leaving about 8,000 homeless and a further 800 injured
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brandon Bell/Getty Images</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An act of terrorism America tried to forget – 360 video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T07:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This video is best viewed on YouTube. Click here.
On the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, artist Bayeté Ross Smith uses archival photos to create immersive 360 scenes of these events. He finds that the underlying political and economic injustices were not only never addressed, but repeated time and again over the past century.
This story was suppressed from history books and the white perpetrators were never held accountable. And it wasn't just Tulsa. Dozens of other racial terrorism events from 1917 to 1921 have also gone untold, even within the victims' families. 

This is part one of Red Summers, a 360 video series by artist and filmmaker Bayeté Ross Smith on the untold American history of racial terrorism from 1917 to 1921. The project is funded by Black Public Media, Eyebeam, Sundance Institute, Crux XR and the Open Society Foundations.

Read more

Essay: It was among the worst acts of violence in US history, and no one was held accountable – how much has changed in the last 100 years?
‘The loss is incalculable’: descendants of the Tulsa massacre on what was stolen from them 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bayeté Ross Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pure poetry: Ralph Fiennes on stage – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/31/pure-poetry-ralph-fiennes-on-stage-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/31/pure-poetry-ralph-fiennes-on-stage-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T05:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Ralph Fiennes tours his solo stage version of TS Eliot’s Four Quartets, look back at some of his greatest stage performances, from Shaw and Shakespeare to The Play What I Wrote
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can the US avoid another Trump?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/31/can-the-us-avoid-another-trump-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/31/can-the-us-avoid-another-trump-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T02:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Obama adviser Ben Rhodes has travelled the world looking for clues to how the US came to elect Donald Trump and he found parallels everywhere. But is there a way of stopping it from happening again?
When Donald Trump won the US election in 2016 it upturned the assumptions of many in America about who was electable to the highest office in the land. It seemed obvious to many that Trump would lose to Hillary Clinton and yet he won a stunning victory. 
For the former Obama aide Ben Rhodes it was a moment to take stock and search for clues as to how it could have happened. He tells Anushka Asthana that his quest took him around the world to countries that had elected their own ‘strongman’ leaders. He asks what lessons can be learned to avoid another Trump-style presidency?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Ben Rhodes; produced by Alice Fordham and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Secure Your Android App – Four Security Best Practices Every Android Dev Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60b08d8811ffb70827ef8c7b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-secure-your-android-app/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've been following the news lately, you may have noticed a worrisome tech trend. The frequency and severity of cybersecurity attacks are exploding.  We've seen news of a sprawling hack involving the SolarWinds management platform. That attack may have compromised the systems of over 18,000 SolarWinds customers.  Then,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Computer Vision with Python]]></title>
        <id>60b0de2211ffb70827ef8d7c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/advanced-computer-vision-with-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T12:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More and more applications are using computer vision these days. We just published a full course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help you learn advanced computer vision using Python. You will learn state of the art computer vision techniques by building five projects with libraries such as]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you in a platonic marriage or a similar relationship?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T09:13:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from couples who have got married as a celebration of deep friendship rather than romance
Although legislation around marriage has changed over the last 10 years – from the introduction of same sex marriage to civil partnerships being extended to heterosexual couples – what has remained the same is the idea that marriage is for two parties romantically involved in each other. 
However, across Europe and America, the beginnings of a trend seem to be emerging: platonic marriage. This is where two parties get married as a celebration of deep friendship, rather than romance, and where their best friend is their significant other with whom they are building a life (eg. raising children).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A state-sponsored ‘hijacking’ – the arrest of Belarus blogger Raman Pratasevich]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T02:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova examines why Alexander Lukashenko, the president of Belarus, apparently diverted a Ryanair flight in order to arrest 26-year-old blogger Raman Pratasevich. Guardian Moscow correspondent, Andrew Roth, discusses the fallout from the action
Anushka Asthana talks to the Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova about the 26-year-old opposition blogger Raman Pratasevich and his 23-year-old girlfriend, Sofia Sapega. On Sunday their Ryanair flight, which was meant to be flying to Lithuania, was forced to make an emergency landing in Minsk and they were arrested. Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, the Belarusian opposition leader, told the European parliament on Wednesday that Lukashenko was “turning the country into the North Korea of Europe: non-transparent, unpredictable and dangerous”.
Anushka also talks to the Guardian’s Moscow correspondent Andrew Roth about the international reaction to what has been called a ‘state-sponsored hijacking’. The British government has told all UK planes to cease flying over Belarus, while the EU has imposed new economic sanctions. Kremlin officials have offered only muted support over the incident.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hanna Liubakova and Andrew Roth, produced by Marilyn Rust and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve Machine Learning Model Performance by Combining Categorical Features]]></title>
        <id>60af931811ffb70827ef85d3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-machine-learning-model-performance-by-combining-categorical-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're training a machine learning model, you can have some features in your dataset that represent categorical values. Categorical features are types of data that you can divide into groups. There are three common categorical data types: Ordinal – a set of values in ascending or descending order. Example: rating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make a Bouncing Basketball in Unity with Materials and Textures 🏀]]></title>
        <id>60a325c6906c5207e3a7da25</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-a-basketball-in-unity-with-materials-and-textures/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll teach you how to make a basketball using materials and textures in Unity. You can extend this micro-concept to create any kind of ball like a football, tennis ball, or snooker balls.  That said, these techniques aren't just limited to creating round 3D objects like balls.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From drag queens to hairdressers: how does it feel to welcome back customers post-lockdown?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/all-in-all-together/2021/may/14/good-to-see-you-businesses-on-welcoming-back-customers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/all-in-all-together/2021/may/14/good-to-see-you-businesses-on-welcoming-back-customers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four business owners tell us how they’ve managed to open safely and welcome their customers back
Even before the Covid-19 pub closures were officially announced, Burnett and his team had made the difficult decision to shut up shop. “We’re best known in Cardiff as a cabaret venue for the LGBT+ scene,” he says. “Even before lockdown, people were starting to get nervous about Covid and were staying away, so I knew we’d have to close.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interviews by Sophie Goddard and Jenny Stallard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin and the city: why your serum needs to protect against urban living]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollution, ultraviolet radiation and cigarette smoke can all cause havoc on our skin – but it doesn’t have to. Here’s how to guard your skin from everyday threats
Our skin is the body’s largest organ and works especially hard to cope with the demands of urban living, protecting your body against the impact of free radical-forming ultraviolet (UV) radiation, pollution and cigarette smoke. Dr Ifeoma Ejikeme, dermatologist and founder of Adonia Medical Clinic, says: “Damage to the skin by free radical or reactive oxygen species can include hyperpigmentation, prominent appearance of pores, dull-looking skin and eventually fine lines and premature ageing.”
These skin stressors, combined with the added dermatological strain after months of life in lockdown – being indoors with the central heating on, anxiety and lack of sleep – can also leave the skin looking dull and prone to blemishes. A good night’s rest, meditation, a balanced diet and regular exercise can all help with internalised stress and anxiety, but what about the effects of pollution on the skin?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ateh Jewel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>