<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-30T01:15:28.261Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-30T01:15:28.261Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.9.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gavin MacLeod, The Love Boat’s Captain Stubing, dies aged 90]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/gavin-macleod-the-love-boats-captain-stubing-dies-aged-90</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/30/gavin-macleod-the-love-boats-captain-stubing-dies-aged-90"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T00:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MacLeod, also known for the Mary Tyler Moore Show, died at his home in California
Gavin MacLeod, the actor who achieved fame as sardonic TV news writer Murray Slaughter on the Mary Tyler Moore Show and cheerful Captain Stubing on The Love Boat, has died aged 90.
MacLeod died early Saturday at his home in Palm Desert, California, said Stephanie Steele Zalin, his stepdaughter. She attributed his death to his age, saying he had been well until very recently.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kumbh Mela: how a superspreader festival seeded Covid across India]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/kumbh-mela-how-a-superspreader-festival-seeded-covid-across-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/30/kumbh-mela-how-a-superspreader-festival-seeded-covid-across-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T00:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From across India, millions of Hindu pilgrims came to take a ritual dip in the Ganges, then returned home carrying Covid-19. Here are their stories 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

On 12 April, as India registered another 169,000 new Covid-19 cases to overtake Brazil as the second-worst hit country, three million people gathered on the shores of the Ganges.
They were there, in the ancient city of Haridwar in the state of Uttarakhand, to take a ritual dip in the holy river. The bodies, squashed together in a pack of devotion and religious fervour, paid no visible heed to Covid protocols.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Ellis-Petersen  and Aakash Hassan in Delhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for protection on Covid loan debts as the bounce-back payback begins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/call-for-protection-on-covid-loan-debts-as-the-bounce-back-payback-begins</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/30/call-for-protection-on-covid-loan-debts-as-the-bounce-back-payback-begins"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T23:05:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MPs fear that, without regulation, pressure on banks to recover cash could lead to a run of bankruptcies
More than 1.5 million small businesses across the UK are gearing up to return some £47bn in government-backed Covid credit from this week, as the first tranche of bounce-back loans fall due.
Lenders have pledged to treat customers fairly, while doing their best to avoid triggering government guarantees that could cost the taxpayer billions of pounds. But campaigners say banks may find it difficult to do right by struggling borrowers, given the pressure to recover cash.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Walden review – Gemma Arterton’s sister act reaches for the stars]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/29/walden-review-harold-pinter-theatre-london-gemma-arterton-amy-berryman</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/29/walden-review-harold-pinter-theatre-london-gemma-arterton-amy-berryman"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:59:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harold Pinter theatre, London
Arterton plays a former Nasa employee whose astronaut twin descends on her wilderness retreat in Amy Berryman’s intelligent, soulful drama
Twin sisters with a fractious history are planning a reunion at the start of Amy Berryman’s play. “We have to act happy,” says Stella to her fiance before her twin has arrived, and the anxious statement prepares us for the unfolding drama of sisterly competition and grudge.
But the first in Sonia Friedman’s Re:Emerge series at the Harold Pinter theatre is not just a psychodrama of spiky sisterhood but an original play of ideas that takes in everything from the ethics of space endeavour to climate activism and the pull between duty, ambition and desire.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arifa Akbar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We love: Fashion fixes for the week ahead – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:55:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Halle Berry’s debut fitness line with Sweaty Betty, SMR Day’s Road Trip collection, and Artist David Shrigley’s artworks on phone cases
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holy moly: 10 of the best crochet pieces – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/holy-moly-10-of-the-best-crochet-pieces-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/holy-moly-10-of-the-best-crochet-pieces-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get ready for the new summer of love and crochet yourself back to the chic 1970s
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Jones and Helen Seamons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer shoes: 25 of the best flat sandals – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/summer-shoes-25-of-the-best-flat-sandals-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/may/29/summer-shoes-25-of-the-best-flat-sandals-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:45:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you don’t want to step out in heels, these flats are the height of fashion
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bevan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City 0-1 Chelsea: player ratings from the Champions League final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/manchester-city-0-1-chelsea-player-ratings-champions-league-final</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/manchester-city-0-1-chelsea-player-ratings-champions-league-final"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:13:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kai Havertz and N’Golo Kanté thrived, helped immeasurably by Fernandinho’s absence from City’s starting lineup
Ederson The Brazilian denied Werner but was left exposed by his defence when Havertz gave Chelsea the lead. His challenge wasn’t enough to save City. 6
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Steinberg at the Estádio do Dragão</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-vaccine passport protesters storm Westfield mall in London]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/anti-vaccine-passport-protesters-occupy-westfield-mall-in-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/anti-vaccine-passport-protesters-occupy-westfield-mall-in-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T22:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping centre in Shepherd’s Bush had to shut after hundreds of marchers arrived chanting ‘no more lockdowns’
Hundreds of anti-vaccine passport protesters invaded the Westfield shopping centre in Shepherd’s Bush on Saturday evening at the culmination of a mass march that drew many thousands and snaked miles through central and west London.
There were tussles with police who tried to block access through one entrance to the shopping centre at about 6pm, before protesters quickly realised that another door just yards away was unguarded.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Gayle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chaotic conductor Pep Guardiola sees his Champions League dream fall apart | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/pep-guardiola-champions-league-final-fall-apart-manchester-city</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/pep-guardiola-champions-league-final-fall-apart-manchester-city"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T21:12:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manchester City’s manager – the defining tactical brain of his age – picked a team that malfunctioned and looked muddled 
At the final whistle in the Estádio do Dragão, as the air whooshed out through the stadium roof and the night sky crackled with a weird, irresistible energy, Pep Guardiola wandered off into a patch of green space and stood watching.
He edged away from the capering figures skirting him tactfully like a hazard in a water course. He ran a hand over his gleaming skull, oddly tender in all that noise and light.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay at the Estádio do Dragão</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea win Champions League after Kai Havertz stuns Manchester City]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/manchester-city-chelsea-champions-league-final-match-report-kai-havertz</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/manchester-city-chelsea-champions-league-final-match-report-kai-havertz"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T20:57:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Thomas Tuchel was given the job of reviving Chelsea at the end of January, he wanted to return them to next season’s Champions League via a top-four Premier League finish. The notion that he might actually win the thing for only the second time in the club’s history was ludicrous.
Not any more. On a night of glory for him and his team, the manager applied the final brush strokes to his renaissance masterpiece, out-manoeuvring his friend and rival, Pep Guardiola, and watching Kai Havertz score the decisive goal just before half-time.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner at the  Estádio do Dragão</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson and Carrie Symonds reportedly marry in secret ceremony]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/boris-johnson-and-carrie-symonds-reportedly-marry-in-secret-ceromony</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/boris-johnson-and-carrie-symonds-reportedly-marry-in-secret-ceromony"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T20:39:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pair exchanged vows at Westminster Cathedral on Saturday, according to newspapers
Boris Johnson has reportedly married Carrie Symonds today at Westminster Cathedral in a ceremony planned in strict secrecy, according to newspapers.
The pair are said to have exchanged vows in front of a small group of close friends and family, the Mail on Sunday and the Sun newspaper have reported.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Wrong and un-American’: Biden blasts Texas Republicans’ SB7 voting bill]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/wrong-un-american-biden-republicans-texas-sb7-voting-rights-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/wrong-un-american-biden-republicans-texas-sb7-voting-rights-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T20:38:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Governor has said he will sign restrictive voting bill
President laments effects on ‘Black and brown Americans’

Joe Biden has condemned as “wrong and un-American” a Texas state bill set to pass into law which the president said “attacks the sacred right to vote”, particularly among minorities.
 Related: ‘A ticking timebomb’: Democrats’ push for voting rights law faces tortuous path 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly, Victoria Bekiempis and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The psychologists signing up for psychedelic therapy training: ‘Amazing things can happen’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/the-psychologists-signing-up-for-psychedelic-therapy-training-amazing-things-can-happen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/30/the-psychologists-signing-up-for-psychedelic-therapy-training-amazing-things-can-happen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T20:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The global renaissance of psychedelic drugs in the treatment of mental health gains further legitimacy in Australia as psychologists sign up for clinical trials
When growing up in Yea, in rural Victoria, Campbell Townsend took a dim view of drugs.
“My parents were born in the shadow of Nixon’s war on drugs, and I was a very simple country boy,” the psychologist says, sitting in his cottage outside Castlemaine. “I grew up with stories from my parents about friends of theirs at university going crazy just from one choof of a bong.”
Townsend’s fears persisted until he read journalist Michael Pollan’s 2018 book, How to Change Your Mind: The New Science of Psychedelics. The book found favour in the most mainstream of media, from Time magazine to The Late Show with Stephen Colbert, and became a New York Times No 1 best-seller as the so-called renaissance in psychedelic research took hold around the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenny Valentish</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How they stay together: what 68 long-term couples taught me about love]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/how-they-stay-together-what-68-long-term-couples-taught-me-about-love</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/30/how-they-stay-together-what-68-long-term-couples-taught-me-about-love"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T20:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a farewell letter, How We Stay Together columnist Alexandra Spring shares the three ingredients to an enduring relationship
“There were times when I think we could have come close to splitting,” says academic David Christian. Author Chardi Christian, his wife of 50 years, nods. “[But] we worked hard at not [splitting],” says David, “and in fact I think we both really didn’t want to split.”
Being in a relationship that endures is something many people aspire to – the romantic ideal of having someone to accompany you through life’s countless ups and downs. And research shows there are very real benefits to being in a successful long-term relationship: couples who stay together are healthier, wealthier, happier, having more sex and living longer than their solo peers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Spring</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Eaton, NBA shot-blocking king and Utah Jazz legend, dies aged 64]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/mark-eaton-dead-utah-jazz-bike-accident</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/mark-eaton-dead-utah-jazz-bike-accident"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T19:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eaton dies at hospital after apparent bike accident on Friday
Jazz center was twice named NBA’s defensive player of the year

Mark Eaton, the 7ft 4in shot-blocking king who twice was the NBA’s defensive player of the year during a career spent entirely with the Utah Jazz, has died. He was 64.
The Jazz said that police said Eaton was found lying in the road around 8.30pm Friday after an apparent bike accident in Summit County, Utah. The Summit County Sheriff’s Office said that Eaton was taken to a hospital, where he later died, and that there was no reason to believe a vehicle was involved in the accident, according to the team.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian sport and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Masked Dancer review: a ludicrous waste of time – but oh so much fun]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/29/the-masked-dancer-review-a-ludicrous-waste-of-time-but-oh-so-much-fun</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/29/the-masked-dancer-review-a-ludicrous-waste-of-time-but-oh-so-much-fun"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T19:30:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Masked Singer judges are back, this time tasked with finding out which celebrity is strutting their stuff in a beetroot costume. It’s thoroughly silly, but you’ll surely be hooked
The Masked Singer usually occupies that lovely Saturday teatime slot that suits mindless television blessed with a touch of the surreal. That slot is why I have spent the past few weeks engrossed in I Can See Your Voice, wondering if a prison officer is lip-syncing to his own voice or not. Now that everyone is doing singing-based guessing games, The Masked Singer – as if bored with its own invention – has briefly transformed into The Masked Dancer (ITV). Over seven episodes starting tonight, celebrities will dress up in elaborate costumes and perform dance routines, while a panel of other celebrities will suggest that an A-list Hollywood star is the one galavanting around on stage in a glittery costume of a root vegetable.
I love The Masked Singer, despite recognising that it is a colossal waste of time, simply because it is so good-natured and ridiculous. Few could have guessed there would be any difficulty involved in guessing some of the participants by their voices, especially when those participants were famous singers. But it proved harder than it looked. You could think: that is definitely Gabrielle, then second-guess that it would be far too easy if it were Gabrielle; the whole thing would unravel, until the mask came off and of course it was Gabrielle after all.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tennessee hat shop in storm over ‘not vaccinated’ Star of David badges]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/tennessee-hat-shop-not-vaccinated-badges-star-of-david</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/tennessee-hat-shop-not-vaccinated-badges-star-of-david"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T19:07:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HatWRKS was slammed on social media as antisemitic and ‘disgusting’ after which the post was deleted
A hat shop in Nashville, Tennessee that reportedly sold “Not Vaccinated” badges resembling the yellow Star of David which Jewish people were forced to wear by the Nazis has removed a post promoting the item, following extensive criticism online.
 Related: ‘Tyranny’: Idaho governor repeals lieutenant’s mask mandate ban 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Bekiempis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We faced an unprecedented crisis, but tens of thousands of second wave Covid deaths were avoidable – and unforgivable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/we-faced-an-unprecedented-crisis-but-tens-of-thousands-of-second-wave-covid-deaths-were-avoidable-and-unforgivable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/we-faced-an-unprecedented-crisis-but-tens-of-thousands-of-second-wave-covid-deaths-were-avoidable-and-unforgivable"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T19:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson has shown a reluctance to take difficult decisions, with deadly consequences, the Labour leader writes
Keir Starmer: Johnson’s botches could hit lockdown lifting

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Behind the allegations and the noise this week are some simple truths. We have the worst coronavirus death toll in Europe. And over two thirds of deaths were in the second wave. That’s not hearsay. It’s not opinion. It’s fact.
Behind all the political drama is one more fact. The most important of all. That 128,000 families are grieving, now wondering whether their loved ones died needlessly.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keir Starmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer: Boris Johnson’s chaos could hit June plan to lift lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/keir-starmer-boris-johnsons-chaos-could-hit-june-plan-to-lift-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/keir-starmer-boris-johnsons-chaos-could-hit-june-plan-to-lift-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T19:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour leader slams Tory ‘civil war’ and says prime minister is ‘unfit for office after errors’

Opinion: Thousands of second-wave Covid deaths were avoidable and unforgivable | Keir Starmer

Labour leader Keir Starmer today warns that plans to lift almost all Covid-19 restrictions on 21 June are at risk because of serial incompetence and “civil war” inside Boris Johnson’s government.
In his strongest attack for months on the prime minister’s handling of the pandemic, Starmer says that the huge death toll in the second wave of cases from last autumn, in which more than 80,000 lives were lost, was “avoidable and unforgivable” and the result of a failure to learn lessons from the early stages of the crisis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm, Robin McKie, Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yorkshire on back foot in Roses match, Essex beat Durham: county cricket – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2021/may/29/lancashire-v-yorkshire-durham-v-essex-and-more-county-cricket-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/live/2021/may/29/lancashire-v-yorkshire-durham-v-essex-and-more-county-cricket-live"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T18:28:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The champions Essex thrashed Durham by 195 runs in a match that included a record 19 LBWs
 7.57pm BST 
His shadow lolling out to the right, a white flannel tucked into the waistband of his trousers and his cropped hair gleaming in the sun, Lancashire’s Matt Parkinson ripped a ball into the rough. Out it fizzed, and Adam Lyth guided the ball off his hip and into the waiting hands of Luke Wells at leg slip. The first “Oh Lanky Lanky” since 2019 trilled over Old Trafford as Lyth stalked towards the dressing room.
Seven overs later, the penultimate of the day, Saqib Mahmood hurtled in off his long, long run and pinned Tom Kohler-Cadmore in front of the stumps. Mahmood punched the air while Kohler-Cadmore slumped back off, followed shortly afterwards by a clatter that sounded very much like a bat being thumped repeatedly against a wall.
 7.28pm BST 
What a final last hour that was at Old Trafford! I felt for the Yorkies, they’d battled so hard, shown such restraint - but Parky and Mahmood proved irresistible. Cracking days elsewhere, and a great win for Essex in the lbw-party at The Riverside. I’m bushed, time for a nice glass of something cold. Till tomorrow, goodnight!
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanya Aldred at Old Trafford</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cornwall officials urge tourists to ‘engage brains’ after car swept into sea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/cornwall-officials-urge-tourists-to-engage-brains-after-car-swept-into-sea</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/cornwall-officials-urge-tourists-to-engage-brains-after-car-swept-into-sea"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T18:22:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Family car washed away at high tide near St Agnes after driver became stuck on a steep slipway while doing a three-point turn
Bemused residents and tourism officials in Cornwall have urged visitors to “engage their brains” after a family car got washed into the sea near St Agnes.
In the second such incident at Trevaunance Cove in the past eight months, the vehicle was swept away at high tide after the driver got stuck on a steep slipway while doing a three-point turn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonny Weeks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[He came. He spoke. But what will Cummings’s explosive claims mean?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/he-came-he-spoke-but-what-will-cummingss-explosive-claims-mean</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/he-came-he-spoke-but-what-will-cummingss-explosive-claims-mean"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T18:18:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tories have closed ranks against the PM’s aide. But privately, many know the party is living in fear of further bombshells

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

After more than two and a half hours of extraordinary testimony from Dominic Cummings to a Commons committee last Wednesday morning, Greg Clark, the former cabinet minister who had chaired the explosive morning session, called a short lunch break. He and his co-chair – the former health secretary Jeremy Hunt – had, like the other 20 MPs who were due to ask questions, been left stunned, appalled and riveted in equal measure by what they had just heard.
Expectations had been set high in advance of the appearance of the highly combustible Cummings. The ex-adviser had been forced out of Downing Street last November in a power struggle that had involved the prime minister’s fiancee, Carrie Symonds. Downing Street was on edge because Cummings had been firing off ominous preparatory salvoes on Twitter for days. But after a morning in the witness chair he had already exceeded his billing, unleashing accusations of such gravity that at times the MPs (and presumably much of the public watching on TV) found it all but impossible to keep up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm and Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Frank hopes Brentford’s promotion helps other clubs to dream]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/thomas-frank-hopes-brentford-promotion-helps-other-clubs-to-dream-championship-playoff-swansea</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/29/thomas-frank-hopes-brentford-promotion-helps-other-clubs-to-dream-championship-playoff-swansea"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T18:08:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frank says club’s journey ‘is absolutely unbelievable’
Swansea manager Cooper says defeat can galvanise club

Thomas Frank said Brentford’s fairytale promotion to the Premier League should encourage clubs across the world to dare to dream, after they returned to the top flight for the first time in 74 years. Brentford’s victory over Swansea City in the Championship play‑off final is worth £178m but Frank said they will not stray from their shrewd data-led philosophy.
“The journey the club has been on is absolutely unbelievable,” the manager said of a club who were in the third tier in 2014 and the fourth tier in 2009. “A lot of credit should go to [the owner] Matthew Benham.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher at Wembley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients were sent back to care homes without Covid test despite bosses’ plea]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/patients-were-sent-back-to-care-homes-without-covid-test-despite-bosses-plea</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/patients-were-sent-back-to-care-homes-without-covid-test-despite-bosses-plea"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T18:01:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure piles up on Matt Hancock after managers say they felt ‘abandoned’ by health ministry in first wave
Thousands of hospital patients were allowed to return to their care homes without a Covid test despite a direct plea to the government from major care providers not to allow the practice, the Observer has been told.
As the crisis began to unfold in early March 2020, providers held an emergency meeting with department of health officials in which they urged the government not to force them to accept untested residents. However, weeks later, official advice remained that tests were not mandatory and thousands of residents are thought to have returned to their homes without a negative Covid result.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage and James Tapper</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of Brazilians march to demand Bolsonaro’s impeachment]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/tens-of-thousands-of-brazilians-march-to-demand-bolsonaros-impeachment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/tens-of-thousands-of-brazilians-march-to-demand-bolsonaros-impeachment"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:59:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protests in over 200 cities and towns in Brazil sparked by president’s handling of the Covid pandemic

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Tens of thousands of protesters have poured on to the streets of Brazil’s largest cities to demand the impeachment of President Jair Bolsonaro over his catastrophic response to a coronavirus pandemic that has claimed nearly half a million Brazilian lives.
The demonstrators turned out in more than 200 cities and towns for what is the biggest anti-Bolsonaro mobilisation since Brazil’s Covid outbreak began
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Phillips in Rio de Janeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fund for Covid victims memorial at St Paul’s hits £2.3m target]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/fund-for-covid-victims-memorial-at-st-pauls-hits-23m-target</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/fund-for-covid-victims-memorial-at-st-pauls-hits-23m-target"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:23:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Online book of remembrance with photographs and tributes will be created at the London cathedral

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A fundraiser to create a memorial in St Paul’s Cathedral for those who have died in the Covid-19 pandemic has reached its £2.3m goal in under a month.
An online book of remembrance will be installed in a portico structure within the London cathedral.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Macron seeks African reset with new view of France’s troubled history on continent]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/macron-tells-africas-leaders-he-seeks-to-reset-french-ties-with-the-continent</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/macron-tells-africas-leaders-he-seeks-to-reset-french-ties-with-the-continent"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:13:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Honest examination of French colonial record in Africa and responsibilty in Rwanda key to new strategy, though critics say little has changed
With the golden winter sun slanting across the palm trees and yellow sandstone, the scene was perfect. Emmanuel Macron and his host, Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa, walked down the red carpet of the Union buildings in Pretoria as the Marseillaise resonated through the clean, crisp air.
The historic setting was apt. Since taking power in 2017, the French president has sought a broad reset of national strategy, relations and intervention in Africa. He has chosen a very contemporary way to do this: by re-examining the past.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Burke in Pretoria</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Esther Freud: ‘I didn’t learn to read till I was about 10’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/29/esther-freud-i-couldnt-love-you-more-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/29/esther-freud-i-couldnt-love-you-more-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Hideous Kinky author on her childhood dyslexia, the frenzy around being a perfect mother, and why there are so few great female artists
Esther Freud is the author of nine novels, including Hideous Kinky, her semi-autobiographical debut, which tells of her unconventional childhood in Morocco. The daughter of Lucien Freud and Bernardine Coverley, she trained as an actor before becoming a novelist. Freud has three children with the actor David Morrissey, from whom she recently separated. I Couldn’t Love You More is the story of three generations of Irish women: Rosaleen, a heroic, headstrong teenager in the early 1960s who begins an affair with an older man; Aoife, her mother, who recounts her life to her dying husband and wonders what became of her flighty daughter; and Kate, in London, married to the useless Matt, trying to make it as an artist while looking after their daughter, Freya. The three lives intertwine and overlap over the course of the novel.
You say in the acknowledgments that I Couldn’t Love You More was inspired by your own mother, bringing up children unmarried and without the support of her family.
I didn’t start the book with the intention of telling that story. I was thinking how much I’d like to write a book where love was the main theme. So I started with a real rush of energy, writing about it from different points of view, three women from different generations. I began really playfully and freely, writing these short chapters. After a while I realised I needed a story and some kind of plot, and it was then that it occurred to me to think more about my mother and how extraordinary it was that she managed to have two children without her parents knowing, and what it was like to be in such an unsupported world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Preston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson and the emperor’s new PPE – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/29/boris-johnson-and-the-emperors-new-ppe-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/29/boris-johnson-and-the-emperors-new-ppe-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the bluster (and Matt Hancock), the prime minister is alarmingly exposed

You can buy your own print of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jimmy Anderson ready for New Zealand battle with eye on record England cap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/jimmy-anderson-ready-for-new-zealand-battle-with-eye-on-record-england-cap</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/jimmy-anderson-ready-for-new-zealand-battle-with-eye-on-record-england-cap"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seamer can equal mark of 161 caps if picked at Lord’s
‘To play this amount of games is … a bit mind-blowing’

Jimmy Anderson approaches the latest milestones of his record-breaking career with an acknowledgment of his good fortune regarding injury and an insistence that his preference has always been to do it the hard way.
Anderson’s 19th summer as a Test cricketer begins with him one cap from equalling Alastair Cook’s England record of 161, while a further eight wickets would make him the first English seamer to reach 1,000 first-class wickets since Andy Caddick in 2005.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The UK’s richest union is fighting in the courts, but not for the low paid | Nick Cohen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/unite-union-funding-legal-battles-low-paid-workers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/unite-union-funding-legal-battles-low-paid-workers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T17:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Covid threatens the jobs of millions, Unite is focused on factional divisions
Capital will stage a brutal demonstration of its power over labour when the furloughs and state protections of the Covid pandemic end. Across the west, but most particularly in the UK, employees’ ability to defend themselves will depend on whether they are in a trade union.
The new working class of young, female and ethnic minority workers in hotels, gyms, security guard huts, supermarkets, call centres, restaurants, shops and bars needs unions. Whatever pain is coming, precarious private sector workers will feel it the most. The labour movement must surely be concentrating its energies on helping radically insecure workers as the crisis approaches.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further unrest in Colombia as talks stall between government and protesters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/further-unrest-in-colombia-as-talks-stall-between-government-and-protesters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/further-unrest-in-colombia-as-talks-stall-between-government-and-protesters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:51:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-poverty demonstrators battle with police across the country as protests enter second month

Violent unrest continues to roil Colombia as anti-poverty demonstrations enter their second month and talks between protesters and the government stall.
A fresh spate of violence swept the South American nation on Friday night, with protesters battling police who attempted to lift roadblocks across the country.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Parkin Daniels in Bogotá</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncovered: the brutal secrets of UK deportation flight Esparto 11]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/asylum-seekers-risked-all-to-get-to-the-uk-then-they-were-deported-at-dawn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/asylum-seekers-risked-all-to-get-to-the-uk-then-they-were-deported-at-dawn"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:51:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On 12 August 2020 at 7.48am the first of a series of Home Office flights carrying asylum seekers left Stansted. This is the harrowing story of the hours before it took off and the anguish of those on board
At 7.15am, half an hour before charter flight Esparto 11 took off from Stansted airport, a detainee with a documented history of self-harm asked to use the plane’s bathroom. He was taken to the toilet by an escort working for the Home Office who held the door ajar with his foot and, after several minutes, peered inside to discover the detainee had slashed his wrist with a blade.
Pinning the man with his body weight to gain “control”, another officer squeezed into the bathroom and placed a handcuff on the wrist. According to an account written by officers, the handcuff was used to “[give] him pain”, a reference to a restraint technique which involves deliberately inflicting suffering to gain submission. In this case, most likely by twisting the cuff or pushing it into the wrist.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Walawalkar, Jessica Purkiss, Eleanor Rose and Mark Townsend</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four arrested at Dover anti-immigration protest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/arrests-at-dover-anti-immigration-protest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/arrests-at-dover-anti-immigration-protest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:40:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kent police say about 60 gathered in town centre and along sea front, causing traffic disruption
Police have arrested four people at an anti-immigration protest in the port of Dover.
About 60 people gathered in the town centre and along the sea front on Saturday, Kent police said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nasa releases new image that shows Milky Way’s energized ‘downtown’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/29/nasa-milky-way-image-downtown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/29/nasa-milky-way-image-downtown"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:31:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The picture is a composite of 370 observations made over the past two decades and depicts billions of stars and black holes
Nasa has released a stunning new picture of our galaxy’s violent, super-energized “downtown”.
 Related: Manhattenhenge: miserable Memorial Day weather mars biannual fiery display 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ai Weiwei on colonialism and statues, Churchill, China and Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/29/ai-weiwei-on-colonialism-and-statues-churchill-china-and-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/29/ai-weiwei-on-colonialism-and-statues-churchill-china-and-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:09:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As his controversial Gilded Cage installation goes on display at Blenheim Palace, the artist and human rights campaigner reflects on the ‘complicated world’
From this week a seven-metre-high installation entitled Gilded Cage, by the exiled Chinese artist and human rights campaigner Ai Weiwei, will be on display at Blenheim Palace in Oxfordshire. The piece, originally constructed for Central Park in New York in 2017, was made as a reflection on the worldwide refugee crisis. Ai Weiwei, 64, is currently based in Lisbon. This conversation took place last week by phone.
Tell me a little bit about Gilded Cage. How did it come about?
I made it not long after I came out of China after four or five years of detention. I was researching migrants in Europe to make a film [Human Flow, 2018] and the Public Art Fund in New York City asked me to do a project. The golden cage was not far from Trump Tower, maybe three blocks away. It looks like a bird cage and it is double layered so that the audience can go into it and see how the world looks from there.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A printmaker’s paean to moths – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/a-printmakers-paean-to-moths-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/a-printmakers-paean-to-moths-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British printmaker Sarah Gillespie was drawn to moths because they’re “overlooked and underloved”. Then she found out they’re in catastrophic decline: 50-60 species have become extinct in the past 80 years. 
So Gillespie has created a series of mezzotints, on show now at Castle Howard in Yorkshire, to highlight their existential plight. “We have done enormous damage to those we share the Earth with. The work of the artist is to pay attention – to refuse not to notice.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alice Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Johan Rockström: ‘We need bankers as well as activists… we have 10 years to cut emissions by half’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/johan-rockstrom-interview-breaking-boundaries-attenborough-biden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/johan-rockstrom-interview-breaking-boundaries-attenborough-biden"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The eminent Earth scientist argues that we cannot just wait for the world order to change when it comes to tackling the climate crisis – we all have a duty to act now
Johan Rockström is one of the world’s most influential Earth scientists. As director of the Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research, he advises governments, corporations and activists, including his Swedish compatriot, Greta Thunberg, about the latest research on the climate and biodiversity and argues for better science communication. Last year, he co-edited Standing Up for a Sustainable World, a book that brought together essays from climatologists, economists, environmental defenders, financiers and school strike activists. In recent months, he has teamed up with David Attenborough to create a new Netflix series, Breaking Boundaries: The Science of Our Planet, participated in President Joe Biden’s climate summit and co-organised a declaration by more than 100 Nobel laureates.
The Nobel prize summit in April declared a planetary emergency. Why now? Scientists have known for at least three decades that human activity is destabilising the climate and accelerating the collapse of ecosystems.
This statement, signed by 126 Nobel laureates, is a world record. Never before have we seen such a global uprising of Nobel prize winners. They issued an emergency call from science to humanity, calling for reason, truth and humanism in the transformation towards an equitable and prosperous future in a safe operating space.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Watts</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Of course Carrie Symonds loves Dilyn, so why mock her for that? | Barbara Ellen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/of-course-carrie-symonds-loves-dilyn-so-why-mock-her</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/of-course-carrie-symonds-loves-dilyn-so-why-mock-her"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PM’s fiancee was right to be upset at the suggestion she would abandon her rescue dog
While obviously not the most important takeaway from The Great Outpouring, Dominic Cummings really hates Carrie Symonds, doesn’t he? Understandable really. She took his best mate away. They were so close, but then she came along and Boris didn’t have time for him any more… Oh sorry, I appear to have segued into a half-remembered Byker Grove storyline – a “teaching moment” for schoolboy viewers about feeling left out when your mate gets a girlfriend. Only in the Westminster version, a pandemic is brewing and Cummings depicts Symonds “going crackers about something completely trivial” – a story claiming that Dilyn, the jack russell cross she rescued with Boris Johnson, was being “reshuffled”. Thing is, though, I understand why Symonds was upset and I rather like her for it.
Cummings clearly wanted to present Symonds as a Violet Elizabeth Bott figure, a preposterous, demanding drag on the prime minister’s focus at a critical moment. Admittedly, the now-leaked letter of complaint Symonds drafted to the Times is an overwrought belter, citing violations, demanding corrections and ending with the classic: “We look forward to hearing from you as a matter of urgency.” Elsewhere, never mind the first fiancee’s taste for swanky decor, stories abound about her pushing animal welfare agendas and exerting undue influence over No 10 hiring and firing. Still, when it comes to being a pandemic liability, I have two words for Cummings: “Barnard” and “Castle”. As for the letter, it’s an absurd, messy, emotional overreaction… and I completely relate.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barbara Ellen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Rayner demands detailed answers on Boris Johnson’s refurb]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/angela-rayner-demands-detailed-answers-on-boris-johnsons-refurb</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/angela-rayner-demands-detailed-answers-on-boris-johnsons-refurb"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T16:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Labour’s deputy leader says it is ‘scarcely believable’ PM did not know who funded work on flat
Labour has demanded that the full details of how Boris Johnson’s Downing Street flat renovation was funded are released after he was cleared of breaching the ministerial code.
Deputy leader Angela Rayner has written to Christopher Geidt, the independent adviser on ministers’ interests, after he ruled on Friday that the prime minister had not broken the rules. Lord Geidt found only that Johnson acted “unwisely” in allowing the refurbishment to go ahead without “more rigorous regard for how this would be funded”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Egan Bernal closes on Giro d’Italia victory while Caruso takes stage 20 win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/egan-bernal-closes-on-giro-ditalia-victory-damiano-caruso-takes-stage-20-win-cycling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/egan-bernal-closes-on-giro-ditalia-victory-damiano-caruso-takes-stage-20-win-cycling"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:50:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bernal enters Sunday’s final time trial with 1min 59sec cushion 
Caruso second after first Grand Tour win, with Simon Yates third

Egan Bernal stands on the verge of Giro d’Italia glory after surviving Saturday’s brutal mountain stage with almost two minutes of an advantage to take into the closing time trial in Milan.
Damiano Caruso, Bernal’s closest challenger in the general classification, celebrated a fine stage victory – his first individual Grand Tour stage win – to increase his hold on a surprise second place, but victory by 24 seconds was not the sort of margin needed to shake the Ineos Grenadiers rider.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ashleigh Barty and Iga Swiatek ready to start new era of dominance on clay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/ashleigh-barty-iga-swiatek-french-open-new-era-dominance-clay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/29/ashleigh-barty-iga-swiatek-french-open-new-era-dominance-clay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:16:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The two former French Open champions head to Roland Garros looking to ignite a rivalry that could last for years to come
There will be two defending champions in the women’s draw at the French Open this year. That is not normally how it works; when a player wins a title one year, they return to the scene of their success and try their hardest to hold on to it. Most fail.
Last year, however, as uncertainty swirled during the first waves of the pandemic, the world No 1, Ashleigh Barty, opted not to travel due to safety concerns and because national border closures in Australia meant she was unable to train with her coach. Instead, as the 19-year-old Iga Swiatek demolished the field to win her first grand slam title, Barty spent her days cheering on her Aussie Rules football team, Richmond, with a beer in her hand.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manhattenhenge: miserable Memorial Day weather mars biannual fiery display]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/manhattenhenge-miserable-memorial-day-weather-mars-biannual-fiery-display</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/manhattenhenge-miserable-memorial-day-weather-mars-biannual-fiery-display"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:06:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forecasts of record cold temperatures produce clouds and rain in New York City, meaning fans of the sight will have to wait until July
Manhattanhenge, a spectacular biannual sight in which the setting sun aligns perfectly with the street grid system on the island at the heart of New York City, was set to be obscured by damp and gloomy weather on Saturday – one high-profile casualty of a disappointing forecast for the Memorial Day weekend, the traditional start of the American summer.
 Related: How to take a terrible photo of Manhattanhenge, in five easy steps 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edinburgh festival fringe threatened by Covid rules, says organiser]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/29/edinburgh-festival-fringe-threatened-by-covid-rules-says-organiser</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/29/edinburgh-festival-fringe-threatened-by-covid-rules-says-organiser"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:01:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CEO calls on Scottish ministers to replace 2-metre rule with 1 metre to secure future of world’s largest arts festival

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The survival of the Edinburgh festival fringe is at stake unless social distancing rules for venues are relaxed within a fortnight, its organiser has said.
Shona McCarthy, the chief executive of the Edinburgh Festival Fringe Society, called on ministers to replace the 2-metre rule with the 1-metre distance used in hospitality in order to help secure the future of the world’s largest arts festival.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cinema chains count on 007 to restore their Covid-hit takings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/29/cinema-chains-count-on-007-to-restore-their-covid-hit-takings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/29/cinema-chains-count-on-007-to-restore-their-covid-hit-takings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hopes are high for the September release of the latest in the super-spy franchise, No Time to Die
As ticket sales flicker back into life following the reopening of cinemas earlier this month, theatre owners are banking on one film to deliver them pre-pandemic-level crowds and box office success: Bond.
Sticking to its roadmap out of lockdown, the government allowed cinemas to reopen from 17 May. This gave Hollywood studios confidence in being able to turn a profit by returning to the big screen with blockbusters such as Marvel’s Black Widow and the latest in the Fast and Furious franchise this summer.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concrete thinking: an astonishing terrace extension]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/concrete-thinking-an-astonishing-terrace-extension</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/concrete-thinking-an-astonishing-terrace-extension"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using concrete and having an open mind means the owners of this London home have something very special on their hands
We can’t resist tinkering with our houses. In the 1980s we knocked through rooms and reached into the rafters to add loft extensions. In the 1990s side passages were glassed over and dusty coal cellars became utility rooms. Next came behemoth basement excavations. Now it’s all about the rear. Terraced houses that appear traditional at the front burst into cavernous open-plan extensions at the back. The glass box, gleaming with marble surfaces and bi-folding doors is every architect’s attempt to bring sunlit Californian modernity to cloudy British climes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Serena Fokschaner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data isn’t oil, whatever tech commentators tell you: it’s people’s lives | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/data-oil-metaphor-tech-companies-surveillance-capitalism</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/data-oil-metaphor-tech-companies-surveillance-capitalism"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pervasive metaphor likening information to crude obscures the reality of surveillance capitalism
The phrase “data is the new oil” is the cliche du jour of the tech industry. It was coined by Clive Humby, the genius behind Tesco’s loyalty card, who argued that data was “just like crude. It’s valuable, but if unrefined it cannot really be used. It has to be changed into gas, plastic, chemicals, etc to create a valuable entity that drives profitable activity; so must data be broken down, analysed for it to have value.”
It turned out to be a viral idea: marketers, tech companies, governments, regulators and the mainstream media went for it like ostriches going after brass doorknobs (as PG Wodehouse might have put it) and it rapidly attained the status of holy writ.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A view to a killing: how Amazon will exploit Bond and other MGM classics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/29/a-view-to-a-killing-how-amazon-will-exploit-bond-and-other-mgm-classics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/29/a-view-to-a-killing-how-amazon-will-exploit-bond-and-other-mgm-classics"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pay-TV giant has the chance to turn popular films into ‘universes’ of stories – and steal a march in the content-hungry streaming wars
Amazon’s $8.5bn deal to buy MGM, the Hollywood studio behind James Bond, The Handmaid’s Tale and Gone With the Wind, has secured it the rights to a century’s worth of TV and film titles that the streaming giant intends to exploit with a wave of remakes, reimaginings and spin-offs.
The deal to buy the 97-year-old Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, which has an immense library of 4,000 film titles and 17,000 hours of TV programming, is designed to supercharge Amazon’s content pipeline, which is the lifeblood of any competitor in the global battle for streaming supremacy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’m still alive’: Gomorrah author hails court victory over mafia threats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/damned-bastards-im-still-alive-gomorrah-author-hails-court-victory-over-mafia-threats</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/damned-bastards-im-still-alive-gomorrah-author-hails-court-victory-over-mafia-threats"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T15:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roberto Saviano says that a court has shown that the crime clans – whose threats forced him to live with a bodyguard – are not invincible
The internationally renowned anti-mafia writer Roberto Saviano has declared that “journalism has been vindicated; words are vindicated – and so am I”, after a landmark judgment in Rome over threats to his life.
Judges ruled on Monday that a courtroom manoeuvre 13 years ago by a Camorra mafia boss and his lawyer constituted a threat to Saviano’s life, and that of a colleague – Rosaria Capacchione, then of the Naples daily Il Mattino – condemning the journalists to live ever since in the shadows, under bodyguard.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Vulliamy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scotland urges Home Office to extend EU settlement deadline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/scotland-urges-home-office-to-extend-eu-settlement-deadline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/29/scotland-urges-home-office-to-extend-eu-settlement-deadline"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:51:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thousands risk having their lives ‘turned upside down’ as 30 June cut-off looms and backlogs remain
With just one month to go until the deadline, Scotland’s Europe minister has urged the Home Office to extend the cut-off date for the EU settlement scheme as thousands of those eligible in Scotland have not applied.
Jenny Gilruth said thousands of people living in Scotland risk their lives being “turned upside down” if they do not meet the deadline on 30 June.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tulsa Race Massacre centenary: major event canceled after payment dispute]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/tulsa-race-massacre-centenary-major-event-canceled</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/tulsa-race-massacre-centenary-major-event-canceled"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:39:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talks break down over how much survivors would be paid

Scheduled for the event were John Legend and Stacey Abrams
Documentary tells long buried story of Tulsa race massacre

A major event to commemorate the centenary of the Tulsa Race Massacre was canceled amid an impasse over payments to three survivors, organizers said.
 Related: ‘I am seeking justice’: Tulsa massacre survivor, 107, testifies to US Congress 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Bekiempis and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[11 Texas sheriff’s office employees fired after death of inmate]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/jaquaree-simmons-death-texas-sheriffs-office-fired-suspended</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/jaquaree-simmons-death-texas-sheriffs-office-fired-suspended"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:07:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Six were also suspended after three-month investigation into death of Jaquaree Simmons, which was ruled a homicide
Eleven employees of a Texas sheriff’s office have been fired and six suspended following the death of an inmate who was hit multiple times in the head by detention officers, authorities said on Friday.
The Harris county sheriff, Ed Gonzalez, said he was “very upset and heartbroken” after a three-month investigation into the death of Jaquaree Simmons, 23, in February. Medical examiners ruled Simmons’ death a homicide from injuries to his head.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Houston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alice: Curiouser and Curiouser review – a stupendous wonderland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/29/alice-curiouser-and-curiouser-review-v-and-a-london-wonderland-lewis-carroll</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/29/alice-curiouser-and-curiouser-review-v-and-a-london-wonderland-lewis-carroll"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[V&A, London
From VR croquet to the real Alice papped in Hollywood, the rabbit hole is just the start of this thrilling immersive exploration of Lewis Carroll’s enduring masterpiece
White rabbits skitter here and there, disappearing abruptly through holes in the wainscot. Tiny theatres open out of outsize Victorian doors. Cunning checkerboard floors lead your mind and feet astray, while giant playing cards hurtle up the walls like flames up a chimney. And the Cheshire Cat’s fabled grin somehow hangs above it all like a crescent moon in mid-air: a fading glow in a midnight blue gallery.
Alice: Curiouser and Curiouser is a stupendous experience. It accomplishes three separate journeys in one – the story of how Lewis Carroll came to write Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland; the voyage of his startlingly original fiction of 1863 out into the world; and a tremendous recreation of Alice’s rabbit-hole adventures in the form of a labyrinthine show.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cruella review – Emma Stone is a joy as the refashioned supervillain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/29/cruella-review-emma-stone-emma-thompson-101-dalmatians-disney</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/29/cruella-review-emma-stone-emma-thompson-101-dalmatians-disney"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[101 Dalmatians’s Cruella de Vil gets an origin story, with a sneering Emma Stone, an icy Emma Thompson – and clothes to die for
In 1996’s 101 Dalmatians, Glenn Close’s gleefully unhinged performance as a puppy-skinning fashion designer riffed on older audience members’ prior knowledge of the actor as a “bunny boiler” in Fatal Attraction. Emma Stone’s Cruella de Vil is much more grounded and thus not as camp, a supervillain with a believable backstory – born Estella, bullied by boys at school and established as a maverick who’s always refused to “follow the pattern” (as her single mother puts it) in both dressmaking and in life.
Set in 1970s London against a backdrop of the emerging punk scene, this playful prequel by Craig Gillespie (I, Tonya) is a fine feat of world-building. Like Phantom Thread or Marie Antoinette, it’s also an excellent fashion film, playing on the myth of the egocentric, detail-oriented genius. One of its main narrative threads involves Estella’s apprenticeship at, and eventual sabotage of, a couture fashion house headed by an icy narcissist named The Baroness (Emma Thompson, exuding Meryl Streep’s energy in The Devil Wears Prada). Fashion enthusiasts may also draw connections between the House of Baroness’s sculptural, Dior-esque gowns and Estella’s Alexander McQueen-influenced lace and leather looks (McQueen, of course, succeeded John Galliano at Givenchy in the 90s when the latter moved to Dior). There is even a reference to McQueen’s 2011 monarch butterfly dress.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simran Hans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life on the other side: meet five people who’ve had an extreme change of heart]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/life-on-the-other-side-meet-five-people-whove-had-an-extreme-change-of-heart</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/life-on-the-other-side-meet-five-people-whove-had-an-extreme-change-of-heart"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T14:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Janice was a drug dealer who now works with ex-prisoners, Christian used to be a neo-Nazi and now helps former extremists… Five people who have radically changed their lives reveal what made them switch
My life as a criminal wasn’t glamorous. People think of the money, but not what happens after midnight: the police you have to hide from; the family members who won’t talk to you; the thieves, robbers and informants on your back. This is what I now remind people who find themselves sucked into the underworld. Living that life taught me how it feels to be on the wrong side of the law, and equipped me with tools to help people escape it, because that’s precisely what I did.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Segalov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Mitch McConnell killed the US Capitol attack commission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/mitch-mcconnell-us-capitol-attack-commission-senate-republicans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/29/mitch-mcconnell-us-capitol-attack-commission-senate-republicans"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T13:47:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The story of how Republicans undermined the 6 January inquiry is informed by eight House and Senate aides, who spoke on the condition of anonymity
Days before the Senate voted down the creation of a 9/11-style commission to investigate the Capitol attack, the Senate Republican leader, Mitch McConnell, was adamant: he would oppose the bill, regardless of any amendments – and he expected his colleagues to follow suit.
The commission that would have likely found Donald Trump and some Republicans responsible for the insurrection posed an existential threat to the GOP ahead of the midterms, he said, and would complicate efforts to regain the majority in Congress.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugo Lowell in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Met drops case and accepts the role of legal observers at protests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/met-drops-case-and-accepts-the-role-of-legal-observers-at-protests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/met-drops-case-and-accepts-the-role-of-legal-observers-at-protests"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T12:47:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four members of Black Protest Legal Support arrested at ‘kill the bill’ protests have their charges dropped
The Metropolitan police has said legal observers at protests have an important role to play in the independent scrutiny of policing, as it dropped actions against four people who were arrested during “kill the bill” protests this spring.
It is believed to be the first time a police force has admitted the role played by legal observers during protests. The observers are independent volunteers who attend protests to monitor police conduct.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Gayle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[His fair lady: how George Bernard Shaw’s wife played a vital role in his masterworks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/29/his-fair-lady-how-george-bernard-shaws-wife-played-a-vital-role-in-his-masterworks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/29/his-fair-lady-how-george-bernard-shaws-wife-played-a-vital-role-in-his-masterworks"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T11:45:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charlotte’s influence has been downplayed, says a new book on how women are written out of history
In the climactic final scene of George Bernard Shaw’s masterpiece Pygmalion, Henry Higgins famously threatens to wring Eliza Doolittle’s neck. “Wring away!” she replies. “Oh, when I think of myself crawling under your feet and being trampled on and called names, when all the time I had only to lift up my finger to be as good as you, I could just kick myself.”
Until now, Shaw’s play about the flower girl who is transformed into a duchess by a wealthy professor was thought to have little in common with the great playwright’s own life. But this summer, a new book will shine a spotlight on the important contributions that Shaw’s wife, Charlotte, an heiress and intellectual, made to his work – and reveal how her connections and influence utterly transformed Shaw’s life and career.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Ferguson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teenager in court charged with conspiracy to murder over Sasha Johnson shooting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/teenager-in-court-charged-with-conspiracy-to-sasha-johnson</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/teenager-in-court-charged-with-conspiracy-to-sasha-johnson"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T11:32:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cameron Deriggs, 18, appeared at Westminster magistrates court over shooting of Black Lives Matter activist
An 18-year-old man has appeared in court charged with conspiracy to murder in relation to the shooting of the Black Lives Matter activist Sasha Johnson.
Johnson, 27, was shot at a house party in Peckham, south-east London, in the early hours of Sunday and remains in a critical condition in hospital.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My closest friend, my biggest enemy: can I make sense of my sister’s life and death?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/closest-friend-biggest-enemy-can-i-make-sense-of-my-sisters-life-and-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/29/closest-friend-biggest-enemy-can-i-make-sense-of-my-sisters-life-and-death"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T11:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Arifa Akbar’s artist sister died suddenly, she was left wondering why their relationship had been so fractious. Could a trove of sketchbooks reveal the truth?

My sister’s illness was a mystery until the day before she died. In the spring of 2016, Fauzia was taken to hospital twice and each time she stayed in intensive care for days on end. Her doctors conducted tests, drew up hypotheses, disproved them, and called in more doctors until her medical team was engorged with expertise but no closer to a diagnosis.
‘The mystery remained even as we were told to gather around her bed in the ICU on 9 June 2016. After she had died, when my mother and I prised out the needles that the nurses hadn’t taken from her neck and wrist, she continued to bleed. My mother, a British Pakistani Muslim who practises her faith quietly but assiduously, whispered the Qur’anic surah Yaseen in her right ear and told me she had seen a tiny black pearl slip out from under Fauzia’s eyelid – a single jewel of a tear – which she had caught in the palm of her hand just before it disappeared, along with my sister’s soul. It was a sign, she said, a parting gift from her firstborn child, who was also the first to die.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arifa Akbar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vietnam discovers new hybrid Covid variant, state media reports]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/vietnam-discovers-new-hybrid-covid-variant-state-media-reports</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/vietnam-discovers-new-hybrid-covid-variant-state-media-reports"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T10:39:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Strain is a combination of UK and India variants and is said to spread quickly

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Vietnam has discovered a new Covid-19 variant which spreads quickly by air and is a combination of variants first identified in India and the UK, state media has reported.
The country is struggling to deal with fresh outbreaks across more than half of its territory including industrial zones and big cities such as Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Hanoi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deadly magnet ‘tongue piercings’ should be banned, says NHS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/deadly-magnet-tongue-piercings-should-be-banned-says-nhs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/deadly-magnet-tongue-piercings-should-be-banned-says-nhs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T10:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teenagers arrive in hospital having ingested tiny metal balls after imitating TikTok craze 
A TikTok trend which involves using tiny magnets as fake tongue piercings has prompted the NHS to call for the metal balls to be banned amid a rise in people swallowing them.
The viral prank has people placing a magnetic ball on either side of their tongue and wiggling them around to create the illusion that the piercing is real.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Original Observer photography]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/original-observer-photography</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/original-observer-photography"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T10:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Director Barry Jenkins, the plight of Syria’s refugees, and the return of live music – the best photography commissioned by the Observer in May 2021
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josy Forsdike</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-fungible tokens aren’t a harmless digital fad – they’re a disaster for our planet | Adam Greenfield]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/non-fungible-tokens-digital-fad-planet-nfts-artists-fossil-fuels</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/29/non-fungible-tokens-digital-fad-planet-nfts-artists-fossil-fuels"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T10:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artists are harnessing NFTs to sell their work but ignoring the vast amount of fossil fuels needed to power them 

If you happen to count yourself among those appalled by the seemingly unstoppable rise of NFTs, or non-fungible tokens, over the past few months, you might be forgiven a little schadenfreude at the recent news that a dispute has broken out over the ownership of Mars House, a digital file that sold in March for $512,000 (£360,000).
Let’s be clear what’s been purchased here. Mars House itself is nothing more than a string of ones and zeroes residing on a server somewhere. But the NFT isn’t even that string. All it is is another such string pointing to that one, certifying that it is the only copy of that precise sequence of ones and zeroes in existence. Put aside, if you can, the obscenity of a purely virtual dwelling selling for half a million dollars. The dispute over Mars House makes plain what should have been obvious all along: NFTs aren’t even capable of guaranteeing the one thing their value is supposedly predicated on, ownership of a unique digital asset.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxford Rhodes statue should be turned to face wall, says Antony Gormley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/29/rhodes-statue-should-be-turned-to-face-wall-says-antony-gormley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/29/rhodes-statue-should-be-turned-to-face-wall-says-antony-gormley"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T09:45:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sculptor suggests solution to row over keeping statue of colonialist in place at Oriel College
The statue of Cecil Rhodes at Oriel College, Oxford, should be turned to face the wall in shame, the sculptor Antony Gormley has proposed.
Gormley’s suggestion, made in an interview with the Financial Times, would be an innovative solution to a years-long battle over whether the 19th-century colonialist and white supremacist should remain in pride of place at the university.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Gayle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘There goes my chance’: house prices rocket as Cornwall locals priced out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/29/there-goes-my-chance-house-prices-rocket-as-cornwall-locals-priced-out</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/29/there-goes-my-chance-house-prices-rocket-as-cornwall-locals-priced-out"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T09:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[St Mawes has biggest increase in average house price of any British seaside town, finds Halifax
Perched on a hill above the fishing harbour of St Mawes, the estate agent H Tiddy has sold houses in this picture postcard corner of Cornwall for more than a century – but business has never been as frantic as it is now.
“Since last March it’s just been so busy,” said Tom Sparkes, a senior valuer. “I think the pandemic has made people think again about their plans. Some have decided to retire early, others have realised if they work from home they might as well do it from here. And there are lots of people who’d like a second home in this area.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK weather: watch out for sunburn this bank holiday, says Met Office]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/uk-weather-watch-out-for-sunburn-this-bank-holiday-says-met-office</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/29/uk-weather-watch-out-for-sunburn-this-bank-holiday-says-met-office"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T09:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forecasters expect ‘very high’ UV levels in southern England, and warn people not to be caught out
Forecasters are warning of a bank holiday sunburn risk as UV rays are expected to reach very high levels during the sunshine this weekend, after weeks of cooler weather.
The Met Office is anticipating UV levels of 8 in the south of England on Monday, which is considered “very high” for the UK and requires extra sun protection.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experts urge minimum alcohol pricing in England after survey shows success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/experts-urge-minimum-alcohol-pricing-in-england-after-survey-shows-success</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/29/experts-urge-minimum-alcohol-pricing-in-england-after-survey-shows-success"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T08:31:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Policy in Scotland and Wales has reduced consumption in heaviest drinking households
Campaigners have called for a minimum unit price (MUP) for alcohol in England after research showed it has reduced consumption in some of the heaviest drinking households in Scotland and Wales.
A 50p per unit price was introduced in Scotland in 2018 and an in-depth shopping survey two years on has found the policy has had a lasting impact.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dwarf pansy blooms on tiny Scilly island after 16-year absence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/dwarf-pansy-blooms-on-isles-of-scilly-after-16-year-absence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/dwarf-pansy-blooms-on-isles-of-scilly-after-16-year-absence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T08:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rare flower reappears on Tean after disappearing in the absence of human inhabitants
The tiny island of Tean was once home to a single resident, a modest chapel, diminutive grazed fields and a dwarf pansy smaller than the tip of a pencil.
All these things vanished from the 0.16 sq km Scilly island in the years after it was abandoned by humans seeking larger things.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sinéad O’Connor: ‘I’ll always be a bit crazy, but that’s OK’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/29/sinead-oconnor-ill-always-be-a-bit-crazy-but-thats-ok-rememberings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/may/29/sinead-oconnor-ill-always-be-a-bit-crazy-but-thats-ok-rememberings"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T07:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a life marked by abuse, fame, scandal and struggle, the Irish singer-songwriter says she never lost faith

Read an exclusive extract from her new memoir 

Sinéad O’Connor has been pretty much invisible for the past few years. There’s a good reason, though, she tells me with her usual disregard for social niceties. “I’ve spent most of the time in the nuthouse. I’ve been practically living there for six years.” She pauses, takes an intense drag on her fag, and warns me off being similarly politically incorrect. “We alone get to call it the nuthouse – the patients.”
O’Connor is a music great – her 1990 version of Prince’s Nothing Compares 2 U is one of the most transcendent five minutes in pop history, the solitary tear falling from her eye in the accompanying video one of its most beautiful images. The single topped the charts worldwide, as did the album it was taken from, I Do Not Want What I Haven’t Got. Astonishingly, in the 31 years that have passed, she has never had another UK Top 10 hit single and only one Top 10 album. And yet she remains a household name.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vague messaging risks causing rise in English Covid cases, say scientists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/vague-messaging-risk-rise-english-covid-cases-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/vague-messaging-risk-rise-english-covid-cases-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T07:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts argue that a repeat of past failings could lead to an increase in transmissions over bank holiday

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

As confusion over whether people should really be travelling to “amber list” countries grew earlier this month, Boris Johnson stressed that his government was trying to move away from “endlessly legislating everything” to relying on guidance and trusting the public to do the right thing.
This vague messaging approach, scientists say, has been a persistent feature of the Covid response in England – to the public’s detriment – and now risks exacerbating a rise in Covid cases as people across the country gear up to travel to see their friends and family over the bank holiday. The continued risks of catching and spreading coronavirus haven’t been sufficiently explained to the public.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flights v flamingos: can Barcelona wildlife reserve survive airport expansion?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/flights-v-flamingos-can-barcelona-wildlife-reserve-survive-airport-expansion-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/flights-v-flamingos-can-barcelona-wildlife-reserve-survive-airport-expansion-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T06:30:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Billion-dollar development threatens the future of one of the western Mediterranean’s most important wetlands
The silence is so complete it is easy to forget you are only a few minutes’ drive from the centre of Barcelona. Just the sough of the willows in the sea breeze, the splash of a fish surfacing and a heron’s cry – until the serenity is obliterated by a plane taking off.
The Delta del Llobregat, one of the most important wetlands in the western Mediterranean, is being eroded on one side by the sea and on the other by the city’s land-hungry airport. As travel to Spain is still restricted, there are few flights and it is possible to revel in the delta’s almost mesmeric tranquillity. But before the pandemic there were already close to 90 flights an hour and, if the airport authority has its way, this will increase still further.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Burgen in the Delta del Llobregat, Spain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Black Wednesday’ for big oil as courtrooms and boardrooms turn on industry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/black-wednesday-for-big-oil-as-courtrooms-and-boardrooms-turn-on-industry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/29/black-wednesday-for-big-oil-as-courtrooms-and-boardrooms-turn-on-industry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T06:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners sense turning point as shareholders, boards and The Hague act to force Chevron, ExxonMobil and Shell to cut pollution

The world’s patience with the fossil fuel industry is wearing thin. This was the stark message delivered to major international oil companies this week in an unprecedented day of reckoning for their role in the climate crisis.
In a stunning series of defeats for the oil industry, over the course of less than 24 hours, courtrooms and boardrooms turned on the executives at Shell, ExxonMobil and Chevron. Shell was ordered by a court in The Hague to go far further to reduce its climate emissions, while shareholder rebellions in the US imposed emissions targets at Chevron and a boardroom overhaul at Exxon.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jillian Ambrose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Younger buyers discover joys of caravanning for Covid-era holidays]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/29/younger-buyers-caravanning-covid-holidays-caravans-motorhomes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/29/younger-buyers-caravanning-covid-holidays-caravans-motorhomes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T06:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With travel abroad restricted, many see caravans and motorhomes through fresh eyes and sales are booming
Looking for a boutique hotel on wheels or a sporty model with room for your surfboard or kayak? Welcome to the UK’s growing number of caravanners – even millennials are itching to join in.
The coronavirus pandemic has made holidaymakers see caravanning, often deemed a less fashionable alternative to camping, through new eyes. The confusion about overseas travel has sent internet searches soaring, while dealerships are struggling to get their hands on enough caravans to meet demand. Buyers face growing waiting times, and rising raw material costs have also pushed up prices.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘From hearsay to hard evidence’: are UFOs about to go mainstream?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/ufos-uap-america-pentagon-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/29/ufos-uap-america-pentagon-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-29T05:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unidentified aerial phenomena are getting serious attention on TV and from Barack Obama and Marco Rubio and next month the Pentagon is set to release a major declassified analysis
Nick Pope spent the early 1990s investigating UFOs for the British ministry of defence. Sequestered in a rarely visited government office – the “metaphorical basement” – he well remembers how his field of work was regarded.
“I would walk down the corridor and people would whistle the theme music to either Close Encounters of the Third Kind or the Twilight Zone,” Pope told the Guardian.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Gabbatt in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Developer Journey – How I Went from Making $1,000 to $100,000 a Year]]></title>
        <id>60acf28e11ffb70827ef6dd9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-developer-journey-how-i-went-from-1000-a-year-to-100000-as-a-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T22:58:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone, my name is Santosh. In this article, I will tell you how I ramped up my career and ended up making $100,000 a year as a developer.  I'll share what I learned from each job along the way, how you can stand out, tips for negotiating salary,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moments in Goomalling: the Mavis Phillips archives – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/moments-in-goomalling-the-mavis-phillips-archives-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/29/moments-in-goomalling-the-mavis-phillips-archives-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T20:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mavis Phillips nee Walley was one of Australia’s earliest known Indigenous photographers. She grew up in Goomalling, in rural Western Australia, and started shooting in the 1930s using a simple cardboard camera called the box Brownie. The images in this collection share the happiest times of her life when her family lived and worked on a farm owned by a white family, protected from native welfare. But they were then moved to the Goomalling native eeserve where they were subject to Western Australia’s apartheid-style laws.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Staff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/28/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/28/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T18:22:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aftermath of the conflict in Gaza and Israel, the one-year anniversary of George Floyd’s death, the Nyiragongo volcano erupts near Goma, and Covid deaths in India: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bard timing: Argentinian TV reports death of Shakespeare after Covid jab]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/28/william-shakespeare-death-mistake-argentinian-tv</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/28/william-shakespeare-death-mistake-argentinian-tv"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T17:56:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newsreader confuses Bill Shakespeare, 81, ‘the first man to get the coronavirus vaccine’ with ‘one of the most important writers in the English language’
In what can only be described as a comedy of errors, an Argentinian TV news channel delivered a stunning, if slightly flawed, scoop on Thursday night when it reported that William Shakespeare, “one of the most important writers in the English language” had died five months after receiving the Covid vaccine.
The gaffe of, well, Shakespearean proportions happened after Noelia Novillo, a newsreader on Canal 26, mixed up the Bard with William “Bill” Shakespeare, an 81-year-old Warwickshire man who became the second person in the world to get the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid and Uki Goñi in Buenos Aires</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on climate change lawsuits: Big Oil is in the dock | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/commentisfree/2021/may/28/the-guardian-view-on-climate-change-lawsuits-big-oil-is-in-the-dock</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/commentisfree/2021/may/28/the-guardian-view-on-climate-change-lawsuits-big-oil-is-in-the-dock"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:44:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fossil fuel firms are being held responsible for greenhouse gas emissions. That’s a good thing
History was made in the Hague district court this week. Judge Larisa Alwin ruled that Shell, one of the world’s biggest oil companies, must cut its emissions by 45% by 2030 relative to 2019 levels. Until Wednesday, courts in the Netherlands, France and Germany had concentrated on holding governments to their commitments under the Paris climate deal of 2015. States were found guilty of denying basic rights to future citizens, triggering more ambitious climate plans. The landmark Hague ruling shows that corporations can now be ordered to comply with the goals of the Paris agreement.
Governments are supposed to design the regulatory frameworks and put in place the laws so that companies and households steadily reduce their carbon emissions. But this relies on private entities playing their part. If they do not, preferring to hide behind slick PR, the law can step in. The judge accepted the argument that Shell had failed in its duty to respect human rights by failing to adequately curb its role in global heating. Shell’s goals to mitigate its climate impact, the court found, “largely amount to rather intangible, undefined and non-binding plans for the long term”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the art of lexicography: ancient Greek lives on]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/28/the-guardian-view-on-the-art-of-lexicography-ancient-greek-lives-on</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/28/the-guardian-view-on-the-art-of-lexicography-ancient-greek-lives-on"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:38:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Old languages are far from dead – and knowledge of their subtleties advances by the day
A new two-volume ancient Greek-English lexicon has just been published by Cambridge University. The work of over 20 years, it defines 37,000 words. One might wonder why such a thing might be needed. After all, Liddell and Scott’s Greek dictionary, with its early-20th-century revisions, has served scholars well since 1843. And isn’t ancient Greek a dead language anyway?
By no means. Scholars constantly broaden knowledge of the language. The later 19th century saw a profusion of Greek texts excavated in Egypt, where the dry sands preserved millions of papyrus fragments – not just literature but bills, letters and even magical spells, full of new usages that are still being studied (not all of this is reflected in the new lexicon). In recent decades, the canon has broadened towards the abundant Greek writing produced under the Roman empire – though, since the new dictionary advances only to the second century AD, it, alas, omits much of this material.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Secure Your Android App – Four Security Best Practices Every Android Dev Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60b08d8811ffb70827ef8c7b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-secure-your-android-app/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T16:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you've been following the news lately, you may have noticed a worrisome tech trend. The frequency and severity of cybersecurity attacks are exploding.  We've seen news of a sprawling hack involving the SolarWinds management platform. That attack may have compromised the systems of over 18,000 SolarWinds customers.  Then,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A shameful betrayal and the deep roots of institutional racism in Britain | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/28/a-shameful-betrayal-and-the-deep-roots-of-institutional-racism-in-britain</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/28/a-shameful-betrayal-and-the-deep-roots-of-institutional-racism-in-britain"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T15:15:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cousins John Ashton and John Ashton on the Chinese seamen deported after serving Britain during the second world war, and their exploitative employer. Plus letters from Gary Craig, Jacqueline Simpson and Mike Owen
We congratulate Dan Hancox, and the family campaigners who helped him, for bringing into the open at last the story of the Chinese seamen secretly rounded up and forcibly deported from Liverpool as soon as their services were no longer required for the war effort (The secret deportations: how Britain betrayed the Chinese men who served the country in the war, 25 May). Nothing can compensate for the suffering inflicted on them, and on the wives and children from whom they were so cruelly separated with neither explanation nor farewell.
Truth and contrition are the least that can be expected. It is sad but revealing that even now ministers cannot bring themselves to apologise to the victims’ descendants for this shameful episode in our history. The institutional racism with which we continue to struggle in our country has deep roots.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Give students time and space to study | Brief letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/28/give-students-time-and-space-to-study</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/28/give-students-time-and-space-to-study"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T15:07:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bob Dylan songs | History and geography | Obituary pages | Pub signs
None of the famous musicians who chose their favourite Bob Dylan songs (24 May) mentioned Like a Rolling Stone, the single song that jolted a generation from acoustic cosiness into electric edginess. The track’s opening drumbeat still sends shivers down my spine 56 years later.
Toby Wood
Peterborough
• “The university told the Guardian only two subjects – history and geography – would no longer be taught” … “‘Overall there has been very little change’, a spokesperson said” (London South Bank University staff sound alarm over drop in courses, 25 May). History and geography – time and space, the coordinates of the human condition!
Robin Milner-Gulland 
Washington, West Sussex
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Computer Vision with Python]]></title>
        <id>60b0de2211ffb70827ef8d7c</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/advanced-computer-vision-with-python/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T12:26:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More and more applications are using computer vision these days. We just published a full course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will help you learn advanced computer vision using Python. You will learn state of the art computer vision techniques by building five projects with libraries such as]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friends: The Reunion – share your reviews of the TV special]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/28/friends-the-reunion-share-your-reviews-of-the-tv-special</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/28/friends-the-reunion-share-your-reviews-of-the-tv-special"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:03:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week saw the Friends cast reunite for an unscripted tribute to the hit show. Send us your reviews and we’ll publish the best
The cast of Friends has reunited for a retrospective of the hit sitcom, broadcast in the UK on 27 May on Sky One and Now. Friends: The Reunion was recorded on the original soundstage with David Schwimmer, Lisa Kudrow, Matt LeBlanc, Jennifer Aniston, Courteney Cox and Matthew Perry, plus guests including Lady Gaga, Justin Bieber and David Beckham.
Did you enjoy the special? Did it live up to your expectations? And what did you think of the revelation that Ross and Rachel almost had a real-life romance?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you in a platonic marriage or a similar relationship?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/28/tell-us-are-you-in-a-platonic-marriage-or-a-similar-relationship"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T09:13:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from couples who have got married as a celebration of deep friendship rather than romance
Although legislation around marriage has changed over the last 10 years – from the introduction of same sex marriage to civil partnerships being extended to heterosexual couples – what has remained the same is the idea that marriage is for two parties romantically involved in each other. 
However, across Europe and America, the beginnings of a trend seem to be emerging: platonic marriage. This is where two parties get married as a celebration of deep friendship, rather than romance, and where their best friend is their significant other with whom they are building a life (eg. raising children).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Milky Way photographer of the year 2021 – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/28/milky-way-photographer-of-the-year-2021-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/28/milky-way-photographer-of-the-year-2021-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T06:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual Milky Way photographer of the year competition features the best photos of our galaxy as selected by Capture the Atlas. This year’s images were taken from around the world by 25 photographers of 14 different nationalities. The best time to see and photograph the Milky Way is usually between May and June with maximum hours of visibility on both hemispheres
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the scenes of The Smartest Giant in Town – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/28/behind-the-scenes-of-the-smartest-giant-in-town-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/gallery/2021/may/28/behind-the-scenes-of-the-smartest-giant-in-town-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T06:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A musical production of Julia Donaldson and Axel Scheffler’s children’s book The Smartest Giant in Town is opening at the Little Angel theatre in Islington, north London. Guardian photographer David Levene went behind the scenes
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Levene</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A state-sponsored ‘hijacking’ – the arrest of Belarus blogger Raman Pratasevich]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/28/a-state-sponsored-hijacking-the-arrest-of-belarus-blogger-raman-pratasevich"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T02:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova examines why Alexander Lukashenko, the president of Belarus, apparently diverted a Ryanair flight in order to arrest 26-year-old blogger Raman Pratasevich. Guardian Moscow correspondent, Andrew Roth, discusses the fallout from the action
Anushka Asthana talks to the Belarusian journalist Hanna Liubakova about the 26-year-old opposition blogger Raman Pratasevich and his 23-year-old girlfriend, Sofia Sapega. On Sunday their Ryanair flight, which was meant to be flying to Lithuania, was forced to make an emergency landing in Minsk and they were arrested. Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, the Belarusian opposition leader, told the European parliament on Wednesday that Lukashenko was “turning the country into the North Korea of Europe: non-transparent, unpredictable and dangerous”.
Anushka also talks to the Guardian’s Moscow correspondent Andrew Roth about the international reaction to what has been called a ‘state-sponsored hijacking’. The British government has told all UK planes to cease flying over Belarus, while the EU has imposed new economic sanctions. Kremlin officials have offered only muted support over the incident.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Hanna Liubakova and Andrew Roth, produced by Marilyn Rust and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve Machine Learning Model Performance by Combining Categorical Features]]></title>
        <id>60af931811ffb70827ef85d3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-machine-learning-model-performance-by-combining-categorical-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T17:55:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're training a machine learning model, you can have some features in your dataset that represent categorical values. Categorical features are types of data that you can divide into groups. There are three common categorical data types: Ordinal – a set of values in ascending or descending order. Example: rating]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make a Bouncing Basketball in Unity with Materials and Textures 🏀]]></title>
        <id>60a325c6906c5207e3a7da25</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-a-basketball-in-unity-with-materials-and-textures/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:16:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll teach you how to make a basketball using materials and textures in Unity. You can extend this micro-concept to create any kind of ball like a football, tennis ball, or snooker balls.  That said, these techniques aren't just limited to creating round 3D objects like balls.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Investing 0.1% of global GDP could avoid breakdown of ecosystems, says UN report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/nature-financial-value-investing-global-gdp-avoid-breakdown-ecosystems-un-report-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/nature-financial-value-investing-global-gdp-avoid-breakdown-ecosystems-un-report-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T15:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nature’s financial value must be considered to avoid ‘irreversible’ degradation to biodiversity and land
The world needs to quadruple its annual investment in nature if the climate, biodiversity and land degradation crises are to be tackled by the middle of the century, according to a new UN report.
Investing just 0.1% of global GDP every year in restorative agriculture, forests, pollution management and protected areas to close a $4.1tn (£2.9tn) financial gap by 2050 could avoid the breakdown of natural ecosystem “services” such as clean water, food and flood protection, the report said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Greenfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your stories of holiday disasters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/27/share-your-stories-of-holiday-disasters"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:32:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear about your holiday catastrophes and trips that didn’t go to plan
With travel still subject to strict Covid rules, many of us will be opting to stay put this summer. But while we often idolise the idea of a sun-filled getaway, in reality, our holidays can sometimes fail to meet expectations – and sometimes they can be downright disastrous.
With this in mind, we’d love to hear about your holiday catastrophes and the trips that didn’t go according to plan, as a reminder that we might not always be missing out after all. Perhaps your luxurious city break was ruined by terrible weather? Or maybe your backpacking adventure plans were quashed by a bout of food poisoning? Whether your family vacation ended in tears, or your romantic weekend away was blighted by lost luggage and booking mishaps, tell us about it below.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Responsive Websites Faster With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Miami’s chief heat officer calls for action on ‘silent killer’ in climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/miami-chief-heat-officer-jane-gilbert-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/27/miami-chief-heat-officer-jane-gilbert-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T08:45:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jane Gilbert urges greater federal and state response to lethal threat posed by rising temperatures
Miami’s new chief heat officer has called for greater federal and state action on the lethal threat posed by rising temperatures after becoming the first official in the US appointed to focus solely on heatwaves.
Jane Gilbert, who has been tasked by Miami-Dade county with coordinating and accelerating efforts to protect lives from extreme heat, said that more focus was needed on what has been called the “silent killer” of the climate crisis.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Milman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rapid heating of Indian Ocean worsening cyclones, say scientists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/27/rapid-heating-of-indian-ocean-worsening-cyclones-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T08:41:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rising ocean temperatures caused by climate crisis increasing number of cyclones and intensity of storms, say experts
India’s cyclone season is being made more intense by the rapidly heating Indian Ocean, scientists have warned.
Last week India was battered by Cyclone Tauktae, an unusually strong cyclone in the Arabian Sea, resulting in widespread disruption. This week, another severe storm, Cyclone Yaas, formed in the Bay of Bengal, leading to more than a million people being evacuated into safe shelters.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Neelima Vallangi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The government failed’: Dominic Cummings takes aim at No 10’s Covid response]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/27/the-government-failed-dominic-cummings-takes-aim-at-no-10s-covid-response"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T02:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former aide lashed out at every aspect of the government’s approach and Boris Johnson and Matt Hancock in particular
Dominic Cummings spent an hours-long session in parliament on Wednesday giving evidence to a joint committee on the government’s response to the Covid pandemic. He took aim at Boris Johnson for overseeing a chaotic response and at the health secretary, Matt Hancock, for what he alleged was lying over preparedness and PPE stocks.
Guardian columnist Gaby Hinsliff tells Anushka Asthana that it was the first chance to get a detailed firsthand account of what was going on in the heart of government as the crisis unfolded. But how much should Cummings himself be seen as culpable for the failures?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Gaby Hinsliff; produced by Ned Carter Miles, Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giphy API Tutorial – How to Generate Animated Text GIFs with ReactJS]]></title>
        <id>60a44b9f906c5207e3a7e098</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/giphy-api-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T21:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial you will create an app that generates dynamic animated text using Giphy's API with ReactJS. After that I'll go over some of the other API features Giphy provides that you can use to make other interesting projects. You can find the code for the tutorial here. Video]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Contribute to Open Source  Projects – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60abe7fb11ffb70827ef63a6</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-contribute-to-open-source-projects-beginners-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're a developer, you've probably come across the term "open source." If you've ever wondered what it's all about and how to contribute, you are in exactly the right place.  I put aside all my fears about how and what to contribute during Hacktoberfest 2020, and made]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Basic Terraform Syntax in 20 minutes]]></title>
        <id>606f4f5fd5756f080ba96b65</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/terraform-syntax-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T18:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll give you a brief overview of the configuration syntax of Terraform.  Terraform's docs provide the most comprehensive look at its syntax. But this article should serve as a condensed quick start introduction that'll give new users a simplified overview. We'll focus on the basic structures without]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a GraphQL API Using Laravel]]></title>
        <id>60abc59d11ffb70827ef6304</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-graphql-api-using-laravel/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T16:34:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll walk you through how to set up your own GraphQL API using PHP and Laravel. Two years ago, I started working professionally as a backend developer. And I was very intimidated by all the technology I didn't yet know. Words like Docker, Kubernetes, and GraphQL seemed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build Super Mario Bros, Zelda, and Space Invaders with Kaboom.js]]></title>
        <id>60aced0011ffb70827ef6d96</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-mario-zelda-and-space-invaders-with-kaboom-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this video course I show you how to build three popular games using the latest game development library for JavaScript called Kaboom.js. This course is exciting for two reasons: First of all, I am going to be introducing a new technology designed especially for game development in JavaScript.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what are your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/may/26/tell-us-what-are-your-travel-plans-for-this-bank-holiday-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T09:24:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This bank holiday weekend will be the first opportunity for many to visit loved ones who live further away. We’d like to hear about your plans
What were your travel plans for this bank holiday weekend – the first opportunity many of us have had to visit grandparents and loved ones who live further away?
What impact have these new No-Go zones had on your arrangements: are you going to adapt or abandon your visits – or are you going ahead, as planned?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Britain becoming a hostile environment for EU citizens? | Podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/26/is-britain-becoming-a-hostile-environment-for-eu-citizens"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T02:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Covid travel restrictions begin to be lifted, a new, far less welcoming post-Brexit attitude is greeting EU citizens at the UK border 
EU citizens living and working in the UK are being met with suspicion and in some cases refused entry at the UK border for the first time in their lives, after the implementation of new post-Brexit rules and the lifting of Covid travel restrictions. 
Chloe, a pastry chef from Denmark, tells Anushka Asthana that, because she could not produce a return ticket, she was denied entry at Calais to the UK recently and forced to make the long drive back to Denmark. It is becoming a familiar story, with other EU citizens reporting hostility from officials and some being held at immigration detention centres. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Rafael Behr; produced by Alex Atack and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[proxy-www]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341153</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/justjavac/proxy-www"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T19:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like a good trick. What if… a URL was…  a promise… that fetched said URL?
www.codepen.io.then((response) ={
  console.log(response);
});
That’s what @justjavac did with JavaScript Proxys. A clever trick, that. Don’t @ me about the practicality. Trick…
The post proxy-www appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340626</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wrangling-control-over-pdfs-with-the-adobe-pdf-embed-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T13:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By our last estimate, there are now more PDFs in the world than atoms in the universe (not verified by outside sources) so chances are, from time to time, you’re going to run into a PDF document or two. Browsers …
The post Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raymond Camden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about male incontinence: six common questions answered]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/lets-talk-about-male-incontinence-six-common-questions-answered</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/lets-talk-about-male-incontinence-six-common-questions-answered"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:26:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wetting yourself isn’t something that happens just to older people or women who’ve given birth. A quarter of men over 40 experience some form of leakage, yet many are loath to speak out
Incontinence comes loaded with misconceptions, not least that it’s a women’s or older person’s problem. This could be why so many younger men stay silent when urinary incontinence strikes. Here, we look at what causes a condition that is far more widespread than many think – and how it’s eminently treatable.
How common is male incontinence?
A quarter of men over the age of 40 experience some form of urine leakage according to research by the global health and hygiene company Essity. And, in the US, the National Association for Continence says that incontinence affects as many as 15% of men aged 15-64, which belies the myth that it’s only postpartum or menopausal women who suffer from it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Koch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I’d tell my 25-year-old self about sex – and how it has improved for me with age]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/what-id-tell-my-25-year-old-self-about-sex-and-how-it-has-improved-for-me-with-age</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/what-id-tell-my-25-year-old-self-about-sex-and-how-it-has-improved-for-me-with-age"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On his 55th birthday, New York-based writer and sex therapist Ian Kerner reflects on his sex life and explains why men don’t need to let ageing get in the way of their desire
I know for a fact that tonight I’m going to get lucky: I’m definitely going to have sex. According to a study published in the Archives of Sexual Behavior, the average American has sex 54 times a year, which roughly translates to once a week with a couple of extra times thrown in for special occasions. And today is my birthday. I’m turning 55. And like all my birthdays for the past 20 years I’ve been married, my bonus present is sex. But, special occasion or not, given that I’m pushing up in years this is a good moment to take stock of how my sex life has changed over time – and what I’ve learned as a sex therapist about how other men age through the life-cycle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Kerner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘As a woman, I don’t feel I can own up to loving sex’: the taboos that still need breaking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/as-a-woman-i-dont-feel-i-can-own-up-to-loving-sex-the-taboos-that-still-need-breaking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/as-a-woman-i-dont-feel-i-can-own-up-to-loving-sex-the-taboos-that-still-need-breaking"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:22:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We may be in 2021, but even so there are aspects of life that feel off limits – when really they shouldn’t. That’s why some readers took this opportunity to get things off their chest
From not wanting kids to grown men crying, and women dating younger men to wetting yourself, we asked you to own up to the things that you don’t tend to talk about. And you spilled the beans because, let’s face it, we’re all friends here …
“I’ve recently started talking to my personal trainer about my period. He’s a good looking 25-year-old and I felt myself burning up with embarrassment when he asked why I was lacking in energy one week. I went to lie but then thought, why do women still feel shame about this? He looked a bit uncomfortable but since then I have tried to make a point of talking about my cycle as ultimately it affects my body and my performance, which is completely relevant to his job as my trainer. It still feels ‘wrong’ and almost distasteful to talk about, but I know it shouldn’t.” Sammy, 43
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Compiled by Samantha Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘To lose weight, I hatched a really bad plan’: how men hide their body-image issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/to-lose-weight-i-hatched-a-really-bad-plan-how-men-hide-their-body-image-issues</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-last-taboo/2021/may/18/to-lose-weight-i-hatched-a-really-bad-plan-how-men-hide-their-body-image-issues"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:19:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over half of all men suffer from body insecurities, so why is it so hard for us to talk about them the way women do, asks Andrzej Łukowski
When I started secondary school I was a bit on the tubby side.
Other than a general aversion to competitive sports (though I did swim, I had badges an’ all!), I’m not really sure there was any particular reason for this.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrzej Łukowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could the Tokyo Olympics still be cancelled? – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/17/could-tokyo-olympic-games-be-cancelled-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:54:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tokyo Olympics are due to begin on 23 July, but calls for the Games to be cancelled are growing due to the worsening Covid-19 situation in Japan. The Guardian's Tokyo correspondent, Justin McCurry, looks at the current state of play. 
A recent spike in coronavirus cases has caused many prefectures to enter a state of emergency, including Tokyo. Japan has been reporting nearly 7,000 daily cases and the surge has put pressure on the country’s healthcare system, with the rollout of its vaccination programme slower than anticipated.
Organisers says tough anti-virus measures, including regular testing of athletes and a ban on overseas fans, will keep the delayed Games safe, but a new poll indicates more than 80% of Japanese people oppose hosting the Olympics this year. In addition, some elite athletes including tennis star Naomi Osaka have expressed their own concerns.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin McCurry, Nicholas Williams &amp; Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>