<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-10T00:34:42.281Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-10T00:34:42.281Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden arrives in UK as domestic agenda hits a Republican wall – live]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/09/joe-biden-uk-democrats-voting-rights-bill-us-politics-live</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jun/09/joe-biden-uk-democrats-voting-rights-bill-us-politics-live"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T00:09:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Key legislation going nowhere as McConnell says bipartisanship is over
President Biden lands in UK ahead of G7 summit in Cornwall
Bernie Sanders says he has ‘limited patience’ with Republicans
Arizona audit backed by secretive donors linked to Trump allies

 12.59am BST 
 12.29am BST 
The unifying theme behind Joe Biden’s European tour this week is a country which will not be at any of the meetings and may not even be mentioned in the final communiques: China.
Before setting out on his first foreign trip as president, Biden has made clear that the competition between the world’s democracies and its authoritarian regimes – mostly importantly Beijing – is the defining global challenge of the age, with victory anything but guaranteed for the US and its allies.
 Related: China the spectre at the feast as Biden aims to rally democracies on Europe trip 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maanvi Singh (now) and Vivian Ho (earlier)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oriel College faces teaching boycott over refusal to remove Rhodes statue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/oriel-college-faces-teaching-boycott-over-refusal-to-remove-rhodes-statue</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/oriel-college-faces-teaching-boycott-over-refusal-to-remove-rhodes-statue"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:29:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announcement by 150 Oxford lecturers accuses college of ‘undermining’ efforts of university to eradicate racism 
About 150 Oxford lecturers have announced they will refuse to teach students at Oriel College over its contentious decision not to remove a statue of the imperialist Cecil Rhodes.
The college was accused of “institutional racism” last month after its governing body said it would not seek to move the monument from its position outside the building.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nadeem Badshah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stamp duty holiday helps drive up UK property prices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/stamp-duty-holiday-helps-drive-up-uk-property-prices</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/stamp-duty-holiday-helps-drive-up-uk-property-prices"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gap between supply and demand for homes at widest level since 2013, says Rics
UK property prices are set to continue to rise after the gap between demand for homes and supply grew to its widest level since 2013, surveyors have reported.
The latest monthly snapshot of the market from the Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors showed new listings had failed to keep up with the number of interested buyers in May, driving up prices across the UK.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hilary Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Access to GPs’ patient data key to new treatments, researchers say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/10/access-to-gps-patient-data-key-to-new-treatments-researchers-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/10/access-to-gps-patient-data-key-to-new-treatments-researchers-say"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Group of scientists contest privacy concerns that they say are hampering research into illnesses such as long Covid 
Researchers have said they could struggle to find new treatments for conditions dealt with by GPs, from long Covid to depression, if they cannot get access to the patient data held by GPs because of concerns over privacy.
 Related: Why has the NHS patient data-sharing scheme been pushed back? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid traffic light system could cost UK airports £2.6bn this summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/covid-traffic-light-system-uk-airports-summer-airline</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/10/covid-traffic-light-system-uk-airports-summer-airline"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airline industry renews call for support and warns coming months could take heavier toll than 2020
The UK aviation sector has warned that airports are likely to lose at least £2.6bn this summer as the “chaotic” Covid traffic light system halts international travel.
Airports said the coming months could deal a heavier financial blow than 2020, while airlines called for grants to offset the impact of travel restrictions and protect jobs.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham  Transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 21: France]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/euro-2020-team-guides-part-21-france</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/10/euro-2020-team-guides-part-21-france"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world champions do not always dazzle but they usually win, and Karim Benzema’s return could make them even more formidable
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
France’s record (W10 D2 L1) since they qualified for the Euros speaks for itself, especially since the sole defeat came in a friendly against Finland in which Didier Deschamps played his second string. The quality of play and entertainment levels have been questionable but when it comes to key games, the world champions keep winning with their typical collective self-belief, clinical finishing and individual flair.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Urbini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPs attack plan to give housebuilders freedom to build over ‘growth’ zones]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/mps-attack-plan-to-give-housebuilders-freedom-to-build-over-growth-zones</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/10/mps-attack-plan-to-give-housebuilders-freedom-to-build-over-growth-zones"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Public must retain rights to object to planning applications, ministers told
A radical government plan to give housebuilders freedom to build over designated “growth” zones has been attacked by MPs who have told ministers the public must retain rights to object to planning applications.
Boris Johnson included in last month’s Queen’s speech plans to bring forward the biggest overhaul of England’s planning system since the second world war. Its boldest idea was to remove the need for detailed planning applications for buildings in designated growth zones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firms on UK Covid test provider list misleading travellers, Which? says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/firms-on-uk-covid-test-provider-list-misleading-travellers-which-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/10/firms-on-uk-covid-test-provider-list-misleading-travellers-which-says"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prices quoted for tests that do not meet travel requirements, and some firms unable to provide tests

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Travellers requiring Covid-19 tests have been misled by firms that appear on the government’s official list of test providers, according to a consumer group.
Prices were quoted for tests that did not meet the requirements for travel, and some firms were unable to provide the tests they advertised, Which? said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham transport correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sexual harassment is a routine part of life, schoolchildren tell Ofsted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/sexual-harassment-is-a-routine-part-of-life-schoolchildren-tell-ofsted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/10/sexual-harassment-is-a-routine-part-of-life-schoolchildren-tell-ofsted"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pupils say incidents in school and online are too common to bother challenging or reporting

Schoolchildren have told Ofsted inspectors that sexual harassment and online sexual abuse are such a routine part of their daily lives they don’t see any point in challenging or reporting it.
Girls suffer disproportionately, complaining of sexist name-calling, online abuse, upskirting, unwanted touching in school corridors and rape jokes on the school bus. Boys share nude pictures on WhatsApp and Snapchat “like a collection game”, inspectors were told.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sally Weale Education correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t feed the ducks: royal parks warn of bullying bird behaviour after lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/dont-feed-the-ducks-royal-parks-warn-bullying-birds-lockdown-london-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/10/dont-feed-the-ducks-royal-parks-warn-bullying-birds-lockdown-london-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:01:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: excessive feeding as visitors flocked to London’s green spaces has led to overcrowding, disease and pollution
London’s royal parks are urging visitors to stop feeding bread to ducks because it is causing overcrowding and bullying among birds, the Guardian can reveal.
A campaign launching today highlights how excessive feeding upsets fragile ecosystems, leading to large groups of aggressive gulls and crows that steal the eggs and chicks of other birds. Leftover food also attracts rats, and soggy bread and waterfowl faeces contaminate the water.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Weston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK lost £16bn in tax revenues over nine years under Conservatives, says Labour]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/uk-lost-16bn-in-tax-revenues-over-nine-years-under-conservatives-says-labour</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/10/uk-lost-16bn-in-tax-revenues-over-nine-years-under-conservatives-says-labour"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T23:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Party shifts narrative to put focus on how ‘decade of Tory misspending’ has weakened economy
The UK lost £16.7bn in tax revenues over nine years of slow growth under the Conservatives, figures unearthed by Labour show, as the party seeks to underline the economic effects of the Tories in office.
Labour, under the new shadow chancellor, Rachel Reeves, hopes to build a narrative about “a decade of Tory misspending” which would undermine Boris Johnson’s levelling-up rhetoric.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uproar after Argentina president says ‘Brazilians came from the jungle’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/argentina-president-comments-uproar</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/argentina-president-comments-uproar"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T22:42:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Misjudged comments to prime minister of Spain sought to play up the South American country’s ties with Europe
Argentina’s president, Alberto Fernández, has triggered a Twitter storm and a regional race debate with misjudged comments to visiting Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez of Spain that sought to play up the South American country’s ties with Europe.
“The Mexicans came from the Indians, the Brazilians came from the jungle, but we Argentines came from the ships. And they were ships that came from Europe,” Fernández said, referring to the many European migrants who arrived in the country. He later apologized for the comments and said his country’s diversity was something to be proud of.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Buenos Aires</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Djokovic shuts out French Open silence and boos to set up Nadal semi-final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/novak-djokovic-battles-past-berrettini-to-set-up-french-open-semi-final-with-nadal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/novak-djokovic-battles-past-berrettini-to-set-up-french-open-semi-final-with-nadal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T22:15:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World No 1 beats Matteo Berrettini 6-3, 6-2, 6-7 (5), 7-5 
Fans urged to leave court before finish due to national curfew

Novak Djokovic moved into the semi-finals at Roland Garros for a 58th showdown with Rafael Nadal, surviving a third-set hiccup to beat Matteo Berrettini 6-3, 6-2, 6-7 (5), 7-5 in a match soundtracked by cheers and silence after the players were forced to leave the court so spectators could be persuaded to go home as the national curfew approached.
A rowdy crowd had convened for the first night session with fans allowed at this year’s tournament due to the relaxation of restrictions in France and a later 11pm curfew. Although they roared for his opponent, they witnessed Djokovic tear past Berrettini with relative ease for much of the match as he established a two-set lead. The world No 1 then conceded only three points on his serve to set up a third-set tie-break.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Slums of Mumbai to a Rented Apartment – My 30-Year Developer Journey]]></title>
        <id>60b357ad11ffb70827ef9a90</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/my-journey-into-tech-from-slums-of-mumbai-to-my-own-apartment/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:55:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year I tweeted about how I was moving from a Slum where I lived for 29 years to a multi-story rented apartment.  The tech community on Twitter responded with nothing but love. Dan Wahlin posted that he would love to hear more about my story. It's not going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden declares the ‘US is back’ and urges democracies to stand together]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/biden-declares-the-us-is-back-and-urges-democracies-to-stand-together</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/biden-declares-the-us-is-back-and-urges-democracies-to-stand-together"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:40:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US president rings changes since Trump but has a serious message on Northern Ireland peace process

Joe Biden has stressed the need for the world’s democracies to stand together as he arrived in the UK on his first overseas trip as US president.
Biden will meet Boris Johnson in Cornwall on Thursday ahead of the G7 summit and is expected to deliver a warning not to let the Brexit trade dispute “imperil” the Northern Ireland peace process.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fear and anger in Canada after Muslim family is killed: ‘How many more people have to die?’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/canada-muslim-family-killed-islamophobia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/canada-muslim-family-killed-islamophobia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mourners attend vigil to honour four members of Afzaal family who were killed in a truck attack Sunday night in London, Ontario
As thousands of people gathered outside Canada’s second-largest mosque in London, Ontario, Reina Persaud was watching her niece and other children chalking brightly-coloured hearts all over the road.
The “pathway of hearts” was a tribute to the Afzaals, a local Muslim family, who every evening would take a walk around the neighbourhood, greeting neighbours and friends – and who were killed on Sunday in what police have described as a premeditated attack motivated by Islamophobia.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fatima Syed in London, Ontario</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in five Britons considering holiday to amber-list country]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/one-in-five-britons-considering-holiday-to-amber-list-country</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/one-in-five-britons-considering-holiday-to-amber-list-country"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Survey finds willingness to consider trip to countries such as Spain increases to a third among young people

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

One in five people are still considering taking a holiday to foreign countries on England’s amber list, including Spain and Greece, despite stringent testing and quarantine requirements, polling has revealed.
The willingness to consider going to restricted destinations increases to a third of 18- to 24-year-olds, despite them being the least likely to be vaccinated, a survey by Survation showed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Miles from Modric’: Declan Rice’s rise from fanzone to England leader | David Hytner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/miles-from-modric-declan-rices-rise-from-fanzone-to-england-leader</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/miles-from-modric-declan-rices-rise-from-fanzone-to-england-leader"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The midfielder is excited to tussle with Croatia’s talisman on Sunday after watching him topple Southgate’s side in 2018
Declan Rice has a confession and it is one that greatly troubled his small audience of newspaper journalists. “Do you know what – until this day, I have never had a beer and I am 22,” the West Ham and England midfielder says. “That is the truth, never had a pint. Don’t drink it.”
Well, you can imagine the scene. Astonishment, soul-searching. Does he ever drink at all? Maybe a spirit here and there, Rice replies. “But a pint? No,” he continues. “People get surprised. I just don’t like the smell of it so I have never gone near it. Will I have one if we win the Euros? Yes. I’ll give it a try – but I will probably spit it out.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US-UK to sign post-Covid Atlantic charter in echo of wartime accord]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/us-uk-to-sign-post-covid-atlantic-charter-in-hint-at-second-world-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/us-uk-to-sign-post-covid-atlantic-charter-in-hint-at-second-world-war"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Johnson and Biden will meet at G7 to sign new version of 1941 document focusing on modern challenges
Boris Johnson and Joe Biden will draw comparisons to Winston Churchill and Franklin D Roosevelt by signing a new Atlantic charter in an attempt to show UK and US leadership can frame a post-Covid order in the same way the 1941 charter signed by the two leaders prefigured a new world order after the second world war.
The symbolic signing of a new version of the Atlantic charter will take place at the first in-person bilateral meeting between the two leaders since Biden became president, and comes before the critical summit of G7 leaders in Cornwall.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US agrees to buy 500m Pfizer vaccine doses to distribute to 100 countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/us-biden-vaccines-pfizer-global-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/us-biden-vaccines-pfizer-global-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T21:17:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s initiative aims to help vaccinate the world against Covid and to restore America’s global influence and soft power
The US has reached an agreement with Pfizer to buy 500m doses of their coronavirus vaccine to distribute to nearly 100 countries around the world, as the centrepiece of Joe Biden’s initiative to help vaccinate the world against Covid-19, according to US reports.
 Related: Vaccine inequality exposed by dire situation in world’s poorest nations 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Cornucopia of Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340967</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-cornucopia-of-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:37:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t know about y’all, but my feeds have been flooded with articles about CSS Container Queries these past few weeks. The buzz about container queries actually started back in December after Miriam Suzanne posted a proposal (picking up on …
The post A Cornucopia of Container Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tottenham in advanced talks with Paulo Fonseca over manager’s role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/totteham-in-advanced-talks-with-paulo-fonseca-over-managers-role</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/totteham-in-advanced-talks-with-paulo-fonseca-over-managers-role"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T20:09:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Roma manager offered three-year deal
Fonseca open to Premier League move

Tottenham are in advanced negotiations with Paulo Fonseca after the former Roma manager was identified as the club’s preferred option to succeed José Mourinho.
The 48-year-old Portuguese, who left Roma in May and was replaced by Mourinho, is understood to have held talks with the Spurs hierarchy about a three-year contract having been recommended by the club’s new director of football, Fabio Paratici. Fonseca is believed to be open to moving to north London having previously managed Shakhtar Donetsk in Ukraine for three years before moving to the Stadio Olimpico in 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Romano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU-UK talks on Northern Ireland appear close to collapse on eve of G7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/eu-uk-talks-to-resolve-northern-ireland-crisis-end-without-agreement</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/eu-uk-talks-to-resolve-northern-ireland-crisis-end-without-agreement"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:56:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Patience wearing very thin,’ says EU negotiator, while Joe Biden expected to raise ‘deep concerns’ about issue at summit 

Talks between the EU and the UK over Northern Ireland appear on the brink of collapse as London indicated it was still considering unilateral action to keep unhindered supplies flowing from Great Britain into the region.
The European commission vice-president, Maroš Šefčovič, said patience was “wearing very, very thin” and described the relationship with the UK as “at a crossroads”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lisa O'Carroll and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FSB agents who tracked Navalny before poisoning also tailed author – Bellingcat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/fsb-agents-who-tracked-navalny-before-poisoning-also-tailed-author-bellingcat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/fsb-agents-who-tracked-navalny-before-poisoning-also-tailed-author-bellingcat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:55:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Open-source investigations report that the agents shadowed Dmitry Bykov, who fell severely ill with similar symptoms in 2019
Russian agents who had tailed opposition leader Alexei Navalny before his poisoning also shadowed a journalist who had earlier fallen severely ill with similar symptoms, according to the investigative organisation Bellingcat.
Dmitry Bykov, an author and journalist who is an outspoken critic of President Vladimir Putin, spent five days in a coma after he became sick aboard an aeroplane while on a lecture tour in 2019.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>AP in Moscow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Hancock ‘was warned of Covid care home risk in March 2020’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/matt-hancock-was-warned-of-covid-care-home-risk-in-march-2020</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/matt-hancock-was-warned-of-covid-care-home-risk-in-march-2020"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:54:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: leading UK operators say they repeatedly raised concerns about not testing people discharged from hospital

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Some of the UK’s biggest care home operators have told the Guardian they repeatedly warned Matt Hancock’s department about the risk of not testing people discharged from hospitals into care homes in March 2020.
Their claims are likely to increase pressure on the health secretary when he appears before MPs on Thursday to defend his handling of the Covid pandemic to a parliamentary inquiry.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Skills You Need to Start Freelancing as a Developer]]></title>
        <id>60c0ccbed3126007592d5781</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-skills-you-need-to-start-freelancing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:45:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here's the bottom line: you don't need much to get started as a freelance developer.  The biggest obstacle developers face when they're thinking about getting started is that they tend to overcomplicate things.  Most are intimidated by the sheer number of different paths or skills deemed necessary by various blog]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Republican asks: can we fix the moon’s orbit to fight climate change?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/texas-republican-louie-gohmert-climate-change</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/texas-republican-louie-gohmert-climate-change"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’d have to follow up with you on that one,’ says forestry official Jennifer Eberlien to bizarre question from Louie Gohmert
The Texas Republican congressman Louie Gohmert has asked a senior US government official if changing the moon’s orbit around the Earth, or the Earth’s orbit around the sun, might be a solution for climate change.
Bizarrely, the question was not posed to anyone from Nasa or even the Pentagon. Instead it was asked of a senior forestry service official during a House natural resources committee hearing on Tuesday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris suffers bumpy baptism over immigration on first foreign trip]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/kamala-harris-immigration-foreign-trip</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/kamala-harris-immigration-foreign-trip"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:34:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice-president’s ‘get tough’ stance on corruption overshadowed by backlash over ‘do not come’ message to migrants
Kamala Harris has returned to the US from her first foreign trip and big test since becoming vice-president – and taking over the hot-potato issue of immigration – battered by criticism over her harsh “Do not come” message to desperate migrants and her testy ambivalence over visiting the US-Mexico border.
Harris arrived back on US soil from a three-day trip to Guatemala and Mexico just as Joe Biden flew out to the UK on Wednesday on his first overseas venture since winning the White House.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colorado records first litter of gray wolf pups since 1940s]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/colorado-first-gray-wolf-pups-since-1940s</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/colorado-first-gray-wolf-pups-since-1940s"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:26:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least three pups spotted with parents
State’s voters backed reintroduction of wolves to public lands

Colorado has its first litter of gray wolf pups since the 1940s, state wildlife officials said on Wednesday.
A state biologist and district wildlife manager both spotted the litter of at least three wolf pups over the weekend with their parents, two adult wolves known to live in the state. Most wolf litters have four to six pups, so there could be more.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fashion chain Gap to close 19 stores in the UK and Ireland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/09/fashion-chain-gap-to-close-19-stores-in-the-uk-and-ireland</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/09/fashion-chain-gap-to-close-19-stores-in-the-uk-and-ireland"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T19:01:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US-owned chain has not yet said which stores will close or how many jobs will be lost
Fashion chain Gap is to close 19 stores in the UK and Ireland as the coronavirus pandemic continues to take its toll on the high street, while a distribution centre in Rugby remains at risk.
A spokesperson confirmed that the US-owned chain had decided not to renew store leases that expire next month, in a retrenchment that follows a strategic review of its European presence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IOC pledges to source doctors from all over globe to keep Tokyo Olympics safe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/ioc-pledges-to-source-doctors-from-around-globe-to-keep-tokyo-olympics-safe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/ioc-pledges-to-source-doctors-from-around-globe-to-keep-tokyo-olympics-safe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:53:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Offer comes amid concern of huge pressure on medical services
Number of spectators at Games to be decided by end of June

The International Olympic Committee has offered to source as many doctors and nurses as needed from around the globe to ensure the Tokyo Olympics is safe – and to help Japan fight a fourth wave of Covid infections.
The IOC’s pledge comes amid mounting concern in Japan that having 70,000 athletes, officials, journalists and support staff arriving into the country could act as super‑spreaders for new variants and put huge pressure on medical services.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid contract case throws light on government’s relationship with truth]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/covid-contract-case-throws-light-on-governments-relationship-with-truth</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/covid-contract-case-throws-light-on-governments-relationship-with-truth"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rather than apologise after defeat, the government issued a statement at odds even with its own case

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Cronyism will be the main accusation made against the government after the high court ruling that the Cabinet Office acted unlawfully, with “apparent bias,” when it awarded a contract last March to a company run by long-term associates of Michael Gove and Dominic Cummings.
But the Good Law Project’s victory, and the Cabinet Office tumult during the pandemic that it exposed, has raised another fundamental question about integrity: the government’s relationship with the truth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Bootstrap 5 and SASS by Building a Portfolio Website]]></title>
        <id>60c10a1dd3126007592d5988</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-bootstrap-5-and-sass-by-building-a-portfolio-website/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrap is one of the most popular CSS frameworks and Sass is one of the most popular preprocessors for CSS. We just released a course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel that will teach you about Bootstrap 5 and Sass by building a portfolio website. Patrick Muriungi developed this course.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German police officers dismissed over alleged online Nazi content]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/german-police-officers-dismissed-over-alleged-online-nazi-content</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/german-police-officers-dismissed-over-alleged-online-nazi-content"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nineteen sacked and one suspended from commando unit after chat groups found during separate investigation
German prosecutors have dismissed 19 police officers in a commando unit and suspended another over claims they glorified violence and made references to a former Nazi organisation in online chats, a spokesperson said on Wednesday.
Investigators in the western state of Hesse found out about the 20 suspects in the course of a separate investigation of an officer in the same commando unit, known as SEK, who was suspected of sharing child sexual abuse images.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Martin Rowson on Brexit, sausages and Northern Ireland – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/09/martin-rowson-on-brexit-sausages-and-northern-ireland-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/09/martin-rowson-on-brexit-sausages-and-northern-ireland-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Rowson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Morrisons chief risks ire of shareholders over £1.7m pandemic bonus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/09/morrisons-chief-shareholders-pandemic-bonus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/nils-pratley-on-finance/2021/jun/09/morrisons-chief-shareholders-pandemic-bonus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bonus schemes grant huge upsides to executives in good years. The system has to be seen to work in reverse in leaner times
This week’s pay row comes at Morrisons. Or, at least, one assumes a few of the supermarket group’s shareholders will rouse themselves to protest against the remuneration committee’s dubious manoeuvre on executive bonuses.
The pandemic was not the executives’ fault, runs Morrisons’ argument, thus bosses should get a full 100% bonus whack even though profits halved in the year. In effect, the committee added back £290m of Covid-related costs to the profits line and declared a triumph.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nils Pratley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skeletons of Viking men to be reunited in Danish exhibition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/09/skeletons-of-viking-men-to-be-reunited-in-danish-exhibition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jun/09/skeletons-of-viking-men-to-be-reunited-in-danish-exhibition"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:29:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DNA tests on ancient bones show men were related and died following violent incidents
The skeletons of two Viking age men who were related but died on opposite sides of the North Sea are to be reunited in an exhibition in Copenhagen this month.
DNA tests on the ancient bones suggest the men were either half-brothers or a nephew and an uncle, according to Prof Eske Willerslev, a Danish evolutionary geneticist based at the University of Cambridge. Both of the Norsemen died following violent incidents.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Sample Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alyssa: Memoirs of a Queen review – ego fest with a helping of humility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/09/alyssa-memoirs-of-a-queen-review-vaudeville-rupaul</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/09/alyssa-memoirs-of-a-queen-review-vaudeville-rupaul"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:12:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vaudeville theatre, London
RuPaul’s Drag Race star Alyssa Edwards rampages into the West End and has an easy way with the crowd
“My favourite subject is talking about me,” Alyssa Edwards tells us – so she must really be enjoying her West End show, in which she does nothing but. Memoirs of a Queen traces Alyssa’s journey from childhood in Mesquite, Texas, to reality TV apotheosis, via coming-out tales, Miss America contests and abundant RuPaul’s Drag Race chit-chat. None of it is very surprising, and the backstage gossip would test the patience of all but the most ardent Drag Race devotees. But Edwards – AKA Justin Johnson – is a likably unpretentious host and, as you’d expect from the self-described “Steven Spielberg of dance”, the choreography catches the eye.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Logan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Edgbaston provides chance for Root and England to change the mood | Ali Martin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/edgbaston-provides-chance-for-root-and-england-to-change-the-mood</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/edgbaston-provides-chance-for-root-and-england-to-change-the-mood"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:08:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After Ollie Robinson and the Lord’s draw, the home team have the opportunity to be viewed positively against New Zealand
English cricket has not exactly seen eye to eye with the government this week but they join forces at Edgbaston for a pilot scheme in which 17,000 spectators will be in attendance for each day of the second Test between England and New Zealand that starts on Thursday. With this comes a pledge from Joe Root that his side will look to put on a show.
Root’s players have faced heavy questioning over the Ollie Robinson affair during the buildup – as ever they face the media when crisis descends, while the senior administrators hide behind statements – but beyond this thorny subject there have been queries about the lack of intent shown on Sunday at Lord’s.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bale does Baku: Wales a long way from home as Euro 2020 warmup hots up | Ben Fisher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/bale-does-baku-wales-a-long-way-from-home-for-euro-2020-warmup</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/09/bale-does-baku-wales-a-long-way-from-home-for-euro-2020-warmup"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T18:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They are preparing for Switzerland on Saturday with 30C training sessions but cards, table tennis, and F1 video games are helping Wales chill out
The scene where Max Verstappen’s Formula One car veered into the safety barriers at 200mph on Baku’s street circuit last Sunday is in full view from Wales’s base on the promenade and, up in their hotel rooms, players have been gearing up for the start of the European Championship by going full throttle on the F1 PlayStation game, inspired by the Netflix series Drive to Survive.
“We all ordered our own steering wheels and pedals,” says the defender Chris Mepham. “There are seven or eight of us involved. Jonny Williams did one race but was never to be seen again ... he wasn’t great. It’s a good laugh and it’s something that puts a smile on our face.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Fisher in Baku</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on hosting the G7: to Biden, Britain is still Europe | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/the-guardian-view-on-hosting-the-g7-to-biden-britain-is-still-europe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/the-guardian-view-on-hosting-the-g7-to-biden-britain-is-still-europe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:59:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s diplomatic priority should be repairing relations with the UK’s continental neighbours
It is a stroke of good luck for Boris Johnson that Britain is hosting this year’s G7 summit. As chair of the club for rich democracies, the prime minister’s centrality to the proceedings is guaranteed. He is first in line to meet Joe Biden, who flies in to Cornwall on Wednesday for his first official foreign trip as US president.
The choreography flatters Mr Johnson, casting him as America’s point man in Europe. That is the role that the UK traditionally sees for itself in transatlantic relations. The truth is more complicated. Leaving the EU removes Britain’s influence in Brussels, which diminishes its utility to Washington as a bridge to the rest of the continent. President Biden sees Brexit as strategic ineptitude, sowing gratuitous division among countries that the US would rather see united.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the super-rich: a billion reasons for a wealth tax | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/the-guardian-view-on-the-super-rich-a-billion-reasons-for-a-wealth-tax</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/the-guardian-view-on-the-super-rich-a-billion-reasons-for-a-wealth-tax"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:59:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When America’s richest are paying proportionately less in tax than those struggling from paycheck to paycheck, the tax system demands a radical overhaul
This week, Jeff Bezos announced his plan to become the first billionaire in space. Next month, on the 52nd anniversary of the launch of Apollo 11, he will fly about 100 km above the rest of us, see the curve of the Earth and experience a few minutes of weightlessness, before a final descent. As a metaphor for the relationship between the super-rich and everyone else, it does not come much better. What also takes some beating is the justification from the world’s richest person for living out the sci-fi dreams he had as a boy: he has so much money he doesn’t know how to spend it.
“The only way that I can see to deploy this much financial resource is by converting my Amazon winnings into space travel,” he said in 2018. “That is basically it.” To which the possible counter-suggestions might include: pay your workers more. Or perhaps: pay higher taxes. Because the other big bit of Bezos news this week is that in 2007 and 2011 the multi-billionaire did not pay a cent in US federal income tax. He was in good company: in 2018 Elon Musk of Tesla also paid no federal income taxes. Michael Bloomberg, Carl Icahn and George Soros are also all recent members of the zero club.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rose Callaghan: the 10 funniest things I have ever seen (on the internet)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/rose-callaghan-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/10/rose-callaghan-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:30:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We asked professional funny people what makes them laugh, and where we can find it online. Here are Rose Callaghan’s tips
Hello, I’m comedian and internet aficionado Rose Callaghan. I have ADHD and am what many would consider “underemployed” so obviously spend most of my time on the internet arguing with people on Twitter and watching TikToks.
I live and breathe the internet and unfortunately/sadly haven’t been able to stop posting since I first created an account on LiveJournal in the year 2002.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rose Callaghan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blushing bridegroom Boris Johnson is not wedded to reality | John Crace]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/blushing-bridegroom-boris-johnson-is-not-wedded-to-reality</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/blushing-bridegroom-boris-johnson-is-not-wedded-to-reality"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:23:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Riding his wave, the PM swats away questions, and the protests of lefties such as Theresa May
Don’t mention the sausage war! With Brexit a no-go zone despite the recent escalation in tension between the UK and the EU over the Northern Ireland protocol, Labour’s official position on the subject appears to be not to have one. Hoping that the cold-cut war would somehow resolve itself and disappear, Keir Starmer chose to go in on the much safer ground of education at prime minister’s questions. Though not before first congratulating Boris Johnson on having recently got married.
The prime minister didn’t seem best pleased to be reminded. Maybe the thought of having had to pay for the ceremony and reception out of his own pocket is still too raw. Rather than accepting the tribute gracefully, he just stared down at the floor in embarrassment and ignored it. It’s just possible that the man who, according to a recent profile in the Atlantic magazine, sees life and politics as a series of stories has yet to come up with a narrative for his new marriage. He wouldn’t be the only one.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Crace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Profits from English children’s care homes indefensible, bosses to be told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/profit-levels-in-childrens-care-homes-in-england-indefensible-bosses-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/profit-levels-in-childrens-care-homes-in-england-indefensible-bosses-told"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:09:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Head of government review of sector will urge private operators to cut costs and be responsive to children’s needs
The children’s residential care home sector is “broken” and dominated by private companies that rack up excessive profits despite delivering consistently poor outcomes for young people, a government adviser is to say.
Josh MacAlister, the head of the government’s review of children’s social care, will warn children’s homes bosses they must cut “indefensible” profits and improve the experience of young people in care or run the risk of intervention.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Butler Social policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China the spectre at the feast as Biden aims to rally democracies on Europe trip]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/joe-biden-china-g7-xi-jinping-democracies</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/09/joe-biden-china-g7-xi-jinping-democracies"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:07:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The US president has become convinced that Beijing is the main adversary in a global battle of governance systems
The unifying theme behind Joe Biden’s European tour this week is a country which will not be at any of the meetings and may not even be mentioned in the final communiques: China.
Before setting out on his first foreign trip as president, Biden has made clear that the competition between the world’s democracies and its authoritarian regimes – mostly importantly Beijing – is the defining global challenge of the age, with victory anything but guaranteed for the US and its allies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Koepka says DeChambeau feud good for golf and will not harm US’s Ryder Cup]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/koepka-says-dechambeu-feud-good-for-golf-and-will-not-harm-uss-ryder-cup</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/09/koepka-says-dechambeu-feud-good-for-golf-and-will-not-harm-uss-ryder-cup"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four-time major insists spat is growing the game’s appeal
‘What you do off the course doesn’t have any effect on it’

Brooks Koepka has insisted his feud with Bryson DeChambeau will not hinder the US team’s Ryder Cup chances. Koepka even claimed the public spat between two of golf’s star names is “good for the game” owing to the interest it has generated.
A leaked video of Koepka being disparaging towards DeChambeau emerged after the recent US PGA Championship. The two players subsequently traded blows on social media, with Koepka promoting a free beer opportunity for anybody who was ejected from the Memorial Tournament last weekend for shouting his name at DeChambeau. In response, DeChambeau implied Koepka should be disciplined by the PGA Tour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ewan Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boundary tinkering won’t fix a broken electoral system | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/boundary-tinkering-wont-fix-a-broken-electoral-system</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/boundary-tinkering-wont-fix-a-broken-electoral-system"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T16:35:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forget redrawing constituency boundaries, just implement proportional representation, writes Alan Fowler. Plus letters from Phil Tate and David Nowell
Electoral demographics are changing dramatically and yet the Boundary Commission is busily shuffling deckchairs while the ship of democracy lies becalmed (UK electoral officials announce biggest shake-up of boundaries in decades, 8 June).
While it attends to the arithmetical niceties of rejigging electoral boundaries, in an attempt to ensure that they all contain around 73,400 constituents each, the fact remains that, due to the distortions of our first-past-the-post voting system, these changes will do nothing whatsoever to correct the absurdity of the existing democratic deficit, and may actually make it worse.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple sightings of missile launcher before MH17 shot down, court told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/multiple-sightings-of-missile-launcher-before-mh17-shot-down-court-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/multiple-sightings-of-missile-launcher-before-mh17-shot-down-court-told"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T16:34:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four men on trial in absentia in the Netherlands over downing of flight with 298 onboard over Ukraine
Multiple witnesses saw an anti-aircraft missile launcher that had secretly crossed into eastern Ukraine from Russia in the hours before it shot down the Malaysia Airlines flight MH17, a trial in the Netherlands has heard.
The Buk system crossed the border in darkness in the early hours of 17 July 2014. It was then loaded on to a trailer and taken to the rebel-held city of Donetsk, the court heard on Wednesday, before it headed east towards the town of Snizhne.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The adoption system isn’t perfect, but it has evolved to protect children | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/the-adoption-system-isnt-perfect-but-it-has-evolved-to-protect-children</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/the-adoption-system-isnt-perfect-but-it-has-evolved-to-protect-children"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T16:28:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anne Porteous shares her perspective on forced adoptions, and Linda Weir and Ann Titman highlight charity work that supports families 
I read Nina Lopez’s letter (1 June) on adoption with sadness, both because of the example she gave and also because she doesn’t tell the whole story around adoption today. “Forced” is an emotive term and that applies appropriately to those adoptions of the 1960s and 1970s. That 90% of adoptions are forced – ie court ordered – is not surprising, given that few children are relinquished (or given up) for adoption these days. Fortunately, parents are not forced to give up their children because they are born out of wedlock. They might be forced if the child in question is being harmed, or likely to be harmed and cannot be placed within the family. Practice has undoubtedly changed since the 1960s, thank goodness. It has evolved to protect children, not to make discriminatory and unfair judgments on parents.
That is not to say mistakes aren’t made. They are, and Lopez gives a clear example of what appears to be very bad practice. But in my 17 years as a social worker specialising in adoption in local authorities, I saw nothing like that occur. The courts might be a closed system, but my many years’ experience of them were generally positive – judges were very aware of the enormity of the decisions they were making.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From rule of six to 6,500 police: Cornwall hosts first Covid-era G7]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/from-rule-of-six-to-6500-police-cornwall-hosts-first-covid-era-g7</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/from-rule-of-six-to-6500-police-cornwall-hosts-first-covid-era-g7"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T16:12:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alongside coronavirus measures, huge security operation under way as thousands plan to join protests
Everybody from the most junior official to the president of the United States will have to follow the rules. Take daily Covid tests, wear masks at appropriate times and respect everything from one-way systems around venues to limits on how many people can gather around a table for a meal or drink.
Welcome to G7 UK 2021, the first world summit in the times of Covid.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Morris and Patrick Wintour</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU takes legal action against Germany after tussle between courts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/eu-launches-legal-case-against-germany-over-alleged-breach-of-eu-law-primacy-principle</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/eu-launches-legal-case-against-germany-over-alleged-breach-of-eu-law-primacy-principle"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:49:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brussels says German court ruling contradicting ECJ sets ‘dangerous precedent’ for integrity of EU law
Brussels has launched a legal case against Germany over an alleged breach of “the principle of the primacy of EU law” by the country’s constitutional court.
The “infringement proceeding” is the result of a ruling last year by the German federal constitutional court in Karlsruhe which it is claimed undermined the pre-eminence of the European court of justice (ECJ).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Euro 96 can teach us about life | Adrian Chiles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/make-life-easy-for-those-around-you-and-grind-through-the-tricky-bits-what-euro-96-can-teach-us-about-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/make-life-easy-for-those-around-you-and-grind-through-the-tricky-bits-what-euro-96-can-teach-us-about-life"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:47:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, I met England football greats Tony Adams and Teddy Sheringham to talk about the historic tournament. But I left with some lessons that go far beyond football
Warning: I am about to bang on about football. Reassurance: it’s not really about football.
Players and ex-players are forever finding new ways of disappointing me and impressing me. Last week, it was the latter. I got to speak at length with a couple of key figures in the famous European Championships of 25 years ago, during which England were surprisingly brilliant until, unsurprisingly, going out to the Germans on penalties. I went to get their memories of Euro 96 but came away with something extra. From Tony Adams, who by then was in absolute crisis with his drinking, I heard how for that tournament he managed to get on the wagon, white-knuckled, one last time to be the team captain they all revered. From Teddy Sheringham, I got what I can only describe as four lessons in life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Chiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Colbert on Capitol riot report: ‘Exactly what you thought, but worse than you imagined’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/09/stephen-colbert-capitol-riot-trevor-noah-jimmy-kimmel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/09/stephen-colbert-capitol-riot-trevor-noah-jimmy-kimmel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:44:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Late-night hosts discuss the Senate’s report on security failures on 6 January, Bitcoin’s declining value and swarms of cicadas
“The country is slowly emerging from a crisis that gripped not just America but the entire globe,” said Stephen Colbert on Tuesday evening, “and we’re still surveying the damage of this unprecedented plague that lost to Joe Biden on November 3.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Horton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Amazon rainforest angel: Claudia Andujar’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/09/amazon-rainforest-angel-claudia-andujars-best-photograph-yanomami</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/09/amazon-rainforest-angel-claudia-andujars-best-photograph-yanomami"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:34:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘When I first visited the Yanomami tribe, they were completely isolated – they hadn’t seen a camera and didn’t know what photography was’

It was 1971 when I photographed the Yanomami tribe of Brazil for the first time. I knew that it would take time to build our relationship, but I wanted to see if we could become friends. For me, the best photographers are those who are truly interested in their subjects.
The Yanomami is a big population of indigenous people who live in the Amazon rainforest in northern Brazil and southern Venezuela; several thousand live in Brazil alone. A small village can be as few as 40 people, or a big one as many as 200. When I first went to the Yanomami villages, the tribe was completely isolated – some still are today. At that time, 50 years ago, they hadn’t seen a camera and didn’t even know what photography was.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Henry Yates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What a Croc! Why has Balenciaga ruined the world’s most practical shoes?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/09/what-a-croc-why-has-balenciaga-ruined-the-worlds-most-practical-shoes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jun/09/what-a-croc-why-has-balenciaga-ruined-the-worlds-most-practical-shoes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:12:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not just plastic clogs that are being elevated right now – flip-flops, trainers and hiking boots all have heels right now. And just when we were all yearning for comfort
Name: Balenciaga Crocs.
Age: Super new. Not even out yet.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brabham review – bumpy portrait of old-school F1 legend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/09/brabham-review-bumpy-portrait-of-old-school-f1-legend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/09/brabham-review-bumpy-portrait-of-old-school-f1-legend"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T15:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Australian motor sports champion’s ‘elbows out’ track style and difficult personality come through in this thorny documentary 
This is a documentary about Australian motor sports legend Jack Brabham that aims to finesse the usual greatest-hits highlights by including some darker material: family strife, on-track bad behaviour, behind-the-scenes fallouts.
Brabham remains best known for being the only Formula One driver to win the world title in a car of their own construction, and this profile makes much of his engineering skills and constant tinkering in the workshop. He also raced throughout the sport’s most dangerous era – see the jaw-dropping BBC documentary Grand Prix: The Killer Years – with apparently barely a scratch, though there are some amusing shots of Brabham being forced to push his car over the line after running out of fuel on a number of occasions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Pulver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid distancing may have weakened children’s immune system, experts say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/covid-distancing-may-have-weakened-childrens-immune-system-experts-say</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/covid-distancing-may-have-weakened-childrens-immune-system-experts-say"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:49:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[End of social distancing and mask-wearing could leave children vulnerable to common bugs

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Scientists are concerned that measures to combat Covid-19 have weakened the immune systems of young children who have not been able to build up resistance to common bugs, leaving them vulnerable when mask-wearing and social distancing eventually end.
Contact with viral pathogens happens on a fairly regular basis and although it does not always lead to sickness, the exposure helps shore the immune system against the threat should the bugs be encountered again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[target=blank]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341916</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/targetblank/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Does that make your eye twitch a little bit? Like… it’s a typo. It should be target="_blank" with an underscore to start the value. As in…
<a target="_blank" href="https://codepen.io"Open CodePen in a New Tab
</a
Welp, that’s correct syntax!…
The post target=blank appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MPs demand proof of Hancock claims from Dominic Cummings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/mps-demand-proof-of-hancock-claims-from-dominic-cummings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/09/mps-demand-proof-of-hancock-claims-from-dominic-cummings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:37:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chair of committee that heard former No 10 adviser’s explosive allegations says it hasn’t received the evidence it was expecting

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

MPs have written to Dominic Cummings demanding that he provide proof for a number of serious allegations against the health secretary, Matt Hancock, who will face a parliamentary inquiry on Thursday.
Cummings, who left his post as Boris Johnson’s most senior aide last year, spoke to a joint committee inquiry into lessons learned from the Covid outbreak last month where he repeatedly said Hancock should have been sacked for incompetence and dishonesty.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oxford University Press to end centuries of tradition by closing its printing arm]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/09/oxford-university-press-to-end-centuries-of-tradition-by-closing-its-printing-arm</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/09/oxford-university-press-to-end-centuries-of-tradition-by-closing-its-printing-arm"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:27:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Falling sales blamed as 20 jobs axed in final chapter for history of printing in the city, which stretches back to the earliest days of book publishing 

Oxford University’s right to print books was first recognised in 1586, in a decree from the Star Chamber. But the centuries-old printing history of Oxford University Press will end this summer, after the publishing house announced the last vestige of its printing arm was closing.
The closure of Oxuniprint, which will take place on 27 August subject to consultation with employees, will result in the loss of 20 jobs. OUP said it follows a “continued decline in sales”, which has been “exacerbated by factors relating to the pandemic”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alison Flood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From My Fair Lady to Grease 2: Guardian writers on their favourite movie musicals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/09/favourite-movie-musicals-my-fair-lady-grease-2-in-the-heights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/09/favourite-movie-musicals-my-fair-lady-grease-2-in-the-heights"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:18:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To celebrate the release of Lin-Manuel Miranda’s upbeat musical In the Heights, Guardian writers have picked their favourite examples of the genre
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Hutchinson, Peter Bradshaw, Lisa Wong Macabasco, Catherine Shoard, Charles Bramesco, Radheyan Simonpillai, Adrian Horton, Benjamin Lee,  Guy Lodge and  Andrew Pulver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fastly says single customer triggered bug behind mass internet outage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/09/fastly-says-single-customer-triggered-bug-that-caused-mass-outage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/09/fastly-says-single-customer-triggered-bug-that-caused-mass-outage"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T14:02:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flaw was introduced in May and lay dormant until a customer updated their settings, firm says
An internet blackout that knocked out some of the world’s biggest websites on Tuesday was ultimately caused by a single customer updating their settings, the infrastructure provider Fastly has revealed.
A bug in Fastly’s code introduced in mid-May had lain dormant until Tuesday morning, according to Nick Rockwell, the company’s head of engineering and infrastructure. When the unnamed customer updated their settings, it triggered the flaw, which ultimately took down 85% of the company’s network.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern Technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The fearful boo those who take the knee. But that won’t stop the world from changing | Hugh Muir]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/boo-take-the-knee-fans-boris-johnson-england-footballers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/boo-take-the-knee-fans-boris-johnson-england-footballers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although Boris Johnson refused to condemn the fans, that doesn’t detract from the bravery of the England footballers
Booooo! As has become their ritual, England’s footballers took the knee this weekend. And as has become their ritual, a section of the England fans, newly permitted to congregate at stadiums post-pandemic, took the opportunity to barrack those for whom taking the knee has become a statement, a gesture of belonging, solidarity and a token of faith.
If you ask those who take the knee why they do so, I am sure the reasons will differ. Some are black players who want to challenge the perception that their status as sporting superstars protects them from the realities of being black in Britain, in a white-dominated country, in a white-dominated sport. They have always felt it; ta…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Muir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why do we cling to vacuous generational labels such as ‘millennial’? | Kitty Drake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/vacuous-generational-labels-millennial</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/vacuous-generational-labels-millennial"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:29:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Birth-year categorisation simplifies the complex work of trying to understand ourselves and others around us
Picture a millennial. Her tastes, like her emotional problems, are oddly specific. She likes squishy pillows because they soothe her anxiety. She likes curvy fonts for this reason, too, and baby cacti. She can’t have a real baby because she is too poor. She can’t find a partner because she is too alienated. Perhaps she has a fish. She is locked in an Oedipal battle with the boomers, her parents, who told her she would inherit the Earth but sucked it dry.
Like the “teenager”, who emerged in post-depression America, in part as a marketing tool that recognised the spending power of adolescents, the “millennial” is largely a work of fiction. Rationally, ascribing similar socioeconomic circumstances to the roughly 1.8 billion people born between 1981 and 1996 makes no sense. Not all millennials are unable to afford to have a child, just as not all boomers are smugly retired (indeed, in the UK 1.9 million people over the age of 65 live in poverty, according to figures from the Department of Work and Pensions).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kitty Drake</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown refunds: why are Ryanair and BA being investigated?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/09/ba-ryanair-investigated-lockdown-refunds-flights-airlines-customers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/09/ba-ryanair-investigated-lockdown-refunds-flights-airlines-customers"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T13:16:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airlines may have broken law by refusing refunds for flights customers could not legally take

BA and Ryanair investigated by CMA over lockdown refunds

British Airways and Ryanair are being officially investigated over whether they treated customers unfairly during the pandemic by failing to offer them flight refunds.
The Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) said it was looking to see if the two airlines had broken consumer law, and indicated it was on the side of consumers on this issue. It has opened enforcement cases into both companies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attack on sisters in London park was frenzied and relentless, trial told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/attack-two-sisters-london-park-frenzied-relentless-trial-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/attack-two-sisters-london-park-frenzied-relentless-trial-told"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T12:59:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prosecution opens case against teenager accused of murdering Nicole Smallman and Bibaa Henry
Two sisters were killed in a “frenzied and relentless” attack last year before their bodies were concealed in park undergrowth, the trial of a teenager accused of their murders has been told.
Danyal Hussein “planned to sacrifice women so that he could make money” in the belief that a “demon” would deliver a lottery win for him, according to the prosecution.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Quinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lotus flowers, button art and a puffin: Wednesday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/09/lotus-flowers-button-art-and-a-puffin-wednesdays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/09/lotus-flowers-button-art-and-a-puffin-wednesdays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T12:33:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selected by Natasha Rees-Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top 10 novels told in a single day | James Clammer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/09/top-10-novels-told-in-a-single-day-james-clammer-insignificance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/09/top-10-novels-told-in-a-single-day-james-clammer-insignificance"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T12:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From James Joyce and Virginia Woolf to Nicholson Baker, the ‘circadian novel’ can pack lifetimes of experience into 24 hours

Recently I had the good fortune to publish a novel based, in part, on the years I spent working as a plumber. After reading it, some of my new literary friends commented, “Ah, so you’re writing in the circadian tradition, then?” I nodded my head – and dived for a dictionary to discover the meaning of “circadian”. It turns out the word describes the process of going around, of returning. Books set within the confines of 24 hours. A day in the life.
I can’t claim that writing such a work had been my intention. In seeking to bring to life the world of manual labour – a world not over-represented in modern fiction – I’d found it necessary to focus on the minute and the granular. If we can have police procedurals, why can’t we also have plumbing procedurals? And quite quickly this technique of the tight focus, the super closeup, found itself being played out within the characters themselves, and their stories. There’s a freedom, after all, to working within limits, and perhaps the most important limit is time itself. New possibilities for compression open up; opportunities for strange amplifications. Lo and behold, and without quite realising it, I’d created a work of circadian fiction.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James Clammer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harry and Meghan reject claim Queen not consulted on Lilibet name]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/harry-and-meghan-push-back-at-claim-queen-not-consulted-on-lilibet-name</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/harry-and-meghan-push-back-at-claim-queen-not-consulted-on-lilibet-name"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T12:09:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BBC correspondent says palace source claims Sussexes did not ask for permission to use name for daughter
Buckingham Palace has become embroiled in a row over whether the Queen was consulted over the naming of the Duke and Duchess of Sussex’s daughter.
Harry and Meghan’s decision to name their second child Lilibet, a childhood nickname of the Queen, was seen as an attempt by the couple to try to mend their rift with the royal family.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Weaver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leading biologist dampens his ‘smoking gun’ Covid lab leak theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/leading-biologist-dampens-his-smoking-gun-covid-lab-leak-theory</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/leading-biologist-dampens-his-smoking-gun-covid-lab-leak-theory"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T11:48:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nobel laureate David Baltimore says he overstated case, and the origins of the virus are still unknown

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

A Nobel prize-winning US biologist, who has been widely quoted describing a “smoking gun” to support the thesis that Covid-19 was genetically modified and escaped from a Wuhan lab, has said he overstated the case.
David Baltimore, a distinguished biology professor, had become one of the most prominent figures cited by proponents of the so-called lab leak theory.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to make the perfect vegan ‘fish’ (AKA tofish) – recipe | Felicity Cloake's The perfect]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/09/how-to-make-the-perfect-tofish-vegan-fish-recipe-felicity-cloake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/09/how-to-make-the-perfect-tofish-vegan-fish-recipe-felicity-cloake"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T11:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smothered in batter and deep-fried, tofu makes a surprisingly good alternative to white fish for a vegan chippie experience at home
I’m no tofu expert – in fact, I’d go so far as to describe myself as a reformed sceptic – but there are two things I do know about it: first, its creamy blandness is a great foil for other flavours (see mapo tofu); and second, it is transformed, Cinderella-style, by frying, with its soft wobbliness irresistible against the crunch of batter. Both these qualities make it an ideal plant-based substitute for white fish in the classic chippie supper, offering a similar delicacy of flavour and satisfying contrast of textures without the distracting saltiness of halloumi or the chew of banana flowers, which are sometimes used as fish-free alternatives instead.
After posting pictures of my various attempts online, I was astonished by the vehemence of the response, to which I say, no one’s forcing you to try it, but you shouldn’t knock it until you have – after all, although tofu isn’t without its environmental concerns, few would deny that we need to be more mindful of the fish we eat and, almost as importantly, this is bloody delicious.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Felicity Cloake</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I fell in the water, but it was worth it!’: Guardian readers on their most extraordinary bird photographs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/i-fell-in-the-water-but-it-was-worth-it-guardian-readers-on-their-most-extraordinary-bird-photographs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/i-fell-in-the-water-but-it-was-worth-it-guardian-readers-on-their-most-extraordinary-bird-photographs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T11:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From friendly Antarctic penguins to the rainbow plumage of a Colombian hummingbird, our readers on their favourite images – and the lengths they went to to capture them.
I took this photo at the end of January in Balloch, Scotland. I have always wanted to take a picture of a male mandarin duck. It is the bird that made me want to start taking photographs. They are beautiful, with so many stunning colours. At the end of January, I had heard via Facebook that there was a pair of them up the road from me. I got up early and drove to Balloch. I had all but given up hope, when all of a sudden I saw the bright orange tail feathers of the duck in between some bushes on the river’s edge. I had to lean on a tree that was in the water to take the pictures. I then fell into the water and tore my trousers, but it was worth it. Paul Fraser, 36, freshwater biologist, Callander, Scotland
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian readers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olivia Rodrigo, DMX, Wolf Alice and more: June’s best album reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/ng-interactive/2021/jun/09/olivia-rodrigo-dmx-wolf-alice-and-more-junes-best-album-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/ng-interactive/2021/jun/09/olivia-rodrigo-dmx-wolf-alice-and-more-junes-best-album-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:45:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover all our four- and five-star album reviews from the last month, from pop to folk, classical and more
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 years after the human genome was first sequenced, dangerous gene myths abound | Philip Ball]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/human-genome-genes-genetic-code</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/09/human-genome-genes-genetic-code"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:43:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Misleading rhetoric has fuelled the belief that our genetic code is an ‘instruction book’ – but it’s far more interesting than that

Twenty years ago, the science journal Nature published the first draft of the human genome: the sequence of chemical “letters” on the gene-bearing DNA of our chromosomes. The Human Genome Project (HGP) had laboured for a decade to read this coded information. In a White House press conference in 2000, Francis Collins, , who led the project as director of the US National Human Genome Research Institute, waxed biblical, calling the human genome “our own instruction book, previously known only to God”.
The HGP has huge potential benefits for medicine and our understanding of human diversity and origins. But a blizzard of misleading rhetoric surrounded the project, contributing to the widespread and sometimes dangerous misunderstandings about genes that now bedevils the genomic age. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philip Ball</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I have a smaller penis than my girlfriend’s exes – should I get surgery?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/i-have-a-smaller-penis-than-my-girlfriends-exes-should-i-get-surgery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/09/i-have-a-smaller-penis-than-my-girlfriends-exes-should-i-get-surgery"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:37:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[She says I’m the best lover she’s ever had. But knowing I’m smaller than previous ones, I can’t stop feeling self-conscious
My girlfriend and I are extremely happy together, but she told me that two of her exes had a bigger penis than me. Depending on the circumstances, my penis is normally about 5.8-6.2in. She said her most recent ex was bigger, at 7in, and the other was maybe an inch longer. I’ve always been self-conscious about it, but this makes me feel worse. For a long time I’ve wanted to get surgery, but she swears that I am the best sexual partner she has had. She also says that she and her most recent ex couldn’t have sex in as many positions, because it would be painful. If I want to get surgery, should I? She says that I’m perfect the way I am and she thinks I’m the perfect size. 
Listen more carefully to your girlfriend. She is telling you that you are “perfect”, but all you hear is “her ex’s penis was bigger”. It is common to use half a story to confirm the negative beliefs one has about one’s self. Work on soothing your male size anxiety and, instead of comparing yourself with others, focus on giving and receiving pleasure. Unfortunately, pornography movies tend to emphasise size and promote the untrue notion that a huge penis automatically produces greater pleasure for a partner. Don’t buy into this rubbish; it is physiologically unsound. An intelligent lover who is willing to learn how to please a partner – without even using his penis – will always be the most appreciated.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pamela Stephenson Connolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet <code>:has</code>, A Native CSS Parent Selector (And More)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/has-native-css-parent-selector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What makes relational selector one of the most requested features and how are we, as developers, working around not having it? In this article, we’re going to check the early spec of the :has selector, and see how it should improve the CSS workflow once it’s released.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German election poll tracker: who will be the next chancellor?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/25/german-election-poll-tracker-who-will-be-the-next-chancellor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/25/german-election-poll-tracker-who-will-be-the-next-chancellor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T10:27:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Find out who is leading the polling to succeed Angela Merkel as chancellor of Germany
Germans will vote on Sunday 26 September to elect a new Bundestag, or federal parliament. The result – after coalition negotiations likely to involve two or three parties – will decide who will succeed Angela Merkel, who is standing down after 16 years as chancellor.
Some recent polls have put Germany’s Green party in the lead, as Merkel’s successor at the conservative CDU, Armin Laschet, struggles to inherit her appeal. German federal elections are proportional, so the share of vote given by polling companies should be read as translating fairly directly into share of seats in the resulting parliament. Only parties with less than 5% of the national vote, or less than three directly elected constituency seats, are not awarded proportional parliamentary seats.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seán Clarke and Antonio Voce</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: what lesson did you learn from your summer job?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/tell-us-what-lesson-did-you-learn-from-your-summer-job</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/tell-us-what-lesson-did-you-learn-from-your-summer-job"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T09:48:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from readers about their past and present experiences of summer work 
With a rise in summer job opportunities in some areas and a lack of gap year opportunities due to the pandemic, many young people are planning to use the summer to work and save. 
We would like to hear from readers about their own summer job experiences, past and present. What did it entail? And what lesson did you learn from it?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I just want what everyone else has’: what homeless people told Jennifer Kavanagh about their lives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/i-just-want-what-everyone-else-has-what-homeless-people-told-jennifer-kavanagh-about-their-lives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/09/i-just-want-what-everyone-else-has-what-homeless-people-told-jennifer-kavanagh-about-their-lives"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T09:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For 15 months the author walked around London, telling the story of its streets, speaking to living statues, sex workers, drug dealers, security guards, cleaners and those who sleep out every night

On a damp Tuesday lunchtime at the north end of Regent Street, George is working his beat as one of one of London’s Big Issue sellers. I have not come to interview him, but his experience is so relevant to what I will be talking about for the next two hours that I feel duty-bound to ask him about his life, and how things have been in the past 15 months.
When he is not in the centre of the city, he tells me, he lives in a hostel for homeless people near Canary Wharf, five or six miles to the east. “Lockdown was hard,” he says, “’cos I couldn’t sell the magazine, and I needed to pay rent to the hostel. And the isolation was really difficult: a little room, and I had to pretty much stay in there, and only go out for, like, an hour a day. I went for weeks on end not speaking to anyone.” Does he have family? “No, no. Not in London. My parents are dead; my brother and sister are abroad. One in Canada, one in Australia. So it’s been isolating, you know?”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raccoon dogs may be Britain’s next non-native pest, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/raccoon-dogs-britain-non-native-pest-invasive-species</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/raccoon-dogs-britain-non-native-pest-invasive-species"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T08:39:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Member of fox family is on list of 20 invasive species likely to reach UK shores and destroy wildlife
They are cute and furry, and could become the UK’s next major non-native pest.
Raccoon dogs, an exotic member of the fox family that is native to Japan, China and Siberia, are one of the most destructive invasive species at risk of becoming established in Britain, experts say.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Sea snot’ plagues the Turkish coast – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/09/sea-snot-plagues-the-turkish-coast-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/09/sea-snot-plagues-the-turkish-coast-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T07:40:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A thick layer of organic matter known as marine mucilage has spread in the Sea of Marmara, covering harbours, shorelines and swathes of the surface south of Istanbul. Some of the ‘sea snot’ has sunk below the waves, suffocating seabed life 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qatar Airways refused us a refund after visa mix-up to Botswana]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/qatar-airways-refused-us-a-refund-after-visa-mix-up-to-botswana</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/09/qatar-airways-refused-us-a-refund-after-visa-mix-up-to-botswana"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T06:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We had all the right documents but weren’t allowed to board our flight
My brother, his wife and young son were denied boarding when flying to Botswana for our mother’s funeral in December. Now Qatar Airways is refusing to refund the flight they missed, or the new one they booked to get to the service. My brother’s wife is a Philippines national and was eligible for a two-week visa issued on arrival in Botswana. They were travelling with all the documentation Botswana immigration officials had advised would be necessary.
Qatar Airways, however, had no knowledge of its system of issuing visas at port of entry, introduced in 2019. When check-in staff refused to accept the documents, my brother phoned the authorities at the destination airport in Maun and they emailed a stamped letter confirming the arrangements. They even offered to talk to Qatar staff, but this was refused. It was only after he obtained emailed letters from Botswana’s deputy director of immigration and the consul general that the airline agreed to let the family travel.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Tims</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peace in the Peak District: walking the Limestone Way]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/peak-district-walking-the-limestone-way-trail-ancient-tracks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/09/peak-district-walking-the-limestone-way-trail-ancient-tracks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T05:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immerse yourself in a landscape of ancient tracks on a quiet trail created by locals to show off a gentler side of the region
If you don’t already know it, the Peak District can be a dauntingly large area to explore. Beginners often gravitate towards familiar names like Edale and Kinder Scout, but I prefer some of the less-well-known areas further south, which may not have the sweep of the moors but isn’t as busy either.
And rather than rely on the more famous Pennine Way, too often an unrelenting if virtuous slog, far better to follow the Limestone Way, created by locals to show off their landscape. Just as the Dark Peak area to the north of the Peak District national park is on gritstone, the White Peak area in the south is so called because it is on paler limestone.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Thomson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hook to plate: how blockchain tech could turn the tide for sustainable fishing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/hook-to-plate-how-blockchain-tech-can-turn-the-tide-for-sustainable-fishing-aoe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/09/hook-to-plate-how-blockchain-tech-can-turn-the-tide-for-sustainable-fishing-aoe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T05:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Could using digital tags to track fish reduce seafood fraud, help conservation and hold everyone in the supply chain to account?
In recent weeks, a new $50m (£35m) hybrid vessel set sail from Mauritius and headed out into the Southern Ocean where the crew will spend three months longline fishing for the Patagonian toothfish. By the time the fish are brought back, processed and sent to customers, consumers will know where and when that specific fish was caught, which boat landed it, who processed it and which certifications have been met. The technology enabling this is blockchain.
“From the day it’s landed to when it ends up on someone’s plate, blockchain gives toothfish traceability right from the start,” says Steve Paku, captain of the Cape Arkona. “People can just scan the barcode and the whole story is right there in front of them.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Turns</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From New Order to Chris Kamara: England’s best and worst tournament songs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/09/from-new-order-to-chris-kamara-englands-best-and-worst-tournament-songs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/09/from-new-order-to-chris-kamara-englands-best-and-worst-tournament-songs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T05:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[England football songs have run the gamut of emotions from misty-eyed hope to the musical expression of deep psychological malaise 
Baddiel, Skinner & the Lightning Seeds – Three Lions
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Beaumont-Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bennifer’s rebooted! Why is Ben Affleck and Jennifer Lopez’s reunion so cheering?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/09/bennifer-rebooted-ben-affleck-jennifer-lopezs-reunion-tiktok</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/09/bennifer-rebooted-ben-affleck-jennifer-lopezs-reunion-tiktok"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T05:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They were a tabloid dream, the super-cool fly girl and the eyeliner-wearing Caped Crusader. Now, 17 years on, Ben and Jen are together again. But what do the ultimate 00s couple mean to the TikTok age?
Brangelina. Kimye. Tomkat. Gyllenspoon. Each pairing is yet another note in the long, sad dirge of failed Hollywood romances. Blending famous monikers has been a showbiz tradition for decades, even if most of these fusions fizzle out quicker than you can say “Vaughniston” (you remember: Vince Vaughn dated Jennifer Aniston for about a minute after her breakup with Brad Pitt). But back in the early 2000s, there was one couple whose tumultuous affair and melded nickname towered above the rest, all but consuming the tabloid press for three whole years, until their abrupt, dramatic breakup just days before their planned wedding. And now, 17 years later, in a plot twist worthy of a Nancy Meyers romcom, those same not-so-young-any-more lovers have shocked the world and delighted the media by getting back together.
That’s right: like the cicadas, Bennifer has risen anew. The details of the Ben Affleck-Jennifer Lopez reunion are still a bit sketchy. There was a New York Post item in April reporting that the two had been observed entering the restaurant at the Pendry hotel in West Hollywood with “arms wrapped around each other”. A few days later, Affleck was spotted making an early-morning departure from Lopez’s LA home (“with a smirk” on his face, the Page Six article noted). A month after that, multiple outlets broke the news that the couple had spent a weekend at a resort in Montana. Then celebrity mag Us Weekly made it semi-official with a quote from an anonymous source: “Jen and Ben are both very happy with each [other] and excited to see where the relationship goes.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Svetkey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lilibet Diana: the baby name that represents a royal rift – and audacious hope]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/lilibet-diana-baby-name-royal-rift-audacious-hope</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/09/lilibet-diana-baby-name-royal-rift-audacious-hope"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T05:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By combining the names of the Queen and the Princess of Wales, Harry and Meghan have highlighted two very different approaches to the monarchy. But which will define the future?
The joyful delivery of a baby girl to Prince Harry and Meghan is lovely news. But it has been lost, ever so slightly, in the couple’s naming choice: Lilibet Diana Mountbatten-Windsor.
I don’t think they had any say in the surname, so let’s stick with the forenames. Lilibet is, of course, the Queen’s nickname; not, as you might suppose, a contraction of Elizabeth that only posh people use, but rather what she called herself when she was too young to pronounce her own name. Only George VI, the Queen Mother, Princess Margaret and Prince Philip used it. “Lilibet is my pride. Margaret is my joy,” the king was quoted as saying, evidently having not caught up with the parenting manual that says you are really supposed to keep the identity of your favourite child to yourself. When Prince Philip died, the nickname died with him.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The interrogation of Matt Hancock - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/09/the-interrogation-of-matt-hancock-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-09T02:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two weeks after Dominic Cummings told MPs that the health secretary was a serial liar who lost the trust of No 10, Matt Hancock will face the same committee to defend himself. Heather Stewart explains what is at stake, and what it could mean for the next stage of the pandemic
When Dominic Cummings appeared before MPs to set out his account of what went wrong in the early stages of the Covid pandemic, he attempted a political assassination. But a fortnight later, Matt Hancock, the health secretary, is still limping on. So far, Hancock has been able to bat away questions from journalists, and at the dispatch box, without much trouble, and has retained the support of the prime minister. But a grilling by MPs, who will have much more time and the chance to follow up on their questions, will present him with a far greater challenge.
Hancock’s day of reckoning comes with the 21 June planned unlocking still uncertain, and the number of cases rising again, so his future will have profound consequences for the country. Rachel Humphreys spoke to the Guardian’s political editor, Heather Stewart, about the questions he is likely to face, the light his answers could shed on what went wrong, and why Boris Johnson appears determined to stick with his man — for now.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Heather Stewart; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deploy Your freeCodeCamp Project on AWS – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide to the Cloud]]></title>
        <id>60bfa4d4d3126007592d5160</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-deploy-your-freecodecamp-project-on-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T23:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Throughout this post we’ll deploy your freeCodeCamp front end project using various services on AWS like S3, ElasticBeanstalk, and Lambda.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create Your Own Electronics With Arduino - Full Course]]></title>
        <id>60bfd986d3126007592d53a1</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/create-your-own-electronics-with-arduino-full-course/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T21:05:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino is an open-source electronics platform based on easy-to-use hardware and software. Arduino boards are able to read inputs - light on a sensor, a finger on a button, or a Twitter message - and turn it into an output - activating a motor, turning on an LED, publishing something]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 150km Velikoretsky procession – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/08/the-150km-velikoretsky-procession-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/08/the-150km-velikoretsky-procession-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T21:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Annual Russian pilgrimage in honour of icon of St Nicholas discovered, as legend has it, in the 14th century
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Images by Dmitry Feoktistov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The island with no water: how foreign mining destroyed Banaba]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/the-island-with-no-water-how-foreign-mining-destroyed-banaba</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/09/the-island-with-no-water-how-foreign-mining-destroyed-banaba"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T20:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Kiribati island survived droughts due to sacred caves that captured rainfall but rampant phosphate extraction ruined this precious resource

Read more of our Pacific Plunder series here

The last decent rain on Banaba was more than a year ago.
Without rain, people on the isolated central Pacific island, which is part of the country of Kiribati, have been forced to rely on a desalination plant for all their water for drinking, bathing and growing crops.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua McDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341982</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/looking-at-wcag-2-5-5-for-better-target-sizes/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T18:31:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever experienced the frustration of trying to tap a button on a mobile device only to have it do nothing because the target size is just not large enough **and it’s not picking up on your press? Maybe …
The post Looking at WCAG 2.5.5 for Better Target Sizes appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Todd Libby</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Pass Data and Events Between Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b23b8911ffb70827ef954e</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/pass-data-between-components-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T16:17:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're trying to implement CRUD operations using API endpoints, you might find that it's hard to manage data across multiple components. Or maybe you have a modal, but you want to trigger it from a different component.  Wrapping your head around how to tackle these scenarios can be difficult.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete CSS Grid Tutorial with Cheat Sheet 🎖️]]></title>
        <id>60be6a3cd3126007592d4a03</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/css-grid-tutorial-with-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T16:02:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we're going to learn CSS Grid properties so that you can make your own responsive websites. I'll explain how each of Grid's properties work along with a CheatSheet that covers everything you can do with Grid. Let's go. 🎖️ Table of Contents: CSS Grid Architecture CSS Grid Chart Grid Parent]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public grasps threat to ocean even as leaders fail to meet targets, poll finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/oceans-fate-linked-to-our-own-poll-finds-amid-rising-concern</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/08/oceans-fate-linked-to-our-own-poll-finds-amid-rising-concern"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T15:06:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Survey to mark World Oceans Day finds 94% in England and Wales believe the fate of oceans and humans is inextricably linked
As people mark World Oceans Day today, an overwhelming 94% of people in England and Wales believe the fate of the oceans and humans are inextricably linked, while more than half rate global ocean health as “poor or very poor”, according to a government survey.
The online survey of 8,000 people, carried out for the Department for Environment, Food & Rural Affairs (Defra) and the Ocean Conservation Trust earlier this year, reveals the depth of public understanding of the link between the health of the oceans and the multiple pressures upon them.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Karen McVeigh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341884</id>
        <link href="https://alex.party/posts/2021-05-31-css-trickz-an-experiment-with-netlify-s-on-demand-builders/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T14:16:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress sites have an API by default. Wanna see this site’s most recent posts, with just a specific set of data… in JSON format? Here ya go. Alex Riviere made a joke site using that.
At first, the site …
The post CSS-Trickz: An Experiment with Netlify’s On-Demand Builders appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AVIF to WebP: A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/image-optimization-book-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s here! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our deep-dive guide to understand how to deliver high-quality images on the web fast.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do we know we’re not living in a simulation like The Matrix?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/08/how-do-we-know-were-not-living-in-a-simulation-like-the-matrix</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/08/how-do-we-know-were-not-living-in-a-simulation-like-the-matrix"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T11:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
How do we know we’re not living in a simulation like The Matrix? Jack Freedom, Bristol
Post your answers (and new questions) below or send them to nq@theguardian.com. A selection will be published on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The look of glove: Nick Cave’s moving first photobook – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/08/nick-cave-photobook-melancholy-little-book-of-lost-gloves</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/gallery/2021/jun/08/nick-cave-photobook-melancholy-little-book-of-lost-gloves"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T06:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the Bad Seeds singer found a solitary child’s glove hanging over a road sign he felt a ‘jolt of grief’ which led him on a photographic journey. He talks us through it 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The danger – and beauty – of ultrarunning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/08/danger-and-beauty-of-ultrarunning-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/08/danger-and-beauty-of-ultrarunning-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T02:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 21 competitors died during a 100km mountain race in Gansu province, the Chinese government last week suspended all extreme sports. But those who love ultrarunning insist it can be safe – and has changed how they see the world. What keeps them coming back?
To most people, the horror of 21 lives being lost during a race across 100km in a Chinese mountain range will have been amplified by how obscure the sport seems to outsiders. But ultrarunning has boomed in popularity in recent years, with the number of finishers around the world rising from 120,000 to more than 600,000 in a decade. Now there are concerns that in China and beyond, a proliferation of new races has created a risk that safety rules will not always be enforced, and with it a chance that some of the most obsessive participants will discard vital protective equipment in the interests of gaining an advantage over their rivals.
Rachel Humphreys talks to Outside magazine’s Will Ford about the tragedy in China, and whether the decision of the government there to ban all extreme sports is the right response. And she hears from the author and ultrarunner Adharanand Finn about the extraordinary appeal of this brutally difficult feat of endurance – and how any analysis of its dangers must sit alongside an understanding of its power to change its devotees’ lives in profound ways.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Adharanand Finn and Will Ford; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Stack Development with Next.js and Supabase – The Complete Guide]]></title>
        <id>60bbd28eacb62507dd1d99fb</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-complete-guide-to-full-stack-development-with-supabas/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T23:33:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to build full stack serverless apps with Supabase and Next.js.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use OpenCV and Python for Computer Vision and AI]]></title>
        <id>60be863cd3126007592d4c36</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-opencv-and-python-for-computer-vision-and-ai/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:54:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCV is a popular Python library for real-time computer vision. We just released a new OpenCV course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. This course comes directly from the creators of OpenCV and is the perfect course for beginners.  You will learn how to use OpenCV for Computer Vision and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Accessibility]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341805</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-accessibility/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T19:52:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Show/Hide password accessibility and password hints tutorial — Nicolas Steenhout goes deep on <input type="password"> accessibility. For one thing, being able to toggle it to type="text" should be possible, while announcing, politely, the change. But also, put the password hints 
…
The post Links on Accessibility appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Closures in JavaScript – A Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>5ff625967af2371468bb8645</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/closures-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T18:18:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Closures are a confusing JavaScript concept to learn, because it's hard to see how they're actually used.  Unlike other concepts such as functions, variables, and objects, you don't always use closures conscientiously and directly. You don't say: Oh! Here I will use a closure as a solution. But at the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us: are you planning on joining protests at the G7 summit?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/07/tell-us-are-you-planning-on-joining-protests-at-the-g7-summit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:45:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from people who’re planning on demonstrating during this week’s G7 summit in Cornwall 
 Later this week, world leaders will be attending the G7 summit, at Carbis Bay, near St Ives in Cornwall, to discuss global issues including the Covid pandemic and climate change.
The coalition comprises seven countries; the UK, Japan, US, Italy, Germany, Canada and France.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VS Code Extensions for HTML]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340390</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/vs-code-extensions-for-html/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T14:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s look at some extensions for VS Code that make writing and editing HTML (and languages that are basically HTML with extra powers) better. You may not like all of them. Maybe some of them don’t appeal to you, solve …
The post VS Code Extensions for HTML appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build A Geocoding App In Vue.js Using Mapbox]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/building-geocoding-app-vue-mapbox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide, we’ll be taking a general look at the concepts of forward geocoding and reverse geocoding, and will build a mini-app that applies these concepts to display specific locations, using Mapbox and Vue.js 2.6.11 to achieve this.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Prince Chukwudire)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TV Baftas 2021: backstage with Michaela Coel, Paul Mescal and more – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/gallery/2021/jun/07/tv-baftas-2021-backstage-with-michaela-coel-paul-mescal-and-more-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/gallery/2021/jun/07/tv-baftas-2021-backstage-with-michaela-coel-paul-mescal-and-more-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T10:19:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Connell and Villanelle sharing a moment to Michaela Coel with her mum, The Guardian’s Sarah Lee had exclusive behind-the-scenes access to this year’s ceremony
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK parents and teachers: what is currently happening in your school?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/07/uk-parents-and-teachers-what-is-currently-happening-in-your-school"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T09:55:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear what the situation is like in UK schools from the parental and teaching point of view

We’re keen to hear from parents, teachers and school leaders across the UK about the situation in schools.
Whether it’s exam preparations, the management of social distancing protocols, the provision of wraparound care or school closures due to rising infections in communities, we’d like to hear about it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British ballerina at the Bolshoi Ballet Academy, Moscow – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/07/british-ballerina-at-the-bolshoi-ballet-academy-moscow-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/07/british-ballerina-at-the-bolshoi-ballet-academy-moscow-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rachel Armstrong, from Northumberland, is due to graduate from the renowned Russian academy this month
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgenia Novozhenina/Reuters. Written by Tatiana Gomozova and Lev Sergeev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why every statue should come down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/07/why-every-statue-should-come-down</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/07/why-every-statue-should-come-down"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Younge was glad to see the figure of Edward Colston removed in Bristol a year ago – but, he argues, even monuments to civil rights leaders are a distortion of how history really works 

How to listen to podcasts: everything you need to know

One year ago, the statue of the slave trader Edward Colston was brought down in Bristol, prompting jubilation among protesters and calls for a wider rethink of public memorials – but also a ferocious backlash.
Gary Younge, the former Guardian columnist who is now a professor of sociology at the University of Manchester, was delighted to see Colston come down – but all too aware of the controversy that would ensue, having previously found himself the subject of a Daily Mail campaign to erect a statue of the Queen Mother. He tells Anushka Asthana that the last year has highlighted the reluctance of some participants in the culture war over statues to grapple with the reality of Britain’s history. And, he argues, even figures of civil rights heroes such as Nelson Mandela and Rosa Parks misrepresent their role in bringing about social change – and underplay the crucial significance of the movements that lifted them up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Gary Younge and Chloe Peacock; produced by Courtney Yusuf and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: can Southgate's England take it one step further? – video preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/video/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-can-southgates-england-take-it-one-step-further-video-preview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/video/2021/jun/07/euro-2020-can-southgates-england-take-it-one-step-further-video-preview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T23:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gareth Southgate's England will be hoping to take it one step further as they go into Euro 2020 as one of the favourites. The question is whether the manager will favour his tried and trusted – Raheem Sterling, Harry Kane and Marcus Rashford – or whether it's time to pick the form players in Jack Grealish, Phil Foden and Jadon Sancho. England start off against Croatia, the team that ended their journey to the final at the World Cup in 2018, before games against Scotland and Czech Republic. The Guardian's Barney Ronay discusses England's chances of European glory
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay &amp; Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>