<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-06T00:53:46.859Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-06T00:53:46.859Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cattle thieves kill 66 villagers in north-west Nigeria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cattle-thieves-nigeria-kill-villagers-</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/06/cattle-thieves-nigeria-kill-villagers-"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T00:28:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police still searching for more bodies after gunmen on motorcycles attacked seven villages 
A gang of cattle thieves have killed 66 people in raids on seven villages in north-west Nigeria’s Kebbi state, police say.
Dozens of assailants on motorcycles attacked seven neighbouring villages in Danko-Wasagu district on Thursday, Kebbi state police spokesman Nafiu Abubakar told AFP on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why cryptocurrencies may remain merely a bit on the side]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/why-cryptocurrencies-may-remain-merely-a-bit-on-the-side</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/06/why-cryptocurrencies-may-remain-merely-a-bit-on-the-side"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T23:05:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wise Bank of England heads are pondering the case for a state-run digital currency this week. But do we really need one?
When Google announced that bitcoin traders would be allowed to buy advertising space on its pages from August, central banks were alerted to the next likely surge in publicity for cryptocurrencies.
The increasing activity around digital currencies has not gone unnoticed at the Bank of England, and on 7 June Threadneedle Street’s brightest will publish a consultation document, setting out how a publicly operated electronic coinage system – one that would rival bitcoin – might work.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We love: Fashion fixes for the week ahead – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/05/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/05/we-love-fashion-fixes-for-the-week-ahead-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T22:55:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stine Goya’s 24-hour party style, upcycled denim from Marques’Almeida and 7 For All Mankind, and necklaces that give back. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Seamons and Jo Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour plans to embarrass government with vote on pupil catch-up plan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/05/labour-plans-to-embarrass-government-with-vote-on-pupil-catch-up-plan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/05/labour-plans-to-embarrass-government-with-vote-on-pupil-catch-up-plan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T22:29:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Opposition to force vote over ‘woefully inadequate’ lost learning scheme after education recovery minister quits

The expert view

Labour has vowed to force a vote over the government’s “totally insufficient” plans to help pupils catch up on learning lost during the pandemic, as Tory MPs demand an urgent rethink of the programme.
Senior Tories are calling for a wider programme that could include trials of a longer school day and extended physical education and wellbeing activities, to help children in England readjust after time out of the classroom.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share vaccines or climate deal will fail, rich countries are told]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/share-vaccines-or-climate-deal-will-fail-rich-countries-are-told</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/share-vaccines-or-climate-deal-will-fail-rich-countries-are-told"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T21:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for ‘solidarity’ in Covid fight as Boris Johnson calls on world leaders to help vaccinate global population by end of 2022
Progress on climate change could be scuppered by developing nations if they are not given equitable access to vaccines, Boris Johnson has been warned, as rich nations come under new pressure to donate more doses.
Figures compiled by the Observer show that the wealthiest nations, including the UK, have enough vaccines to inoculate their populations more than twice over.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey, Toby Helm and Ashley Kirk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mo Farah’s Tokyo Olympic hopes hang by thread after shock 10,000m defeat]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/mo-farahs-tokyo-hopes-in-balance-after-disappointing-return-to-track</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/mo-farahs-tokyo-hopes-in-balance-after-disappointing-return-to-track"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T21:07:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Briton finishes eighth at European Cup on return to track
Olympic champion ran first race over distance since 2017

Mo Farah is facing a desperate struggle to make the Olympics after failing to post the qualifying time for Tokyo and finishing a shock eighth at the European Athletics 10,000m Cup in Birmingham.
Despite it being his first 10,000m race for nearly four years, Farah was expecting to run easily the 27min 28sec needed to make it on the plane to Japan. Instead the 38-year-old was toiling and grimacing by halfway – the result, he said, of a niggle to his left ankle sustained 10 days ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Ingle at the University of Birmingham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Naomi Wolf banned from Twitter for spreading vaccine myths]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/naomi-wolf-banned-twitter-spreading-vaccine-myths</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/naomi-wolf-banned-twitter-spreading-vaccine-myths"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:13:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many social media users applaud termination of author’s account, but some have said move is a blow to freedom of speech
The author Naomi Wolf has been suspended from Twitter after using it to spread myths about the pandemic, vaccines and lockdown.
Wolf, who wrote the influential feminist work The Beauty Myth, holds staunch anti-vaccine views. Last month she told a US congressional committee that vaccine passports would “re-create a situation that is very familiar to me as a student of history. This has been the start of many, many genocides.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Connett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing lightning: a photographer’s pursuit of the elements – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/06/chasing-lightning-a-photographers-pursuit-of-the-elements-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will Eades is an award-winning photographer based on the mid north coast of NSW. His mission is to see and capture spectacular moments in nature, and to share these rare moments with others. A self-taught Nikon shooter, Will’s main focus is on storms and other weather phenomena as he strives to be present when the elements align for a great photograph
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Eades</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A journey down WA’s mighty Martuwarra, raging river and sacred ancestor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/a-journey-down-was-mighty-martuwarra-raging-river-and-sacred-ancestor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Traditional owners are standing together to protect the Fitzroy – a ‘beautiful, living water system’. Just watch out for the bird-sized spiders …
A Nyikina man, Mark Coles Smith, and his fellow travellers began their 400km journey down the mighty Martuwarra (Fitzroy River) on a flood plain covered in giant spiders.
“Bird-sized” spiders were clinging to the canopy, jostling for space on branches protruding above flood water that stretched for kilometres in every direction.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorena Allam;  production: Carly Earl; photographs: Jackson Gallagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where mining meets rainforest: the battle for Tasmania’s Tarkine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/06/where-mining-meets-rainforest-the-battle-for-tasmanias-tarkine</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/06/where-mining-meets-rainforest-the-battle-for-tasmanias-tarkine"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T20:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Campaigners say plans for a new tailings dam threatens wilderness that should be declared a heritage area
Four days before the Morrison government was due to decide the future of a mining development in the takayna/Tarkine, 77-year-old Frits Harmsen planted a camping chair in front of trucks on an unsealed road snaking through Australia’s largest temperate rainforest.
Harmsen, a former French horn player with the Tasmanian Symphony Orchestra, was part of a small band of Bob Brown-endorsed protesters who on Friday began a 19th day attempting to block work by MMG, a majority Chinese-owned minerals company, in Tasmania’s remote north-west.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Morton Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Disgusting slap in the face’: California governor slams judge as assault rifles ban overturned]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/california-assault-rifles-ban-gavin-newsom-judge-roger-benitez-ar-15-swiss-army-knife</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/california-assault-rifles-ban-gavin-newsom-judge-roger-benitez-ar-15-swiss-army-knife"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T19:53:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gavin Newsom responds after Judge Roger Benitez compares AR-15s to Swiss army knives ‘good for both home and battle’

Opinion: I survived a school shooting. My kids shouldn’t have to

The governor of California, Gavin Newsom, slammed a federal judge’s decision to overturn his state’s three-decade-old ban on assault rifles as “a direct threat to public safety and the lives of innocent Californians”.
 Related: America’s gun obsession is rooted in slavery | Carol Anderson 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez endorses Maya Wiley for New York mayor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/aoc-endorsement-new-york-mayor-maya-wiley</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/aoc-endorsement-new-york-mayor-maya-wiley"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T19:30:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congresswoman’s support could heighten chances of city electing a woman for the first time and its second Black leader
Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez has endorsed Maya Wiley for mayor of New York, a dramatic intervention that could heighten the chances of the city electing a woman for the first time and only its second Black leader.
 Related: Fewer police, more housing: how Maya Wiley wants to transform New York 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Bekiempis and Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 draw puts England’s high hopes of a festival of relief falling flat | Jonathan Wilson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/05/euro-2020-draw-puts-englands-hopes-for-a-festival-of-relief-at-risk-of-falling-flat</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2021/jun/05/euro-2020-draw-puts-englands-hopes-for-a-festival-of-relief-at-risk-of-falling-flat"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T19:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A talented squad’s involvement could end before a euphoric momentum to match 1996 and 2018 has a chance to build
International tournaments are only tangentially about the football – which is probably just as well given how unsophisticated it often is beside the very best of the club game, how sluggish it can appear. They are about the stories and the mood, about the scandal and the drama and, most of all, the sense of shared experience.
Russia 2018 was a very good World Cup and an enjoyable tournament to cover, but watching England’s victory over Colombia alone in a drab flat in Samara, surrounded by another journalist’s drying laundry, and seeing the scenes of jubilation from back home, there was a distinct sense of being bypassed by something significant. As the Irish columnist Con Houlihan observed of Italia 90: “I missed it … I was in Italy at the time.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rory Burns’ battling century gives England hope but New Zealand on top]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/rory-burns-battling-century-gives-england-hope-but-new-zealand-on-top</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/rory-burns-battling-century-gives-england-hope-but-new-zealand-on-top"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T18:45:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First Test day four: New Zealand 378 and 62-2; England 275

Opener steadies the ship after England’s morning collapse 

There are 98 overs remaining in this first Test between England and New Zealand and though a draw remains the most likely outcome, a sparkling fourth day that saw Rory Burns and Tim Southee claim places on the Lord’s honours boards suggested further twists are still possible.
Certainly none of the 6,500 spectators who came through the turnstiles could claim to have been short-changed despite nine unbowled overs disappearing into the ether, after Burns rescued England from a morning collapse with his third Test century and Tim Southee underlined his class with sublime figures of six for 43. As the players strolled off at stumps to hearty applause New Zealand sat at 62 for two from 30 overs, extending their first innings lead of 103 to 165. Ollie Robinson finally cracked the Devon Conway code, bowling the debutant double-centurion for 23 before trapping Kane Williamson lbw on one, but the tourists still faced the more relaxing evening back in the bubble.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin at Lord's</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battling Norrie unable to derail the Nadal French Open juggernaut]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/battling-norrie-unable-to-derail-the-nadal-juggernaut</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/battling-norrie-unable-to-derail-the-nadal-juggernaut"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T18:25:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spaniard cruises to a 6-3, 6-3, 6-3 victory over British No 2
Novak Djokovic advances in three sets, Roger Federer in four

Having never stepped on to a tennis court with Rafael Nadal in the opening three years of his ATP tour career, Cameron Norrie is starting to become familiar with the best. For a third time this year, Norrie stared down the Spaniard and showed the merits of his game, but ultimately he was unable truly to trouble Nadal, who moved into the fourth round of the French Open with a 6-3, 6-3, 6-3 win.
As they prepared to face each other once more, Norrie was asked in his press conference if a match against Nadal at Roland Garros is the toughest task in sport. He concurred, but he also offered an interesting account of what he took from their previous encounters: “I’ve learned that he’s actually a human being,” said Norrie. “He can miss shots. He can play short at times. But then you give him a little bit of room for him to find his forehand, he gets it going. He can be extremely dangerous. It can be absolute carnage going into the forehand there.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We were deceived’: hundreds protest in Venice at return of giant cruise ships]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/angry-protests-in-venice-at-shock-return-of-cruise-ships</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/angry-protests-in-venice-at-shock-return-of-cruise-ships"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T18:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ban on huge vessels passing St Mark’s Square proves to be temporary after liner docks in city for first time in 17 months
Anti-cruise ship campaigners in Venice claim they were “deceived” by the Italian government as hundreds protested against huge vessels docking in the historic city’s port on Saturday.
Residents were caught by surprise on Thursday when a cruise liner sailed into the lagoon city for the first time since the pandemic began, despite prime minister Mario Draghi’s government declaring that the ships would be banned from the historic centre. The 92,000 tonne ship MSC Orchestra collected 650 passengers before leaving for Bari, in southern Italy, on Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a cracking statue, Gromit: Preston unveils ‘wrong trousers’ bench]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/05/preston-wallace-and-gromit-statue-wrong-trousers-bench</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/05/preston-wallace-and-gromit-statue-wrong-trousers-bench"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:35:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hometown honours Nick Park for his Oscar-winning animated duo with a thumbs-up from Wallace

A statue of Wallace and Gromit is to be unveiled in Preston, home town of their creator Nick Park. The pair will be sculpted with Wallace wearing the “techno trousers” that brought him grief in Park’s Oscar-winning film The Wrong Trousers.
The statue is intended to attract more visitors to the Lancashire city as coronavirus rules ease and is due to be installed outside Preston Markets in August. It will feature Gromit sitting on a bench reading a newspaper while Wallace – resplendent in his ex-Nasa trousers – balances on one leg giving the thumbs up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scroungers, lefty lawyers... the Tories duck scrutiny by inventing enemies | Nick Cohen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/in-court-of-boris-johnson-no-room-for-scrutiny-by-judges</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/in-court-of-boris-johnson-no-room-for-scrutiny-by-judges"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:30:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abiding by judicial oversight is alien to a government that acts as if it’s above the law
You cannot say anything coherent without generalising, and so, and to generalise, the British will lose their rights to challenge an over-mighty and underwhelming state because they hate foreigners more than they love political accountability.
The Johnson administration knows that as long as it portrays asylum seekers as cheats arriving in the UK illegally and their solicitors as activist “lefty lawyers”, tricking the trusting public into allowing scrounging aliens to remain on our island, it can end scrutiny of its abuses of power.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Cohen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adam Kirby wins Derby on Adayar after losing original big-race ride to Dettori]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/adam-kirby-wins-the-derby-on-adayar-after-losing-original-big-race-ride-to-frankie-dettori-horse-racing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/adam-kirby-wins-the-derby-on-adayar-after-losing-original-big-race-ride-to-frankie-dettori-horse-racing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jockey lost mount on fancied John Leeper to Frankie Dettori
Favourite Bolshoi Ballet hugely disappointing in Classic

Adam Kirby’s gaunt features tell the story of his constant battle with scales to pursue his career as a rider on the Flat, and his voice was close to cracking with emotion as he talked through his winning ride on Adayar in the Derby here on Saturday. “I’m not really a person to get overly excited about things but I was then, it was a real buzz,” he said. “I hope my kids were watching. At least they know that when people call daddy an all-weather jockey, he’s not an all-weather jockey.”
He had every right to feel a little dazed after Adayar’s smooth four-and-a-half length defeat of 50-1 outsider Mojo Star, with the winner’s better-fancied stable companion, Hurricane Lane, back in third. Until Wednesday evening, after all, he had expected to be riding John Leeper for Ed Dunlop, a horse with a much better chance on paper than Adayar, who was the apparent third-string in Charlie Appleby’s Derby team.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood at Epsom</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One death, 11 jailed teenagers: was a Moss Side murder trial racist?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/one-death-11-jailed-teenagers-was-a-moss-side-trial-racist</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/one-death-11-jailed-teenagers-was-a-moss-side-trial-racist"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:22:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, 11 Manchester teenagers were jailed for a total of 168 years for their part in a killing. Now three are appealing amid claims that the investigation and trials were riddled with racism
Early one morning in Moss Side, Manchester, several winters ago, a group of teenagers gathered at a youth club to make a rap video. The shoot had been arranged by Kemoy Walker, an award-winning youth worker who is now a head of year at a large school in the city and an ambassador for Manchester city council.
Walker’s organisation, “Manchestarz”, had attracted public funding, including from Greater Manchester Police (GMP), for work that engaged young people in music. The video, shot by a film student at Manchester Metropolitan University who had answered a call on the social network Instagram for somebody with the necessary skills, was the perfect project. “We met early in the morning, everybody came on time,” recalls Walker. “We made the video in the park – it was quite cold – and it was really good. It was friends coming together and creating music.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England will take a knee before Euro 2020 matches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/england-will-take-a-knee-before-euro-2020-matches</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/england-will-take-a-knee-before-euro-2020-matches"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:15:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manager Gareth Southgate insists that the team ‘is more determined than ever’ to ignore boos from the crowd
England will continue to take a knee before their games throughout Euro 2020 and are “more determined than ever” to ignore any boos from the stands, according to manager Gareth Southgate.
The squad held a meeting to discuss their next steps after a loud minority of supporters jeered them for taking the anti-racism stance at their friendly against Austria in Middlesbrough. They agreed overwhelmingly to carry on, starting when they play Romania in another warm-up game on Sunday, and Southgate said his players had “had enough” of being called on to explain an action that should speak for itself.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick Ames</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zakiya Dalila Harris: ‘Publishing is such a spoofable world’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/zakiya-dalila-harris-publishing-is-such-a-spoofable-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/zakiya-dalila-harris-publishing-is-such-a-spoofable-world"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The author of a debut novel about diversity in the workplace on how black people act around white people, embracing her hair, and what’s changed a year after George Floyd’s murder
Zakiya Dalila Harris was born and raised in Connecticut and is currently based in Brooklyn. Now a full-time writer, she previously worked in book publishing, an experience she draws on in her highly anticipated debut novel, The Other Black Girl, which combines thriller with social satire to tell the story of Nella, the only black employee at a fictional publishing house, until Hazel joins the company. The book charts how the two become frenemies, explores the challenges of surviving in a systemically racist workplace, and was the subject of a 15-way auction prior to publication in the US.
What were your own experiences in publishing and how have they played into the book?
I worked in publishing for two and a half years. I was an editorial assistant then promoted to assistant editor. I felt fortunate, as a part of me enjoyed editing and I felt I was good at it, but it’s also an exhausting job for an entry-level person in terms of the pay. I was also one of the very few black people in the company – it wasn’t as bad as Nella in the book, but I was the only black woman in editorial in a full-time position for a while. I thought: why does it feel like we’re living in 1955 still, in terms of what we value? Publishing is such a rich, easily spoofable world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Sethi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Going on holiday? Not if the Delta variant has its way – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/05/going-on-holiday-not-if-the-delta-variant-has-its-way-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/05/going-on-holiday-not-if-the-delta-variant-has-its-way-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red, amber or green is starting to look a bit irrelevant in the face of another Covid surge 
• You can order your own copy of this cartoon
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Riddell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Catching up in Britain: experts assess the scale of the challenge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/catching-up-covid-public-sector</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/catching-up-covid-public-sector"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T17:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From education to the NHS, mental health and justice, we interview specialists in their fields about recovering ground after the pandemic

Counting the cost

The scale of the challenge facing a creaking criminal justice system is perhaps best articulated by the recent decision to allow the lord chief justice to ask for unlimited funding to open up more courtrooms in England and Wales.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Townsend,  Nosheen Iqbal, Richard Adams, Denis Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK beachgoers bask in sunshine but good weather may not last]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/05/uk-weather-beachgoers-bask-in-sunshine-as-temperatures-reach-almost-23c</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/05/uk-weather-beachgoers-bask-in-sunshine-as-temperatures-reach-almost-23c"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:46:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Temperatures reach 23C but Met Office warns of risk of showers on Sunday
Crowds have flocked to the beaches to soak up the sunshine as temperatures hit almost 23C across parts of England amid warnings the warm weather is not going to last.
Photographs show hundreds of people packed on to Bournemouth beach in Dorset on Saturday, while in the north kayakers took to Derwentwater in the Lake District.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salford residents each face £100,000 bill for post-Grenfell fire safety costs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/salford-residents-each-face-100000-bill-for-post-grenfell-fire-safety-costs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/salford-residents-each-face-100000-bill-for-post-grenfell-fire-safety-costs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:15:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leaseholders fear they won’t qualify for grants that were meant to protect them
A single parent who has been working on NHS Covid testing is among dozens of residents told that they each face a £100,000 bill to remove flammable cladding and make a series of other fire safety improvements to their apartment block.
Matthew Harris said he would be “destroyed” by the costs, which amount to more than he paid for his Salford flat less than a decade ago. Other residents in the Transport House development are said to have been off sick and sought mental health support, in a case that they say exposes serious inadequacies in the government scheme designed to protect leaseholders from serious fire safety costs after the Grenfell tragedy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump set to return to public arena as emails reveal how he pushed election lie]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/arizona-emails-donald-trump-rudy-giuliani-maricopa-audit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/arizona-emails-donald-trump-rudy-giuliani-maricopa-audit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former president to give speech at North Carolina Republican convention as Arizona emails show how audit came to be set up

Will America soon be unable to call itself a democracy?

Donald Trump was forced to confront his drastically diminished online presence this week, as a two-year suspension from Facebook for inciting the Capitol attack followed the closure of his blog, an endeavour which failed to attract an audience.
 Related: Facebook to suspend Trump’s account for two years 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly and Victoria Bekiempis in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunlit Santa Fe: images of New Mexico – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/05/sunlit-santa-fe-images-of-new-mexico-in-pictures-007-natalie-christensen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/05/sunlit-santa-fe-images-of-new-mexico-in-pictures-007-natalie-christensen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After 25 years as a psychotherapist, Natalie Christensen decided it was time for a change. She got married, quit her job and left her native Kentucky for the sunlit plains of Santa Fe, New Mexico. 
“It’s like another world; it has 300 days a year of sunshine and the cloudscapes are incredible,” she says. Inspired by the many artists who lived and worked in the area – Georgia O’Keeffe, Judy Chicago, Edward Weston – Christensen turned to photography to capture landscapes set against bright, angular buildings. 

007 by Natalie Christensen is published by Setanta Books and Open Doors Gallery, £20
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anger on the streets of Porto as Britain shuts down free flow of travel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/anger-on-the-streets-of-porto-as-britain-shuts-down-free-flow-of-travel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/anger-on-the-streets-of-porto-as-britain-shuts-down-free-flow-of-travel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tourism chiefs slam the ‘unfair’ downgrading after invasion of football fans 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Britain’s decision to relegate Portugal to the amber travel list left Francina Pinheiro totally exasperated. “We’ve done everything by the book here,” said Pinheiro, the owner of a cafe beside Torre dos Clérigos, one of Porto’s landmark sights, as customers arrived for lunch on Friday.
“We sanitise everything, we’ve reduced our table numbers. All so we can welcome our friends from overseas.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Balch in Porto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of Britain’s best hotels for spas and beauty treatments]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/05/10-best-britain-hotels-spas-beauty-treatments</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2021/jun/05/10-best-britain-hotels-spas-beauty-treatments"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If post-lockdown relaxation is in order, book a treatment at one of these spa hotels – and add an overnight stay for additional pampering
Missing winter already? This sumptuous spa on picturesque Barnby Moor has a snow-storm shower walk alongside 11 warmer steam and sauna options as well as massages, scrubs and a fully equipped beauty salon. The latest treatments include a salt-inhalation room and another that releases UV. There is also a vitality pool with water jets and a spa restaurant, all built next to the original 17th-century coaching inn.
• Breaks with spa time, lunch and B&B accommodation start at £149.50pp, yeoldebell-hotel.co.uk
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Turner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Education for girls and vaccines can save Africa from disaster | Phillip Inman]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/education-for-girls-and-vaccines-can-save-africa-from-disaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/education-for-girls-and-vaccines-can-save-africa-from-disaster"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parts of the continent potentially face a decade of crisis. These two measures are more important than any other in avoiding it
There are so many good causes in the world it is often difficult to know where aid money should go. As leaders line up to attend the G7 summit in Cornwall, the most effective destinations for aid money have become clearer – a global vaccination programme and improving girls’ education.
This is especially true in sub-Saharan Africa, where so much can go wrong over the next 10 years – a population explosion, massive biodiversity loss, desertification, famine and mass migration to mention just a few – that unless we focus our efforts on vaccines and girls’ education, whatever is done to alleviate poverty or tackle the climate emergency will be threatened or even sabotaged in almost every other region of the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: The Great Post Office Trial; Sound Heap; Made of Stronger Stuff; Bernie: Who Killed the Prince of Soho?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/05/the-week-in-audio-the-great-post-office-trial-sound-heap-made-of-stronger-stuff-bernie-who-killed-the-prince-of-soho</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/05/the-week-in-audio-the-great-post-office-trial-sound-heap-made-of-stronger-stuff-bernie-who-killed-the-prince-of-soho"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The anger is palpable in an update on the Post Office scandal, while the life and death of a famous Soho character fails to strike the right tone
The Great Post Office Trial: The Reckoning (BBC Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Sound Heap | Various podcast providers 
Made of Stronger Stuff (BBC Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Bernie: Who Killed the Prince of Soho? | Various podcast providers
The reporter Nick Wallis made his first piece about the Post Office scandal 10 years ago. Last week, he was back with The Reckoning, an enraging coda to his 10-part series on what we now know to be one of the biggest miscarriages of justice in British legal history. In April, you’ll remember, the convictions for theft, fraud and false accounting of 39 subpostmasters were quashed by the court of appeal. Yet the end of this shameful affair seemingly remains some way off. We still don’t know why the Post Office’s 14-year prosecution spree continued for so long (736 people were criminalised on the basis of information supplied by its faulty Horizon IT system between 2000 and 2014). Nor do we have any sense of when, or even if, anyone will be held to account for it. Standing outside the home of Paula Vennells, the company’s former CEO, in the hope of an interview, Wallis sounded at once determined and weary. Needless to say, her front door remained firmly closed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Cooke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peru faces poll dilemma: a leftist firebrand or the dictator’s daughter?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/peru-poll-dilemma-leftist-firebrand-or-dictators-daughter-carlos-davalos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/peru-poll-dilemma-leftist-firebrand-or-dictators-daughter-carlos-davalos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Novelist Carlos Dávalos says his homeland has an unenviable choice in bitterly divisive presidential election
“Peru has always been a gloomy country; it’s not the Caribbean,” says the writer and journalist Carlos Dávalos as the traffic rolls down the Gran Vía in Madrid on a sunny June morning. “There’s that sense of a kind of Andean melancholy.”
Although Dávalos’s debut novel, La Furia del Silencio (The Fury of Silence), has drawn comparisons with both The Catcher in the Rye and Alfonso Cuarón’s Oscar-winning Roma, the coming-of-age tale is profoundly, and inescapably, Peruvian.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Jones in Madrid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just enjoy your success, Kate Winslet. Your husband can take care of himself | Barbara Ellen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/enjoy-your-success-kate-winslet-your-husband-can-take-care-of-himself</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/enjoy-your-success-kate-winslet-your-husband-can-take-care-of-himself"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T16:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor’s ‘ocean warrior’ spouse does what wives do each day, so why the huge praise?
Why do highly successful women feel they must overpraise spouses who merely do what women do all the time? Kate Winslet is having a “moment” with the television series Mare of Easttown and deservedly so. Still, why did she feel the need to uber-gush about her husband, Edward Abel Smith (Richard Branson’s nephew, formerly self-christened Ned Rocknroll) in a recent New York Times interview? According to Winslet, Abel Smith is a “super-hot, superhuman stay-at-home dad” and an “absolutely extraordinary life partner”. He looks after her and the children. Although dyslexic, he helps Winslet with her lines. He maintains his zen with veganism, yoga, breath work and cold swims. His long hair makes him resemble “an ocean warrior”.
Note to Kate: there are acceptable levels of spousal gushing and then there’s “umbrella for the journalist, please!”. Winslet adds: “He didn’t particularly plan on meeting and marrying a woman who is in the public eye and therefore having been so judged.” And there perhaps you have it: while Winslet stops short of technically de-alpha-ing herself, she could be endeavouring to ensure that her husband doesn’t feel quite so beta.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barbara Ellen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[St Helens hold off thrilling Hull fightback to reach Challenge Cup final]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/hull-st-helens-rugby-league-challenge-cup-semi-final-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/05/hull-st-helens-rugby-league-challenge-cup-semi-final-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T15:55:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Semi-final: Hull 18-33 St Helens
Incredible 90-metre run from Regan Grace decides game

The wait is almost over for St Helens. Anyone who has followed one of rugby league’s most successful clubs in the 13 years since their last Challenge Cup triumph in 2008 would argue the most difficult hurdle is still to be cleared on 17 July when they walk out at Wembley against Castleford, winners of the second semi-final here, for the final of the sport’s most prestigious competition for the 23rd time in their history.
But afternoons like these, where the opposition are resilient, the conditions are energy-sapping and the stakes are high, are the ones where you really find out what a team is made of.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Bower at Leigh Sports Village</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two more teenagers held over fatal stabbing of Dea-John Reid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/05/two-teenagers-held-over-fatal-stabbing-of-dea-john-reid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/05/two-teenagers-held-over-fatal-stabbing-of-dea-john-reid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T15:38:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police ‘acting on information’ arrest two boys aged 14 and 16 on suspicion of Reid’s murder 
Two more teenage boys have been arrested in connection with the fatal stabbing of 14-year-old Dea-John Reid.
Reid was killed in College Road in the Kingstanding area of Birmingham at about 7.30pm on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Slawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Tove Jansson’s love of nature shaped the world of the Moomins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/tove-jansson-moomins-woman-fell-in-love-with-an-island-summer-book</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/tove-jansson-moomins-woman-fell-in-love-with-an-island-summer-book"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T15:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Finnish artist’s work was hugely influenced by her passion for the great outdoors – in particular the tiny island of Klovharun
In 1964, when she was in her 50s, the Moomin creator Tove Jansson settled on her dream island. Klovharun in the Finnish archipelago is tiny – some 6,000 sq metres – and isolated, “a rock in the middle of nowhere”, according to Jansson’s niece, Sophia. It has scarcely any foliage, no running water and no electricity. Yet for Jansson, it was an oasis. For 18 years she and her partner Tuulikki Pietilä spent long summers there, heading out from Helsinki as soon as the ice broke in April, leaving only in early October. The island meant “privacy, remoteness, intimacy, a rounded whole without bridges or fences”.
Klovharun encapsulates something of Jansson’s originality as an artist and writer – and her human presence. Her illustrated Moomin books, which began to be published just after the second world war, brought her phenomenal acclaim and devotion. The tales of amiable troll creatures have been taken to generations of hippy hearts; their pear-shaped faces have adorned a million ties. Their marketing triumph – in which Jansson enthusiastically participated – has overshadowed her other achievements as a painter, novelist, short-story writer, anti-Nazi cartoonist, and designer of magazine covers. Success may also have obscured how ambivalent she was, how often on the cusp of identities. She was brought up in Finland speaking Swedish, had male and female lovers, told her stories in pictures and in prose, lived on water as well as land. More and more she appears as a pioneer. Not least in her crystalline descriptions of the natural world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Susannah Clapp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I can’t recruit chefs’: Brexit and Covid plunge hospitality into crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/brexit-and-covid-plunge-hospitality-into-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/brexit-and-covid-plunge-hospitality-into-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T15:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sunny days should see the UK’s restaurants and pubs welcoming customers, but they face a staffing nightmare
Lunchtime in St Albans on a sunny weekday in half-term, and restaurants, bars and cafes are doing a roaring trade. Demand has bounced back strongly among residents of the Hertfordshire commuter town, who appear eager to eat and drink out again after lockdown.
And after months of enforced closure, hospitality venues, too, are pleased to have finally been able to reopen both their indoor and outdoor seating areas. But the easing of coronavirus restrictions has brought a fresh set of challenges.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna Partridge and Richard Partington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Hanks urges US educators to teach students about Tulsa race massacre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/tom-hanks-tulsa-race-massacre-essay-educators-students</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/05/tom-hanks-tulsa-race-massacre-essay-educators-students"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:09:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Actor writes in New York Times that he ‘never read a page of any school history book’ about 1921 massacre

Opinion: America is recognising Tulsa. Reparations are next

In an essay lamenting the long neglect of the Tulsa race massacre, the Oscar-winning actor Tom Hanks said “white educators and school administrators” in the US had “omitted the volatile subject for the sake of the status quo, placing white feelings over Black experience – literally Black lives in this case”.
 Related: ‘They didn’t talk about it’: how a historian helped Tulsa confront the horror of its past 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suspected extremist attack on Burkina Faso village kills 130 people]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/suspected-extremist-attack-on-burkina-faso-village-kills-100-people</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/suspected-extremist-attack-on-burkina-faso-village-kills-100-people"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Homes burned in Solhan village in one of worst attacks in country beset by jihadist violence
Suspected extremists have killed more than 130 civilians in an overnight attack on a village in northern Burkina Faso, the government said on Saturday, in one of the worst attacks in the country beset by jihadist violence.
The assailants struck during the night on Friday, killing residents of the village of Solhan in Yagha province, near the eastern border with Niger. They also burned homes and a market, the government said, describing the attackers as terrorists.
Roch Kabore, the president, lamented the attack, the worst recorded since jihadist attacks erupted across the country in 2015, destroying ordinary life for millions of mainly impoverished people. “I bow before the memory of the hundred civilians killed in this barbaric attack and extend my condolences to the families of the victims,” he said.
“Several injured have succumbed to their wounds and new bodies have been discovered. The still provisional toll is 138 deaths,” one local official said to Agence France Presse on Saturday evening. “The bodies were buried in mass graves. There are dozens injured.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emmanuel Akinwotu and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Quiet Place Part II review – slick horror sequel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/05/a-quiet-place-part-ii-review-slick-horror-sequel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/05/a-quiet-place-part-ii-review-slick-horror-sequel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emily Blunt is back as the mother silently protecting her kids from aliens in John Krasinski’s skilful if unsatisfying thriller
John Krasinski’s slick, skilful follow-up to his 2018 post-apocalyptic thriller works well as a genre exercise; with patriarch Lee (Krasinski) sacrificed to the first film, Evelyn (Emily Blunt, Krasinski’s real-life partner) and her three children must once again outwit an army of aliens with exceptional hearing. The brains behind the operation is the hearing-impaired Regan (Millicent Simmonds), who is teamed up with reluctant protector Emmett (Cillian Murphy) while Noah Jupe’s nervy little brother tends to the family’s newborn. To suggest Krasinski is only interested in surface thrills feels at odds with the seriousness of his craft. Judicious pacing, clever cross-cutting and visceral sound design build tension, but there’s an absence of soul, and no satisfying sense of what the monsters might be a metaphor for.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simran Hans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On my radar: Omari Douglas’s cultural highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/05/on-my-radar-omari-douglass-cultural-highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/05/on-my-radar-omari-douglass-cultural-highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The It’s a Sin actor on loving Eurovision, going back to 1971 with Asif Kapadia, and Channel 4’s female Muslim punk comedy
Actor Omari Douglas was born in Wolverhampton in 1994 and trained at the Arts Educational Schools in London, graduating in 2015. Earlier this year he made his TV debut playing Roscoe Babatunde in It’s a Sin, Russell T Davies’s Channel 4 drama about the 80s Aids crisis. His theatre credits include Rush (King’s Head theatre), Jesus Christ Superstar (Regent’s Park Open Air) and Emma Rice’s Old Vic adaptation of Wise Children. On 16 June, Douglas will be in conversation with Davies for a Guardian Live event; next month he appears in Constellations at the Donmar.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[And then there was one: the last resident of Bond Street]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/05/the-last-resident-of-bond-street-ollie-claridge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/05/the-last-resident-of-bond-street-ollie-claridge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Dior, Cartier and Asprey as neighbours, Oli Claridge is now the only true local on the famous street. He reveals what it’s like to live among the super-rich
From his vantage point at the oriel windows of his Bond Street flat, Oli Claridge has an unrivalled view of the super-rich going about their business. In London’s most opulent shopping street, where a billion pounds is spent each year, this might involve choosing a £5,000 handbag, trying on a £3m diamond ring, bidding at auction for a Mercury Cougar used in a James Bond movie or sipping pink champagne mid-morning as flawless shop assistants flutter around.
Claridge is a part of this world and apart from it. “I’m a bit of an anomaly,” he says. “Lowering the tone.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harriet Sherwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why self-belief is a superpower that can be harnessed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/talk-yourself-up-the-simple-science-behind-boosting-your-self-belief-confidence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/talk-yourself-up-the-simple-science-behind-boosting-your-self-belief-confidence"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdowns may have eroded people’s swagger, but research suggests there are ways to remedy the situation
In July 2007, the Irish golfer Padraig Harrington won one of golf’s most coveted competitions, the British Open. The story of how he did this, one of the most remarkable finishes in golfing history, illustrates one of the ways confidence works.
The Claret Jug – the Open’s famous prize – was within Harrington’s grasp as he teed off at the penultimate hole of the tournament. He had a one-shot lead on his arch-rival, Sergio García. He was entirely in the zone – “I am literally the most confident person at that point in time,” he said later. Then, something strange happened – a twinge of doubt came out of nowhere at the top of his back swing and he sliced the ball into the murky waters of the notorious Barry Burn river.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Robertson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Despite everything, we’re no unhappier than we were a year ago | Tim Adams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/despite-everything-we-are-no-unhappier-than-we-were-a-year-ago</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/despite-everything-we-are-no-unhappier-than-we-were-a-year-ago"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T14:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest wellbeing index confirms the theory that we quickly get used to almost anything that life throws at us
Among the stranger pieces of psychological research is the idea of thermostatic contentment or, to give it its fancier title, “hedonic adaptation”. The original work was led in the 1970s by the US professor Philip Brickman and published under the title Lottery Winners and Accident Victims: Is Happiness Relative?
The study examined the effects of extreme life-changing events on perceived contentment. Against all intuitive expectation, it discovered that after a short period of adjustment the reported “happiness” of those who had enjoyed a major windfall hardly changed, while those who had suffered an accident still rated themselves above averagely happy. The researchers concluded that happiness adjusted in relation to expectation and that there was a strong genetic element in feelings of contentment.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Midi review – punk-jazz power is a recipe for success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/05/black-midi-review-st-john-at-hackney-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/05/black-midi-review-st-john-at-hackney-london"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T13:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[St John at Hackney, London
The London rockers pack a punch with a thunderous recital of their new album. Shame about the sound…
A sense of frustration hangs over this Black Midi gig, disguised as early evening light filtered through stained glass. In part, it’s down to the times. Rather than celebrate the release of their expansive second album, Cavalcade, by handing out free tinnitus to fans in some low-ceilinged sweatbox as in the before-times, Black Midi’s vivid, stop-start skronk is unleashed in a recently refurbished east London church.
The ceiling is high, the venue is beautiful and two shows on release day double the attendance, making up for social distancing. Tonight’s vibe is very much gratitude for being out of the house, almost having fun. We all know the moves: scan QR code, beer appears. Someone is wearing a cape. “You can have a dance, but stay in your pod,” requests a voice over the PA. A handful of people take up the offer to jerk around.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kitty Empire</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One to Watch: Loraine James]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/05/one-to-watch-loraine-james</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/05/one-to-watch-loraine-james"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T13:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Enfield’s electronic adventurer produces dreamlike, fractured soundscapes flavoured with free jazz, jungle and more
You wouldn’t know it from her fragmented crushes of electronic sound, but Loraine James’s musical journey began with an unexpected choice: 2000s emo band Death Cab for Cutie. Then came the diverse tastes of her mum, who played anything from calypso to heavy metal in the Enfield tower block where James grew up, and where she also came out in her teens. The brightly hued Alma Road Estate appeared on the cover of her 2019 debut, For You and I, both a tender memory of her childhood and a chilling reminder of inner-city gentrification.
James’s work has been described as “fearlessly queer” but, if anything, its defining quality is its unwillingness to sit still: time signatures are out the window and rushes of beats twitch and glitch around each other like free jazz. Her productions are deeply textural, thuds of drum punching through the dense, deconstructed thickets that incorporate IDM, grime, broken beat, jungle and beyond. Often her songs also have a gentle, dream-like quality, marking James out as a Squarepusher for the xx generation, perhaps.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Hutchinson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anna Friel: ‘I thought acting would be a hobby – never a job’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/anna-friel-i-thought-acting-would-be-a-hobby-never-a-job</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/anna-friel-i-thought-acting-would-be-a-hobby-never-a-job"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T13:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The actor, 44, on learning to relax, the double edge of kindness, and the power of herbs
I don’t know which memory came first: falling down the stairs and knocking down our Christmas tree, being bought my first nail varnish and getting it on my Wonder Woman pyjamas, or accidentally setting my brand-new parka on fire the first day I wore it. Each probably reveals something about my soul.
Pop stardom was my plan for a while, although briefly. Coming from an Irish family, I’d often walk into the living room to find 15 musicians going at it. My voice was my instrument, how I discovered self-expression. But deep down I wanted to be a barrister fighting for justice.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Segalov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We are born hungry for faces’: why are they so compelling?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/we-are-born-hungry-for-faces-why-are-they-so-compelling</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/we-are-born-hungry-for-faces-why-are-they-so-compelling"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T13:00:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve spent a year obscured by masks and pixellated by Zoom. Are you ready to go back to reading real-life facial expressions in all their fascinating glory?
This has been the year of a thousand faces. Every face is an inch or two high on my laptop screen, and trapped inside a rectangle. The rectangles form a wall of faces that builds up brick by brick. As each new face arrives, the wall shifts and rearranges itself. Outside, in the real world, other people’s faces have been frustratingly elusive, half-hidden by masks. Or they have averted their gaze, focused on completing their essential journeys and not wishing to exchange their spittle with mine. But here the faces keep coming, popping up magically from wherever they are in the world, happy to be seen.
During lulls in meetings, my eyes scan the virtual room. You can look long and hard at people’s faces online in a way that would be rude in real life. I have never before paid this much attention to how a hairline runs along the top of a forehead, or an eye sits in its socket, or a jawline segues into a neck. I hadn’t noticed how vulnerable faces are – so soft, fleshy and bruisable – and how mercurially they move between moods. The faces look by turns dazed, dogged, sweetly attentive, full of faraway thoughts that no one could guess at, and as if they are trying hard to be bright-eyed and smiley but might suddenly dissolve into tears. It’s been that kind of year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Moran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak announces ‘historic agreement’ by G7 on tax reform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/rishi-sunak-announces-historic-agreement-by-g7-on-tax-reform</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/rishi-sunak-announces-historic-agreement-by-g7-on-tax-reform"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T12:24:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finance ministers agree deal to force multinationals to pay tax in all countries where they operate
The G7 group of wealthy nations have signed a landmark deal to tackle tax abuses by some of the world’s biggest multinationals and establish a minimum global corporation tax for the first time.
Finance ministers from the group agreed the plan on Saturday as part of talks held in London, the chancellor, Rishi Sunak, said. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phillip Inman and Michael Savage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘He was just a child’: dead of Indigenous residential schools haunt Canada]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/canada-indigenous-residential-schools-first-nations-children</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/canada-indigenous-residential-schools-first-nations-children"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T11:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Generations of First Nations children were abducted to institutions to solve the country’s ‘Indian problem’. Thousands never returned
When they came to take Jonnish Saganash away, he was only five years old.
It was 1954, and the Canadian government had decided he was to be sent to a residential school in Ontario – hundreds of kilometers from his Indigenous community in Quebec.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Justin Ling in Montreal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When missing people don’t want to be found: ‘I’d removed myself to push the world away’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/when-missing-people-dont-want-to-be-found-id-removed-myself-to-push-world-away</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/when-missing-people-dont-want-to-be-found-id-removed-myself-to-push-world-away"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T10:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What happens if you decide to disappear – then find yourself plastered over the internet?
At 10pm on Friday 29 January 2016, Esther Beadle closed the front door and walked out of her life. A journalist at the Oxford Mail, she was seen leaving her shared house in Cowley, about an hour’s walk from the centre of Oxford. Then she was gone.
When she didn’t turn up to meet a friend in London the next day, alarm bells started ringing. Within hours there were hundreds of tweets about her, describing her, detailing her last known movements, and asking for information.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francisco Garcia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corner shops got us through lockdown. Now delivery apps could destroy them | Michelle Meagher]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/corner-shops-lockdown-delivery-apps-grocery-stores</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/corner-shops-lockdown-delivery-apps-grocery-stores"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T10:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If the might of global finance crushes grocery stores, communities will lose an important local service
When the first lockdown came into force in the UK last March, supermarket delivery slots vanished. Many people – myself included – began to rely on our local corner shops, stocked with toilet roll and bakers’ yeast. They were somewhere you could pick up a bottle of wine after a shell-shocking day of home schooling, or replenish basics like pasta and rice. They provided a lifeline for families, elderly and isolated people, and those without cars.
These days, though, no sector can flourish without tech companies trying to muscle in. You may have already seen the adverts for apps like Weezy, Jiffy, Getir and Dija: these companies promise they can deliver your groceries faster than it would take you to walk around the corner and back. They cater to harried parents who have run out of nappies, students with late-night munchies, and desperate dinner party hosts short on booze.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flask ceviche, onion tart and pork tonnato sandwiches: Max Halley’s picnic recipes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/05/flask-ceviche-onion-tart-pork-tonnato-sandwich-max-halley-picnic-recipes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/05/flask-ceviche-onion-tart-pork-tonnato-sandwich-max-halley-picnic-recipes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T10:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The quintessential onion tart, the ultimate luxury picnic sandwich and don’t tell us you haven’t tried serving ceviche from a flask...
Weather’s good? You need to get out? Meeting friends in the park but aren’t sure what to make for lunch and you want to look as cool as Christmas? Fret not – I got you!
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Halley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stephen Mangan: ‘Whenever I considered writing, I thought: “What right do you have?”’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/stephen-mangan-whenever-i-considered-writing-i-thought-what-right-do-you-have</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/05/stephen-mangan-whenever-i-considered-writing-i-thought-what-right-do-you-have"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Green Wing and Episodes star talks about making the leap from acting to writing a children’s book about bereavement, and grieving for Helen McCrory and Paul Ritter
“It’s hard to say this without sounding like a dick,” begins the actor Stephen Mangan taking a sip of his black coffee, steeling himself. “But if you’re sensitive – OK, already I sound like a dick, but go with me – and you have trouble revealing that day to day, acting is a great way to deal with it. And if you find people interesting but don’t always know how to deal with them, writing is a great way to explore them from a sniper’s range.”
Mangan, 52, and I are sitting outside a cafe, and the endearing wide-eyed goofiness for which he’s known on screen and stage is replaced, in person, by much gentler self-deprecation. We are just around the corner from his house in Primrose Hill, north London, where he lives with his wife, the actor Louise Delamere, and their three young sons. He has lived in the area for more than 30 years and seems to know pretty much everyone – the waiter, passing pedestrians – but despite being surrounded by all that is familiar, there is a palpable nervousness. As an actor, he has given hundreds of interviews, promoting, among many other things, the peerless sitcom Green Wing, the megahit Episodes, co-starring Tamsin Greig and Matt LeBlanc, and – my personal favourite – Hang Ups, the short-lived sitcom he wrote and starred in about a therapist who talks to everyone over Skype (“I did think [during lockdown] that we were really ahead of the game with that one,” he says). But this is one of his first interviews as an author, because Mangan has written a book for primary-age children called Escape the Rooms, illustrated by his sister, Anita Mangan.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadley Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second world war through the lenses of German soldiers – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/05/the-second-world-war-through-the-lens-of-german-soldiers-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/gallery/2021/jun/05/the-second-world-war-through-the-lens-of-german-soldiers-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T09:52:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1939, thousands of German soldiers, many of them conscripts, were dispatched across Europe. They went armed not only with weapons but with cameras – the famous German Leica and Rolleiflex – in their bags and orders to capture what they saw.

As Britain, France and the Allied countries mark the 77th anniversary of the Normandy landings on D-day this weekend, a recently released book All at War: Photography by German Soldiers 1939-45, is a compilation of these photographs taken from a vast collection held by the Archive of Modern Conflict in London. Here are some of the photographs from the book
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid: Glasgow and 13 other Scottish councils delay move to level 1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/covid-glasgow-and-13-other-scottish-councils-delay-move-to-level-1</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/covid-glasgow-and-13-other-scottish-councils-delay-move-to-level-1"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T09:36:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mainland Scotland was due to drop to less onerous measures on Monday, but some areas to remain at level 2

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The people of Glasgow can finally hug loved ones, meet in homes and drink alcohol indoors for the first time in months, after the city dropped to level 2 of Scotland’s coronavirus measures – alongside an easing of restrictions across the country.
While the whole of mainland Scotland was supposed to move to level 1 on Monday, the city will join 13 other council areas in remaining in level 2 for another few weeks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kevin Rawlinson and agency</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nerves in the Commons as MPs await Boundary Commission report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/05/nerves-in-the-commons-as-mps-await-boundary-commission-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/05/nerves-in-the-commons-as-mps-await-boundary-commission-report"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T09:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[English MPs will be the first to hear their fate as new constituency borders are announced on Monday
Some time before midday on Monday, quite a lot of English MPs will start getting distinctly twitchy. It is then that they will first see the results of a major redrawing of parliamentary boundaries, with a number of seats set to change, even disappear.
The report by the Boundary Commission for England is the latest development in a decade-long process which has previously failed to change the parliamentary map. This time the expectation is it will go ahead, with new constituencies finalised in 2023.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We have to participate’: what Europe’s Gen Z want from their post-Covid lives – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/jun/05/what-europe-gen-z-want-from-their-post-covid-lives-video"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:39:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 policies risk leaving psychological and socioeconomic scars on millions of young people across Europe, with far-reaching consequences for them and society, a wide-ranging Guardian project has revealed.
Taking a snapshot, the Guardian asked five members of Europe’s Generation Z how the worst global pandemic in a century has affected their lives, what they have learned and how they see their future after the pandemic

‘A sacrificed generation’: psychological scars of Covid on young may have lasting impact
How the Covid shock has radicalised Generation Z
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we really are a 'global Britain' we must keep our commitment to international aid | Tobias Ellwood]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/global-britain-commitment-international-aid-g7-summit-soft-power</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/global-britain-commitment-international-aid-g7-summit-soft-power"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the G7 summit gathers, now is not the time for the UK to retreat on a key part of its soft power 
Next week the seven most powerful leaders in the democratic world meet at the G7 summit in Cornwall – literally to put the world to rights.
Britain, as host, has wisely invited three other top democratic nations – Australia, South Korea and India – to join the US, Canada, Japan, France, Germany and Italy.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Ellwood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new summer of love: ‘People are desperate to have sex – it’s been a long year’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/new-summer-of-love-people-desperate-to-have-sex-its-been-a-long-year</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/05/new-summer-of-love-people-desperate-to-have-sex-its-been-a-long-year"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether single, curious or just plain horny, many people are planning to make the most of life after lockdowns. Are we ready to get up close and personal?

The past year has changed 35-year-old Georgie’s outlook on dating. Several disappointing socially distanced dates and limp text exchanges meant she stopped using dating apps at the beginning of 2021. And now her parents have been vaccinated, she feels confident about returning to physical dates, “but not to the apps”, she says. “As things open up, I’m going to lean into spontaneity; I’m going to say yes to every invitation and seize every opportunity. If I feel a connection with someone at a social gathering, a festival or even a bus stop, I’ll go and talk to them. I’m going to be way more carpe fucking diem about it.”
Liam, 25, lives in Manchester and has never had a serious relationship. He can’t wait to meet people in real life: “If I never have another conversation via Zoom or WhatsApp, I’d be very happy – especially within my love life.” He gave up on dating apps this year, and is looking forward to the return of proper flirtation. “Vibing with someone on an app or a screen is not the same as seeing someone across a room and feeling that excitement in your stomach. That’s what I need right now.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandra Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Broadmarsh, Nottingham: city tries to rebuild itself as shopping centre goes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/broadmarsh-nottingham-city-tries-to-rebuild-itself-as-shopping-centre-goes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/05/broadmarsh-nottingham-city-tries-to-rebuild-itself-as-shopping-centre-goes"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demolition of the retail landmark begins this month as the council plans to reinvent the city
Metal rods protrude from half-demolished floors like roots, there’s no roof on what was once BHS and panels of 1970s honeycomb ceiling are stacked like giant Lego pieces.
Nottingham’s Broadmarsh shopping centre is a monument to a retail heyday now past. Final demolition will begin this month after works to reinvent the building, which opened in 1975, were abandoned when its owner, the retail property group Intu, went bust last year and the lease was taken on by the local council.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offset mortgages: are they making a post-Covid comeback?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/05/offset-mortgages-are-they-making-a-post-covid-comeback</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/05/offset-mortgages-are-they-making-a-post-covid-comeback"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T08:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People who have built up a cash pile in lockdown are putting their money to work in accounts linking home loans to savings
Their heyday was the late 1990s and early 2000s, but since then they have fallen out of favour. However, offset mortgages appear to be making a comeback, with some brokers reporting increasing demand.
They link your savings to your home loan, so a savings balance is used to reduce – or offset – the interest you pay on your mortgage. And the renewed interest is partly down to one of the financial side-effects of the pandemic: the fact that some consumers have been lucky enough to be able to build up large pots of “lockdown savings”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If we can vaccinate the world, we can beat the climate crisis | Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/poorer-nations-climate-promises-vaccines-vaccinating-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/05/poorer-nations-climate-promises-vaccines-vaccinating-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T07:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rich countries can’t expect to be trusted on their climate promises if they fail the poorest on vaccines
It would only cost $50bn to ensure 40% of the world’s population is vaccinated by the end of the year, and 60% by the first half of 2022. This is a recent estimate from the IMF, the latest institution to join a chorus of voices calling for a global vaccination programme to bring Covid-19 under control. The IMF has highlighted the economic benefits of global vaccines, which would be huge. But there is another powerful reason for a worldwide campaign.
Vaccinating the world will be crucial if countries are going to act together to confront the climate crisis, which will require many of the same things as delivering vaccines: resources, innovation, ingenuity and a true partnership between rich and developing countries. The Cop26 climate conference in November will be an opportune moment for building this partnership. But to do so, rich countries need to deliver on their early promises to deliver global vaccines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Never stopped me dreaming: how Euro 96 illuminated our world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/never-stopped-me-dreaming-how-euro-96-illuminated-our-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/never-stopped-me-dreaming-how-euro-96-illuminated-our-world"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T07:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty-five years ago, when football last came home, the Euros captured the hope and spirit of the time. Is there any chance this year’s tournament can do the same? 

A quarter of a century on and history repeats itself. England are hosting the Euros, playing Scotland in the group stage, and football’s coming home again. In 1996, it came home for the first time. It was the first major tournament England had hosted since the World Cup victory of 1966. England fans also hoped it was coming home in the larger sense – that the country was going to win the European Championship and end 30 years of hurt. But despite the best efforts of a team fired by the maverick brilliance of Paul Gascoigne, England lost in the semi-final. On penalties, of course. To Germany, of course. Plus ça change, plus c’est la même chose.
Now it’s 55 years, and the clock still ticks away relentlessly, mockingly.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 richest UK families urged to commit £1bn to tackle climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/05/100-richest-uk-families-urged-to-commit-1bn-to-tackle-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/05/100-richest-uk-families-urged-to-commit-1bn-to-tackle-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T07:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As UK prepares for environment push at G7 summit, letter asks richest to make climate charitable focus
The UK’s 100 richest families are being urged to commit £1bn over the next five years to tackle the climate emergency and halt the destruction of the natural world, as the world prepares for a big push on environmental issues at the G7 summit.
Each of the 100 richest families in the UK, and the 100 biggest charitable foundations, will receive a letter on Saturday asking them to make the climate and biodiversity crises a focus of their philanthropic efforts, in order to stave off pending disasters that would imperil all their other charitable efforts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stonewall is at centre of a toxic debate on trans rights and gender identity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/stonewall-trans-debate-toxic-gender-identity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/stonewall-trans-debate-toxic-gender-identity"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T07:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Some have called the LGBT rights charity extremist, others say it’s on the right side of history
Since its 1989 inception in response to a ban on the “promotion of homosexuality” by schools and councils in section 28 of the Local Government Act, Stonewall has been a part of every major struggle for LGBT rights in the UK. But in the past few weeks it has become embroiled in a toxic row.
A founding member has accused it of taking an “extremist stance”, a report accused it of giving incorrect advice on equality law and a cabinet minister was reported to be pushing for all government departments to withdraw from its Diversity Champions programme, which the Equality and Human Rights Commission (EHRC) quit last month.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magawa the mine-sniffing rat ends career in Cambodia on a high]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/magawa-the-mine-sniffing-rat-ends-career-in-cambodia-on-a-high</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/magawa-the-mine-sniffing-rat-ends-career-in-cambodia-on-a-high"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T06:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After five years at the top, it’s retirement for one of the most successful rodents ever trained in finding landmines
After five years of sniffing out landmines and unexploded ordnance in Cambodia, Magawa is retiring.
The African giant pouched rat has been the most successful rodent trained and overseen by a Belgian nonprofit, APOPO, to find land mines and alert its human handlers so the explosives can be safely removed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kim Leadbeater on running for her sister Jo Cox’s seat: ‘I know this is what she would want me to be doing’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/jun/05/kim-leadbeater-on-running-for-her-sister-jo-coxs-seat-i-know-this-is-what-she-would-want-me-to-be-doing</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2021/jun/05/kim-leadbeater-on-running-for-her-sister-jo-coxs-seat-i-know-this-is-what-she-would-want-me-to-be-doing"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T06:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five years after Jo Cox MP was murdered in her constituency, her sister is standing for Labour in a crucial byelection there. She explains why she’s ready to take on Cox’s political legacy
It was the most shocking day in British politics this century. On 16 June 2016, a week before the Brexit vote, brooding tensions came to a climax with one horrific act of violence: the murder of Jo Cox. It was only 13 months since she had been elected to parliament as Labour’s MP for Batley and Spen in West Yorkshire. Cox had been a symbol of hope in politics: young, idealistic, popular, a doer who wanted to make a difference. Then she was fatally shot and stabbed outside a library in Birstall, a small market town in her constituency. Her killer, Thomas Mair, a local resident and far-right extremist, shouted “Britain first” as he attacked her.
Today, her sister Kim Leadbeater says she has blocked out much of what happened. “I know I haven’t really dealt with the day,” she says. “Maybe I never will. Maybe I’ll never need to.” Leadbeater, a fun-loving extrovert, is virtually whispering. “What’s the point? The only person who’ll suffer is me.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Hattenstone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Italian climate activists sue government over inaction]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/italian-climate-activists-sue-government-over-inaction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/italian-climate-activists-sue-government-over-inaction"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T06:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plaintiffs want court to order Mario Draghi’s government to adopt more ambitious climate policies
Environment campaigners in Italy are suing the government for failing to sufficiently tackle the climate crisis in what is the first legal action of its kind in the country.
The 203 plaintiffs will submit their lawsuit to Rome’s civil court on Saturday. They want the court to order the government, led by the prime minister, Mario Draghi, to adopt more ambitious climate change policies as well as significantly increase its carbon emissions reduction target.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Giuffrida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young country diary: an A-Z of my nature walk]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/05/young-country-diary-an-a-z-of-my-nature-walk</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/05/young-country-diary-an-a-z-of-my-nature-walk"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T04:30:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robin Hood’s Bay, North York Moors: My mum and I went on a walk one afternoon in May, and this is what we saw
A is Ash, a type of tree. B is Bees, honey and bumblebee. C is Clovers, with white, pearly petals. D is Dock leaves, a cure for nettles. E is Egg, cracked this time. F is Footprint, an interesting sign. G is Grass, common as cows in herds. H is Hedge, bustling with birds. I is Ivy, climbing up higher. J is Jenny Wren, calling out a desire. K is Kestrel, higher than any trees. L is Light, breaking through the leaves. M is Mud, a long haul. O is Oak, growing strong and tall. N is Nettles, watch out they sting. P is Pine cones, the most intricate thing. Q is Queenie, our chicken who lives in our bay. R is Rays of sunshine, that light up our day. S is Sky, as far as you can see. T is Tracks, whose could they be? U is Unknown, a haven of fun. V is a near Vertical climb, not easy to get done. W is web, a spider’s trap. X is X marks the spot, often on a map. Y is a Y-shaped tree, home to wildlife. Z is Zest, zest for life.
Ellen Hall, 11
• Young country diary: my dream day being a farmer
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Turkey experiments with cannabis crops to boost hemp production]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/turkey-experiments-with-cannabis-crops-to-boost-hemp-production</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/turkey-experiments-with-cannabis-crops-to-boost-hemp-production"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T04:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While cannabis remains taboo topic, economic crisis means Turkey is trialling hemp for industrial use
A bespectacled, well-dressed Islamist recently expelled from the Turkish Journalists’ Association for comparing campaigners against domestic violence to prostitutes is perhaps not the most likely candidate for ardent cannabis advocate.
But Abdurrahman Dilipak, 72, is one of Turkey’s loudest voices in favour of legalisation as attitudes change and the country begins to experiment with reintroducing the once widespread crop.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan in Istanbul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft blocks Bing from showing image results for Tiananmen ‘tank man’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/microsoft-bing-tiananmen-tank-man-results</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/microsoft-bing-tiananmen-tank-man-results"/>
        <updated>2021-06-05T03:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Company blames ‘human error’ after users in US, Germany, Singapore and France reported no results shown on the crackdown’s anniversary 
Microsoft has blamed human error after its search engine, Bing, blocked image and video results for the phrase “tank man” – a reference to the iconic image of a lone protester facing down tanks during the 1989 protests in Tiananmen Square – on the 32nd anniversary of the military crackdown.
Users reported that no results were shown for the search query in countries including the US, Germany, Singapore, France and Switzerland, according to Reuters and Vice News.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong and Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gambling logos feature 700 times in football match, says C4 documentary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/gambling-logos-feature-700-times-in-football-match-says-ch4-documentary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/gambling-logos-feature-700-times-in-football-match-says-ch4-documentary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Scottish Tory chief says ‘radical rethink’ of industry’s ‘parasitic’ ties with the sport is needed
Gambling logos can appear more than 700 times in a single football match, according to a documentary in which former Scottish Conservative leader Ruth Davidson calls for a “radical rethink” of the relationship between the sport and betting.
In her first outing as a TV presenter, Davidson describes the gambling industry’s relationship with football as a “parasite that’s taking over the host” in the Channel 4 programme, due to air on Monday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Search and Filter Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b3480c11ffb70827ef9a88</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/search-and-filter-component-in-reactjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're building a React app, you want your users to be able to search and get exact results. And if you are getting tons of items from an API, then you need to create a way for users to be able to find various items easily.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning in Python – The Top New Scikit-Learn 0.24 Features You Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60ba33d7acb62507dd1d9050</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-python-new-scikit-learn-features-you-should-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scikit-learn is one of the most popular open-source and free machine learning libraries for Python.  The scikit-learn library contains a lot of efficient tools for machine learning and statistical modeling including classification, regression, clustering, and dimensionality reduction. Many data scientists, machine learning engineers, and researchers rely on this library for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Recover from Deployment Hell – What I Learned After My Discord Bot Crashed on a 1000+ User Server]]></title>
        <id>60b8f5c7acb62507dd1d8500</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recovering-from-deployment-hell-what-i-learned-from-deploying-my-discord-bot-to-a-1000-user-server/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I deployed a Discord bot to a 1000+ user server. In the first hour, Deployment Hell struck and my bot crashed. In the next hour, I brought it back, surviving and even thriving in Deployment Hell. In this post, I'll show you how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Zealand’s prison penpals: ‘I had to look at the good things I see in him’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/new-zealands-prison-penpals-i-had-to-look-at-the-good-things-i-see-in-him</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/new-zealands-prison-penpals-i-had-to-look-at-the-good-things-i-see-in-him"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts say writing to people on the outside can help prisoners build purpose – but it goes both ways in what can be a difficult relationship
For the first time since 82-year-old Jan Skilling was a young girl, she has time to spare.
Widowed at 40 and responsible for a nest of kids, grandkids, and now “more great-grandkids than I care to count”, Skilling has spent any spare hour since she can remember looking after everyone but herself. So, in 2017, with retirement from her teaching career looming, she knew it was time for a change.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leni Ma'ia'i in Dunedin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/04/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/04/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:15:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aftermath of the conflict in Gaza and Israel, the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, the Nyiragongo volcano near Goma, and Covid deaths in India: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn TypeScript Basics in this Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b2a4c611ffb70827ef9842</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-typescript-basics/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TypeScript has taken the development world by storm. No wonder it has over 15 million weekly downloads on npm. But what is TypeScript, and what do you need to know about it?  In this article, I am going answer those questions. By the end you'll have a grasp of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barclay family calls truce to end Ritz espionage case in high court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/barclay-family-calls-truce-to-end-ritz-espionage-case-in-high-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/barclay-family-calls-truce-to-end-ritz-espionage-case-in-high-court"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:45:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Frederick Barclay settles case against nephews over alleged secret bugging of hotel’s conservatory
The billionaire Barclay family has declared a truce to end a high court battle over alleged “commercial espionage on a vast scale” that included the bugging of thousands of private conversations at the five-star Ritz hotel.
Sir Frederick Barclay announced on Friday that he had reached a settlement with his nephews, who he was suing over the alleged secret bugging of the Ritz’s conservatory, where he regularly held meetings with his daughter Amanda.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Portugal travel U-turn: red, amber and grey | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-portugal-travel-u-turn-red-amber-and-grey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-portugal-travel-u-turn-red-amber-and-grey"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK government’s about-turn is another example of Boris Johnson’s pandemic policymaking at its worst 
The UK government’s decision to move Portugal from the green to the amber foreign travel list is messy, dubious and disturbingly characteristic of Boris Johnson at his worst. Most immediately, in human terms, it is an instant inconvenience, including financially, to UK travellers to Portugal. Many will have assumed they would get more notice if their plans were under review. To most, the decision came out of a clear blue sky.
The government has dumped visitors from the UK with a difficult choice. They can scramble home before the Tuesday deadline – rebooking flights, and the necessary Covid tests. Or they can remain in Portugal and accept that they will have to quarantine when they return. Disruption for those about to fly out, and who have now had to cancel, is almost as bad. It is a rubbish way to treat citizens. It is also a casual rudeness to Portugal, which has stricter Covid protocols than Britain, and which put itself out for UK visitors when the traffic-light lists were being introduced.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Wigmore Hall: happy 120th birthday | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-wigmore-hall-happy-120th-birthday</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-wigmore-hall-happy-120th-birthday"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may seem staid – to some. But the music played at the Wigmore Hall, and at vital venues like it, stirs the soul



 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you meeting family and friends in a ‘green list’ country to avoid quarantine?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:58:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those who are meeting others in countries that are listed as safe to travel to without quarantine

Friends, families and couples who have been separated by coronavirus restrictions and want to avoid quarantine are able to meet in some countries that are listed as safe to travel to.
We want to hear from those who are travelling to other countries to meet loved ones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK strikes trade deal with Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/uk-strikes-trade-deal-norway-iceland-liechtenstein-liz-truss</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/uk-strikes-trade-deal-norway-iceland-liechtenstein-liz-truss"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:01:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital documents to be used to cut post-Brexit paperwork under agreement hailed by Liz Truss as ‘massive boost’

A trade deal struck with Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein with provisions for digital paperwork to cut down the time and costs of post-Brexit border bureaucracy has been championed by the international trade secretary, Liz Truss, as a “major boost”.
After months of difficult talks, the comprehensive trade deal was hailed by both the UK and Norwegian governments as being pioneering in its scope and measures, with tariff-free trade in industrial goods secured.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tear down every statue? Here’s what to do instead | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/tear-down-every-statue-heres-what-to-do-instead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/tear-down-every-statue-heres-what-to-do-instead"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:45:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gerrard Raven on statues that will never be inappropriate, Toby King on democratic symbols, Ron Fraser on traffic cones, Tim Gossling on adding context, Mike Morrogh on historical evidence, Anthony Isaacs on deliberate disintegration, Michael Cunningham on four plinths for letter writers, and Austen Lynch on ordure’s usefulness
Gary Younge argues that no statues should be erected because perspectives of people’s achievements change over time, and so those celebrated in one age may be derided in another (Why every single statue should come down, 1 June). To me, this seems to be going too far.
It is highly unlikely, for instance, that one day, attitudes towards smallpox will change so radically that a memorial to Edward Jenner is no longer considered appropriate.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My husband knew all about the waterworks | Brief letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/my-husband-knew-all-about-the-waterworks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/my-husband-knew-all-about-the-waterworks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obituary mistakes | Short walks | Ageing | Medical euphemisms | Cuckoos
Regular readers will know that Barbara Ewing (Letters, 3 June) is far from alone in appearing prematurely in the obituary pages and subsequently in corrections. Might it not be an idea to arrange an occasional “resurrections” column? 
Mike Hine 
Kingston upon Thames, London
• With the current long waiting lists for hip and knee replacements, these shorter walks are just what is needed for the older, lamer family members too (10 easy walks in Britain for families with younger children, 2 June). I would have welcomed the presence of a few more pubs.
Alberta Swan 
Scarborough, North Yorkshire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS test and trace alerted Michael Gove four days after Portugal return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/nhs-covid-app-alerted-michael-gove-four-days-after-portugal-return</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/nhs-covid-app-alerted-michael-gove-four-days-after-portugal-return"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:14:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senior Tory returned from Porto after supporting Chelsea in Champions League final

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The Cabinet Office minister, Michael Gove, received an alert from test and trace to say he had come into contact with someone with coronavirus, less than a week after returning from Portugal.
The senior Tory recently returned from Porto, where he had travelled with his son, Will, to support Chelsea in the Champions League final last Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Yorkshire and West Midlands police agree payouts for Hillsborough ‘cover-up’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/south-yorkshire-police-agree-payouts-for-hillsborough-cover-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/south-yorkshire-police-agree-payouts-for-hillsborough-cover-up"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 600 people are to be compensated for false campaign that tried to blame victims for disaster
South Yorkshire and West Midlands police have agreed a settlement with more than 600 people to compensate them for the false police campaign aimed at avoiding responsibility for the 1989 Hillsborough disaster and blaming the victims instead, which bereaved families have always said was a cover-up.
The forces will pay compensation to families whose relatives were among the 96 men, women and children unlawfully killed at Hillsborough, and to survivors of the disaster, for additional trauma and psychiatric damage caused by the police campaign.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World leaders ‘ignoring’ role of destruction of nature in causing pandemics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ending the destruction of nature to stop outbreaks at source is more effective and cheaper than responding to them, scientists say 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The root cause of pandemics – the destruction of nature – is being ignored, scientists have warned. The focus of world leaders on responding to future outbreaks overlooks the far cheaper and more effective strategy of stopping the spillover of disease from animals to humans in the first place, they have said.
The razing of forests and hunting of wildlife is increasingly bringing animals and the microbes they harbour into contact with people and livestock. About 70% of new infectious diseases have come from animals, including Covid-19, Sars, bird flu, Ebola and HIV.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences during the Covid pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you’ve suffered in the past year or been lucky enough to escape the worst of it, we would like to hear your stories about the pandemic
The pandemic has been a difficult, dramatic time for so many of us, for so many different reasons. We have lost loved ones, had our families torn apart, struggled financially and emotionally. Some of us have been stressed by overwork; others by sudden unemployment. We have had to shield from the outside world – or been reluctantly obliged to mix with it.
If you have a story to share we would love to hear from you. You might be a doctor working flat out in A&E, a student who was locked down at university, a key worker forced to serve the public with inadequate PPE, a single mother who had to go months without childcare, a son who couldn’t visit his dying father in the care home … or even one of the lucky ones who has come out of the past year feeling stronger and more optimistic about life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN body pushed to demand stronger climate action from Australia to save Great Barrier Reef]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T06:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservationists lobby World Heritage Committee to demand Australia reduce emissions or risk reef being placed on ‘in danger’ list
Members of the United Nations World Heritage Committee are being lobbied to pressure Australia to commit to more ambitious climate action as part of its plan to slow the decline of the Great Barrier Reef ahead of a key July meeting.
Conservationists have lobbied representatives of 13 of the 21 countries that make up the committee, saying the threat of placing the reef on an “in danger” list should be used to lever more domestic action on greenhouse gas emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Readfearn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazônia: life and death in the Brazilian rainforest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/amazonia-life-and-death-in-the-brazilian-rainforest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/amazonia-life-and-death-in-the-brazilian-rainforest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10th edition of the Carmignac photojournalism award was dedicated to the Amazon and the issues related to its deforestation. Photojournalist Tommaso Protti, accompanied by journalist Sam Cowie, travelled thousands of miles across the Brazilian Amazon. From the eastern region of Maranhão to the western region of Rondônia, through the states of Pará and Amazonas, they portrayed modern-day life in the Brazilian Amazon, where social and humanitarian crises overlap with destruction of the rainforest.

On display at the Saatchi Gallery from 8 June-18 July 2021

As I sat in my hotel room in Marabá, a city in the Amazon state of Pará, Jornal Nacional – Brazil’s flagship news programme – transmitted images of the country’s newly elected president, Jair Bolsonaro. “The Indigenous in their reservations are like animals in a zoo,” he said. It was November 2018.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tommaso Protti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python for Bioinformatics: Use Machine Learning and Data Analysis for Drug Discovery]]></title>
        <id>60b98ebfacb62507dd1d8ec4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-for-bioinformatics-use-machine-learning-and-data-analysis-for-drug-discovery/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you looking for a way to apply Python and machine learning to a real-world application? You should consider Bioinformatics. Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data, in particular when the data sets are large and complex. We just released a course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s mouse plague - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Families and farmers in New South Wales are doing everything they can to fend off a biblical incursion of rodents. Guardian Australia’s Matilda Boseley has spent months reporting on the story – and hearing the experiences of those who have been affected
When mice started breeding in large numbers in New South Wales more than six months ago, residents went to war to repel them. Now they have reached a grim acceptance of their presence – and are counting the costs of a “plague” that has seen crops ravaged and homes ruined.
Rachel Humphreys spoke to Matilda Boseley, who has been reporting on the story, about how the mice came, what damage they have caused, and how difficult it is to get rid of them. And we hear residents’ accounts of what life is like with thousands of mice underfoot, in hay bales, and even in the washing machine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Matilda Boseley; produced by Hannah Moore and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Tutorial – How to Set Up a Front End Development Project]]></title>
        <id>60b11ff811ffb70827ef8f94</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-set-up-a-front-end-development-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T21:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you plan to build a website. Before you start, you want to set up a few tools to make your life easier. But which tools should you have? The JavaScript ecosystem is changing so fast that it can be overwhelming to pick the best tools to use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pain, sweat and smiles: World Sports Photography Awards 2021 – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/pain-sweat-and-smiles-world-sports-photography-awards-2021-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/pain-sweat-and-smiles-world-sports-photography-awards-2021-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T20:31:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With sport mothballed for the best part of the last 12 months, the awards criteria was extended to allow entries from across the past 25 years for any of the 26 categories. The competition is intended for professional and semi-professional sport photographers plus specialist sports photographic agencies. With the wider timeframe there were four times as many entries as normal. Here, we showcase the 10 overall winning entries, click here to check out the winning entries in each category
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield&#x27;s Laws of Computing – What they Are and Why You Should Know Them]]></title>
        <id>60afd68611ffb70827ef86d8</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/schofields-laws-of-computing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:46:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield's Laws of Computing are principles that anyone who works with computers should know. They're focused on data portability, integrity, and security.  Jack Schofield was a prolific journalist who wrote for The Guardian and covered technology for nearly four decades. During that time, he wrote three particular articles called "Schofield's]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lists in Python – A Comprehensive Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b7c02cacb62507dd1d7b80</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lists-in-python-comprehensive-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:42:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s suppose you’re planning to visit your neighborhood store to stock up on essentials. What is the first thing you’d do?  Have the answer already? Yes, you'd probably write down a shopping list! Python also has a built-in data structure called List that’s very similar to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Hackintosh - Install MacOS Big Sur on a PC Using OpenCore]]></title>
        <id>60affbe411ffb70827ef8951</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-hackintosh/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Hackintosh is a non-Mac computer system, made with PC parts, that runs the macOS operating system. In this tutorial, you will learn how to create a Hackintosh. You will learn how to install macOS Big Sur (or any other version of macOS) using OpenCore. The main benefit of a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless vs Fully Managed Services: What&#x27;s the Difference?]]></title>
        <id>60aa708711ffb70827ef5f4b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/serverless-fully-managed-service-difference/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're new to cloud technologies, you might be confused about the difference between serverless technologies and managed services.  So in this article you'll learn what these terms mean and what the main differences are.    What Are Managed Services? A managed service let the end-user focus on using a service]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your best tips for giving up smoking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T13:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on how best to quit smoking 
After a 40-year decline, the number of smokers in England has increased during the pandemic, according to a new study. The biggest rise has been among 18 to 24-year-olds.
We know that many smokers are keen to kick the habit, but quitting can notoriously difficult. With this in mind, we’d love to hear your top tips for giving up. Perhaps you found nicotine replacements, such as patches or chewing gum, helpful while trying to quit? Or maybe you found you needed a distraction, such as a crossword or a Rubik’s cube, to keep your hands and mind busy? Tell us what worked for you.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wuhan lab leak theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden has asked US intelligence services to urgently investigate the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, including the possibility that it began with an accident in a laboratory. The Guardian’s Peter Beaumont looks at the available evidence 
When Covid-19 first emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan, much of the focus of the initial investigation fell on a seafood market that also sold exotic animals for human consumption. But in the months since, no definitive link has been proven and the precise origin story remains unsolved. 
In the intervening period numerous conspiracy theories have spread: that somehow 5G phone signals could be involved, or that the virus is a hoax. Bracketed in with these was a theory that Covid-19 may have been released (accidentally or otherwise) from a lab. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Peter Beaumont; produced by Sami Kent and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the eviction ban ending?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from renters in England who are at risk from losing their home due to the lifting of the eviction ban
The eviction ban in England was lifted on 31 May leaving nearly two million private renters concerned about whether they will be able to find another property if they lose their home. 
We would like to hear from those who have been affected by the eviction ban ending.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad’s decade of destruction in Syria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T02:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Syria’s president, Bashar al-Assad, has presided over a devastating civil war that has caused the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. Martin Chulov describes a man who came back from the brink of defeat to strengthen his grip on a country deeply scarred by war
Bashar al-Assad succeeded his father as president of Syria in 2000. He was just 34, had studied in London, and some hoped he would open up the autocratic country. Instead, following the Arab spring uprising he has cracked down harder than ever on the Syrian people. In the decade-long civil war that followed, more than 500,000 people are thought to have died. 
The Guardian’s Middle East correspondent, Martin Chulov, tells Anushka Asthana that as Assad lost control of vast areas of Syria following the uprising, he was at maximum vulnerability. But the intervention of Iran and Russia proved decisive. Now, after a widely discredited election victory with 95% of the vote, Assad begins his fourth term as president of a country deeply scarred by war. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Martin Chulov; produced by Alice Fordham and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An act of terrorism America tried to forget – 360 video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T07:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This video is best viewed on YouTube. Click here.
On the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, artist Bayeté Ross Smith uses archival photos to create immersive 360 scenes of these events. He finds that the underlying political and economic injustices were not only never addressed, but repeated time and again over the past century.
This story was suppressed from history books and the white perpetrators were never held accountable. And it wasn't just Tulsa. Dozens of other racial terrorism events from 1917 to 1921 have also gone untold, even within the victims' families. 

This is part one of Red Summers, a 360 video series by artist and filmmaker Bayeté Ross Smith on the untold American history of racial terrorism from 1917 to 1921. The project is funded by Black Public Media, Eyebeam, Sundance Institute, Crux XR and the Open Society Foundations.

Read more

Essay: It was among the worst acts of violence in US history, and no one was held accountable – how much has changed in the last 100 years?
‘The loss is incalculable’: descendants of the Tulsa massacre on what was stolen from them 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bayeté Ross Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free radicals to antioxidants: the science behind caring for oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:27:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problem skin often needs special attention. Here’s how to keep a blemish-prone complexion in check
Dr Emma Craythorne has spent her life studying skin; she is a consultant dermatologist, dermatological and laser surgeon and has a private practice on Harley Street. Problem skin, or skin types that can be challenging to manage, is something Craythorne knows a lot about. Here, she gives her unique insight into the way she helps people identify whether they have oily, blemish-prone skin and the skincare ingredients that’ll work best to target it …
Understand your skin type
“The first step in choosing the right skincare products is understanding what your skin type is,” says Craythorne. “To find out if you have oily skin, you want to assess what it feels like after you’ve washed it in the morning and patted it down. Wait 20 minutes; if after 20 minutes oily areas are appearing then you have oily skin.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Gunavardhana</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin and the city: why your serum needs to protect against urban living]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollution, ultraviolet radiation and cigarette smoke can all cause havoc on our skin – but it doesn’t have to. Here’s how to guard your skin from everyday threats
Our skin is the body’s largest organ and works especially hard to cope with the demands of urban living, protecting your body against the impact of free radical-forming ultraviolet (UV) radiation, pollution and cigarette smoke. Dr Ifeoma Ejikeme, dermatologist and founder of Adonia Medical Clinic, says: “Damage to the skin by free radical or reactive oxygen species can include hyperpigmentation, prominent appearance of pores, dull-looking skin and eventually fine lines and premature ageing.”
These skin stressors, combined with the added dermatological strain after months of life in lockdown – being indoors with the central heating on, anxiety and lack of sleep – can also leave the skin looking dull and prone to blemishes. A good night’s rest, meditation, a balanced diet and regular exercise can all help with internalised stress and anxiety, but what about the effects of pollution on the skin?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ateh Jewel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>