<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-05T01:00:18.702Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-05T01:00:18.702Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.10.2</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frightened terns abandon 3,000 eggs after drone illegally crashes on beach]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/tern-bird-eggs-abandoned-drone</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/tern-bird-eggs-abandoned-drone"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:07:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Departure marks one of the largest-scale abandonments of eggs ever at coastal site north of San Diego
About 3,000 elegant tern eggs were abandoned at a southern California nesting island after a drone crashed and scared off the birds, a newspaper reported Friday.
Two drones were flown illegally over the Bolsa Chica ecological reserve in Huntington Beach in May and one of them went down in the wetlands, the Orange County Register said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft blocks Bing from showing image results for Tiananmen ‘tank man’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/microsoft-bing-tiananmen-tank-man-results</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/microsoft-bing-tiananmen-tank-man-results"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Users in US, Germany, Singapore, France and Switzerland reported no results were shown on Friday, the anniversary of the crackdown
Microsoft blocked its search engine, Bing, from returning image and video results for the phrase “tank man” – a reference to the iconic image of a lone protester facing down tanks during the 1989 protests in Tiananmen Square – on Friday, the 32nd anniversary of the military crackdown.
Users reported that no results were shown for the search query in countries including the US, Germany, Singapore, France and Switzerland, according to Reuters and Vice News.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020 team guides part 11: North Macedonia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/euro-2020-team-guides-part-11-north-macedonia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/05/euro-2020-team-guides-part-11-north-macedonia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just being here is a big deal but this creative team can go further, particularly with two group games close to home in Bucharest
This article is part of the Guardian’s Euro 2020 Experts’ Network, a cooperation between some of the best media organisations from the 24 countries who qualified. theguardian.com is running previews from two countries each day in the run-up to the tournament kicking off on 11 June.
North Macedonia will make history this summer, taking part in their first major tournament, and the national team’s success has created total euphoria in the country. Goran Pandev, Elif Elmas, Enis Bardhi, Arijan Ademi, Stefan Ristovski, Ezgjan Alioski, Boban Nikolov and the rest are already heroes back home for what they have done. Just to qualify is a huge success for a small Balkan country with a huge football heart but the coach, Igor Angelovski, does not want the story to end there. The main aim is to continue to achieve this summer and not be a footnote.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vladimir Bulatovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One in four elderly black people in the UK still not vaccinated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/one-in-four-elderly-black-people-in-the-uk-still-not-vaccinated</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/one-in-four-elderly-black-people-in-the-uk-still-not-vaccinated"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Black people in every age group have the lowest vaccination rate, although hesitancy is improving 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 
A quarter of elderly black people in the UK have not been vaccinated, recent figures show, despite signs that hesitancy is improving generally.
Nearly six months after the government kicked off the country’s most ambitious vaccination campaign, almost one in four black people over the age of 70 were not vaccinated as of 26 May, compared with 97% of white people of the same age.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aamna Mohdin and Caelainn Barr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gambling logos feature 700 times in football match, says Ch4 documentary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/gambling-logos-feature-700-times-in-football-match-says-ch4-documentary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/05/gambling-logos-feature-700-times-in-football-match-says-ch4-documentary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-Scottish Tory chief says ‘radical rethink’ of industry’s ‘parasitic’ ties with the sport is needed
Gambling logos can appear more than 700 times in a single football match, according to a documentary in which former Scottish Conservative leader Ruth Davidson calls for a “radical rethink” of the relationship between the sport and betting.
In her first outing as a TV presenter, Davidson describes the gambling industry’s relationship with football as a “parasite that’s taking over the host” in the Channel 4 programme, due to air on Monday evening.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking Horses: Hurricane Lane can blow rest of field away in Derby]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/05/talking-horses-hurricane-lane-can-blow-rest-of-field-away-in-derby-horse-racing-tips</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2021/jun/05/talking-horses-hurricane-lane-can-blow-rest-of-field-away-in-derby-horse-racing-tips"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T23:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charlie Appleby’s colt has progressed with every run and looks a value each-way alternative to the hot favourite 
A little over a week ago, a report suggested that Aidan O’Brien could send as many as eight colts to Epsom Downs for Saturday’s Derby. Instead, for the first time since 2004, O’Brien will rely on a single runner – Bolshoi Ballet, the favourite – just as he did two decades ago when Galileo, Bolshoi Ballet’s sire, gave him the first of his record eight victories in the Classic.
It could be pointed out that Meath, O’Brien’s only runner 17 years ago, finished last of the 14 runners, was subsequently gelded and then sold to race in Hong Kong. The parallels between Saturday’s market leader and his sire, though, are more compelling, not least the fact that both horses were impressive winners of the Derrinstown Derby Trial in May.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Wood</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeanette Winterson burns her own books in protest at ‘cosy little blurbs’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/04/jeanette-winterson-burns-her-own-books-in-outrage-at-cosy-little-blurbs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/04/jeanette-winterson-burns-her-own-books-in-outrage-at-cosy-little-blurbs"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:53:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British novelist says republished works were presented as ‘wimmins fiction of the worst kind’
The author Jeanette Winterson has set fire to a pile of her newly republished books after saying she “hated the cosy little domestic blurbs” on them.
In a tweet on Friday night, the author defiantly wrote: “Absolutely hated the cosy little domestic blurbs on my new covers. Turned me into wimmins fiction of the worst kind! Nothing playful or strange or the ahead of time stuff that’s in there. So I set them on fire.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edna Mohamed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katie Hill ordered to pay $220,000 in costs after failed intimate photos suit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/katie-hill-ordered-to-pay-220000-costs-intimate-photos-suit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/katie-hill-ordered-to-pay-220000-costs-intimate-photos-suit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:49:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ex-congresswoman had sued Daily Mail and two journalists
Hill resigned from Congress in 2019 after photos published

The former California congresswoman Katie Hill has been ordered to pay about $220,000 in attorneys’ fees to the Daily Mail and two conservative journalists she sued after the publication of intimate photos without her consent.
 Related: Ex-congresswoman Katie Hill is ‘still here’ – and she wants the world to know it 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Los Angeles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Search and Filter Components in React]]></title>
        <id>60b3480c11ffb70827ef9a88</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/search-and-filter-component-in-reactjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're building a React app, you want your users to be able to search and get exact results. And if you are getting tons of items from an API, then you need to create a way for users to be able to find various items easily.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tottenham call off move for Antonio Conte after talks with coach break down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/spurs-close-to-hiring-paratici-as-sporting-director-and-target-conte-reunion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/spurs-close-to-hiring-paratici-as-sporting-director-and-target-conte-reunion"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:33:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spurs concerned about Italian’s transfer budget demands
Club are close to hiring Fabio Paratici as sporting director

Tottenham have called off their move to appoint Antonio Conte as their new manager a little over 24 hours after believing they were close to a deal. The London club are primed to hire Fabio Paratici in the role of sporting director as the chairman, Daniel Levy, drives a return to a two-tier management structure.
But they have now gone cold on Conte, the former Chelsea manager, who has just left Internazionale after guiding them to the Serie A title, after growing concerned over his demands and whether he would commit to blooding young players.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Hytner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[G7 aims to reach historic deal on corporate tax abuse this weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/g7-aims-to-reach-historic-deal-on-corporate-tax-abuse-this-weekend</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/g7-aims-to-reach-historic-deal-on-corporate-tax-abuse-this-weekend"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T21:19:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talks hosted by Rishi Sunak believed to be very close to agreement in principle on global reforms
The G7 group of wealthy nations is close to a historic agreement to radically reshape international tax rules by using a global minimum rate of corporation tax to prevent abuse of the system by multinationals.
Finance ministers from the world’s biggest western economies were negotiating details late on Friday with the aim of reaching a landmark deal early on Saturday as part of talks being held in London.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning in Python – The Top New Scikit-Learn 0.24 Features You Should Know]]></title>
        <id>60ba33d7acb62507dd1d9050</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-python-new-scikit-learn-features-you-should-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:58:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scikit-learn is one of the most popular open-source and free machine learning libraries for Python.  The scikit-learn library contains a lot of efficient tools for machine learning and statistical modeling including classification, regression, clustering, and dimensionality reduction. Many data scientists, machine learning engineers, and researchers rely on this library for]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[American Legion official who silenced speech about black history steps down]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/american-legion-silenced-speech-black-history-ohio</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/american-legion-silenced-speech-black-history-ohio"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:54:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Video of colonel having mic cut on Memorial Day went viral
Veterans’ organization moves to close post in Hudson, Ohio

The head of an American Legion post in Ohio stepped down on Friday, amid criticism over a decision to turn off a retired officer’s microphone while he was speaking about how freed black slaves honored fallen soldiers just after the civil war.
 Related: Memphis exhumes body of Klan leader Nathan Bedford Forrest from city park 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Hudson, Ohio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sale make light of Manu Tuilagi’s late withdrawal in rout of Harlequins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/sale-make-light-of-manu-tuilagis-absence-to-thrash-harlequins</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/sale-make-light-of-manu-tuilagis-absence-to-thrash-harlequins"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:44:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sale 45-12 Harlequins
England centre misses match as Covid precaution

Sale blitzed past Harlequins with a seven-try victory and the kind of relentless power performance that made you wonder just how many they might have scored had Manu Tuilagi not been a late withdrawal.
The Sharks move into second place, above Exeter who they face next weekend, and are reaching the business end of the season in superb form.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerard Meagher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Recover from Deployment Hell – What I Learned After My Discord Bot Crashed on a 1000+ User Server]]></title>
        <id>60b8f5c7acb62507dd1d8500</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/recovering-from-deployment-hell-what-i-learned-from-deploying-my-discord-bot-to-a-1000-user-server/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:41:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I deployed a Discord bot to a 1000+ user server. In the first hour, Deployment Hell struck and my bot crashed. In the next hour, I brought it back, surviving and even thriving in Deployment Hell. In this post, I'll show you how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principles for user-centered front-end development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341793</id>
        <link href="https://colinoakley.medium.com/the-web-we-choose-to-build-e921510e3f1b"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:36:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colin Oakley:
• Accessible — Use semantic HTML, and make sure we meet the WCAG 2.1 AA standard as a minimum and it works with assisted technologies (this sits alongside the DWP Accessibility Manual)
• Agnostic — Build 
…
The post Principles for user-centered front-end development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From blame game to dog’s breakfast: how Australia’s aged care homes were left open to Covid again]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/from-blame-game-to-dogs-breakfast-how-australias-aged-care-homes-were-left-open-to-covid-again</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/from-blame-game-to-dogs-breakfast-how-australias-aged-care-homes-were-left-open-to-covid-again"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grave lessons were supposed to have been learned from the 655 pandemic-related aged care deaths in Victoria in 2020. So what went wrong?
As Victoria was in the grips of a Covid-19 second wave that was killing hundreds of people in aged care, the acting chief medical officer, Prof Paul Kelly, said federal, state and territory governments would “redouble our efforts” to make sure the sector was “absolutely prepared” for outbreaks in the future.
On Monday – nine months after the federal government spent $9m to step up Covid preparedness checks in aged care homes, and after the aged care royal commission’s special report into Covid-19 – staff and residents in the sector in Victoria were once again being swabbed and locked down as the virus was detected in two homes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Melissa Davey and Christopher Knaus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Regulator investigates Presbyterian Church of Queensland fund as $26m from investors frozen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/regulator-investigates-presbyterian-church-of-queensland-fund-as-26m-from-investors-frozen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/05/regulator-investigates-presbyterian-church-of-queensland-fund-as-26m-from-investors-frozen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: Parishioners fear individual churches could be sold after receivers appointed to manage debts understood to be $101m
The corporate regulator has launched an investigation into an investment fund run by the collapsed Presbyterian Church of Queensland that took $26m from investors, including church employees and clergy.
Queensland’s supreme court appointed receivers to the church earlier this month. Guardian Australia has learned the church has debts of about $101m, mostly related to its aged care business, Prescare.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Smee and Ben Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australian fashion week resort 2022: key collections – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/05/australian-fashion-week-resort-2022-key-collections-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/gallery/2021/jun/05/australian-fashion-week-resort-2022-key-collections-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the first physical fashion week in more than a year, signs of the pandemic crept into collections, but so did a focus on sustainability – and a sense of optimism 

A swimsuit model at 71: ‘You’ve only got one body so you may as well be proud of it’
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Georgina Safe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Zealand’s prison penpals: ‘I had to look at the good things I see in him’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/new-zealands-prison-penpals-i-had-to-look-at-the-good-things-i-see-in-him</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/05/new-zealands-prison-penpals-i-had-to-look-at-the-good-things-i-see-in-him"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts say writing to people on the outside can help prisoners build purpose – but it goes both ways in what can be a difficult relationship
For the first time since 82-year-old Jan Skilling was a young girl, she has time to spare.
Widowed at 40 and responsible for a nest of kids, grandkids, and now “more great-grandkids than I care to count”, Skilling has spent any spare hour since she can remember looking after everyone but herself. So, in 2017, with retirement from her teaching career looming, she knew it was time for a change.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leni Ma'ia'i in Dunedin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A movement, not a moment: Indigenous design in the spotlight at Australian Fashion Week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/05/a-movement-not-a-moment-indigenous-design-in-the-spotlight-at-australian-fashion-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/05/a-movement-not-a-moment-indigenous-design-in-the-spotlight-at-australian-fashion-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades of underrepresentation and appropriation, First Nations fashion designers and creatives finally hit the runway
Grace Lillian Lee is used to standing ovations; Australian Fashion week is not. On Wednesday 2 June, the designer and creative director of First Nations Fashion and Design, along with her CEO and fellow designer Teagan Cowlishaw, made history with the first runway show featuring only First Nations talent: on the catwalk, making the clothes, and behind the scenes.
First Nations Fashion and Design is a not-for-profit Indigenous corporation aimed at supporting the growth of the Indigenous fashion industry, with self-determination at the heart of their mission. Lee, who has ties to Torres Strait which she explores through her work, and Cowlishaw, who has kinship with Nyikina people and paternal connections with Bardi and Nyul Nyul people, founded the organisation in 2020. They have been running FNFD on a voluntary basis, close to full time, ever since, and both say the project has been years in the making.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alyx Gorman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where will I fill up? My week driving Toyota’s hydrogen car in locked down Melbourne]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/04/where-will-i-fill-it-up-my-week-in-lockdown-with-a-toyota-hydrogen-powered-car</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/04/where-will-i-fill-it-up-my-week-in-lockdown-with-a-toyota-hydrogen-powered-car"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T20:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mirai is a sleek and silent ride but somewhat inconvenient when the only refuelling station in the state was behind a locked security gate
As long as you live near a refuelling station, driving a hydrogen-powered car is brilliant. They’re silent and sleek. They’re good for the environment (I mean the emissions are literally just water), and even more than with a Tesla, you feel like you’re part of some exclusive club.
The only time a hydrogen car might be a bit of a liability is, say if your entire state went into hard lockdown, the company that lent you the car shuts down their headquarters for the week meaning there is no way to return it or get your old car back, and the only refuelling station in the whole state is now behind a locked security gate. In that case, you might be forced to incessantly ration your driving time, constantly checking the fuel gauge, paralysed by the fear that you will end up stranded in the middle of nowhere with no earthly way to get the car moving again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matilda Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donald Trump responds to Facebook ban by hinting at return to White House]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/donald-trump-facebook-white-house</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/donald-trump-facebook-white-house"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taunt directed at Mark Zuckerberg suggests either a presidential run or the unfounded belief that ex-president might be reinstated

US politics – live coverage

Donald Trump has appeared to drop his strongest hint yet at another presidential run in 2024, responding to news of his two-year ban from Facebook on Friday by saying he would not invite Mark Zuckerberg to dinner “next time I’m in the White House”.
It has also been widely reported this week that Trump believes he will be reinstated in the presidency by August.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iran’s supreme leader says rejected election candidates were ‘wronged’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/irans-supreme-leader-says-rejected-election-candidates-were-wronged</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/irans-supreme-leader-says-rejected-election-candidates-were-wronged"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ayatollah Ali Khamenei concedes that some candidates disqualified from 18 June vote were unfairly treated
Iran’s supreme leader has said that some candidates rejected from this month’s presidential election had been “wronged” and unfairly smeared, but the country’s powerful Guardian Council said the decision to ban them would not be reversed.
Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has the final say on Iran’s affairs, last month endorsed the watchdog’s rejection of several prominent candidates – including former parliament speaker Ali Larijani – for the 18 June vote.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/04/20-photographs-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/04/20-photographs-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:15:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The aftermath of the conflict in Gaza and Israel, the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, the Nyiragongo volcano near Goma, and Covid deaths in India: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The need for speed: Mark Wood deserves his moment of supremacy | Barney Ronay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/mark-wood-deserves-moment-supremacy-england-cricket-worlds-quickest-bowler</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/mark-wood-deserves-moment-supremacy-england-cricket-worlds-quickest-bowler"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s quickest bowler is also England’s best and remains an impossibly likable everyday sporting hero
Speed has always been a fascination in sport, from the first Olympic event, the Stadion – essentially an oiled-up naked foot race – to the sense of wellbeing to be found in rewatching YouTube films of Jeff Thompson slingshotting a cricket ball into the chests of sad, stiff-collared Englishmen.
There is something here that stands outside the nuts and bolts of scorecards and victories. In his novel End Zone Don DeLillo called human speed “the last excitement left, the one thing we haven’t used up”. Although, DeLillo probably wasn’t basing this on the prospect of eight wicketless overs with a spongy ball on a desiccated pitch in Galle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Barney Ronay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Bell on Priti Patel and the high court ruling on Napier barracks – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/04/steve-bell-on-priti-patel-and-the-high-court-ruling-on-napier-barracks-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/jun/04/steve-bell-on-priti-patel-and-the-high-court-ruling-on-napier-barracks-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T19:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steve Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigeria suspends Twitter after president’s tweet was deleted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-after-presidents-tweet-was-deleted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/nigeria-suspends-twitter-after-presidents-tweet-was-deleted"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T18:29:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Information minister blames use of platform for ‘activities capable of undermining Nigeria’s corporate existence’
Nigeria’s government has announced an indefinite suspension of Twitter in the country, two days after the social media company removed a post from president Muhammadu Buhari that threatened to punish regional secessionists.
The information minister, Lai Mohammed, said the government had acted because of “the persistent use of the platform for activities that are capable of undermining Nigeria’s corporate existence”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Abuja</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn TypeScript Basics in this Beginner&#x27;s Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b2a4c611ffb70827ef9842</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-typescript-basics/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T18:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TypeScript has taken the development world by storm. No wonder it has over 15 million weekly downloads on npm. But what is TypeScript, and what do you need to know about it?  In this article, I am going answer those questions. By the end you'll have a grasp of the]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[School leaders say pupils should vaccinated as matter of priority]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/04/school-leaders-say-pupils-should-vaccinated-as-matter-of-priority</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/jun/04/school-leaders-say-pupils-should-vaccinated-as-matter-of-priority"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:47:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call follows the approval of Pfizer jab for 12-to 15-year olds and Delta variant outbreaks in English schools
School leaders are calling for pupils to be vaccinated as a matter of priority after UK regulators approved a jab for 12- to 15-year-olds and data showed outbreaks of the Delta variant in schools throughout England.
The Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Authority (MHRA) on Friday gave its approval for the use of the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine in children aged 12 to 15, paving the way for its use among all but the youngest secondary school pupils.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Adams and Sarah Boseley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police ‘flabbergasted’ London Bridge terrorist survived first few shots, inquest hears]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/police-flabbergasted-at-time-it-took-london-bridge-terrorist-to-die-inquest-hears</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/police-flabbergasted-at-time-it-took-london-bridge-terrorist-to-die-inquest-hears"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:46:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Usman Khan was shot at 20 times by firearms officers after killing Jack Merritt and Saskia Jones in 2019
Police have told an inquest they were “flabbergasted” when the convicted terrorist Usman Khan, who was shot to death on London Bridge in 2019, survived the first few shots.
Khan killed 25-year-old Jack Merritt and 23-year-old Saskia Jones at a rehabilitation conference in Fishmongers’ Hall on 29 November 2019. He was chased on to London Bridge and shot at 20 times in two spells, eight minutes apart.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barclay family calls truce to end Ritz espionage case in high court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/barclay-family-calls-truce-to-end-ritz-espionage-case-in-high-court</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/barclay-family-calls-truce-to-end-ritz-espionage-case-in-high-court"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:45:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sir Frederick Barclay settles case against nephews over alleged secret bugging of hotel’s conservatory
The billionaire Barclay family has declared a truce to end a high court battle over alleged “commercial espionage on a vast scale” that included the bugging of thousands of private conversations at the five-star Ritz hotel.
Sir Frederick Barclay announced on Friday that he had reached a settlement with his nephews, who he was suing over the alleged secret bugging of the Ritz’s conservatory, where he regularly held meetings with his daughter Amanda.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Portugal travel U-turn: red, amber and grey | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-portugal-travel-u-turn-red-amber-and-grey</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-portugal-travel-u-turn-red-amber-and-grey"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:30:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The UK government’s about-turn is another example of Boris Johnson’s pandemic policymaking at its worst 
The UK government’s decision to move Portugal from the green to the amber foreign travel list is messy, dubious and disturbingly characteristic of Boris Johnson at his worst. Most immediately, in human terms, it is an instant inconvenience, including financially, to UK travellers to Portugal. Many will have assumed they would get more notice if their plans were under review. To most, the decision came out of a clear blue sky.
The government has dumped visitors from the UK with a difficult choice. They can scramble home before the Tuesday deadline – rebooking flights, and the necessary Covid tests. Or they can remain in Portugal and accept that they will have to quarantine when they return. Disruption for those about to fly out, and who have now had to cancel, is almost as bad. It is a rubbish way to treat citizens. It is also a casual rudeness to Portugal, which has stricter Covid protocols than Britain, and which put itself out for UK visitors when the traffic-light lists were being introduced.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A potent historical artefact’: the statue of Edward Colston’s new role]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/edward-colston-statue-potent-historical-artefact-david-olusoga</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/edward-colston-statue-potent-historical-artefact-david-olusoga"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:28:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Historian David Olusoga says the memorial, on display graffitied and supine, is now telling a story
The statue of the slave trader Edward Colston, which now lies damaged and daubed with graffiti on a museum stand, has been transformed into the most important artefact of Britain’s relationship with its role in the Atlantic slave trade, the historian David Olusoga has said.
As the 19th-century bronze memorial went on display in Bristol, almost a year since it was dragged from its plinth by Black Lives Matter protesters and hurled into Bristol harbour, Prof Olusoga said it had become “a far more important and potent historical artefact”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Gayle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on the Wigmore Hall: happy 120th birthday | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-wigmore-hall-happy-120th-birthday</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/the-guardian-view-on-the-wigmore-hall-happy-120th-birthday"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:25:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It may seem staid – to some. But the music played at the Wigmore Hall, and at vital venues like it, stirs the soul



 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[James Roby urges St Helens to ignore Challenge Cup famine and focus on Hull]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/james-roby-urges-st-helens-ignore-challenge-cup-famine-hull-rugby-league</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/james-roby-urges-st-helens-ignore-challenge-cup-famine-hull-rugby-league"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roby: ‘It’s been a long time between drinks for a club this size’
Saints face Hull in Leigh semi-final on Saturday

The St Helens captain, James Roby, has called on his side to ignore their Challenge Cup drought and focus solely on Saturday’s semi-final with Hull, as the reigning Super League champions look to take another step closer to a first cup success in 13 years this weekend.
Roby, the last Saints player still in the side from the last time they won the Challenge Cup in 2008, admits it has been too long a wait for a club of their stature. However, the 35-year-old believes any obsessing over that record this weekend could contribute to their undoing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Bower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Outrageous’: why was a US health worker charged with spreading Covid?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/new-jersey-josefina-brito-fernandez-home-health-aide-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/new-jersey-josefina-brito-fernandez-home-health-aide-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T17:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attempt to hold a worker criminally liable for the spread of Covid resulted in Josefina Brito-Fernandez losing her license to work, fearing deportation
Prosecutors in Camden, New Jersey, charged a home health aide accused of inadvertently exposing an elderly patient to Covid-19 early in the pandemic in what appears to be the only case of its kind. The patient, an 80-year-old woman, died of the illness in May last year.
The attempt to hold an essential worker criminally liable for the spread of Covid-19 resulted in the worker, 51-year-old Josefina Brito-Fernandez, permanently losing her license to work and entering a probation program for fear she would be deported.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Glenza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you meeting family and friends in a ‘green list’ country to avoid quarantine?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/oct/23/are-you-meeting-family-and-friends-in-european-countries-to-avoid-quarantine-coronavirus"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:58:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those who are meeting others in countries that are listed as safe to travel to without quarantine

Friends, families and couples who have been separated by coronavirus restrictions and want to avoid quarantine are able to meet in some countries that are listed as safe to travel to.
We want to hear from those who are travelling to other countries to meet loved ones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN experts urge Canada and Vatican to hold swift mass graves investigation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/canada-catholic-church-un-experts-mass-graves</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/canada-catholic-church-un-experts-mass-graves"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:42:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nine experts call for ‘full-fledged investigations’ after discovery of remains of 215 Indigenous children at former residential school
UN human rights experts have urged the Canadian government and the Vatican to hold swift and thorough investigations into the discovery of unmarked graves at a former residential school in British Columbia.
The unmarked graves of up to 215 Indigenous children were discovered at the Kamloops Indian Residential Schools last week, using ground-penetrating radar.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agence France-Presse in Geneva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sunderland police seek sheep rustler leaving lambs in suburban gardens]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/police-seek-sunderland-prankster-who-steals-lambs-and-leaves-them-in-gardens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/police-seek-sunderland-prankster-who-steals-lambs-and-leaves-them-in-gardens"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:41:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Northumbria force and RSPCA baffled as to the motive behind three incidents in the last two weeks
Police in Sunderland are looking for a person who has been stealing new-born lambs and leaving them in suburban gardens.
Residents have emerged from their homes three times in the last fortnight to find a lamb abandoned on their lawn after being taken from its mother in the night.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robyn Vinter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holidays abroad: many Britons plan to press on despite government advice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/holidays-abroad-many-britons-plan-to-press-on-despite-government-advice</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/holidays-abroad-many-britons-plan-to-press-on-despite-government-advice"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:40:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tui says half of its passengers booked to visit Portugal in June are still planning to travel

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

As recriminations continue over the UK government’s decision to remove Portugal from the travel green list, many Britons have decided to press ahead with overseas holiday plans, even if that means going against official advice.
At 4.45pm on Sunday 6 June, Pont-Aven, one of Brittany Ferries’ flagship cruise liners, will leave Plymouth for Santander in Spain – the company’s first sailing on that route for eight months. The UK government says people should not travel to amber list locations such as Spain and advises against all but essential travel to the country – but that has not stopped the company, or the more than 800 people making the trip.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drug dealers caught after undertaking police on M6 hard shoulder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/drug-dealers-caught-on-m6-after-overtaking-police-on-hard-shoulder</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/drug-dealers-caught-on-m6-after-overtaking-police-on-hard-shoulder"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:32:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two men took off at 100mph when asked to stop and were later found to have cocaine with street value of £500,000
Two drug dealers were caught with £500,000’s worth of cocaine after they sped past a police patrol car while using the hard shoulder to avoid queues on the motorway.
In a BMW i8 worth more than £100,000, the pair took off at 100mph when police asked them to stop. They were later found to have a rucksack full of cocaine, weighing 5kg and with an estimated street value of £500,000, in their possession.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lando Norris fears marathon F1 season may affect mental health of personnel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/lando-norris-fears-marathon-f1-season-may-affect-mental-health-of-personnel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/lando-norris-fears-marathon-f1-season-may-affect-mental-health-of-personnel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:30:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[McLaren driver moved to speak out by Naomi Osaka withdrawal
‘F1 are going down the right path but 23 races is not a help’

Britain’s Lando Norris has expressed fears that the 2021 Formula One season may exert a heavy toll on the mental health of its teams’ personnel. With Naomi Osaka drawing attention to mental-health issues around professional sport, Norris voiced his concern before this weekend’s Azerbaijan Grand Prix, a meeting that forms part of the longest season in F1 history.
The McLaren driver is enjoying a hugely competitive season and is currently third in the drivers’ championship. He and McLaren may be riding high but Norris was moved to highlight his disquiet over the demands of a 23-race season by Osaka’s withdrawal from the French Open.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giles Richards</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netanyahu embodied dishonest, divisive demagoguery. If he's gone, good riddance | Jonathan Freedland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/netanyahu-exit-israel-problems-coalition-prime-minister</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/netanyahu-exit-israel-problems-coalition-prime-minister"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:15:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although the new coalition taking shape may not agree on much, the prime minister’s downfall is long overdue
It could be over before it starts. As you read this, it may already be unravelling. But a new government has been formed in Israel, thereby removing the man who has ruled that country longer than anyone else. Benjamin Netanyahu has dominated Israeli politics for most of the past quarter-century: first elected as prime minister in 1996, he has ruled Israel uninterrupted for the past 12 years. But now, if the new coalition holds together – a big if – the reign of Bibi, King of Israel, will come to an end. Even if we should have no illusions about what comes next, that itself is a cause for celebration.
It is also the new government’s sole, animating purpose. The motley collection of parties, which runs from the settler hard right through the centre to the liberal left – and which includes a Palestinian Islamist party – has next to nothing else in common. It cannot be described as hawkish or dove-ish, left or right: it is simply the anti-Netanyahu bloc, forged to prise his fingers off the prime ministerial desk once and for all.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Freedland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK strikes trade deal with Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/uk-strikes-trade-deal-norway-iceland-liechtenstein-liz-truss</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/uk-strikes-trade-deal-norway-iceland-liechtenstein-liz-truss"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T16:01:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital documents to be used to cut post-Brexit paperwork under agreement hailed by Liz Truss as ‘massive boost’

A trade deal struck with Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein with provisions for digital paperwork to cut down the time and costs of post-Brexit border bureaucracy has been championed by the international trade secretary, Liz Truss, as a “major boost”.
After months of difficult talks, the comprehensive trade deal was hailed by both the UK and Norwegian governments as being pioneering in its scope and measures, with tariff-free trade in industrial goods secured.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tear down every statue? Here’s what to do instead | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/tear-down-every-statue-heres-what-to-do-instead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/tear-down-every-statue-heres-what-to-do-instead"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:45:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gerrard Raven on statues that will never be inappropriate, Toby King on democratic symbols, Ron Fraser on traffic cones, Tim Gossling on adding context, Mike Morrogh on historical evidence, Anthony Isaacs on deliberate disintegration, Michael Cunningham on four plinths for letter writers, and Austen Lynch on ordure’s usefulness
Gary Younge argues that no statues should be erected because perspectives of people’s achievements change over time, and so those celebrated in one age may be derided in another (Why every single statue should come down, 1 June). To me, this seems to be going too far.
It is highly unlikely, for instance, that one day, attitudes towards smallpox will change so radically that a memorial to Edward Jenner is no longer considered appropriate.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Major joins push to overturn cut to UK overseas aid budget]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/04/john-major-joins-push-to-overturn-cut-to-uk-overseas-aid-budget</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2021/jun/04/john-major-joins-push-to-overturn-cut-to-uk-overseas-aid-budget"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:36:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intervention means all five living former prime ministers have voiced their opposition to the move
John Major has thrown his weight behind efforts to overturn government cuts to the UK’s overseas aid.
Ahead of a possible Commons vote on the issue next week, the former prime minister said the UK needed to remain “a nation that keeps its word”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker Political correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My husband knew all about the waterworks | Brief letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/my-husband-knew-all-about-the-waterworks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/my-husband-knew-all-about-the-waterworks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obituary mistakes | Short walks | Ageing | Medical euphemisms | Cuckoos
Regular readers will know that Barbara Ewing (Letters, 3 June) is far from alone in appearing prematurely in the obituary pages and subsequently in corrections. Might it not be an idea to arrange an occasional “resurrections” column? 
Mike Hine 
Kingston upon Thames, London
• With the current long waiting lists for hip and knee replacements, these shorter walks are just what is needed for the older, lamer family members too (10 easy walks in Britain for families with younger children, 2 June). I would have welcomed the presence of a few more pubs.
Alberta Swan 
Scarborough, North Yorkshire
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[German cardinal offers to resign over sexual abuse ‘catastrophe’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/german-cardinal-offers-to-resign-over-sexual-abuse-catastrophe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/german-cardinal-offers-to-resign-over-sexual-abuse-catastrophe"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T15:23:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reinhard Marx tells pope he wants to share responsibility for church’s failure to deal with abuse by clergy
Cardinal Reinhard Marx, one of Germany’s most senior Catholics, has offered his resignation to the pope over the “catastrophe” of sexual abuse by clerics and other church members.
Marx, the archbishop of Munich and Freising and a prominent liberal, said in a letter to Pope Francis that he wanted to share responsibility for the abuse that had taken place over decades and the failure of the church to deal with it.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kate Connolly in Berlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EU bans Belarus planes from its airspace over activist arrest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/eu-bans-belarus-planes-from-its-airspace-over-blogger-raman-pratasevich-arrest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/eu-bans-belarus-planes-from-its-airspace-over-blogger-raman-pratasevich-arrest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:49:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move follows forced landing of Ryanair flight and detention of Raman Pratasevich last month
The EU has banned Belarusian carriers from its airspace and airports over the forced landing of Ryanair flight FR4978 and arrest of the opposition activist and journalist Raman Pratasevich.
EU ambassadors agreed during a meeting on Friday to require member states to deny the country’s carriers landing and taking off rights and forbid them from overflying the territory of the 27 member states from Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Brussels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[376,000 people in UK have had long Covid symptoms for at least a year – ONS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/04/1-million-people-in-uk-report-experiencing-long-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/04/1-million-people-in-uk-report-experiencing-long-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:44:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data shows marked increase in self-reported cases of symptoms lasting 12 months or more

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Almost 400,000 people in the UK have reported having symptoms of long Covid for at least a year after their initial infection, data suggests, as new figures show coronavirus infection rates are once again rising in England.
This represents a marked increase in the number of people with self-reported long Covid that has lasted for at least a year, according to the Office for National Statistics.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can I :has()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341968</id>
        <link href="https://bkardell.com/blog/canihas.html"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:37:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just joked that we’re basically getting everything we want in CSS super fast (mostly referring to container queries, my gosh, can you imagine they are actually coming?). Now we might actually get parent selectors?! As in .parent:has(.child) { …
The post Can I :has() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modi’s bulldozing of parliament shows him as the architect of a Hindu Taliban | Anish Kapoor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/modi-parliament-taliban-anish-kapoor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/04/modi-parliament-taliban-anish-kapoor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:27:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flattening the majestic Murghal-inspired buildings is the latest stage in a hateful, vanity-fuelled campaign to de-Islamify India
At the heart of New Delhi, the capital of India, sits a Mughal-inspired monument that houses the seat of the Indian parliament. Built by the British architect Edwin Lutyens between 1911 and 1931, the parliament buildings and their grand roadways and water channels follow the form established by the Islamic rulers of Iran and elaborated by the Islamic sultanate of Samarkand and the Mughal rulers of India.
Lutyens designed perhaps the most important Islamic-inspired edifice of modern times. The buildings quote architectural emblems from Hindu temples and palaces, but the grand plan follows the design of Mughal-Islamic landscape with a light nod to Roman triumphalism. It is, in my view, the greatest set of government buildings anywhere in the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anish Kapoor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tory rebellion on aid shows Johnson’s support is a mile wide and an inch deep | Katy Balls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/tory-aid-rebellion-boris-johnson-surprise-theresa-may</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/tory-aid-rebellion-boris-johnson-surprise-theresa-may"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:12:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government has been taken by surprise by a disparate alliance led by a string of former ministers
When Tory MPs went public this week with their plans to thwart Boris Johnson’s decision to cut foreign aid, Downing Street was caught by surprise. While tensions have been bubbling ever since the plan to reduce the aid budget was first set out by the chancellor last year, the assumption in government has been that its majority of 80 would be enough to get it through.
This has proved overly optimistic. As the numbers opposed became clearer, the government has been trying to dodge a vote on the matter. But the rebels appear to have found a way to bring the issue to the floor of the Commons using the legislation for Dominic Cummings’ pet project, the Advanced Research and Invention Agency, as a vehicle for an amendment on foreign aid. “The spectre of Cummings is never far away,” complains a member of government.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katy Balls</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[French Open draw opens up as Serena Williams beats Danielle Collins]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/aryna-sabalenka-french-open-woes-return-anastasia-pavlyuchenkova-tennis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/jun/04/aryna-sabalenka-french-open-woes-return-anastasia-pavlyuchenkova-tennis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:10:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Third seed Sabalenka loses to Pavlyuchenkova
Williams only top ten player in her half of draw

Serena Williams is now the only top ten player left in the bottom half of the women’s Roland Garros draw, a scenario that in almost all other years would mark her as a clear title favourite, no questions asked. At 39 years old, five years removed from her last successful clay season and as she tries to scrape off three-month old cobwebs in time, answers are needed. With her 6-3, 6-4 third-round win over Danielle Collins on Friday, some were indeed provided.
The match itself was high quality from all parts of the court and it pitted Williams against one of the more fascinating players. Florida-born Collins is an excellent athlete and her two-handed backhand is a stunning shot. Throughout the encounter, she lasered it from every part of the court. She is also loud and combative, known for shaking stadiums with the force of her cheers.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender-critical feminist charged over allegedly transphobic tweets]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/gender-critical-feminist-charged-over-allegedly-transphobic-tweets"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:02:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scottish accountant Marion Millar’s case seized on as exemplar of clash between free speech and trans rights
An accountant working for a gender-critical feminist group in Scotland has been charged in relation to allegedly homophobic and transphobic tweets in a case that has been seized on as an exemplar of the apparent clash between free speech and transgender rights.
Marion Millar, from Airdrie, was bailed to appear at Glasgow sheriff court next month. Millar works at For Women Scotland, a group that brought a legal challenge against the Scottish government in January over its definition of “woman” in an act to improve gender representation on public boards.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can I stop my mother’s constant criticism bringing me down?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/how-can-i-stop-my-mothers-constant-criticism-annalisa-barbieri</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/how-can-i-stop-my-mothers-constant-criticism-annalisa-barbieri"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T14:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes family patterns become so set that we no longer challenge them, says Annalisa Barbieri. I wonder if there might be a conversation to be had
I love my mother most of the time, but sometimes I hate her. She has always been critical of me; it’s as if she has to find fault (with my hair, my clothes, the way I do things). My brother is spared this criticism.
My mum is in her late 70s, and unlikely to change. It’s never worth arguing with her – especially now, as she is grieving and vulnerable following the death of my father last year. I suppress my anger, keep quiet and change the subject. I call and visit often, as I now have to help her with legal and financial affairs; my brother lives abroad and this isn’t his skill set. Mum lives in a different part of the country from me, and it’s not practical to go just for the day, so I am very much on her turf when I visit; if I don’t do things the way she wants, there is an explosion. She then seems to recognise that she has gone over the top and sends sweet emails a day or two later about how capable I am.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annalisa Barbieri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Any menstrual changes after Covid jab would be short-lived, experts say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/04/any-menstrual-changes-covid-jab-would-be-short-lived-experts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/04/any-menstrual-changes-covid-jab-would-be-short-lived-experts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:30:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists responding to anecdotal accounts say there is no fertility risk and experiences are highly variable 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Researchers exploring whether Covid vaccines may disrupt menstrual cycles have said any potential changes to periods are short-term and do not affect fertility.
Though any link between the jab and changes in periods is yet to be proven, anecdotal accounts have been highlighted in blogs and on social media. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicola Davis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US government report finds no evidence UFOs were alien – but doesn’t rule it out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/us-government-ufo-report-aliens-navy-pilots</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/us-government-ufo-report-aliens-navy-pilots"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:25:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Officials cannot explain strange movements in skies that baffle the US military and scientific establishment, New York Times reports
US intelligence authorities have not found any evidence that unidentified flying objects (UFOs) seen by navy pilots in recent years were otherworldly alien spacecraft– but apparently did not rule it out, either.
Officials cannot explain the strange movements in the skies that continue to baffle the US military and scientific establishment, the New York Times has reported, based on information from senior administration officials who were briefed on the outcome of a much-awaited government assessment about these phenomena.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Bekiempis in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tories have worked out how to pull off an NHS data grab: do it during a pandemic | Marina Hyde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/tories-nhs-data-grab-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/tories-nhs-data-grab-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:17:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking data from patients in England was so unpopular in 2014 it had to be shelved. Now it’s happening without the scrutiny
It feels so wrong starting an article with the words “you need to hear about this” when it doesn’t concern things Gwyneth Paltrow wants you to put up your vagina, or 20 of the world’s most important kitchen islands. Even so, would you … could you possibly consider listening to this?
Eight years ago the government had a plan so good it couldn’t tell you about it. It wanted to scrape everyone in England’s entire GP records and put them on one central database, where they would be anonymised – well, sort of! – then made available for research purposes to third parties, including private corporations. And called it Care.data, which is precisely the sort of name you’d give to either (a) a plan to grab everyone’s health data and let commercial firms like Google use it without their explicit consent, or (b) a desktop folder with pictures of everyone in your workplace using the second-floor toilets. But it’s OK, because you don’t show their heads. You set the camera up so it’s just neck-down.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Hyde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS test and trace alerted Michael Gove four days after Portugal return]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/nhs-covid-app-alerted-michael-gove-four-days-after-portugal-return</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/nhs-covid-app-alerted-michael-gove-four-days-after-portugal-return"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:14:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Senior Tory returned from Porto after supporting Chelsea in Champions League final

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The Cabinet Office minister, Michael Gove, received an alert from test and trace to say he had come into contact with someone with coronavirus, less than a week after returning from Portugal.
The senior Tory recently returned from Porto, where he had travelled with his son, Will, to support Chelsea in the Champions League final last Saturday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Campbell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump’s ex-counsel quizzed on Russia investigation after two-year fight]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/trump-counsel-don-mcgahn-testify-russia-investigation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/04/trump-counsel-don-mcgahn-testify-russia-investigation"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:13:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don McGahn to testify to House judiciary committee on Friday
McGahn defied subpoena to testify in 2019 on Trump’s orders

Don McGahn, the former White House counsel to Donald Trump, “shed new light” on the investigation into Russia’s meddling in the 2016 elections, two years after House Democrats originally sought his testimony.
McGahn, who served as Trump’s presidential lawyer for nearly two years before resigning in October 2018, testified in a day-long, closed-door session before the US House of Representatives judiciary committee.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Laughland and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gordon Brown: Boris Johnson’s mistakes could still catch up with him]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/gordon-brown-boris-johnson-mistakes-catch-up-with-him</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/jun/04/gordon-brown-boris-johnson-mistakes-catch-up-with-him"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:12:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: ex-PM cites example of Margaret Thatcher whose political demise came soon after landslide win

Boris Johnson’s conduct in office could still sink him despite his buoyancy in opinion polls, Gordon Brown has said, recalling the demise of Margaret Thatcher three years after a landslide election victory because “mistakes … caught up with her”.
The former Labour prime minister, speaking to the Guardian as he publishes a new book, also praised the climate movement, #MeToo and Black Lives Matter and predicted huge electoral changes across the world that he said would be led by the young.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Yorkshire and West Midlands police agree payouts for Hillsborough ‘cover-up’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/south-yorkshire-police-agree-payouts-for-hillsborough-cover-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/jun/04/south-yorkshire-police-agree-payouts-for-hillsborough-cover-up"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:02:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 600 people are to be compensated for false campaign that tried to blame victims for disaster
South Yorkshire and West Midlands police have agreed a settlement with more than 600 people to compensate them for the false police campaign aimed at avoiding responsibility for the 1989 Hillsborough disaster and blaming the victims instead, which bereaved families have always said was a cover-up.
The forces will pay compensation to families whose relatives were among the 96 men, women and children unlawfully killed at Hillsborough, and to survivors of the disaster, for additional trauma and psychiatric damage caused by the police campaign.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Conn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My six-year-old son has taken up football– I’ve become his team’s biggest fan | Romesh Ranganathan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/my-six-year-old-son-has-taken-up-football-ive-become-his-teams-biggest-fan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/my-six-year-old-son-has-taken-up-football-ive-become-his-teams-biggest-fan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:00:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have found myself getting more and more into the games. I stop short of giving advice, but I shout encouragement to my son, and then last week...
It was just about the moment when I loudly cheered the crunching tackle that took out a child and left him on the floor that I realised that I may have crossed a line in my spectating of my son’s football team. For the last few weeks I have been spending Sunday mornings watching them and, as with many extracurricular activities, discovered that there are a whole series of social etiquette issues and parental judgments involved that I hadn’t anticipated.
First, just to be clear, the kid who was floored got up and walked away unhurt. It was an example, hilariously, of a very young child mimicking professional footballers, which means there are lots of children collapsing and rolling around on the grass in a way that you never would if you were actually injured. There have also been some insanely over-the-top goal celebrations. We are yet to see the kids surround the referee, but they’re only six, so let’s give it a year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Romesh Ranganathan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harry Trevaldwyn: ‘I would quote SNL instead of developing a personality of my own’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/04/harry-trevaldwyn-i-would-quote-snl-instead-of-developing-a-personality-of-my-own</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/04/harry-trevaldwyn-i-would-quote-snl-instead-of-developing-a-personality-of-my-own"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The comedian, actor and writer on the things that make him laugh the most
At university – brag! – I would quote SNL instead of developing a personality of my own. Kristen Wiig and Fred Armisen’s Garth and Kat is so silly and so wonderful.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hoppy days: our pick of the best no- and low-alcohol beers and ales | Fiona Beckett on drink]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/04/hoppy-days-our-pick-of-the-best-no-and-low-alcohol-beers-and-ales</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/04/hoppy-days-our-pick-of-the-best-no-and-low-alcohol-beers-and-ales"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T13:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The days of anaemic alcohol-free lager being the only option are long gone – these days, you can find something you’ll like in almost any style of beer
It’s a bit of an irony that to enjoy the best of what the world of alcohol-free drinks has to offer, you need to be a bit of a hop head in the first place – or, in other words, a beer-lover. Or, perhaps more accurately, not have a mental block about drinking the stuff. As with full-strength craft beers, there’s now enough booze-free choice out there to engage almost anyone who loves flavour, whether or not they identify as a beer drinker.
But why is alcohol-free beer so successful, especially when no-alcohol wine isn’t? The main reason is that the two main flavouring ingredients of beer, malt and hops, are still present, while brewers can, and do, add other ingredients to flavour their beers (cocoa nibs to porter, for example). Plus, it’s lower in alcohol to start with than wine, so there isn’t so much ground to make up.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Beckett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Narrative verdict in inquest into death of woman who leant out of train window]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/narrative-verdict-in-inquest-into-death-of-woman-who-leant-out-of-train-window</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/narrative-verdict-in-inquest-into-death-of-woman-who-leant-out-of-train-window"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T12:50:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jury concludes Bethan Roper, 28, died after hitting head on tree branch as she travelled home to south Wales
A woman was killed by an overhanging tree branch when she stuck her head out of a window of a moving train, an inquest jury has concluded.
Bethan Roper, 28, received fatal head injuries in the incident on a Great Western Railway (GWR) train that was travelling at around 75mph. Roper was returning home to south Wales on 1 December 2018 from a day out with friends Christmas shopping in Bath.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time, teaching and tutoring? The UK government has coined yet another pointless slogan | Zoe Williams]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/time-teaching-tutoring-uk-government-pointless-slogan</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/04/time-teaching-tutoring-uk-government-pointless-slogan"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The education recovery tsar has quit, tutoring is being outsourced and Gavin Williamson is in charge. Business as usual, then
The government’s vision to restore a year of lost education to England’s children has had the ramshackle start you might have expected. It unveiled a plan so bad that the man holding the title of education recovery commissioner, Sir Kevan Collins, immediately resigned. Its cost works out at so little per pupil that it would probably have brought children more material benefit to just buy them all a scratchcard and let them fight for the winnings.
As dispiriting as the situation is, it was foreseeable from the moment ministers came out with their strategy. Of all the myths of political communication, one of the most insulting is that the public responds really well to alliteration. Thus, “time, teaching and tutoring” was born, because we would hear all those “Ts” and think: ah, those noises sound alike! How elegant – this policy must have emerged from substantial amounts of thought.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zoe Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Axe to I May Destroy You: who will win the 2021 TV Baftas – and who deserves to?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/04/small-axe-to-i-may-destroy-you-who-will-win-the-2021-tv-baftas-steve-mcqueen-michaela-coel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/04/small-axe-to-i-may-destroy-you-who-will-win-the-2021-tv-baftas-steve-mcqueen-michaela-coel"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T12:42:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steve McQueen’s anthology series and Michaela Coel’s daring drama are the frontrunners – but the judges have tough decisions to make when it comes to reflecting the pandemic
The 2021 Bafta TV awards are unusual in reflecting a year in which there were many months with no production – the closest equivalent is the industrial strikes of the 70s and 80s, which took networks off air. But, as so much material was made before the pandemic, there are still tough decisions for this year’s judges.
Here are some points to bear in mind. Juries – viewing a longlist based on Bafta members’ votes – sit separately, with no reference to each other. This prevents ticket-splitting (“We’ll give A the acting prize because B got the directing one”). Also, jurors leave the room not knowing the final winner, which rules out leaks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Lawson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Powfu: the lo-fi rapper who became a Covid-era star without leaving his bedroom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/04/rap-powfu-isaiah-faber-death-bed-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/04/rap-powfu-isaiah-faber-death-bed-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T12:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year the Canadian musician scored a global hit with Death Bed (Coffee for Your Head) – now he’s finally ready to meet his fans
For the lockdown superstar, omnipresent fame feels very much like obscurity used to. “I’ve been waiting a long time to go play with the fans,” says Powfu – AKA 22-year-old, Canadian lo-fi rapper Isaiah Faber – gazing around at the same four walls he was staring at before his breakthrough track Death Bed (Coffee for Your Head) unexpectedly racked up 360m YouTube streams, 4bn TikTok plays in March 2020 alone, and major chart placings worldwide at the very start of the pandemic. “But it’s made it a bit easier because it wasn’t like everything hit me at once. It’s not full-level yet.”
 Related: The Guide: Staying In – sign up for our home entertainment tips 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Beaumont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to dress for your vaccine appointment | Jess Cartner-Morley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/04/how-to-dress-for-your-vaccine-appointment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/04/how-to-dress-for-your-vaccine-appointment"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T12:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The one-shoulder top: not just good for getting a jab
Did you get a vaccine selfie? Man, I wanted one so bad. I wanted one almost as much as I wanted the jab itself. But what with the speed of the vaccine rollout being the only not-rubbish thing that had happened in the world in for ever, when it was my turn, I didn’t feel I could hold up proceedings by asking someone to take a photo. Which is a shame, because naturally I had planned an outfit. I mean, if there was ever a red-letter day to dress up for, this was it. I was never going to settle for rolling up a shirt sleeve when I had a great excuse to wear a Studio 54-esque one‑shoulder number on a weekday morning.
The vaccine top is the new Zoom collar, except with added feelgood factor. Like the Zoom collar, it is fashion that has been art-directed by the pandemic, rather than by the catwalk. It is practical (the naked shoulder offers easy access to prime arm real estate, saving you from the indignity of trying to squeeze your arm through a tight sleeve, which can be surprisingly difficult) but it is also a way of honouring the moment. You could just go in a short-sleeve T-shirt, but where’s the photo op in that?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jess Cartner-Morley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Death of a Black Man review – an inflammatory study of social mobility]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/04/the-death-of-a-black-man-review-hampstead-theatre-alfred-fagon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/04/the-death-of-a-black-man-review-hampstead-theatre-alfred-fagon"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:58:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hampstead theatre, London
Depravity takes hold of a pair of young black entrepreneurs in 1970s London in this revival of Alfred Fagon’s idea-filled play

It has taken almost half a century for Alfred Fagon’s play to be revived since its 1975 premiere at Hampstead theatre. It is high time, too: it is an example of the maverick imagination that made the late playwright a key figure in the black British theatre movement of his time.
The man of the title is set to die in a gutter off-stage but the characters we encounter could not be further removed from him: they are up-and-coming entrepreneurs Shakie (Nickcolia King-N’Da), an 18-year-old living in a fancy flat in Chelsea, west London, and his best friend Stumpie (Toyin Omari-Kinch), as well as Jackie (Natalie Simpson), the mother of Shakie’s child who has come to stay.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arifa Akbar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong finds new ways to remember Tiananmen Square amid vigil ban]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/hong-kong-finds-new-ways-to-remember-tiananmen-square-amid-vigil-ban</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/hong-kong-finds-new-ways-to-remember-tiananmen-square-amid-vigil-ban"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:54:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents light candles, lay flowers and paint messages as police enforce ban on annual vigil for massacre

Hong Kong vigil leader arrested as 7,000 police enforce ban on protests

A man walked down a Hong Kong street on Friday wearing a shirt hand-painted with “There is nothing to say”. The previous night an artist held a placard aloft reading: “Don’t go to Victoria Park and light candles”.
On any other day these sights would have been confusing, but on Friday they were a small symbol of resistance to authorities’ efforts to stop anyone from commemorating the 4 June 1989 massacre of student protesters in Beijing.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdown makes humble flip-flop summer’s high-fashion hit]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/04/lockdown-makes-humble-flip-flop-summers-high-fashion-hit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/fashion/2021/jun/04/lockdown-makes-humble-flip-flop-summers-high-fashion-hit"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:50:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gucci flip-flops on sale for £220 and heeled styles become bestsellers as consumers opt for comfort
Flip-flops have long been a staple of heatwaves, found everywhere from beaches to barbecues. But, in 2021, the humble footwear – which can cost as little as £5 – are set to be fashion’s shoe of the summer.
Flip-flops featured in the collections of high-fashion brands usually associated with high heels. Jacquemus, Stella McCartney and even fashion’s arbiter of glamour, Tom Ford, endorsed flip-flops this spring.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Cochrane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toddler dies in Derbyshire paddling pool incident]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/toddler-dies-in-derbyshire-paddling-pool-incident</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/toddler-dies-in-derbyshire-paddling-pool-incident"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:49:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say 23-month-old boy was discovered unresponsive in village of Somercotes on Wednesday
A toddler has died after being found unresponsive in a paddling pool in a Derbyshire village.
The 23-month-old boy was discovered in Somercotes on Wednesday, Derbyshire police said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Panda’s ice-cream and the Pillar of Shame: Friday’s best photos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/04/pandas-ice-cream-and-the-pillar-of-shame-fridays-best-photos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/jun/04/pandas-ice-cream-and-the-pillar-of-shame-fridays-best-photos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:43:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joe Plimmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anthony Bourdain: trailer released for Oscar-tipped documentary Roadrunner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/04/anthony-bourdain-trailer-roadrunner-morgan-neville</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/04/anthony-bourdain-trailer-roadrunner-morgan-neville"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:37:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Morgan Neville’s posthumous study of the much-loved chef and TV star will be narrated by Bourdain himself
Roadrunner, a new documentary examining the life, death and legacy of Anthony Bourdain, has released a first trailer.
The film, which is directed by Oscar-winner Morgan Neville, splices unseen and archive footage of the much-loved chef, author and TV star with new talking-head interviews from those close to him. Bourdain’s own voiceover is used, so he appears to narrate his own story.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian Film</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dazzle with colour! 15 easy June gardening tasks to kickstart the summer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/dazzle-with-colour-15-easy-june-gardening-tasks-to-kickstart-the-summer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/04/dazzle-with-colour-15-easy-june-gardening-tasks-to-kickstart-the-summer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:22:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With warmer weather finally here, it’s time to fill every square inch of the garden with bedding plants, climbers, rainbow chard ...
Now is the moment to fill every spare container and bare patch of earth with summer bedding. If you’re bored with petunias, lobelias and the usual “pub hanging basket” favourites, there are lots of more exotic options: I’ve listed five of my favourites below. If you’re panicking that you haven’t got started with any gardening yet, don’t worry, there’s plenty you can get on with now to kickstart the growing year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jane Perrone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Euro 2020: your complete guide to all 622 players]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/04/euro-2020-complete-guide-to-all-622-players-ratings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/ng-interactive/2021/jun/04/euro-2020-complete-guide-to-all-622-players-ratings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:08:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about all the players, including pets, hobbies and heroes. Click on the circular player picture for a full profile 

If you like this interactive, and would like to support our journalism, you can make a contribution from as little as £1. It only takes a minute. Thank you. 

 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Christenson and Steven Bloor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lisey’s Story review – a swollen snoozefest from Stephen King]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/04/liseys-story-review-stephen-king-julianne-moore</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jun/04/liseys-story-review-stephen-king-julianne-moore"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T11:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supernatural silliness, metaphorical monsters, and dread that doesn’t so much as build as never lets up ... not even Julianne Moore’s turn as a grieving wife can save this bloated bore
The advice that a writer should “kill all your darlings” has been variously attributed. William Faulkner, Allan Ginsberg, Oscar Wilde, GK Chesterton and Arthur Quiller-Couch all get a look-in. Stephen King approved the accepted wisdom in his book On Writing. “Kill your darlings, kill your darlings,” he said with the relish one would hope for from a master of horror. “Even when it breaks your egocentric little scribbler’s heart, kill your darlings.”
 Related: Joan Allen: ‘Acting’s like tennis. You bring your game’ 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucy Mangan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World leaders ‘ignoring’ role of destruction of nature in causing pandemics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/end-destruction-of-nature-to-stop-future-pandemics-say-scientists"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:56:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ending the destruction of nature to stop outbreaks at source is more effective and cheaper than responding to them, scientists say 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The root cause of pandemics – the destruction of nature – is being ignored, scientists have warned. The focus of world leaders on responding to future outbreaks overlooks the far cheaper and more effective strategy of stopping the spillover of disease from animals to humans in the first place, they have said.
The razing of forests and hunting of wildlife is increasingly bringing animals and the microbes they harbour into contact with people and livestock. About 70% of new infectious diseases have come from animals, including Covid-19, Sars, bird flu, Ebola and HIV.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dea-John Reid murder accused to stand trial in February]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/dea-john-reid-accused-to-stand-trial-in-february</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jun/04/dea-john-reid-accused-to-stand-trial-in-february"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:51:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Shields, 35, appears before crown court charged with killing 14-year-old in Birmingham
A 35-year-old man is due to stand trial next year charged with the murder of a teenager who was chased and stabbed to death in Birmingham.
Dea-John Reid, 14, was killed in College Road in the Kingstanding area of the city at about 7.30pm on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[World’s soils ‘under great pressure’, says UN pollution report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/soils-great-pressure-un-pollution-report-food-farming-mining</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/soils-great-pressure-un-pollution-report-food-farming-mining"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:30:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soils provide 95% of all food but are damaged by industrial, farming, mining and urban pollution
The world’s soils, which provide 95% of humanity’s food, are “under great pressure”, according to a UN report on soil pollution.
Soils are also the largest active store of carbon, after the oceans, and therefore crucial in fighting the climate crisis. But the report said industrial pollution, mining, farming and poor waste management are poisoning soils, with the “polluter pays” principle absent in many countries.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damian Carrington Environment editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell us about your experiences during the Covid pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/tell-us-about-your-experiences-during-the-covid-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether you’ve suffered in the past year or been lucky enough to escape the worst of it, we would like to hear your stories about the pandemic
The pandemic has been a difficult, dramatic time for so many of us, for so many different reasons. We have lost loved ones, had our families torn apart, struggled financially and emotionally. Some of us have been stressed by overwork; others by sudden unemployment. We have had to shield from the outside world – or been reluctantly obliged to mix with it.
If you have a story to share we would love to hear from you. You might be a doctor working flat out in A&E, a student who was locked down at university, a key worker forced to serve the public with inadequate PPE, a single mother who had to go months without childcare, a son who couldn’t visit his dying father in the care home … or even one of the lucky ones who has come out of the past year feeling stronger and more optimistic about life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started With Webpack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/getting-started-webpack/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern browsers provide good support for JavaScript modules, but module bundlers such as webpack stay a critical part of the JavaScript toolchain. Let’s take a deep dive into what webpack is and how to use it in your development workflow.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Nwani Victory)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Belize gripped by arrest of Ashcroft son’s partner over officer’s death]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/belize-gripped-by-arrest-of-ashcroft-sons-partner-jasmine-hartin-over-officers-death</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/belize-gripped-by-arrest-of-ashcroft-sons-partner-jasmine-hartin-over-officers-death"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T09:54:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discontent simmers over police handling of investigation as Canadian Jasmine Hartin awaits bail hearing
A late-night stroll in the moonlight, then a sudden and fatal gunshot. What exactly happened between the socialite partner of the son of a billionaire Tory donor and a senior police officer in the early hours of last Friday in the resort of Mata Rocks has gripped the small Caribbean nation of Belize and turned into an international drama. It is now a major test for the country’s legal and criminal system.
This week a 32-year-old Canadian woman, Jasmine Hartin, was accused of the negligent manslaughter of a local police superintendent, Henry Jemmott. The case has attracted attention because Hartin is the partner of Andrew Ashcroft, son of Michael Ashcroft, the Conservative party donor and Belize’s most influential resident. Lord Ashcroft is a former Tory party deputy chairman, a one-time member of the House of Lords, and a billionaire.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What do you think of it so far? Voters rate Amlo’s Mexico ‘transformation’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-amlo-mexico-midterm-elections</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-amlo-mexico-midterm-elections"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T09:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Andrés Manuel López Obrador remains popular but midterm elections may reflect judgments of his handling of the pandemic and endemic violence
Nearly three years have passed since Andrés Manuel López Obrador was elected president of Mexico and, before a sea of euphoric supporters, promised: “I will not fail you. You will not be disappointed.”
 Related: ‘Huge incentives to kill’: Mexico crime groups target election candidates 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Agren in Mexico City and Analy Nuño in Guadalajara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week five]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-five</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jun/04/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-five"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T09:00:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first four of the six stories were reprinted in the Guardian on 7, 14, 21 and 28 May. The fifth is below, with the final one to follow on Friday 11 June along with the other five, alongside a form for entries. You must guess the date that each of the stories appeared. The first 10 randomly chosen readers who correctly identify the dates (or got closest to them) will receive prizes, including a ti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I started streaming video games on Twitch at the age of 43]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/04/why-i-started-streaming-video-games-on-twitch-at-the-age-of-43</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/04/why-i-started-streaming-video-games-on-twitch-at-the-age-of-43"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over lockdown, comedian, mother of two and former games journalist Ellie Gibson took up livestreaming, loved the community – and learned to love playing again
Like so many things in my life, it began as a daft experiment. I love learning new stuff, and over the course of my 43 years I’ve tried all sorts. Some things have stuck, like comedy, running, and having kids. Some haven’t, like kung fu, olives and holidays in Germany. To be honest, I thought that livestreaming games on Twitch would fall into the latter category.
For those who aren’t familiar (I wasn’t until this year), Twitch involves playing video games live on the internet while providing a running commentary. People watch you, and chat to you via a message window, and sometimes give you money. It’s sort of like exotic dancing, but with fewer breasts.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ellie Gibson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Naomi Osaka's French Open withdrawal means for tennis – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/jun/04/what-naomi-osakas-french-open-withdrawal-means-for-tennis-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:02:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is growing pressure on tennis authorities and the conduct of grand slam tournaments after world No 2 Naomi Osaka withdrew from Roland Garros following a fallout over her choice not to conduct her media obligations, which she says was an effort to preserve her mental wellbeing.

The Guardian’s Tumaini Carayol says the heavy-handed statement and response from the French Open to the 23-year-old’s decision marks a ‘shameful moment for tennis’. He explains how we got here, looks back at press conference controversies in tennis and examines what could come next

Sport loves athletes with mental health issues – if they just shut up and play | Marina Hyde
I played alongside Jordan. I’ve seen the pressure on athletes like Naomi Osaka | Etan Thomas
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tumaini Carayol, Jamie Macwhirter and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of the best songs from Small Axe, chosen by Steve McQueen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/04/10-best-songs-music-small-axe-steve-mcqueen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2021/jun/04/10-best-songs-music-small-axe-steve-mcqueen"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T08:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the Wailers to Al Green to Small Faces, the Oscar-winning director selects his favourite tunes from the world of his acclaimed series of films
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>As told to Steve Rose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Unchain your wife’: the Orthodox women shining a light on ‘get’ refusal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/jewish-orthodox-women-divorce-get-refusal</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jun/04/jewish-orthodox-women-divorce-get-refusal"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T07:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Orthodox Jewish men give their wives a ‘get’ as the couple is divorcing, which seals the divorce according to religious law
On Route 59 in Monsey, New York, an Orthodox Jewish enclave in upstate New York, there is a large billboard that says in big block letters: “Dovid Wasserman. Give your wife a get!”
A “get” is a document Orthodox Jewish men give their wives as the couple is divorcing; it seals the divorce according to religious law, meaning that the husband decides if and when the divorce is final. Without it, the woman cannot move on with her life.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caren Chesler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[After Love director Aleem Khan: ‘I walked around Mecca and prayed not to be gay’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/04/after-love-director-aleem-khan-i-walked-around-mecca-and-prayed-not-to-be-gay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/04/after-love-director-aleem-khan-i-walked-around-mecca-and-prayed-not-to-be-gay"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T07:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The director’s debut feature draws on his experiences of loss and identity confusion, with a memorable role for Joanna Scanlon as a fictionalised version of his white English Muslim-convert mother
Mary, the central character of Aleem Khan’s debut film After Love, is a white English woman who met her Pakistani husband as a teenager on the London housing estate where they both lived. After they got married, they moved to the Kent coast. Mary converted to Islam, started to wear traditional dress, learned how to cook curries from scratch and to speak Punjabi.
It does not take an enormous amount of detective work to understand from where Khan drew inspiration: his mother is a white English woman who met her Pakistani husband as a teenager on the London housing estate where they both lived. After they got married, they moved to the Kent coast; she converted to Islam, started to wear traditional dress, learnt how to cook curries from scratch and to speak Punjabi.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarfraz Manzoor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN body pushed to demand stronger climate action from Australia to save Great Barrier Reef]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/un-body-pushed-to-demand-stronger-climate-action-from-australia-to-save-great-barrier-reef"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T06:47:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Conservationists lobby World Heritage Committee to demand Australia reduce emissions or risk reef being placed on ‘in danger’ list
Members of the United Nations World Heritage Committee are being lobbied to pressure Australia to commit to more ambitious climate action as part of its plan to slow the decline of the Great Barrier Reef ahead of a key July meeting.
Conservationists have lobbied representatives of 13 of the 21 countries that make up the committee, saying the threat of placing the reef on an “in danger” list should be used to lever more domestic action on greenhouse gas emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Graham Readfearn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazônia: life and death in the Brazilian rainforest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/amazonia-life-and-death-in-the-brazilian-rainforest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/04/amazonia-life-and-death-in-the-brazilian-rainforest"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 10th edition of the Carmignac photojournalism award was dedicated to the Amazon and the issues related to its deforestation. Photojournalist Tommaso Protti, accompanied by journalist Sam Cowie, travelled thousands of miles across the Brazilian Amazon. From the eastern region of Maranhão to the western region of Rondônia, through the states of Pará and Amazonas, they portrayed modern-day life in the Brazilian Amazon, where social and humanitarian crises overlap with destruction of the rainforest.

On display at the Saatchi Gallery from 8 June-18 July 2021

As I sat in my hotel room in Marabá, a city in the Amazon state of Pará, Jornal Nacional – Brazil’s flagship news programme – transmitted images of the country’s newly elected president, Jair Bolsonaro. “The Indigenous in their reservations are like animals in a zoo,” he said. It was November 2018.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tommaso Protti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python for Bioinformatics: Use Machine Learning and Data Analysis for Drug Discovery]]></title>
        <id>60b98ebfacb62507dd1d8ec4</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/python-for-bioinformatics-use-machine-learning-and-data-analysis-for-drug-discovery/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:32:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you looking for a way to apply Python and machine learning to a real-world application? You should consider Bioinformatics. Bioinformatics is an interdisciplinary field that develops methods and software tools for understanding biological data, in particular when the data sets are large and complex. We just released a course]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australia’s mouse plague - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/04/the-biblical-mouse-plague-ravaging-new-south-wales-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T02:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Families and farmers in New South Wales are doing everything they can to fend off a biblical incursion of rodents. Guardian Australia’s Matilda Boseley has spent months reporting on the story – and hearing the experiences of those who have been affected
When mice started breeding in large numbers in New South Wales more than six months ago, residents went to war to repel them. Now they have reached a grim acceptance of their presence – and are counting the costs of a “plague” that has seen crops ravaged and homes ruined.
Rachel Humphreys spoke to Matilda Boseley, who has been reporting on the story, about how the mice came, what damage they have caused, and how difficult it is to get rid of them. And we hear residents’ accounts of what life is like with thousands of mice underfoot, in hay bales, and even in the washing machine.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Matilda Boseley; produced by Hannah Moore and Sami El-Enany; executive producers Archie Bland and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Tutorial – How to Set Up a Front End Development Project]]></title>
        <id>60b11ff811ffb70827ef8f94</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-set-up-a-front-end-development-project/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T21:44:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s say you plan to build a website. Before you start, you want to set up a few tools to make your life easier. But which tools should you have? The JavaScript ecosystem is changing so fast that it can be overwhelming to pick the best tools to use.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pain, sweat and smiles: World Sports Photography Awards 2021 – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/pain-sweat-and-smiles-world-sports-photography-awards-2021-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/pain-sweat-and-smiles-world-sports-photography-awards-2021-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T20:31:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With sport mothballed for the best part of the last 12 months, the awards criteria was extended to allow entries from across the past 25 years for any of the 26 categories. The competition is intended for professional and semi-professional sport photographers plus specialist sports photographic agencies. With the wider timeframe there were four times as many entries as normal. Here, we showcase the 10 overall winning entries, click here to check out the winning entries in each category
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield&#x27;s Laws of Computing – What they Are and Why You Should Know Them]]></title>
        <id>60afd68611ffb70827ef86d8</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/schofields-laws-of-computing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:46:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Schofield's Laws of Computing are principles that anyone who works with computers should know. They're focused on data portability, integrity, and security.  Jack Schofield was a prolific journalist who wrote for The Guardian and covered technology for nearly four decades. During that time, he wrote three particular articles called "Schofield's]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lists in Python – A Comprehensive Guide]]></title>
        <id>60b7c02cacb62507dd1d7b80</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/lists-in-python-comprehensive-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:42:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s suppose you’re planning to visit your neighborhood store to stock up on essentials. What is the first thing you’d do?  Have the answer already? Yes, you'd probably write down a shopping list! Python also has a built-in data structure called List that’s very similar to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Hackintosh - Install MacOS Big Sur on a PC Using OpenCore]]></title>
        <id>60affbe411ffb70827ef8951</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-hackintosh/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T18:07:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Hackintosh is a non-Mac computer system, made with PC parts, that runs the macOS operating system. In this tutorial, you will learn how to create a Hackintosh. You will learn how to install macOS Big Sur (or any other version of macOS) using OpenCore. The main benefit of a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless vs Fully Managed Services: What&#x27;s the Difference?]]></title>
        <id>60aa708711ffb70827ef5f4b</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/serverless-fully-managed-service-difference/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T16:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you're new to cloud technologies, you might be confused about the difference between serverless technologies and managed services.  So in this article you'll learn what these terms mean and what the main differences are.    What Are Managed Services? A managed service let the end-user focus on using a service]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>freeCodeCamp.org</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341584</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hexagons-and-beyond-flexible-responsive-grid-patterns-sans-media-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A little while back, Chris shared this nice hexagonal grid. And true to its name, it’s using —wait for it — CSS Grid to form that layout. It’s a neat trick! Combining grid columns, grid gaps, and creative clipping …
The post Hexagons and Beyond: Flexible, Responsive Grid Patterns, Sans Media Queries appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341494</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/monitoring-lighthouse-scores-and-core-web-vitals-with-debugbear/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T14:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DebugBear takes just a few seconds to start using. You literally point it at a URL you want to watch, and it’ll start watching it. You install nothing.
It’ll start running tests, and you’ve immediately got performance charts you can …
The post Monitoring Lighthouse Scores and Core Web Vitals with DebugBear appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share your best tips for giving up smoking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/jun/03/share-your-best-tips-for-giving-up-smoking"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T13:20:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear your advice on how best to quit smoking 
After a 40-year decline, the number of smokers in England has increased during the pandemic, according to a new study. The biggest rise has been among 18 to 24-year-olds.
We know that many smokers are keen to kick the habit, but quitting can notoriously difficult. With this in mind, we’d love to hear your top tips for giving up. Perhaps you found nicotine replacements, such as patches or chewing gum, helpful while trying to quit? Or maybe you found you needed a distraction, such as a crossword or a Rubik’s cube, to keep your hands and mind busy? Tell us what worked for you.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Shared State In Vue 3]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/managing-shared-state-vue3/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing large-scale Vue applications can be a challenge. In this article, Shawn Wildermuth dives into the pros and cons of approaches like factories, shared objects, and using Vuex. He also explains what is coming in Vuex 5.0 that might change how we all use shared state in Vue 3.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shawn Wildermuth)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The jobs went, the drugs moved in’: America’s addiction nightmare – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/the-jobs-went-the-drugs-moved-in-americas-addiction-nightmare-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jun/03/the-jobs-went-the-drugs-moved-in-americas-addiction-nightmare-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T06:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From opioids to crack, families have been torn apart by the drug crisis rampaging through the US – as the stark work of these three photographers shows
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wuhan lab leak theory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/03/the-wuhan-lab-leak-theory-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T02:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden has asked US intelligence services to urgently investigate the origins of the Covid-19 pandemic, including the possibility that it began with an accident in a laboratory. The Guardian’s Peter Beaumont looks at the available evidence 
When Covid-19 first emerged in the Chinese city of Wuhan, much of the focus of the initial investigation fell on a seafood market that also sold exotic animals for human consumption. But in the months since, no definitive link has been proven and the precise origin story remains unsolved. 
In the intervening period numerous conspiracy theories have spread: that somehow 5G phone signals could be involved, or that the virus is a hoax. Bracketed in with these was a theory that Covid-19 may have been released (accidentally or otherwise) from a lab. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Peter Beaumont; produced by Sami Kent and Dominic Fitzgerald; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debugging iOS Safari]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341724</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/debugging-ios-safari/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T21:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I debug Safari on iOS?
These are my general steps, starting with not even using iOS Safari.
1. Is this just a small-screen problem?
Lemme just use the device mode in Chrome quick.
Note that this does a …
The post Debugging iOS Safari appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iggy Pop ascends to greatness: Tom Copi’s best photograph]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/iggy-pop-stage-dive-tom-copi-best-photograph</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/jun/02/iggy-pop-stage-dive-tom-copi-best-photograph"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:56:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[‘Iggy dived off the stage into the crowd, where he was lifted up by fans and stood above them in triumph. Someone handed him a jar of peanut butter and he smeared it on his chest’
Iggy Pop and I went to the same high school in Ann Arbor, Michigan, where I graduated a year ahead of him. I was not particularly into the local rock scene but I did photograph activities on and around the university campus, including a band called the Prime Movers, in which Jim Osterberg played drums. Later, Jim started a band called Iggy and the Iguanas, and thenceforth, he was Iggy.
I photographed Iggy’s new band the Stooges at the university’s Hill Auditorium. One of the pictures from that session in 1968 was later used on the movie poster to promote Jim Jarmusch’s 2016 documentary on the band, Gimme Danger: The Story of the Stooges.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Daniel Dylan Wray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341442</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-crash-course-in-wordpress-block-filters/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocks in WordPress are great. Drop some into the page, arrange them how you like, and you’ve got a pretty sweet landing page with little effort. But what if the default blocks in WordPress need a little tweaking? Like, what …
The post A Crash Course in WordPress Block Filters appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmitry Mayorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341572</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/are-custom-properties-a-menu-of-what-will-change/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:35:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PPK laid out an interesting situation in “Two options for using custom properties” where he and Stefan Judis had two different approaches for doing the same thing with custom properties. In one approach, hover and focus styles for a …
The post Are Custom Properties a “Menu of What Will Change”? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/how-to-fix-cumulative-layout-shift-issues/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Core Web Vitals initiative has taken the SEO and Web Performance worlds by storm and many sites are busy optimizing their Page Experience to maximize the ranking factor. The Cumulative Layout Shift metric is causing trouble to a lot of sites, so let’s have a look at ways of addressing any issues for that metric.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of An Online Store (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/front-end-performance-online-store-jewellerybox/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a good performance score from Google is hard for any website — but doing so for an online store is even harder. We achieved green scores — even several for mobile. Here is how we did it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jennifer Brehm)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How have you been affected by the eviction ban ending?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jun/02/how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-eviction-ban-ending"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T09:53:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from renters in England who are at risk from losing their home due to the lifting of the eviction ban
The eviction ban in England was lifted on 31 May leaving nearly two million private renters concerned about whether they will be able to find another property if they lose their home. 
We would like to hear from those who have been affected by the eviction ban ending.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bashar al-Assad’s decade of destruction in Syria]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/jun/02/bashar-al-assads-decade-of-destruction-in-syria-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T02:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Syria’s president, Bashar al-Assad, has presided over a devastating civil war that has caused the deaths of hundreds of thousands of people. Martin Chulov describes a man who came back from the brink of defeat to strengthen his grip on a country deeply scarred by war
Bashar al-Assad succeeded his father as president of Syria in 2000. He was just 34, had studied in London, and some hoped he would open up the autocratic country. Instead, following the Arab spring uprising he has cracked down harder than ever on the Syrian people. In the decade-long civil war that followed, more than 500,000 people are thought to have died. 
The Guardian’s Middle East correspondent, Martin Chulov, tells Anushka Asthana that as Assad lost control of vast areas of Syria following the uprising, he was at maximum vulnerability. But the intervention of Iran and Russia proved decisive. Now, after a widely discredited election victory with 95% of the vote, Assad begins his fourth term as president of a country deeply scarred by war. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Martin Chulov; produced by Alice Fordham and Sami el-Enany; executive producers Phil Maynard and Archie Bland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code blocks, but better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341720</id>
        <link href="https://ped.ro/blog/code-blocks-but-better"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T22:08:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedro Duarte made a wishlist for styled code blocks in blog posts and documentation, then hand-rolls a perfect solution for that wishlist. For example, a feature to be able to highlight certain lines or words within the code block. The …
The post Code blocks, but better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Front-End Testing is For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341342</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/front-end-testing-is-for-everyone/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:17:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Testing is one of those things that you either get super excited about or kinda close your eyes and walk away. Whichever camp you fall into, I’m here to tell you that front-end testing is for everyone. In fact, …
The post Front-End Testing is For Everyone appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evgeny Klimenchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341296</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/jetpack-boost-handles-critical-css-for-you/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:16:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critical CSS is one of those things I see in my performance reports but always seem to ignore. I know what it means. It means to put only the CSS required to render things immediately visible in a <style>…
The post Jetpack Boost Handles Critical CSS For You appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 38 With Ivan Akulov: Why Is My React App Slow?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/smashing-podcast-episode-38/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about React performance. What factors slow our React apps down, and how can we fix it? Drew McLellan talks to expert Ivan Akulov to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up A Currency Convertor With ExchangeRatesApi.io]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/06/currency-convertor-exchangeratesapi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-01T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon allows visitors to display prices in their own currency. Thanks to *ExchangeRatesApi.io*, we can do the same for our online shops, providing a better experience to our customers. Let’s find out how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340465</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/serverless-functions-the-secret-to-ultra-productive-front-end-teams/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:16:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern apps place high demands on front-end developers. Web apps require complex functionality, and the lion’s share of that work is falling to front-end devs:
building modern, accessible user interfaces
creating interactive elements and complex animations
managing complex application state
…
The post Serverless Functions: The Secret to Ultra-Productive Front-End Teams appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Lengstorf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local: Always Getting Better]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341482</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/local-always-getting-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T17:13:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been using Local for ages. Four years ago, I wrote about how I got all my WordPress sites running locally on it. I just wanted to give it another high five because it’s still here and still great. In …
The post Local: Always Getting Better appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy June Vibes For Your Screen (2021 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-june-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What could be a better way to welcome June than with some colorful inspiration? Well, we might have something for you: wallpapers created with love by artists and designers from across the globe.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An act of terrorism America tried to forget – 360 video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/video/2021/may/31/an-act-of-terrorism-america-tried-to-forget-360-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-31T07:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note: This video is best viewed on YouTube. Click here.
On the 100-year anniversary of the Tulsa race massacre, artist Bayeté Ross Smith uses archival photos to create immersive 360 scenes of these events. He finds that the underlying political and economic injustices were not only never addressed, but repeated time and again over the past century.
This story was suppressed from history books and the white perpetrators were never held accountable. And it wasn't just Tulsa. Dozens of other racial terrorism events from 1917 to 1921 have also gone untold, even within the victims' families. 

This is part one of Red Summers, a 360 video series by artist and filmmaker Bayeté Ross Smith on the untold American history of racial terrorism from 1917 to 1921. The project is funded by Black Public Media, Eyebeam, Sundance Institute, Crux XR and the Open Society Foundations.

Read more

Essay: It was among the worst acts of violence in US history, and no one was held accountable – how much has changed in the last 100 years?
‘The loss is incalculable’: descendants of the Tulsa massacre on what was stolen from them 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bayeté Ross Smith</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adding A Commenting System To A WYSIWYG Editor]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/commenting-system-wysiwyg-editor/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll be re-using the foundational WYSIWYG Editor built in the first article to build a commenting system for a WYSIWYG Editor that enables users to select text inside a document and share their comments on it. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful VS Code Extensions For Front-End Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/useful-vs-code-extensions-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet useful Visual Studio Code extensions for web developers: little helpers to minimize slow-downs and frustrations, and boost developer’s workflow along the way. With auto log messages, auto code formatting, file utils, file labels, code snippets, highlight brackets, tags, indents and workspaces, onboarding and remote SSH.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build And Launch Powerful Responsive Websites With Editor X]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/build-launch-responsive-websites-editorx/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While web builders have been around for a long time, it wasn’t until recently that they became practical for professional use. Closing the gap between design and code has become the north star for many companies and we are seeing a wave of tools that deliver on this promise.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Miroslav Bekyarov)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessible SVGs: Perfect Patterns For Screen Reader Users]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/accessible-svg-patterns-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover which SVG patterns we should avoid and which patterns are the most inclusive when comparing different combinations of OSs, browsers, and screen readers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part2/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mistakes. These cruel villains do not even stop at the beautiful world of software development. But although we cannot avoid making mistakes, we can learn to undo them! This post will show the right tools for your daily work with Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Way To Reduce Font Loading Impact: CSS Font Descriptors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-font-loading-impact-css-descriptors/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web fonts are often terrible for web performance and none of the font loading strategies are particularly effective to address that. Upcoming font options may finally deliver on the promise of making it easier to align fallback fonts to the final fonts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container Queries: Use-Cases And Migration Strategies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/css-container-queries-use-cases-migration-strategies/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Container queries bring media queries closer to the target elements themselves and enables them to adapt to virtually any given container or layout. In this article, we’re going to cover CSS container query basics and how to use them today with progressive enhancement or polyfills.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building A Rich Text Editor (WYSIWYG)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/building-wysiwyg-editor-javascript-slatejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s build a rich text, WYSIWYG-editor that supports rich text, images, links and some nuanced features from word processing apps. We will use SlateJS to build the shell of the editor and then add a toolbar and custom configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shalabh Vyas)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boost Your Skills Online: Smashing Workshops On Front-End And Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/new-online-workshops-front-end-ux/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Front-end and design are remarkably complex these days. That’s why we invite kind, smart folks from the community to run online workshops for all of us to learn together. And we have new ones coming up, and we’d like to kindly welcome you to join in.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Iris Lješnjanin)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Implement Authentication In Next.js With Auth0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/implement-authentication-nextjs-auth0/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A step-by-step tutorial on adding authentication and authorization to your Next.js apps, with Auth0. We’ll be using a Next.js SDK to connect our application to the Auth0 API and will create the dynamic API route for React.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Facundo Giuliani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My psychologist had never seen a black man with self-harm scars | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/20/my-psychologist-had-never-seen-a-black-man-with-self-harm-scars-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T10:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, Guardian journalist Iman Amrani speaks to writer Derek Owusu about his journey to being diagnosed with borderline personality disorder (BPD). They discuss growing up in foster care, his positive experiences of the NHS and why he thinks it is so hard for black men to have open conversations about mental health.
This video references suicide and self harm. 

In the UK and Irish Republic contact Samaritans on 116 123 or email jo@samaritans.org.
In the US the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline is 1-800-273-8255.
In Australia the crisis support service Lifeline is 13 11 14.
Other international suicide helplines can be found at www.befrienders.org
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Alex Healey, James Turner, Grace Shutti, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns: Mega-Dropdown Hover Menus]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-mega-dropdown-hover-menus/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T11:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything to keep in mind when designing and building a mega-dropdown, common pitfalls, hover entry/exit delays, trajectory triangle technique and SVG path exit areas.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Create, Edit And Animate SVGs All In One Place With SVGator 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/create-edit-animate-svg-svgator3/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are taking a closer look at [SVGator 3.0](https://www.svgator.com/?utm_source=article&utm_medium=smashingmag&utm_campaign=svgator3_smashing), a new major release of the popular SVG application that lets you create, edit and animate SVG files and make the best out of what SVG has to offer — from start to finish.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mikołaj Dobrucki)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 37 With Adam Argyle: What Is VisBug?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-37/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re talking about VisBug. What is it, and how is it different from the array of options already found in Chrome DevTools? Drew McLellan talks to its creator Adam Argyle to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Improved Our Core Web Vitals (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/core-web-vitals-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s “Page Experience Update” will start rolling out in June. At first, sites that meet Core Web Vitals thresholds will have a minor ranking advantage in mobile search for all browsers. Search is important to any business, and this is the story of how Beau Hartshorne and his team at Instant Domain Search improved their Core Web Vitals scores.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Beau Hartshorne)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen war: mass displacement fears as fighting intensifies in Marib
Yemen condemns international donor funding shortfall as UK cuts aid
War and famine could wipe out the next generation of Yemenis
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free radicals to antioxidants: the science behind caring for oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/11/from-free-radicals-to-antioxidants-the-science-behind-caring-for-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T11:27:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problem skin often needs special attention. Here’s how to keep a blemish-prone complexion in check
Dr Emma Craythorne has spent her life studying skin; she is a consultant dermatologist, dermatological and laser surgeon and has a private practice on Harley Street. Problem skin, or skin types that can be challenging to manage, is something Craythorne knows a lot about. Here, she gives her unique insight into the way she helps people identify whether they have oily, blemish-prone skin and the skincare ingredients that’ll work best to target it …
Understand your skin type
“The first step in choosing the right skincare products is understanding what your skin type is,” says Craythorne. “To find out if you have oily skin, you want to assess what it feels like after you’ve washed it in the morning and patted it down. Wait 20 minutes; if after 20 minutes oily areas are appearing then you have oily skin.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Gunavardhana</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos from the Anywhere but Westminster series 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin and the city: why your serum needs to protect against urban living]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/10/skin-and-the-city-why-your-serum-needs-to-protect-against-urban-living"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T12:11:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollution, ultraviolet radiation and cigarette smoke can all cause havoc on our skin – but it doesn’t have to. Here’s how to guard your skin from everyday threats
Our skin is the body’s largest organ and works especially hard to cope with the demands of urban living, protecting your body against the impact of free radical-forming ultraviolet (UV) radiation, pollution and cigarette smoke. Dr Ifeoma Ejikeme, dermatologist and founder of Adonia Medical Clinic, says: “Damage to the skin by free radical or reactive oxygen species can include hyperpigmentation, prominent appearance of pores, dull-looking skin and eventually fine lines and premature ageing.”
These skin stressors, combined with the added dermatological strain after months of life in lockdown – being indoors with the central heating on, anxiety and lack of sleep – can also leave the skin looking dull and prone to blemishes. A good night’s rest, meditation, a balanced diet and regular exercise can all help with internalised stress and anxiety, but what about the effects of pollution on the skin?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ateh Jewel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>