<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-17T00:36:45.171Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-17T00:36:45.171Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.7.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social care cuts mean thousands with dementia taken to A&E, charity says]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/social-care-cuts-mean-thousands-with-dementia-taken-to-ae-charity-says</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/social-care-cuts-mean-thousands-with-dementia-taken-to-ae-charity-says"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T23:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been a 27% increase over four years in avoidable illnesses and injuries caused by failures in care
Tens of thousands of people with dementia are taken to hospital each year for emergency admission because inadequate social care has left them unprotected from infections, falls and dehydration, an investigation has found.
There has been a 27% increase over a four-year period in avoidable illnesses and injuries caused by failures in care for those living with dementia, according to the Alzheimer’s So…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Hill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK ‘faces labour shortage’ as Covid and Brexit fuel exodus of overseas workers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/uk-faces-labour-shortage-as-covid-and-brexit-fuel-exodus-of-overseas-workers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/17/uk-faces-labour-shortage-as-covid-and-brexit-fuel-exodus-of-overseas-workers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T23:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts say recovery at risk amid sharp fall in EU workers and dwindling interest in UK jobs from abroad
Britain’s employers are struggling to hire staff as lockdown lifts amid an exodus of overseas workers caused by the Covid pandemic and Brexit, industry figures reveal.
According to the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development (CIPD) and the recruitment firm Adecco, employers plan to hire at the fastest rate in eight years, led by the reopening of the hospitality and retail sectors as pandemic res…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Partington Economics correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Average asking price for UK homes hits record £333,564]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/17/average-asking-price-for-uk-homes-hits-record-333564</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/may/17/average-asking-price-for-uk-homes-hits-record-333564"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T23:01:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prices have increased most in Wales and the north-west of England and least in London, says Rightmove
The average asking price of homes coming on to the UK property market hit a high of a third of a million pounds in May, according to figures from the listings website Rightmove.
The average asking price has increased by 1.8%, or £5,767, over the past month to £333,564, the website said, with an “unexpected mini-boom” that started last year continuing well into 2021.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hilary Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LGBT+ youths twice as likely to contemplate suicide, survey finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/lgbt-youths-twice-as-likely-to-contemplate-suicide-survey-finds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/17/lgbt-youths-twice-as-likely-to-contemplate-suicide-survey-finds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: cut off from support networks and often facing tension at home, young LGBT+ people suffered more than most during lockdowns
Young LGBT+ people are three times more likely to self-harm and twice as likely to contemplate suicide as their non-LGBT+ peers, according to a survey.
The research was carried out by Just Like Us, an LGBT+ young people’s charity, which surveyed 2,934 pupils aged 11-18, including 1,140 pupils who identify as LGBT+.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rhi Storer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mother Earth denied Classic double as Couersamba rides to shock Paris win]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/mother-earth-denied-classic-double-as-couersamba-rides-to-shock-paris-win</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/17/mother-earth-denied-classic-double-as-couersamba-rides-to-shock-paris-win"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T23:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Outsider wins Poule d’Essai des Pouliches at ParisLongchamp
Mother Earth was 6-4 favourite after 1,000 Guineas success

Coeursamba denied Mother Earth a Classic double with a shock victory in the Poule d’Essai des Pouliches at ParisLongchamp.
Having swooped to victory in the 1,000 Guineas at Newmarket a fortnight ago, the Aidan O’Brien-trained Mother Earth was the 6-4 favourite to follow up in the French equivalent, with Christophe Soumillon coming in for the ride.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delia Derbyshire: The Myths and the Legendary Tapes review – playful paean to a musical pioneer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/16/delia-derbyshire-the-myths-and-the-legendary-tapes-review-playful-paean-to-a-musical-pioneer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/16/delia-derbyshire-the-myths-and-the-legendary-tapes-review-playful-paean-to-a-musical-pioneer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T21:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental and inventive, Caroline Catz’s film paints a fond, intimate and arty portrait of the influential electronic musician
I hope films like Delia Derbyshire: The Myths and the Legendary Tapes (BBC Four) will still have a home at the BBC after BBC Four becomes an archive-only channel, as is planned. I cannot imagine anything so wilfully arty sitting on a more mainstream channel. This is a wonderfully inventive piece of storytelling that celebrates the strange brilliance of a mysterious pioneer of ele…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Nicholson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour proposes new offences for violence against women and girls]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/16/labour-proposes-new-offences-for-violence-against-women-and-girls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2021/may/16/labour-proposes-new-offences-for-violence-against-women-and-girls"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T21:30:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Green paper calls for misogyny to be made hate crime and bans on street harassment and sex-for-rent
Labour would create a slew of new offences concerning violence against women and girls, including prohibiting street harassment, making misogyny a hate crime and banning sex-for-rent.
The proposals also include introducing criminal sanctions for tech executives who do not act fast enough to remove misogynistic abuse on their platforms, building on previous proposals from the party to tackle online hate speech…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barcelona stun Chelsea with early blitz to win Women’s Champions League]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/chelsea-barcelona-womens-champions-league-final-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/chelsea-barcelona-womens-champions-league-final-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:52:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barcelona shrugged off their Champions League final demons to obliterate Chelsea and deliver a crushing blow to the prestige of the Women’s Super League.
A first-minute own goal and another three inside 36 minutes, from the midfielders Alexia Putellas, Aitana Bonmatí and the Norwegian forward Caroline Graham Hansen, quietened the usually vocal Emma Hayes, who stood alone in her technical area, unable to mastermind a way past an exhilarating team that has played 26 and won 26 on the way to a La Liga title wi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suzanne Wrack at the Ullevi Stadium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 May reopening: how Covid measures across Britain are changing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/britain-england-scotland-wales-changing-coronavirus-restrictions-17-may</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/britain-england-scotland-wales-changing-coronavirus-restrictions-17-may"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:47:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coronavirus restrictions are set to be eased in England, Wales and most of Scotland from Monday

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Coronavirus restrictions will be eased further on Monday in England, Wales and most of Scotland. Northern Ireland will review its measures on Thursday, with a view to lifting more restrictions on 24 May.
The next phase of relaxation comes despite the spread of the coronavirus variant first detected in India, though Boris Johnson warned on Friday that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clea Skopeliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conservative MP condemned for ‘racist’ tweet about Israel protests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/conservative-mp-criticised-racist-anti-palestinian-tweet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/conservative-mp-criticised-racist-anti-palestinian-tweet"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:34:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Fabricant, the MP for Lichfield, called pro-Palestine demonstrators who clashed with police ‘primitives’
Tory MP Michael Fabricant has been criticised for describing pro-Palestinian demonstrators clashing with police as “primitives”.
Anti-racism campaign Hope Not Hate called for the Conservative party to suspend the backbencher on Sunday, accusing him of “hateful racism that stirs up division”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sheffield United’s Daniel Jebbison pounces early to deepen Everton woes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/everton-sheffield-united-premier-league-match-report</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/everton-sheffield-united-premier-league-match-report"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:10:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carlo Ancelotti’s luck is about to run out. His Everton team have delivered the worst Premier League campaign at Goodison Park since 1993-94, when a final-day miracle was needed against Wimbledon to keep Mike Walker’s side in the top flight, and to a backdrop of silence instead of the scorn that would usually descend from full and furious terraces. There will be no opportunity for escape when 6,500 Evertonians return against Wolves on Wednesday.
Bottom club Sheffield United, relegated with only one previous…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Hunter at Goodison Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘God put his hand on my head’: Alisson devotes Liverpool winner to late father]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/emotional-alisson-thanks-football-family-for-support-after-scoring-winner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2021/may/16/emotional-alisson-thanks-football-family-for-support-after-scoring-winner"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:05:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Goalkeeper scored 95th-minute winner at West Brom
‘Football is my life ... I hope he was there celebrating’

Liverpool kept alive their dreams of qualifying for the Champions League in remarkable circumstances as goalkeeper Alisson scored a 95th-minute winner at West Bromwich Albion.
The emotional Brazilian, who lost his father in a drowning accident in February, dedicated the first goal of his senior career – a fine, glancing header – to his family as he said: “God put his hand on my head today”.
 Continue…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Lansley at the Hawthorns</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who owns Australia?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/17/who-owns-australia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/ng-interactive/2021/may/17/who-owns-australia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T20:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Complex web of data reveals large swathes of country controlled by small number of billionaires and large companies
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Calla Wahlquist , Josh Nicholas, Andy Ball and Nick Evershed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ben Jennings on UK’s delay in adding India to red list – cartoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/16/ben-jennings-uk-delay-india-red-list-coronavirus-cartoon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/picture/2021/may/16/ben-jennings-uk-delay-india-red-list-coronavirus-cartoon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T19:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Jennings</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel and Palestine heading for ‘uncontainable’ crisis, UN chief warns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/un-chief-warns-israel-palestine-heading-uncontainable-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/un-chief-warns-israel-palestine-heading-uncontainable-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:54:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Forty-two Palestinians killed by airstrikes in Gaza as Hamas launches more rocket attacks on Israel
The eruption of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict is heading for an “uncontainable security and humanitarian crisis”, the UN secretary general has warned after a day of significant escalation with 42 Palestinians killed by airstrikes in Gaza.
The death toll made it the deadliest single attack since fighting broke out between Israel and the Palestinian militant group Hamas a week ago. Fifty Palestinians were in…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes in Jerusalem, Bethan McKernan and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four arrests over video ‘showing antisemitic abuse shouted from cars in London’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/police-investigate-video-antisemitic-abuse-shouted-cars-london</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/police-investigate-video-antisemitic-abuse-shouted-cars-london"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:53:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson and Keir Starmer condemn ‘utterly disgusting’ footage of convoy in St John’s Wood 
Four men have been arrested by officers investigating a video that appeared to show antisemitic abuse being shouted from a car in north London.
Politicians had earlier condemned the footage, which was posted on Twitter and showed the cars travelling through the St John’s Wood area on Sunday afternoon. The cars were covered in Palestinian flags with a speaker blasting out antisemitic slurs and threats against Jew…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nazia Parveen North of England correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignore lockdown easing to curb Indian Covid variant, health experts urge]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/ignore-lockdown-easing-to-curb-indian-covid-variant-health-experts-urge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/ignore-lockdown-easing-to-curb-indian-covid-variant-health-experts-urge"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:49:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leading specialists call on the public to avoid socialising indoors to prevent a third wave of the disease

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

People should ignore Monday’s easing of lockdown and avoid socialising indoors in pubs and restaurants to prevent the new Covid-19 variant first detected in India sparking a third wave of the disease, health experts say.
A former government chief scientific adviser, a leading public health specialist and the union representing Britain’s do…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell and Jessica Elgot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew McConaughey ‘making calls’ about run for Texas governor – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/16/matthew-mcconaughey-considering-run-texas-governor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/16/matthew-mcconaughey-considering-run-texas-governor"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:47:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dallas Buyer’s Club star has been ‘quietly making calls to influential people in Texas political circles’, according to Politico
The actor Matthew McConaughey appears to be seriously considering entering politics, according to a report on Sunday which said the Dallas Buyer’s Club star has been “quietly making calls to influential people in Texas political circles” as he mulls a run for governor.
 Related: Caitlyn Jenner’s bid to be California’s next Governator is falling flat 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tyson Fury announces he will fight Anthony Joshua in Saudi Arabia]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/tyson-fury-announces-he-will-fight-anthony-joshua-in-saudi-arabia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/tyson-fury-announces-he-will-fight-anthony-joshua-in-saudi-arabia"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:47:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bout will take place on 14 August, Fury says on Twitter
First time all four heavyweight world titles will be contested

Tyson Fury has announced his all-British heavyweight showdown with Anthony Joshua will take place in Saudi Arabia on 14 August.
In a video posted to Twitter, the 32-year-old said: “I have got some massive news. I have just got off the phone with Prince Khalid of Saudi Arabia and he told me this fight is 100 per cent on, August 14.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[England’s Jofra Archer out of New Zealand Tests and may need surgery]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/england-jofra-archer-new-zealand-tests-surgery</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/england-jofra-archer-new-zealand-tests-surgery"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:43:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fast bowler’s persistent elbow problem flares up again
Mark Wood and Olly Stone set to offer pace options

Jofra Archer has been ruled out of England’s two-match Test series against New Zealand next month and is waiting to discover whether his persistent elbow problem requires an operation.
The fast bowler had made his first appearance of the season for Sussex in the latest round of County Championship fixtures but, having sent down 18 overs and claimed three wickets, did not bowl on the final two days of h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lambeth Labour council leader faces sexual harassment probe]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/lambeth-labour-council-leader-faces-sexual-harassment-probe</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/lambeth-labour-council-leader-faces-sexual-harassment-probe"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T18:06:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[London councillor, who resigned from post last week, is accused of sexual harassment and unwanted touching
The leader of one of Labour’s flagship local councils, who resigned from his role last week, is being investigated by the party over an allegation of sexual harassment and unwanted touching, the Guardian understands.
Lambeth council has rejected any link between the allegation and the announcement last week that Jack Hopkins was stepping aside after two years in the role. It is understood that Hopkins …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on David Cameron’s lobbying: a cynical defence won’t wash | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/the-guardian-view-on-david-camerons-lobbying-a-cynical-defence-wont-wash</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/the-guardian-view-on-david-camerons-lobbying-a-cynical-defence-wont-wash"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lobbying law needs updating because the government is run by people who know the price of everything and value of nothing

Last week, David Cameron, Britain’s former Conservative prime minister, claimed rather implausibly that his frantic lobbying of ministers and officials last year on behalf of failed Australian financier Lex Greensill was motivated by public service rather than private gain. Mr Cameron could say this with a straight face because he would not reveal, in four hours of testimony to MPs, his…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Home Office is  still not fit for purpose | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/why-the-home-office-is-still-not-fit-for-purpose</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/16/why-the-home-office-is-still-not-fit-for-purpose"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T17:26:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Readers respond to coverage of the government department’s failings and to a letter from the civil servant who leads it
I read Daniel Trilling’s article on the Home Office (Cruel, paranoid, failing: inside the Home Office, 13 May), and its story of delay, confrontation and the “hostile environment” echoed my experience of dealing with immigration cases as an MP. Time after time, people came to my surgeries pleading for help with the labyrinthine processes imposed on them by the Home Office, with many of the…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian view on declining birthrates: there may be trouble ahead | Editorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/the-guardian-view-on-declining-birthrates-there-may-be-trouble-ahead</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/the-guardian-view-on-declining-birthrates-there-may-be-trouble-ahead"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T17:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Europe’s ageing societies must make it easier for young people to start a family 
Europe’s baby deficit is becoming impossible to ignore. In Rome on Friday, Italy’s prime minister, Mario Draghi, and Pope Francis were the star attendees at a special conference to discuss the country’s declining birthrate. According to latest figures, 2020 saw the lowest number of births recorded since Italian unification in 1861. Spain is ageing at a similar pace, as is much of eastern Europe. In Britain, it is the same stor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Editorial</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bawdy monks and the Cerne Abbas giant | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/16/bawdy-monks-and-the-cerne-abbas-giant</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/may/16/bawdy-monks-and-the-cerne-abbas-giant"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T17:17:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alice Raw of the University of Oxford and Richard North of University College London respond to research suggesting that the chalk hill figure in Dorset dates from Anglo-Saxon times
Why the surprise at a late 10th-century date for the Cerne Abbas giant (Cerne Giant in Dorset dates from Anglo-Saxon times, analysis suggests, 12 May)? If we find it hard to believe that the inmates of the monastery at Cerne Abbas could have sponsored the making of the giant, that says more about us than it does about them. Earl…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As foreign travel rules ease, what is required to enter the UK?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/as-foreign-travel-rules-ease-what-is-required-to-enter-the-uk-covid</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/as-foreign-travel-rules-ease-what-is-required-to-enter-the-uk-covid"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T17:01:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a range of proofs needed, the market for fake Covid test and vaccination certificates is booming 

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

When the UK reopens for foreign travel on Monday, a number of requirements for entry to the UK will be in force, involving a number of different types of tests and certificates.
 Related: Fake Covid vaccine and test certificate market is growing, researchers say 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Grierson Home affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fauci: ‘Undeniable effects of racism’ have worsened Covid for US minorities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/fauci-racism-covid-us-black-hispanic-native-americans-emory-university-graduation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/fauci-racism-covid-us-black-hispanic-native-americans-emory-university-graduation"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:48:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[White House medical adviser speaks to Emory graduates
Biden aides defend controversial mask guidance change

Joe Biden’s chief medical adviser, Dr Anthony Fauci, said on Sunday “the undeniable effects of racism” have worsened the coronavirus pandemic for Black, Hispanic and Native Americans.
 Related: Republican Covid lies follow foreign strongmen’s lead – and are deadly for it | Robert Reich 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in Atlanta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What threat does Indian Covid variant pose and do vaccines work against it?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/what-threat-does-indian-covid-variant-pose-and-do-vaccines-work-against-it</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/what-threat-does-indian-covid-variant-pose-and-do-vaccines-work-against-it"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:45:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The number of identified cases of the B.1.617.2 variant in the UK has more than doubled in a week

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The number of identified cases of the Indian variant in the UK has more than doubled in a week, from 520 to 1,313, according to the most recent figures. The areas with the highest numbers so far include Bolton, Blackburn with Darwen, Erewash in Derbyshire and Bedford, all in England, and Moray in Scotland.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denis Campbell Health policy editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden feels political ground shift as Israel-Gaza conflict rages on]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/joe-biden-feels-political-ground-shift-as-israel-gaza-conflict-rages-on</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/joe-biden-feels-political-ground-shift-as-israel-gaza-conflict-rages-on"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:36:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: US president may find himself increasingly isolated in his resolute defence of Israel
In his staunch defence of Israel, Joe Biden is sticking to a course set decades ago as a young senator, and so far he has not given ground on the issue to the progressive wing of his party or many Jewish Democrats urging a tougher line towards Benjamin Netanyahu. 
Biden has even been prepared to face isolation at the UN security council, at the potential cost of his own credibility on multilateralism and human ri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critics of UK low-traffic schemes told that 25,000 filters already existed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/critics-of-uk-low-traffic-schemes-told-that-25000-filters-already-existed</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/critics-of-uk-low-traffic-schemes-told-that-25000-filters-already-existed"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:19:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers find road blocks that we’d already accepted before introduction of divisive low-traffic neighbourhoods
At least 25,000 traffic filters similar to those found in low-traffic neighbourhoods already exist across the UK, research has shown, with campaigners saying it proves both the efficacy of such schemes and the futility of demands to scrap them.
Dozens have been built in cities over the last year by councils seeking to boost walking and cycling levels during the coronavirus pandemic, prompting a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Egan Bernal takes overall Giro d’Italia lead after winning ninth stage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/egan-bernal-takes-giro-ditalia-lead-after-winning-ninth-stage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/egan-bernal-takes-giro-ditalia-lead-after-winning-ninth-stage"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:14:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Colombian rider pips Giulio Ciccone to win 158km stage
‘My teammates had a lot of confidence in me, this is for them’

Egan Bernal stormed to victory on the ninth stage of the Giro d’Italia to take the leader’s pink jersey.
The Colombian rider ended the stage, Castel di Sangro to Campo Felice, seven seconds clear of Giulio Ciccone and Aleksandr Vlasov following a fine finish to the 158km route.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universities are failing to tackle rape culture on campus, students say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/universities-rape-culture-on-campus-students-protest</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/universities-rape-culture-on-campus-students-protest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T16:12:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sit-in protest over sexual misconduct at Warwick University enters its ninth week

Students at a sit-in protest over sexual misconduct at Warwick University that is entering its ninth week have said universities are still failing to tackle rape culture on campus.
Student group Protect Warwick Women has been camping in tents outside the student union building since March to protest over what they see as the university’s failure to tackle an “ingrained” problem of rape culture and sexual harassment on campus.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-year-old dies in suspected Lancashire gas explosion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/lancashire-police-declare-major-incident-after-suspected-gas-explosion</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/lancashire-police-declare-major-incident-after-suspected-gas-explosion"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:52:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parents pay tribute to George Arthur Hinds as two adults remain critically injured in hospital

A two-year-old boy has died and four other people have been injured in a suspected gas explosion in Heysham, Lancashire that destroyed two homes.
A major incident was declared after the explosion on Mallowdale Avenue at about 2.30am on Sunday that also left a third house badly damaged.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK railways brace for shake-up and cuts as long-overdue review arrives]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/16/railway-braces-for-shake-up-and-cuts-as-overdue-review-arrives</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/may/16/railway-braces-for-shake-up-and-cuts-as-overdue-review-arrives"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:40:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biggest change since 90s privatisation looks to halt franchise failures, reform fares and, for the Treasury, slash costs
Sweeping reforms to bring the railway’s track and trains together under a new Great British Railways will be set out this week – but reforms of fares will be limited, with the industry braced to have its budget slashed.
The Treasury is understood to be demanding cost cuts of between 10% and 20% after expanding its subsidy to the rail industry by £10bn during the Covid-19 pandemic as fare …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’m filled with hope’: cash-strapped Algarve awaits return of UK tourists]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/cash-strapped-algarve-awaits-return-uk-tourists-portugal-faro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/cash-strapped-algarve-awaits-return-uk-tourists-portugal-faro"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:38:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People in Faro are relieved and excited but do not expect a speedy recovery from impact of Covid

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Tatiana stands by the counter of the souvenir shop where she works in downtown Faro, with little in the way of company besides the postcard racks, the shelves of trinkets and towels, and an all too familiar silence.
“Only three customers have come into the shop so far today,” says Tatiana, who lost her job at Faro’s airport last October after her co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mia Alberti in Faro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Black Widow to unseen Beatles footage: what films to see as cinemas reopen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/16/what-films-to-see-as-cinemas-reopen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/may/16/what-films-to-see-as-cinemas-reopen"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grab your popcorn as we pick the best post-lockdown movie offerings – featuring a medieval thriller, a Ben Wheatley chiller and Emma Stone’s youthful Cruella

More events to enjoy: Pop | Art | Classical | Stage

 Frances McDormand delivers the performance of her career in this triple Oscar-winner from Chloé Zhao: best film, director and actress. It is a docu-fiction about the American phenomenon of “nomads”: sixtysomething retirees pauperised by the 2008 crash and roaming the country in camper vans looking …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only an international effort can put an end to China’s crimes in Xinjiang | Jewher Ilham and Sophie Richardson]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/international-effort-china-crimes-xinjiang-uyghur-</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/international-effort-china-crimes-xinjiang-uyghur-"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:29:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the daughter of a Uyghur economist imprisoned for life, I call on governments and the UN to act together

Jewher Ilham, the daughter of Ilham Tohti, is an author at the Project to Combat Forced Labor at the Worker Rights Consortium. Sophie Richardson is China director at Human Rights Watch

China’s president, Xi Jinping, declared back in 2014 in a series of speeches delivered in private to officials that he intended to crack down harshly in Xinjiang, the north-western region of China where about 13 milli…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jewher Ilham and Sophie Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Cheney defiant over Trump as Republican civil war heats up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/liz-cheney-regrets-vote-donald-trump-republican-party-civil-war-kinzinger-stefanik</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/may/16/liz-cheney-regrets-vote-donald-trump-republican-party-civil-war-kinzinger-stefanik"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:22:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crenshaw, Kinzinger and others exchange shots on talk shows
Will Republicans back a Capitol attack commission?

Liz Cheney has become the figurehead of the conservative Never Trumpers – but the Wyoming congresswoman was for the former president in the last election.
 Related: Can ‘Never Trump’ Republicans gain party control – or is it a lost cause? 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Pengelly in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tony Armatrading obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/16/tony-armatrading-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/may/16/tony-armatrading-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T15:10:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stage and screen actor who enjoyed success with the RSC and in many TV and film roles, including Empire Road and Notting Hill
Tony Armatrading, who has died aged 59 of cancer, was a big, warm-hearted actor in the second wave of black British performers who began to make an impact in theatre and television in the mid-1970s. Before relocating to Los Angeles in 1999, he had three busy seasons with the Royal Shakespeare Company and featured impressively in contemporary black theatre classics at the Theatre Roya…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Coveney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[London tower block residents warned of smoke danger two years before fire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/16/london-tower-block-residents-warned-of-smoke-danger-two-years-before-fire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/may/16/london-tower-block-residents-warned-of-smoke-danger-two-years-before-fire"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T14:48:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People in building with Grenfell-style cladding and combustible balconies also said fire wardens were ineffective
Residents of an east London tower block that caught fire earlier this month had warned about the danger of smoke spread and protested that fire wardens were ineffective during a years-long wrangle to make their homes safe, the Guardian has learned.
Leaseholders at New Providence Wharf, which has Grenfell-style cladding and combustible wooden balconies, told the developer Ballymore more than two …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Booth Social affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are Palestinians protesting? Because we want to live | Mariam Barghouti]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/palestinians-protesting-live-regime-oppression</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/palestinians-protesting-live-regime-oppression"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T14:26:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just as the Black Lives Matter protests were not only about one killing, we are facing a whole regime of oppression
I started going to demonstrations when I was 17. At first, I went to protests against Israel’s military occupation. Then we also began to protest against the authoritarianism of the Palestinian Authority and Hamas, and the sickening rivalry between Palestinian political factions. For Palestinians, protest has become a way of life – a way to be steadfast, to persevere.
Over the past decade, muc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mariam Barghouti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opportunities beckon as Eddie Jones ponders options for summer Tests]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/opportunities-beckon-as-eddie-jones-ponders-options-for-summer-tests</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/opportunities-beckon-as-eddie-jones-ponders-options-for-summer-tests"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T14:13:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marcus Smith and Max Malins could be in tandem for England’s June games against United States and Canada at Twickenham
Premiership crowds are finally returning from Monday evening and the chance to nudge the national selectors offers a further powerful incentive as the business end of the domestic season approaches. With 11 England players making the British and Irish Lions tour party there is obvious scope for summer experimentation, just as there was in Argentina in 2017 when, among others, Tom Curry made…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Kitson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swimming among coral and Chilean elections – the weekend in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/16/swimming-with-coral-chilean-elections-weekend-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/gallery/2021/may/16/swimming-with-coral-chilean-elections-weekend-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T13:56:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian’s picture editors select photo highlights from around the world
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jo Blason</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trouble brews between Trappist monks and Belgian mineral empire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/trouble-brews-between-trappist-monks-and-belgian-mineral-empire</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/trouble-brews-between-trappist-monks-and-belgian-mineral-empire"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T13:36:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David and Goliath legal battle ensues as silent religious order seeks to protect the taste of its beer

For a decade the monks of Notre-Dame de Saint-Remy, in Rochefort, south Belgium – one of only 14 abbeys in the world producing Trappist beer – have been fighting with a quarry owner over the purity of the local spring water.
The monks have doggedly claimed that plans by Lhoist, an international company run by one of Belgium’s richest families, to deepen its chalk quarry and redirect the Tridaine spring ri…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Boffey in Rochefort, Belgium</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sex Education writer aims to boost diversity in TV with fellowship scheme]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/16/sex-education-writer-aims-to-boost-diversity-in-tv-with-fellowship-scheme</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/16/sex-education-writer-aims-to-boost-diversity-in-tv-with-fellowship-scheme"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T13:16:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bisha K Ali teams up with Netflix and Sky to support six screenwriters from minority backgrounds
The Sex Education and Ms Marvel writer Bisha K Ali is launching a screenwriting fellowship with Netflix and Sky that will give six people from under-represented communities a year’s salary in an effort to make the TV industry more inclusive.
Ali hopes that taking away the “sense of clawing financial instability” that many young writers face will reduce the barriers to entry for people from black, Asian and other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tara Conlan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could England’s future be a left-leaning south facing off against a conservative north? | John Harris]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/england-future-left-leaning-south-conservative-north</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/england-future-left-leaning-south-conservative-north"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T13:11:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic has accelerated the movement of people, creating clusters of like-minded, homogenous communities
London is changing, and so is the south of England. Whether recent predictions of a lasting drop in the capital’s population and emptied-out office districts will come true is still unclear. But something has definitely been happening, for the best part of a year: thanks to Covid and its disruptions, a sizeable number of people are deciding to leave the city and head elsewhere, chasing space, greene…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readers reply: do people’s names affect their personality?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/16/readers-reply-do-peoples-names-affect-their-personality</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/16/readers-reply-do-peoples-names-affect-their-personality"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T13:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
Do people’s names affect their personality? Max Crane, Sydney
Send new questions to nq@theguardian.com.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-hand stories shed new light on Nazi death marches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/first-hand-stories-nazi-death-marches-wiener-holocaust-library</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/first-hand-stories-nazi-death-marches-wiener-holocaust-library"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:50:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wiener Holocaust Library in London has gathered testimonies and photographs of forced evacuations at end of second world war
First-hand accounts from survivors of Nazi death marches, which formed a last ruthless chapter of the genocide, are to go on display with testimonies translated into English for the first time.
During the death marches, tens of thousands of people died on roadsides of exhaustion, shot for failing to keep up, or murdered in seemingly random massacres as the Nazis moved people from conc…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caroline Davies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UN champions Mauritian control of Chagos Islands by rejecting UK stamps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/un-favours-mauritian-control-over-chagos-islands-by-rejecting-uk-stamps</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/un-favours-mauritian-control-over-chagos-islands-by-rejecting-uk-stamps"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:46:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Refusal to recognise British Indian Ocean Territory stamps is latest move to assert Mauritian sovereignty
Stamps issued by the British Indian Ocean Territory could soon be rendered invalid after the United Nations’ Universal Postal Union (UPU) council recommended they no longer be recognised, in the latest step rejecting the UK’s claim to the Chagos Islands.
The move by the UPU, the second oldest international organisation, is in recognition of Mauritian sovereignty over the strategically important islands …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haroon Siddique Legal affairs correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBC delays Panorama programme on Bashir interview with Diana]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/16/bbc-delays-panorama-programme-on-bashir-interview-with-diana</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/16/bbc-delays-panorama-programme-on-bashir-interview-with-diana"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:35:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monday’s scheduled broadcast of investigation postponed because of ‘significant duty of care issue’

The BBC has delayed the broadcast of a Panorama investigation into Martin Bashir’s 1995 interview with Diana, Princess of Wales.
The programme was expected to air on BBC One on Monday but has been postponed due to a “significant duty of care issue”, according to the broadcaster. A new broadcast date has not yet been confirmed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What do animals feel? Humans must follow the evidence to find out | Jonathan Birch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/animals-feel-humans-evidence-sentient</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/animals-feel-humans-evidence-sentient"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:13:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government proposals to recognise vertebrates as sentient beings are welcome, but this should be just the start
Look a dog in the eye and a conscious being looks back. A being that feels hunger, thirst, warmth, cold, fear, comfort, pleasure, pain, joy. No one can seriously doubt this. The same is true of any mammal. You cannot watch rats playing hide and seek and doubt that they have feelings – that they are sentient creatures. But as animals become more distant from us in evolutionary terms, some doubt beg…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Birch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Kahneman: ‘Clearly AI is going to win. How people are going to adjust is a fascinating problem’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/16/daniel-kahneman-clearly-ai-is-going-to-win-how-people-are-going-to-adjust-is-a-fascinating-problem-thinking-fast-and-slow</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/may/16/daniel-kahneman-clearly-ai-is-going-to-win-how-people-are-going-to-adjust-is-a-fascinating-problem-thinking-fast-and-slow"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nobel-winning psychologist on applying his ideas to organisations, why we’re not equipped to grasp the spread of a virus, and the massive disruption that’s just round the corner
Daniel Kahneman, 87, was awarded the Nobel prize in economics in 2002 for his work on the psychology of judgment and decision-making. His first book, Thinking, Fast and Slow, a worldwide bestseller, set out his revolutionary ideas about human error and bias and how those traits might be recognised and mitigated. A new book, Nois…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making of Rodin review – the sculptor in a ghostly new light]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-making-of-rodin-tate-modern-review-plaster</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-making-of-rodin-tate-modern-review-plaster"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T12:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tate Modern, London
A succession of plaster arms, legs and heads reveal Rodin’s working practices in a fascinating show that nevertheless leaves you longing for the finished work
The Making of Rodin is a show almost entirely composed of plaster casts: fragile and small, delicate or solid, heavyweight, lifesize or gargantuan. It is thronged with figure groups, solo statues, trays of hands and feet in glass cases. Smooth, chipped, marked up in pencil for rearrangement or enlargement, provisional studies or fi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hancock: most Bolton Covid patients eligible for jab but haven’t had it]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/hancock-defends-india-travel-ban-delay-as-covid-variant-cases-mount</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/hancock-defends-india-travel-ban-delay-as-covid-variant-cases-mount"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T11:40:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Health secretary’s comments come amid mounting concerns over spread of Indian B.1.617.2 variant

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

The majority of people in hospital with Covid in Bolton were eligible for the vaccine but have not had it, Matt Hancock has said, saying that health authorities would go “door-to-door” offering jabs.
His comments came as concern mounted over increased cases of the B.1.617.2 variant first detected in India, particularly in the north-west and parts of …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half of emissions cuts will come from future tech, says John Kerry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/half-of-emissions-cuts-will-come-from-future-tech-says-john-kerry</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/half-of-emissions-cuts-will-come-from-future-tech-says-john-kerry"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T11:01:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[US climate envoy says people will not have to give up quality of life to achieve some of net zero goals
The US climate envoy, John Kerry, has said 50% of the carbon reductions needed to get to net zero will come from technologies that have not yet been invented, and said people “don’t have to give up a quality of life” in order to cut emissions.
He said Americans would “not necessarily” have to eat less meat, because of research being done into the way cattle are herded and fed in order to reduce methane em…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Murray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferdinand ‘Budgie’ Montoya’s Filipino family recipes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/ferdinand-montoya-filipino-family-recipes-chicken-inasal-seafood-sinigang-cassava-cheesecake</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/ferdinand-montoya-filipino-family-recipes-chicken-inasal-seafood-sinigang-cassava-cheesecake"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T11:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chicken in coconut vinegar, vegetables with fermented shrimp, and cassava cheesecake – the Sarap chef’s homage to his mother’s cooking 
I was born in Mindanao, in the south of the Philippines, but I grew up in Sydney. We used to return quite often when I was younger, but there was a lot of instability during the late 1990s and early 00s, so we stopped and I never really went back. I tried to be as Aussie as possible, assimilate as much as I could. “Budgie” is an old nickname I’ve had since high school when …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Interview by Molly Tait-Hyland, recipes by Ferdinand Montoy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lockdowns and panic-buying in Taiwan as Covid cases rise]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/lockdowns-and-panic-buying-in-taiwan-as-covid-cases-rise</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/lockdowns-and-panic-buying-in-taiwan-as-covid-cases-rise"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:38:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Country widely considered to have had one of best pandemic responses now racing to contain outbreak

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

Taiwan reported 206 new local cases of Covid-19 on Sunday, breaking the previous day’s record high of 180 as authorities brought in the strictest measures yet in a bid to contain the virus. 
The outbreak, which began about three weeks ago among employees of the national airline and a connected quarantine hotel, has now produced about 85% of Taiwa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignore the hype of Republicans threatening to ‘break away’ over Trump | Cas Mudde]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/commentisfree/2021/may/16/ignore-the-hype-of-republicans-threatening-to-break-away-over-trump</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/commentisfree/2021/may/16/ignore-the-hype-of-republicans-threatening-to-break-away-over-trump"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:20:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Trump Republicans get lots of media attention. That doesn’t mean they are relevant within the Republican party
“Over 100 Republicans, including former officials, threaten to split” from the Republican party, the New York Times declared on Tuesday. The next day the Washington Post upped the ante, headlining that the 100 Republicans were vowing “civil war”; the columnist Jennifer Rubin proclaimed the beginning of “the stampede away from the GOP”.
Sounds exciting, but what has really happened?
 Continue r…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cas Mudde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twenty arrested after Rangers fans march in central Glasgow]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/20-arrested-after-rangers-fans-march-in-central-glasgow</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/may/16/20-arrested-after-rangers-fans-march-in-central-glasgow"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:02:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three police reported injured after crowd gathered to celebrate title win despite rising Covid infection rates
Rangers supporters who marched on Glasgow’s George Square to celebrate their club’s Scottish Premiership win, as the city faces a surge in Covid infections and an extension of lockdown, have been condemned as selfish, irresponsible and endangering lives after the rally descended into violence.
First minister Nicola Sturgeon said she was “utterly disgusted by the Rangers fans who rampaged through th…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Libby Brooks Scotland correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The new food stars of TikTok]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/the-new-food-stars-of-tiktok</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/the-new-food-stars-of-tiktok"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The app’s snappy videos are the new gateway to food fame. Its breakout stars explain the secrets of their success
When Poppy O’Toole was made redundant from her job as junior sous chef at the AllBright private members club in Mayfair during the first wave of the pandemic, she expected to return to work soon enough. “I thought, I’ve got three weeks to cook some nice food at home,” 27-year-old O’Toole remembers, “and be back in work in a few weeks.”
With lockdown opening up in front of her, O’Toole decided to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free solo … with a permit: will Yosemite’s new rules put a damper on climbing culture?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/yosemite-national-park-rock-climbing-permit</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2021/may/16/yosemite-national-park-rock-climbing-permit"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The national park is instituting a permitting system for overnight rock climbers. Many see it as inevitable as the sport gets more popular
For years, rock climbers Graham Ottley and Keith Bouma-Gregson dreamed of scaling the 2,800ft (853 meters) pillar of granite known as the Lost Arrow Spire in Yosemite national park.
In early May the pair finally got their chance, making a climb that required spending two windy nights camped on tiny ledges with harnesses holding them to the rocks. But Ottley and Bouma-Gre…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Iranian culture has huge depths and continues to be relevant today’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/epic-iran-5000-years-of-culture-v-and-a-exhibition-ina-sarikhani-sandmann</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/epic-iran-5000-years-of-culture-v-and-a-exhibition-ina-sarikhani-sandmann"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T10:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Five thousand years of Iranian art goes on show at the V&A this month. A private collector who lent many of the works reveals what light these treasures cast on the country
The drive from London to a certain nameless valley in rural Oxfordshire - a preposterously pretty realm of flint cottages, quaint pubs, willow trees and gentle hills - is always slightly unnerving. This part of the country is so close to London and yet the feeling is of stepping back in time, a remoteness that is sudden and unexpected. B…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Cooke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We’re ready for you’: English galleries and museums throw open their doors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/16/were-ready-for-you-english-galleries-and-museums-throw-open-their-doors</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/16/were-ready-for-you-english-galleries-and-museums-throw-open-their-doors"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T09:45:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With few overseas tourists, curators think there has never been a better time for Britons to see their own national treasures
Leading museum and gallery directors have urged the public to grab a once-in-a-lifetime chance to see national treasures up close when the buildings reopen in England on Monday. Social distancing means that great art, like the newly restored Gainsborough, Cornard Wood, at the National Gallery, or the precious archaeological finds from Sutton Hoo in the British Museum, will be easier …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vanessa Thorpe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel Slater’s recipes for a spring vegetable tart, and ricotta stracciatella dessert]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/nigel-slater-recipes-spring-vegetable-tart-and-ricotta-stracciatella-dessert</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/nigel-slater-recipes-spring-vegetable-tart-and-ricotta-stracciatella-dessert"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T09:30:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Capture the taste of spring with green veg and a fresh fruit trifle
I bring radishes home, two bunches at a time, snowy tipped and bushy leaved, and plunge them, leaves and all, into deep, icy water. It feels like the start of something. And so it is, with those late-spring, early-summer trips to the greengrocer, coming home with peas and broad beans – tiny, like doll’s house vegetables – the first tomatoes from the Isle of Wight and, of course, asparagus. There is mint and basil in pots on the windowsill g…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nigel Slater</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How will isolation affect long-term immunity?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/how-will-isolation-affect-long-term-immunity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/how-will-isolation-affect-long-term-immunity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T09:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Healthy immune systems work best when exposed to microbes. So what will lockdown have done to our resistance to germs? 
Every time you kiss another human being intimately for 10 seconds, more than 80m bacteria are transferred from mouth to mouth. If you’re at a party and double dip your tortilla chip into the salsa three times, around 10,000 bacteria will be transferred from your lips to the dip. Say “hi” to your co-workers as you sit down at your office desk and you’ll also be greeted by over 10m bacteria …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Tait</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pity the poor standup in Boris Johnson’s kleptocracy | Stewart Lee]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/pity-the-poor-standup-in-boris-johnsons-kleptocracy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/pity-the-poor-standup-in-boris-johnsons-kleptocracy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T09:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How’s a comedian supposed to be keep pace with this ever more farcical government and its diktats?
Like a great sloppy spaff, the flying shit of the Queen’s speech has hit the fan of functioning democracy full in the face. More than two million of the electorate least likely to support Boris Johnson are to be robbed of their right to vote, while millions of the sort of true Brits who moved to Spain when the local shopping centre installed a Muslamic prayer room are to have theirs reinstated; key environment…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stewart Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mexico faces up to uneasy anniversary of Chinese massacre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/mexico-chinese-massacre-centenary-torreon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/mexico-chinese-massacre-centenary-torreon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T09:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Andrés Manuel López Obrador will mark the killings of 303 Chinese people during the revolution that the city of Torreón has tried to forget
The first to die were Chinese agricultural workers, who were killed in the orchards and gardens surrounding the Mexican city of Torreón by advancing revolutionary forces in the early hours of 13 May 1911.
After skirmishes at the outskirts of the city, the outnumbered federal garrison abandoned their positions and slipped away under the cover of darkness.
 Cont…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Agren in Torreón</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny traces of DNA found in cave dust may unlock secret life of Neanderthals]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/16/tiny-traces-of-dna-found-in-cave-dust-may-unlock-secret-life-of-neanderthals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/may/16/tiny-traces-of-dna-found-in-cave-dust-may-unlock-secret-life-of-neanderthals"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T08:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced technique used to recover genetic material may help solve the mystery of early man
Scientists have pinpointed major changes in Europe’s Neanderthal populations – from traces of blood and excrement they left behind in a Spanish cave 100,000 years ago.
The discovery is the first important demonstration of a powerful new technique that allows researchers to study DNA recovered from cave sediments. No fossils or stone tools are needed for such studies. Instead, minuscule traces of genetic material that…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I fled Syria with just £12 … now I have my own restaurant in Soho]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/i-fled-syria-with-just-12-now-i-have-my-own-restaurant-in-soho</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/i-fled-syria-with-just-12-now-i-have-my-own-restaurant-in-soho"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T08:45:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imad Alarnab lost everything to the war. He never dreamed he could rebuild his restaurants in the UK
When Imad Alarnab, a Syrian chef, arrived in the UK as a refugee five years ago, he could barely afford to eat. Meals were regularly skipped and a Snickers bar could be eked out over a whole day to help him survive. On Monday, the 43-year-old father of three will be celebrating lockdown rules easing with a fairytale twist: Alarnab will be opening the doors to his very own central London restaurant.
“This is …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nosheen Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The secret of how Amundsen beat Scott in race to south pole? A diet of raw penguin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/the-secret-of-how-amundsen-beat-scott-in-race-to-south-pole-a-diet-of-raw-penguin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/the-secret-of-how-amundsen-beat-scott-in-race-to-south-pole-a-diet-of-raw-penguin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T08:15:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starving and trapped by ice, the Norwegian’s crew had discovered how to beat scurvy on an earlier voyage. The benefits proved crucial
Thirteen years before he became the first person ever to reach the south pole in 1911, the Norwegian explorer Roald Amundsen experienced his first merciless taste of winter in the Antarctic. Stuck onboard the Belgian expedition ship Belgica, which was grounded in pack ice, he and the rest of the crew contracted scurvy and faced certain death.
That is when, according to a new …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Ferguson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joanna Scanlan: ‘People do seem to ask me to take my clothes off all the time’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/16/joanna-scanlan-after-love-interview</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/may/16/joanna-scanlan-after-love-interview"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T08:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loved for her biting comedy roles, the actor is enjoying a late-blooming career. She talks about playing a convert to Islam in After Love, and her TV series about women’s sex lives during lockdown
Joanna Scanlan is sitting in splendid isolation in a country house hotel in Sussex, where she has been transforming herself into HE Bates’s voluptuous matriarch, Ma Larkin, for a six-part ITV miniseries. But we’re not here to talk about the Larkins, or any of the other TV roles that have earned her a place as one …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Armitstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour won’t see power again until it remembers the essentials of winning | Andrew Rawnsley]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/labour-will-not-see-power-again-until-it-remembers-the-essentials-of-winning</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/may/16/labour-will-not-see-power-again-until-it-remembers-the-essentials-of-winning"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the all too rare occasions when it has achieved office in the past, Labour has done so with a broad appeal attracting diverse groups of voters
No political party has a divine right to exist. If they did, Britain would still be ruled by the Whigs. There have been a lot of doomy prognostications about Labour’s life expectancy since the big set of elections that alarmed many people in the party with the thought that the calamitous 2019 performance might not be the lowest they could go. 
A trauma was then tu…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Rawnsley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Could ‘engineered’ coral save the planet’s reefs from destruction?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/could-engineered-coral-save-the-planets-reefs-from-destruction</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/could-engineered-coral-save-the-planets-reefs-from-destruction"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:15:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[London Zoo’s latest exhibition shows how scientists hope to halt the devastation caused by overheated oceans
This weekend, conservationists will put the final touches to a giant artificial reef they are assembling at London zoo. Samples of the planet’s most spectacular corals – vivid green branching coral, yellow scroll, blue ridge and many more species – will be added to the giant tank along with fish that thrive in their presence: blue tang, clownfish and many others.
The scene will then be set for Monday…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin McKie Science editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nish Kumar: ‘Do they just hate my jokes?’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/16/nish-kumar-standup-comedian-do-they-just-hate-my-jokes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/may/16/nish-kumar-standup-comedian-do-they-just-hate-my-jokes"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nish Kumar considers himself a mild-mannered British Asian man who does comedy. So why does he attract so much rage from the rightwing press and social media?
Hide your commemorative Brexit coins! Here comes Nish Kumar, scourge of the sensible right, pirate-chief of the woke left, swinging in fresh from a morning spent toppling statues, hexing Conservative politicians, rolling up Union Jack flags and smoking them like giant cartoon cigars… Kidding. The real Nish Kumar is boyish and bearded, a 35-year-old co…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Lamont</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Divorces of the rich and famous: a 1% solution or the start of a trend?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/16/celebrity-divorces-bill-melinda-gates-jeff-bezos-mackenzie</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/16/celebrity-divorces-bill-melinda-gates-jeff-bezos-mackenzie"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With such high-profile splits at Bill and Melinda Gates and Jeff and Mackenzie Bezos, some say the wealthy play by their own rules but celebrities often set standards the rest of us follow
A cascade of recent high-profile divorces of the very rich and famous has presented new questions for the divorce industry – and offered a voyeuristic thrill-ride for millions of the less well-known.
Some of the divorces of recent years have apparently been amicable or pseudo-amicable, such as the tech billionaires Bill a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edward Helmore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can get a table inside again – but what’s the long-term future of restaurants?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/we-can-get-a-table-inside-again-but-whats-the-future-of-restaurants</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/we-can-get-a-table-inside-again-but-whats-the-future-of-restaurants"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Restaurants across the UK are ready to open, indoors and out. We ask a top chef, a restaurateur and a street food team where the hospitality industry will go from here
Tom Kerridge
The Hand & Flowers, Marlow
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tony Naylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I’m seen as the fool’: the farmers putting trees back into the UK’s fields]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/im-seen-as-the-fool-the-farmers-putting-trees-back-into-the-uks-fields</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/16/im-seen-as-the-fool-the-farmers-putting-trees-back-into-the-uks-fields"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T07:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s hoped a 12-year trial in Devon will persuade policymakers to back silvopasture to benefit the soil, livestock and climate
Andy Gray stands beside an enormous hill of bare red earth and smiles with a hint of mischief. This is his best field, its soils known as Crediton red land. The region was once known for producing swedes prized by Covent Garden market. Now, every six metres, planted in rows 14 metres apart, stands a tree guard shielding a young oak, aspen or alder.
“You can grow anything on it and I…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Barkham Photographs by Jim Wileman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The big picture: in celebration of youthful freedom]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-big-picture-sven-jacobsen-photography-like-birds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/16/the-big-picture-sven-jacobsen-photography-like-birds"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T06:00:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Sven Jacobsen’s painterly images, the young become as one with their environment, seemingly without a care in the world
Sven Jacobsen’s photographs ask interesting questions about innocence and bliss. A new book concentrates on images of youthful freedom; teenagers scale fences and climb trees and plunge into lakes, they skateboard and snog and do headstands and backflips and laugh like they will never, ever stop. Any of the pictures might lead advertising campaigns for spring water or blue jeans or perf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Adams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secret history: the warrior women who fought their enslavers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/secret-history-the-warrior-women-who-fought-their-enslavers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/secret-history-the-warrior-women-who-fought-their-enslavers"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T05:15:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Historian Rebecca Hall works with a graphic artist in her new book to reclaim the stories of the female rebels on ships and plantations
Growing up in New York in the 1970s Rebecca Hall craved heroes she could relate to – powerful women who could take care of themselves and protect others. But pickings were slim. The famed feminists of the time, Charlie’s Angels and The Bionic Woman, didn’t cut it for her.
But every night when she went to sleep, her father would recount stories of her grandmother’s life. Har…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rob Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only Food and Courses, London: ‘Deserves to be taken seriously’ – restaurant review]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/only-food-and-courses-london-deserves-to-be-taken-seriously-restaurant-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/may/16/only-food-and-courses-london-deserves-to-be-taken-seriously-restaurant-review"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T05:00:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Del Boy pun is a laugh, but there’s real intent behind the cooking at this Brixton venture
Only Food and Courses, Pop Brixton, 49 Station Road, London SW9 8PQ (onlyfoodandcourses.co.uk). Starters £10, mains £14, desserts £10, wines from £24
On the wall of the space housing this week’s restaurant is a sign which reads: “A brilliantly cheeky twist on classic British food.” There is a lot to unpack here, not least the second word; I’ll be the judge of that and so on. Even before you get to that sign, you h…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Rayner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New York City Pride organisers to ban police from marching until 2025]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/new-york-city-pride-organisers-to-ban-police-from-marching-until-2025</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/16/new-york-city-pride-organisers-to-ban-police-from-marching-until-2025"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T02:32:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Event organisers say police are threatening to some in the LGBTQ+ community, while NYPD called decision ‘disheartening’
Organisers of New York City’s Pride events say they will ban police and other law enforcement personnel from marching in their annual parade until at least 2025 and will also seek to keep on-duty officers a block away from the celebration of LGBTQ+ people and history.
In a statement released on Saturday, NYC Pride urged members of law enforcement to “acknowledge their harm and to correct c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Associated Press</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blue cushion sea stars, short-nosed snakes and sea slugs: 21 days beneath the Timor sea – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/16/blue-cushion-sea-stars-short-nosed-snakes-and-sea-slugs-21-days-beneath-the-timor-sea-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2021/may/16/blue-cushion-sea-stars-short-nosed-snakes-and-sea-slugs-21-days-beneath-the-timor-sea-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T20:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In April, documentary photographer and film-maker Conor Ashleigh walked the gangplank of the research vessel Falkor (RV Falkor) in Darwin to begin a 21-day journey as part of an expedition with the Schmidt Ocean Institute. Having never spent more than a day or two at sea, Ashleigh felt as though he were heading into the unknown. There he discovered intriguing creatures in a seascape of vibrant colours in the pristine waters of Ashmore Marine Park in the Timor sea
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Conor Ashleigh/Schmidt Ocean Institute</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Burnham: ‘Has Labour still got what it takes to fight an injustice? No’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/15/andy-burnham-has-labour-still-got-what-it-takes-to-fight-an-injustice-no</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/may/15/andy-burnham-has-labour-still-got-what-it-takes-to-fight-an-injustice-no"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T19:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Blair minister and twice mayor of Manchester thinks not. But, he says, if members should now decide that he has the vision needed to win back voters, he might consider a return to Westminster 
Andy Burnham is wearing a black sweatshirt, jeans and trainers, having just returned from what he calls a “homelessness walkabout” in central Manchester, talking to rough sleepers. He is in high spirits, as the homeless numbers are right down.
His mood is boosted further when the director of his office, Kevin Lee,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toby Helm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When a vinyl record becomes an artist’s canvas – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/15/when-a-vinyl-record-becomes-an-artists-canvas-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/15/when-a-vinyl-record-becomes-an-artists-canvas-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-05-15T16:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once an album is complete, a test pressing of it is usually made on vinyl. These fragile and extremely rare copies are often kept by musicians as souvenirs, but for a new exhibition called Pressing Matters, 33 test pressings were sent to 33 artists, who were given free rein to use the vinyl and sleeve as a canvas. This week, an auction of their work will be launched and all proceeds will go to mental health charity Music Support
Auction opens 20 May, ends 5 June at heliumlondon.com. On display at Matches, W…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kathryn Bromwich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-Generated Social Media Images]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340136</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/auto-generated-social-media-images/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:34:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about social media images again. You know, the images that (can) show up when you share a link in places like Twitter, Facebook, or iMessage. You’re essentially leaving money on the table without them, because they …
The post Auto-Generated Social Media Images appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is SendGrid? SMTP Email Newsletter Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>609d63e962ab9107fe5aa2ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/what-is-sendgrid-smpt-email-newsletter-tutorial/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:31:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may have heard of the term SMTP before, and wondered what it is. SMTP is a common method for handling email messages. Today I am going to explain what SMTP is, and how to use an SMTP provider such as SendGrid to send emails from your address. What Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React for Beginners: Complete React Cheatsheet for 2021]]></title>
        <id>609ea83362ab9107fe5aa920</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/react-for-beginners-cheatsheet/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T20:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the React for Beginners guide. It's designed to teach you all the core React concepts that you need to know to start building React applications in 2021. I created this resource to give you the most complete and beginner-friendly path to learn React from the ground up. By]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 photographs of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/20-photographs-of-the-week-from-around-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/may/14/20-photographs-of-the-week-from-around-world"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T18:38:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The escalating conflict in Gaza and Israel, young migrants on the border between Mexico and the US, protests against the government in Colombia and the enduring impact of Covid-19: the most striking images from around the world this week
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jim Powell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Development for Beginners – Learn Basic HTML and CSS to Build Your First Web Page]]></title>
        <id>609e8c2162ab9107fe5aa77d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/web-development-for-beginners-basic-html-and-css/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T17:13:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered how websites are built and designed? Do you want to learn the art of web development but you're not that tech savvy – yet? Well, then this tutorial is for you. It's an introduction to Web Development for beginners so you can learn the basics even if]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third of global food production at risk from climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/third-of-global-food-production-at-risk-from-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/may/14/third-of-global-food-production-at-risk-from-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T16:28:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Food-growing areas will see drastic changes to rainfall and temperatures if global heating continues at current rate
A third of global food production will be at risk by the end of the century if greenhouse gas emissions continue to rise at their current rate, new research suggests.
Many of the world’s most important food-growing areas will see temperatures increase and rainfall patterns alter drastically if temperatures rise by about 3.7C, the forecast increase if emissions stay high.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fiona Harvey Environment correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘The therapy has never waned’: Guardian readers on their long relationships with us | Letters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/the-therapy-has-never-waned-guardian-readers-on-their-long-relationships-with-us"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:55:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don Borland on how the paper helped him recover from TB, plus letters from Peter Bird, Elizabeth Jurd, Elizabeth Monger, Graham Head, John Boyle, Andrew Dean, Chas Ball, Tony Meacock, Janet Hulme and Robert Daws

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber. 

In 1953, at the age of 16, I caught tuberculosis. I was in a sanatorium for 18 months. Antibiotics were new and bed rest and lots of fresh air were de rigueur. So I pas…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Letters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340343</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-stylesheet-feature-flags-with-sass-default/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[!default is a Sass flag that indicates conditional assignment to a variable — it assigns a value only if the variable was previously undefined or null. Consider this code snippet:
$variable: 'test' !default;
To the Sass compiler, this line …
The post Creating Stylesheet Feature Flags With Sass !default appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Babcock</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML Boilerplates]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340403</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/html-boilerplates/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T14:13:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manuel Matuzović goes line-by-line through a boilerplate HTML document. I like it. It’s a good reference and has a lot of the same type of stuff I tend to put in the main HTML template. It makes me think about …
The post HTML Boilerplates appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tree-Shaking: A Reference Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/tree-shaking-reference-guide/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Tree-shaking” is a must-have performance optimization when bundling JavaScript. In this article, we dive deeper on how exactly it works and how specs and practice intertwine to make bundles leaner and more performant. Plus, you’ll get a tree-shaking checklist to use for your projects.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Átila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competition: name the date of the Guardian article – week two]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/14/guardian-200-competition-name-the-date-article-week-two"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guess the date the story first appeared to be in with a chance of winning prizes including a ticket to a Masterclass of your choice 
To mark the Guardian’s bicentenary, we are running a competition for readers. We have selected six stories that have appeared over the past 200 years. There is a link between them, but just to make it a little spicier we will not be telling you what that link is.
The first of the six stories was reprinted in the Guardian last Friday (7 May). The second is below, with the other…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blackstock Road: the world on my doorstep – a photo essay]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/blackstock-road-the-world-on-my-doorstep-a-photo-essay</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2021/may/14/blackstock-road-the-world-on-my-doorstep-a-photo-essay"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T06:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photographer Timothy Spurr has been a lifelong resident of Finsbury Park, north London. His work Blackstock Road focuses on food and the environments in which it is served, and examines the stories of independent family businesses of the multi-ethnic community in the area, celebrating the fruits of London’s diversity
Many years later, while sitting at my parents’ home during the first national lockdown of the coronavirus pandemic, I would remember the late afternoons in school uniform, returning to Blacksto…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timothy Spurr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Israel and Palestine on the brink of another war?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/14/are-israel-and-palestine-on-the-brink-of-another-war"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T02:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, discusses what has prompted the worst unrest in Israel and Palestine since 2014
Oliver Holmes, the Guardian’s Jerusalem correspondent, talks to Rachel Humphreys about the violence that has broken out between Israel and Palestine. In recent weeks there has been a sharp escalation in anger over Israel’s half-century occupation, its ever-deepening military grip over Palestinian life and a wave of evictions and demolitions. In Jerusalem, hundreds of Palesti…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Rachel Humphreys with Oliver Holmes, produced by Ned Carter Miles and Axel Kacoutié, executive producers Nicole Jackson and Phil Maynard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340490</id>
        <link href="https://chenhuijing.com/blog/devtools-for-css-layouts-2021-edition/#%F0%9F%9A%B2"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T23:22:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chen Hui Jing covers some recent movement in DevTools:
Firefox’s grid inspector was pretty full-featured from the get-to and released together with CSS grid in Firefox 52. It was constantly improved upon since. Chrome added a basic grid inspector 
…
The post DevTools for CSS layouts 2021 edition appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340573</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/2021-design-systems-survey-courses/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T22:55:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My friends at Sparkbox are doing a survey on design systems, as they do each year. Go ahead and fill it out if you please. Here are the results from last year. In both 2019 and 2020, the vibe was …
The post 2021 Design Systems (Survey/Courses) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create an Email Newsletter [2021 Tutorial] – Design, Layout, Send]]></title>
        <id>609414f32cd0545b5e943526</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-an-email-newsletter-design-layout-send/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T21:19:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you manage a large community, chances are you need a way to communicate updates to your members quickly and efficiently. An email newsletter can be a very effective way to do so. In this article, I am going to provide some tips and suggestions for maximizing the impact and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is Software Testing? The 10 Most Common Types of Tests Developers Use in Projects]]></title>
        <id>609952396008950828b3ea8d</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/types-of-software-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T19:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development and testing go hand in hand. And in the era of agile software development, with quick releases of small iterations, you should do testing more and more frequently.  In order to perform effective testing, you need to know about the different types of testing and when you should]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Tutorial – How to Work with Multiple Checkboxes]]></title>
        <id>609bcc6a62ab9107fe5a9f08</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-work-with-multiple-checkboxes-in-react/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T18:17:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Handling multiple checkboxes in React is completely different from how you use regular HTML checkboxes. So in this article, we'll see how to work with multiple checkboxes in React. You will learn: How to use a checkbox as a Controlled Input in ReactHow to use the array map and reduce]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Lawyer to Engineer at Google – How to Switch Careers and Learn New Skills]]></title>
        <id>609ccb0d62ab9107fe5aa0ce</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/from-lawyer-to-google-engineer/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T16:25:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was a corporate lawyer for 12 years. I never thought I'd be working at Google as a software engineer, but that's what I have been doing for the past year. I'm working remotely until COVID subsides and we can move to San Francisco.  In this article I'm going to]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in the UK: how have you been affected by the Covid variant found in India?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/13/living-in-the-uk-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-covid-variant-found-in-india</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/13/living-in-the-uk-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-covid-variant-found-in-india"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:46:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from those in the UK who have been affected by a rise in cases of the Covid variant, first discovered in India
Scientists have raised concerns about the dramatic rise in cases of a Covid variant first discovered in India in some areas of the UK, including north-west England and London.
With evidence growing that the B.1.617.2 variant is more transmissible than the ‘Kent variant, which fuelled the UK’s second wave of infections, we want to hear from anyone who has been affected by the n…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier()]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340036</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/advanced-css-animation-using-cubic-bezier/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with complex CSS animations, there is a tendency to create expansive @keyframes with lots of declarations. There are a couple of tricks though that I want to talk about that might help make things easier, while staying in …
The post Advanced CSS Animation Using cubic-bezier() appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340118</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svgator-3-0-reshapes-the-way-you-create-and-animate-svg-with-extensive-new-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T14:24:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building animations can get complicated, particularly compelling animations where you aren’t just rolling a ball across the screen, but building a scene where many things are moving and changing in concert. When compelling animation is the goal, a timeline GUI …
The post SVGator 3.0 Reshapes the Way You Create and Animate SVG With Extensive New Features appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['They saw me as mad and needing to be medicated’ | Modern Masculinity]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/video/2021/may/13/they-saw-me-as-mad-and-needing-to-be-medicated-modern-masculinity"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T10:02:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of Modern Masculinity, journalist Iman Amrani speaks to Chris, who after being diagnosed with schizophrenia spent a long time in the mental health system. They discuss medication, frustration at the system, and the importance of being listened to and heard. Dr Rufus May, a clinical psychologist, speaks about how he worked with Chris and other patients to show compassion and empathy, and how this can help people with mental health issues navigate society

Watch other episodes of Modern Mascul…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iman Amrani, Noah Payne-Frank, Mat Heywood, Kyri Evangelou, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making a splash: the best – and funniest – Guardian headlines over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/13/guardian-200-making-a-splash-the-best-and-funniest-headlines-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/may/13/guardian-200-making-a-splash-the-best-and-funniest-headlines-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T06:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Witty, pithy, pretty and hitty, sometimes the headline is better than the story it sits upon

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber.

It’s late. It always is. Just 10 minutes until the front page has to be sent for printing. And above the main story, the splash, hangs a big white space, awaiting inspiration.
The story: Donald Trump’s fractious state visit to the UK in 2019. The words are on the page, but the most impor…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jamie Fahey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is the UK slashing its international aid budget? – podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/13/why-is-the-uk-slashing-its-international-aid-budget-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T02:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson’s government has blamed the Covid crisis for its decision to cut its international aid budget, but is there more to it?
When David Cameron rose to become Conservative party leader, he set about identifying totemic policies that would show his party was changing. As well as promoting new thinking on the environment, he made an effort to highlight his commitment to overseas aid. When he was prime minister, his government signed a target of spending 0.7% of national income on foreign aid into law…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with Patrick Wintour; produced by Joshua Kelly and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build and Deploy a Portfolio with Vue.js Axios, the GitHub REST API, and Netlify]]></title>
        <id>5fde208ae6787e09839407c3</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/build-a-portfolio-with-vuejs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T20:53:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this free book, we will build two simple projects and deploy them on Netlify. We will use Vue.js as our front-end framework, and use different technologies to build our projects.  If you follow this tutorial to the end, you will build a simplified version of Twitter and a]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use the Kivy Python Library to Create Games and Mobile Apps]]></title>
        <id>609c215862ab9107fe5a9fa9</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/use-the-kivy-python-library-to-create-games-and-mobile-apps/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T18:49:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kivy is a free and open source Python framework for developing mobile apps and games with a natural user interface. We just released a 5-hour Kivy course on the freeCodeCamp.org YouTube channel. In this Kivy course, you will learn to create games and applications with Python for every platform]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339960</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/making-disabled-buttons-more-inclusive/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T14:31:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s talk about disabled buttons. Specifically, let’s get into why we use them and how we can do better than the traditional disabled attribute in HTML (e.g. <button disabled> ) to mark a button as disabled.
There are lots of …
The post Making Disabled Buttons More Inclusive appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sandrina Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Palestine: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-palestine-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Palestine and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Hamas and Israel, Israeli jets and Palestinian militants have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Palestine and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in Israel: how have you been affected by the recent violence?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/may/12/living-in-israel-how-have-you-been-affected-by-the-recent-violence"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T13:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We would like to hear from people living in Israel and those who are part of the diaspora on the situation in the region
In the worst violence since the 2014 war between Israel and Hamas, Palestinian militants and Israeli jets have exchanged airstrikes and rocket fire.
We would like to hear from those living in Israel and who are part of the diaspora on how they have been affected.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustrating Design Patterns That Need Fixing: Birthday Picker]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/frustrating-design-patterns-birthday-picker/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this new series of articles on UX, we take a closer look at some frustrating design patterns and explore better alternatives, along with plenty of examples to keep in mind when building or designing one. Let’s start with an infamous birthday picker.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Smashing Stories]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/little-smashing-stories/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the day we sent out our 300th edition of the Smashing Newsletter. This article is a little celebration in which we share little Smashing stories from people working behind the scenes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Yemen's civil war is about to get worse – video explainer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/12/why-yemens-civil-war-is-about-to-get-worse-video-explainer"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T07:05:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than six years after Houthi rebels seized Yemen's capital and forced its government into exile, a bloody civil war still rages across the country. Despite a Saudi-led bombing campaign that has destroyed Yemeni infrastructure and crippled its economy, the Houthis remain in control of most of the country's population centres. 
The Guardian's Middle East correspondent, Bethan McKernan, explains why a new Houthi offensive could heap more misery on the millions of civilians caught in the crossfire

Yemen wa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan, Jamie Macwhirter, Meital Miselevich, Nikhita Chulani and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can Labour survive Britain’s political realignment? - podcast]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/12/can-labour-survive-britains-political-realignment-podcast</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/audio/2021/may/12/can-labour-survive-britains-political-realignment-podcast"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T02:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After another set of disappointing election results, columnist John Harris asks if Labour can ever reconnect with voters in its former heartlands, where support is increasingly swinging to the Conservatives
Last week’s local elections were the first serious electoral test for the Labour leader, Keir Starmer, whose first year in the job has been dominated by Covid-19. It did not go well. On Friday morning the news came through from Hartlepool that Labour had been beaten into second place by the Conservatives…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Presented by Anushka Asthana with John Harris; produced by Sami Kent and Axel Kacoutié; executive producers Phil Maynard, Archie Bland and Nicole Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Selenium and Python to Scrape Websites More Effectively]]></title>
        <id>6096aafe2cd0545b5e944430</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/improve-web-scraping-with-selenium/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:53:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're scraping data from the web with Python, Selenium will often come up as an helpful tool to use. It was originally designed for automated testing, but its scraping capabilities are impressive, too. This is because Selenium can do things that other libraries or frameworks often can't when collecting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name/>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340359</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-pie-timer-re-revisited/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T22:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kitty reflected on an ancient blog post here on CSS-Tricks on how to make an animated pie timer. The old technique is still clever. The new technique is equally clever and much easier. I particularly like the steps() animation function…
The post CSS Pie Timer Re-Revisited appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I could build this during the weekend]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340186</id>
        <link href="https://world.hey.com/joaoqalves/i-could-build-this-during-the-weekend-aa093c5e"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T21:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How many times have you heard that (or even uttered it under your own breath)? I know I’ve heard it in conversations. I also know I’ve wondered the same thing about a product or two — hey, the idea here …
The post I could build this during the weekend appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next Gen CSS: @container]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339138</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/next-gen-css-container/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome is experimenting with @container, a property within the CSS Working Group Containment Level 3 spec being championed by Miriam Suzanne of Oddbird, and a group of engineers across the web platform. @container brings us the ability to …
The post Next Gen CSS: @container appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Una Kravets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340106</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/distributed-persistent-rendering-dpr/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T14:33:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like Jamstack, Netlify is coining this term.
If your reaction is: great, a new thing I need to know about and learn, know that while Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) does involve some new things, this is actually a push …
The post Distributed Persistent Rendering (DPR) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Primer On CSS Container Queries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/complete-guide-css-container-queries/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A prototype of the long-awaited CSS container queries has landed in Chrome Canary and is available for experimentation. Let’s look at what problem is being solved, learn how container queries work, and see how they compare with and complement existing CSS features for layout.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living in the UK: what are your plans on 17 May?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/may/10/tell-us-who-will-you-hug-first-when-the-restrictions-are-lifted"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T13:16:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’d like to hear from those in the UK about how they feel and what they plan to do when restrictions are further eased
Hugging and mixing indoors with friends and family will be allowed in England from next week, and also in Scotland with the exception of Moray, which will “very likely” remain under level three restrictions after a surge in cases.
In Wales, up to six people from different households will be able to meet indoors at pubs, cafes and restaurants from Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian community team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hands, face and empty space: where Covid has left politics - video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/video/2021/may/11/hands-face-and-empty-space-where-covid-has-left-politics-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:59:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among vacant shops and 15% unemployment, John Harris and John Domokos get immersed in Birmingham as it emerges from the pandemic. Amid despair, they discover hope - focused not on a Tory/Labour race for mayor, but communities brilliantly helping themselves 
If you valued this film, please consider supporting the Guardian. Your contribution will help us create more quality journalism free from billionaire backers or political interference. Thank you for being part of our global audience.

Watch other videos …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Domokos, John Harris, Bruno Rinvolucri and Katie Lamborn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Conference Platform We Use For Our Online Events: Hopin]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashingconf-conference-platform-hopin/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the beginning of 2020, the SmashingConf team was ready for a new year. We had so many things that excited us. New speakers, new workshops, new cities, new attendees, new experiences. And as we all know, 2020 had other ideas. With so many people working from home, we thought we would bring our [Smashing workshops](https://smashingconf.com/online-workshops/) from our home offices to yours — but how?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Amanda Annandale)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topframe]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/topframe/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is extremely fun. Jeff Lindsay has created Topframe, and writes:
Anybody that knows how to mess around with HTML can now mess around with their desktop computing experience. Topframe is an open source tool that lets you 
…
The post Topframe appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340208</id>
        <link href="https://benfrain.com/migrating-from-parcel-to-snowpack-build-tool-comparison/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T21:13:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I find build tooling endlessly interesting, especially right now as we’re in a juicy next-gen transitional period with players like Vite, wmr, Snowpack, and esbuild. Hugh Haworth has a good run-down of the new players, and we’ve chatted on …
The post Migrating from Parcel to Snowpack appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339203</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/variable-aspect-ratio-card-with-conic-gradients-meeting-along-the-diagonal/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T14:13:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently came across an interesting problem. I had to implement a grid of cards with a variable (user-set) aspect ratio that was stored in a --ratio custom property. Boxes with a certain aspect ratio are a classic problem in …
The post Variable Aspect Ratio Card With Conic Gradients Meeting Along the Diagonal appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Tudor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Started With React By Building A Whac-A-Mole Game]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/get-started-whac-a-mole-react-game/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Want to get started with React but struggling to find a good place to start? This article should have you covered. We’ll focus on some of the main concepts of React and then we’ll be building a game from scratch!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Jhey Tompkins)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andrew Cotton: from his Nazaré nightmare to surfing world's biggest waves again – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/video/2021/may/10/andrew-cotton-from-his-nazare-nightmare-to-surfing-worlds-biggest-waves-again-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-10T10:53:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2017, big-wave surfer Andrew Cotton suffered what could have been a potential career-ending and life-changing injury after breaking his back during a wipeout in Nazaré, Portugal. Three years later he returned to the same spot to redeem himself and achieve his dream of surfing one of the biggest waves ever. The 37-year-old professional surfer took time to speak to the Guardian to talk through his injury, recovery and journey back to the top.

'A liquid catapult': big-wave surfer returns to scene of nightm…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rukmini Iyer’s recipe for baked ricotta with new-season asparagus]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/feasting-with-ocado/2021/may/07/rukmini-iyers-recipe-for-baked-ricotta-with-thyme-roast-jersey-royals-new-season-asparagus-and-lemon"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:11:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A one-dish wonder full of the joys of spring, The Roasting Tin author’s vibrant, verdant traybake is ready to shop on Ocado.com
This is a lovely seasonal traybake, starring a whole baked ricotta at the centre. Drizzled with olive oil, sea salt and herbs, the warm ricotta works beautifully with the crisp, lemony roast potatoes, the garlic, peas and asparagus. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rukmini Iyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We were there: the Guardian’s most memorable journalism over 200 years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/ng-interactive/2021/may/07/we-were-there-the-guardians-most-memorable-journalism-over-200-years"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T11:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian has published more than 5m pieces of journalism since 1821. With the help of staff, readers, supporters and alumni we pick 200 of the most powerful, and ask Guardian staff past and present to reflect on their enduring appeal. Day eight: British news- power, corruption and spies.

Celebrate 200 years of independent Guardian journalism, and help power our future – make a contribution, or become a subscriber
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff, Ben Longden Mark Rice-Oxley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Organize Product-Related Assets And Collaborate Better]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/product-records-organization-collaboration-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you organize your Google Drive assets? How do you name your Dropbox Paper documents? How do you deal with comments? Let’s get it right.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Valeriia Panina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improving The Performance Of Shopify Themes (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/improving-performance-shopify-themes-case-study/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When dealing with themes for large platforms and CMS, legacy issues often become a bottleneck. In this article, Carson Shold discusses how his team improved the performance and organization of their Shopify themes, and improved maintainability along the way.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carson Shold)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing HTML Payload With Next.js (Case Study)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/reduce-data-sent-client-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article showcases a case study of Bookaway’s landing page performance. We’ll see how taking care of the props we send to Next.js pages can make loading times and Web Vitals better.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From de-stressing to vitamin C: the route to radiance for oily skin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/from-de-stressing-to-vitamin-c-the-route-to-radiance-for-oily-skin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/game-changing-skincare/2021/may/04/from-de-stressing-to-vitamin-c-the-route-to-radiance-for-oily-skin"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T16:31:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a fine line between a dewy glow and shiny skin. Here’s how to achieve the right amount of sheen
An abundance of sebum, the skin’s naturally occurring protective oil, is a good thing. Without it, hair would have no shine and skin no moisture. But overproduction of sebum leads to shiny, oily skin and, often, blemishes.
On the face, sebum is emitted from sebaceous glands, predominantly in the T-zone, the forehead, nose and chin. You can’t change how your skin operates, but you can manage it. Here’s how…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beatrice Aidin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Undoing Mistakes With Git]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/undoing-mistakes-git-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[No matter how experienced you are, mistakes are an inevitable part of software development. But we can learn to repair them! And this is what we'll be looking at in this two-part series: how to undo mistakes using Git.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Tobias Günther)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 36 With Miriam Suzanne: What Is The Future Of CSS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/smashing-podcast-episode-36/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-04T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode, we’re starting our new season of the Smashing Podcast with a look at the future of CSS. What new specs will be landing in browsers soon? Drew McLellan talks to expert Miriam Suzanne to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution Of Jamstack]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/05/evolution-jamstack/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Web-oriented databases, frameworks like Nuxt and Next.js, and even frameworkless approaches are evolving the Jamstack, but the core principles are more powerful than ever.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mathias Biilmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hindu priest struggling to cremate India’s Covid dead – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/video/2021/may/01/the-hindu-priest-struggling-to-cremate-indias-covid-dead-video"/>
        <updated>2021-05-01T06:25:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RamKaran Mishra is a Hindu priest who performs the last rites at the Ghazipur crematorium in east Delhi, on the frontline of India's Covid crisis. He's been cremating up to 150 bodies day after day, working long hours into the night. With no end in sight, and feeling abandoned by his government, Mishra must deal with traumatised families and an ever-present smell of burning bodies

Grief and anger as Covid victims overwhelm Delhi’s crematoriums 


 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmer Khan, Siddharth Bokoli, Puneet Sharma, Richard Sprenger, Katie Lamborn and Charlie Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[May Is In The Air (2021 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you need a little inspiration boost? Well, then our new collection of wallpapers is for you. Designed with love by the community for the community, the wallpapers are available with and without a calendar for May 2021.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Humble `<img>` Element And Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/humble-img-element-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-29T12:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Images have also been a key part of the web. They communicate ideas instantly, but they are also a lot heavier than text to load. This means that it’s essential to get loading and displaying them right, if you want to give your users a fantastic first impression. An excerpt from [Addy's new book](https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/) (also, check a [free PDF preview](http://provide.smashingmagazine.com/eBooks/image-optimization-sample-chapter.pdf)).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Addy Osmani)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From using unexpected tools to practical prepping advice: how to nail DIY with TikTok]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/the-joy-of-trying/2021/apr/28/from-using-unexpected-tools-to-practical-prepping-advice-how-to-nail-diy-with-tiktok"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:35:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tackling a new DIY project can be intimidating – especially if you’ve never tried it before. Tom Druker overcame his fears with help from short videos
Like most of us, I’ve spent much of the past year staring at walls. I moved house shortly before the first lockdown and managed to channel at least some existential anxiety into painting the house. But after that, I hit a wall. So to speak.
I was not raised in a DIY-competent environment. My dad is less DIY and more GSI (get someone in), so while I understand…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Druker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Image Optimization, A New Smashing Book By Addy Osmani]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/image-optimization-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-28T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cat is out! For the last year, we’ve been working with Addy Osmani on a new Smashing Book all around image optimization. And now it’s here. Meet “Image Optimization”, our practical modern guide to delivering high-quality images on the web with the best performance.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Easing Functions For CSS Animations And Transitions]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/easing-functions-css-animations-transitions/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Easing functions can change the look and feel of an animation by affecting the rate, or speed, of an animation. In this article, we’re going to take a deep dive into easing functions and see how we can use them to create those natural and stunning animations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Bake Layers Of Accessibility Testing Into Your Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/bake-layers-accessibility-testing-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility experts Kate Kalcevich and Mike Gifford introduce readers to "layered accessibility testing”, a practice of using a variety of tools and approaches at different stages in the digital product lifecycle to catch accessibility issues early — when it’s easier and cheaper to fix them.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kate Kalcevich &amp; Mike Gifford)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protest in a pandemic: voices of young climate activists – video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/video/2021/apr/23/voices-of-young-climate-activists-how-the-pandemic-changed-the-way-we-protest-video"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T16:39:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From flooding the streets with thousands of activists to mass Zoom calls, Twitter storms and isolation, young protesters have had to adapt to a global pandemic and find new ways to push forward their calls for action on the climate crisis.
We spoke to six 'school strikers', all members of Fridays for Future, about the impact the pandemic and social distancing have had on their movement, and what the future could hold for their protests after more than a year of Covid-19

Climate protesters gather in person …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Morresi and Nikhita Chulani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide To Newly Supported, Modern CSS Pseudo-Class Selectors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/guide-supported-modern-css-pseudo-class-selectors/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-23T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CSS Working Group Editor’s Draft for [Selectors Level 4](https://drafts.csswg.org/selectors-4/) includes several pseudo-class selectors that already have proposal candidates in most modern browsers. This guide will cover ones that currently have the best support along with examples to demonstrate how you can start using them today!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Stephanie Eckles)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design Done Well: The Ordinary Made Extraordinary (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/web-design-done-well-part1/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-22T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes it’s the little things in web life that make us look twice. From carousels to documentation to cookie disclaimers, here are some sites taking the mundane and sprinkling in a little magic.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Frederick O’Brien)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Complete Guide To Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) With Next.js]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/incremental-static-regeneration-nextjs/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T13:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Incremental Static Regeneration (ISR) is a new evolution of the Jamstack, allowing you to update static content instantly without needing a full rebuild of your site. The hybrid approach of Next.js allows you to use ISR for e-commerce, marketing pages, blog posts, ad-backed media, and more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lee Robinson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Content Is Such A Fundamental Part Of The Web Design Process]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/content-fundamental-part-web-design-process/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-21T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As designers, we are often burdened by the responsibility of producing and managing website content. It’s not our job to write it, but it’s not the client’s either. We can avert disaster by including content production in the design process.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Matt Saunders)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making GraphQL Work In WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/making-graphql-work-in-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-20T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s explore the plugins providing GraphQL servers to WordPress. When should we use WPGraphQL, and when the GraphQL API for WordPress? Is there some advantage of one over the other, or some particular task that is easier to accomplish with one of them? In this article, we will find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Leonardo Losoviz)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An In-Depth Guide To Measuring Core Web Vitals]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2021/04/complete-guide-measure-core-web-vitals/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-19T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How are Core Web Vitals measured? How do you know your fixes have had the desired effect and when will you see the results in Google Search Console? Let’s figure it out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Barry Pollard)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>